<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_Host_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.wff</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>NASA GODDARD SPACE FLIGHT CENTER WALLOPS FLIGHT FACILITY</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_Host_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.unk.unk::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:atm.wff::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Anon., Doing Business at Wallops Flight Facility: A Customer Guide,
                   http://sites.wff.nasa.gov/multimedia/docs/CG2007.pdf, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ANONYMOUS2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_Host_PDS3>
        <instrument_host_name>NASA GODDARD SPACE FLIGHT CENTER WALLOPS FLIGHT FACILITY</instrument_host_name>
        <instrument_host_desc>
 
 
  Instrument Host Overview
  ========================
 
  The following information comes from the NASA Wallops website
  (http://www.nasa.gov/centers/wallops/about/index.html):
 
  &apos;NASA Goddard Space Flight Center&apos;s Wallops Flight Facility, located on
  Virginia&apos;s Eastern Shore, was established in 1945 by the National Advisory
  Committee for Aeronautics, as a center for aeronautic research.&apos;
 
  &apos;Wallops is now NASA&apos;s principal facility for management and implementation
  of suborbital research programs. The Wallops Mission Plan includes the
  following objectives:
 
  1. To help achieve NASA&apos;s strategic objectives for scientific and
  educational excellence through cost efficient integration, launch, and
  operations of suborbital and small orbital payloads.
 
  2. To enable scientific, educational, and economic advancement by providing
  the facilities and expertise to enable frequent flight opportunities for a
  diverse customer base.
 
  3. To serve as a key facility for operational test, integration, and
  certification of NASA and commercial next-generation, low-cost orbital
  launch technologies.
 
  4. To pioneer productive and innovative government, industry, and academic
  partnerships.
 
  The research and responsibilities of Wallops Flight Facility are centered
  around the philosophy of providing a fast, low cost, highly flexible and
  safe response to meet the needs of the United States&apos; aerospace technology
  interests and science research. The 1000 full-time Civil Service and
  contractor NASA Wallops employees act as a team to accomplish our mission
  in the spirit of this philosophy.
 
  NASA also opens its unique facilities to industry for space and aeronautics
  research. Wallops expects an increase in commercial launch activity in the
  very near future.&apos;
 
  See &apos;Doing Business at Wallops Flight Facility: A Customer Guide&apos;
  [ANONYMOUS2007] for more information.

        </instrument_host_desc>
        <instrument_host_id>WFF</instrument_host_id>
        <instrument_host_type>Earth Based</instrument_host_type>
    </Instrument_Host_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_Host_PDS3>
