<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:nnsn.lspn</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>unk for LSPN</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.lspn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_PDS3>
        <instrument_name>Unknown</instrument_name>
        <instrument_desc>
 
Instrument Overview
===================
Correspondence indicated the existence of about 4000 images that might
qualify for the archive, and about 3700 were received. Most observers
had done a good job of filtering out the unusable data, and 3540 images
were cataloged and reformatted for the archive. Digital CCD images
comprise 98% of the collection. Many observers, faced with the task of
flat fielding large numbers of CCD images for the first time, submitted
images up until the deadline. With the exception of 65 photographs
digitized at the NNSN Center, only reduced data were accepted. It was
assumed that the observers were the best qualified and equipped properly
to flat field their images. Improved detectors, more telescopes, and
dedicated observers overcame the poor observing circumstances of Comet
Halley&apos;s 1986 apparition to obtain some truly remarkable images that
show much finer detail than the best images taken during the very
favorable 1910 apparition. This, and the fact that there is nearly
continuous coverage for 2 months both pre- and post-perihelion,
provides an unprecedented data set for the study of near-nucleus
phenomena for any comet.
 
The NNSN data are of uneven quality for many possible reasons, and sub-
standard images were often included in cases when there were no other
data. The rationalization for including substandard images is that it
may be possible, with future sophisticated image reconstruction
software, to compensate for imperfect focus or guiding that currently
limits the value of these images.  It was felt that a present-day
archivist cannot accurately predict what data may be useful in the
future as far as the next apparition of Comet Halley. In some cases, the
images are very weak, but these were usually the only narrow-band
images available. In most cases, information on identified defects is
included in the header comments.
 
The Halley Archive contains 3540 NNSN images, which range in time from
recovery in 1982 through the 1989 observing season. The number of images
is near the middle of our range of early estimates. The majority of
images (about three quarters) were taken from mid-October 1985 through
May 1986, during the period of major jet activity, when the comet was
within 2 AU of the Sun. The coverage (see Table II) was excellent during
the spacecraft encounters. There are some gaps during full moon periods
pre-perihelion, as well as solar conjunction Jan. 29 through Feb. 27,
1986.
 
There are no calibration frames included in the archive. Calibration
information, such as step wedge input intensities and output counts, are
included in the HISTORY or COMMENT lines. In some cases, there might be
conversion factors from counts to magnitude or flux units. In other
cases, total counts, times and exposures of standard stars are given.
 
Table I lists the filters used and their wavelengths at 50 percent (and
for some also at 10 percent) of maximum transmission. These numbers do
not take into account detector responses or atmospheric extinction. For
more information on transmission characteristics, the observers should
be contacted directly.  There are five general categories of filters:
 
(1) Four standard broadband photometry filters sets are not specifically
intended to isolate cometary emissions. During the period of maximum
activity (January-April 1986) the dominant source was dust, but the V
and B bands have sizable contributions from C2 and CN emissions. Some
filter data were obtained from Thuan and Gunn (1976) and from Bessell
(1979).
 
(2) Schott glass filters were used primarily as short-wavelength cutoff
filters. The table indicates the 10 percent and 50 percent cutoff
wavelengths, while the effective peak and the long wavelength cutoffs
were defined by the detectors.
 
(3) IHW/IAU cometary filters are imaging quality versions of the
standard photometry bandpasses. The values in the table are the mean of
all those measured and are correct to 1 nm. Further details can be found
in the Photometry and Polarimetry Network summary. Our IHW filter
names are intended to indicate the effective peak wavelengths (in nm)
and the emissions they should isolate. The continuum bands are indicated
by BC (blue continuum), MC (mid continuum) and RC (red continuum).
 
(4) Giotto Halley Multicolor Camera filters were used to provide ground-
based calibration during the flyby. The filter characteristics are taken
from Keller et al. (1982).
 
(5) Special bandpass filters are the remaining miscellaneous filters
that observers usually selected to investigate special spectral
features. A particularly useful example is the 618H2O+, which isolates
the (0,8,0) emission of H2O+ and provides excellent images of the ion
tail.
 
 
Table I. Characteristics of Filters Used for NNSN Images.
______________________________________________________________________
 
      Category             Cut-on (nm)                  Cut-off (nm)
____________________     _______________    Central   ________________
                                          Wavelength
IHW name  Other name      10%       50%      (nm)       50%       10%
______________________________________________________________________
 
Standard Broadband
 
B         Johnson B                 386       440       494
V         Johnson V                 491       548       605
R         Johnson R                 585       650       715
I         Johnson I                 729       825       921
 
Gunn G                              458       493       528
Gunn R                              610       655       700
Gunn I                              690       780       880
 
Mould B                             386       442       498
Mould V                             501       546       591
Mould R                             585       647       708
Mould I                             732       829       927
 
Cousins B                           390       440       530
Cousins V                           500       550       600
Cousins R                           620       640       700
Cousins I                           700       790       900
 
Wide B                              400       450       500
Wide R                    550       560        -         -         -
 
Schott Glass
 
GG7                       475       460        -         -         -
GG11                      420       480        -         -         -
GG13                      440       490        -         -         -
GG455                     450       455        -         -         -
GG495                     490       495        -         -         -
OG530                     525       530        -         -         -
RG1                       600       610        -         -         -
RG610                     600       610        -         -         -
RG665                     660       665        -         -         -
 
IHW/IAU Comet Imaging
 
309OH                     305       306       309       313       314
365BC                     360       362       365       368       370
387CN                     384       386       387       390       401
406C3                     401       402       406       409       410
426CO+                    422       423       426       429       430
485MC                     481       482       485       487       489
514C2                     507       508       514       519       520
684RC                     678       679       684       688       689
703H2O+                   689       691       703       713       714
 
Giotto Multicolor Camera
 
314OH     C10             293       295       298       323       336
408C3     C11             399       403       410       419       422
HMCB      C5              320       336       395       488       489
450BC     C8              441       443       453       457       458
509C      C12             499       502       511       520       524
HMCO      C4              578       585       652       702       714
731RC     C9              715       718       728       743       746
HMCR      B/C3            695       705        -         -         -
 
Special Bandpasses
 
315OH                               310       315       320
457CO+                              454       457       459
598NH2                              596       598       600
600HN2                              580       600       620
619H2O+                             617       619       621
625CONT                             624       625       625
630OI                               628       630       632
630TLT                              627       629       631
H ALPHA                             646       656       666
701RC                               691       701       711
852CONT                             826       852       878
860CONT                             854       860       866
910CN                               900       910       920
918CN                               912       918       924
______________________________________________________________________
 
 
Listed below some features of some specific data sets that the user
should be aware of.
 
The Wise Observatory polarization images of Eaton (402601-21) are broken
into separate fields separated by blank spaces.
 
The COMETMAX and SKYMIN values for the images taken when Comet Halley
was at large heliocentric distances (400001-012, 403801-950, 406001-124)
are only guideline values to produce a good display, since the comet is
sometimes only a few counts above the background.
 
The photographs from Mt. Johns Observatory and Cerro El Roble (402501-
546, 402551-566) were digitized using an LPL CCD camera and macro lens
adjusted to give an appropriate scale. When there is sensitometric
calibration, the digitized step values and their relative input
intensities are given in the header comments.  The Cerro El Roble films
had multiple exposures, so when there are two images per field, the time
and exposure of the faintest image is given in the header comment. The
user should be aware that there will be two sets of field stars in these
images.
 
Scientific Objectives Summary
=============================
When the International Halley Watch (IHW) was formed, cometary near
nucleus study was a field with little quantitative foundation, based
largely on descriptive reports of primarily visual observations of coma
morphology. One of the most extensive of these was Bobrovnikoff&apos;s (1931)
monograph on the 1910 apparition of Comet Halley. The potential of such
studies was underscored with the publication of the Atlas of Cometary
Forms by Rahe et al. (1969), which illustrated some of the interesting
coma patterns in Comet Halley observed over the previous two
apparitions. The application of modern photographic emulsions in
recording the spectacular spiral jets in Comet Bennett (1970 II) (Larson
and Minton, 1972), the analysis of expanding haloes to estimate nucleus
rotation periods by Whipple (1978, 1980), and the quantitative modeling
of fans and jets by Sekanina (1979, 1981a,b) provided further
justification for a dedicated network to observe the expected changing
coma pattern of Comet Halley. From the onset it was clear that the NNSN
strategy for obtaining data would be similar to that of the Large Scale
Phenomena Network (LSPN), but that details, such as optimum detectors,
plate scales, temporal coverage, and acquisition of telescope time
needed to be defined.
 
In the broadest sense, the goal of near-nucleus studies is to understand
the processes taking place in the coma as they relate to the physical
nature of the cometary nucleus. Assuming that the observed coma
distribution results from the ejection of material from a possibly
inhomogenous, rotating nucleus, coma anisotropy can be used as a tracer
of nucleus activity and motion. By measuring the motions of coma
features and extrapolating back to the time of ejection, it is possible
to locate the active areas on the nucleus, and by observing a sufficient
number of features over time, determine or constrain the nucleus
rotational motion. Knowledge of the distribution and evolution of active
areas may provide important clues to the internal structure of the
nucleus and of the comet formation environment. To fulfill these goals
for Comet Halley, the Near Nucleus Studies Network (NNSN) was designed
to obtain data on the spatial and temporal distribution of matter in the
coma at the highest possible resolution, especially during the period of
maximum activity in 1985-86.

        </instrument_desc>
        <instrument_id>NNSN</instrument_id>
        <instrument_serial_number>not applicable</instrument_serial_number>
        <instrument_type>Camera</instrument_type>
        <instrument_version_id>not applicable</instrument_version_id>
    </Instrument_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_PDS3>
