<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:hsotp.mtsc14</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>HIGH SPEED OCCULTATION TIMING PHOTOMETER for MTSC14</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.mtsc14::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_PDS3>
        <instrument_name>HIGH SPEED OCCULTATION TIMING PHOTOMETER</instrument_name>
        <instrument_desc>
 
Instrument Overview
===================
 
  The High-Speed Occultation Timing Photometer is operated by the
  University of Maryland (UMD).  The system consists of a portable
  Celestron C-14 Schmidt-Cassegrain telescope, a photometry package
  (optics, selectable apertures, eyepiece, and detector), and
  an electronics package for operating the system and recording data.
 
 
Optics
======
 
  The following optical parameters can be found at manufacturer&apos;s
  (Company 7) web site, http://www.company7.com/celectron/products:
 
    Design               : Schmidt-Cassegrain Catadioptric
    Effective Aperture   : 14 inches, 355.6 millimeters
    Nominal Focal Length : 154 inches, 3910 millimeters
    Nominal Focal Ratio  : f/11
    Primary Mirror       : 14.25-inch diameter, f/2.14, spherical
    Secondary Mirror     : 3.5-inch diameter, spherical
    Central Obstruction  : 4.5 inches overall
    Optical Tube         : 30 inches long, 16-inch diameter
    Back Focus           : 14 inches from apex of primary mirror
    Optimum back focus   : Approximately 4 inches
    Finder scope         : 5-inch diameter
 
  For observations with the photomultiplier detector, any one of
  four apertures is inserted into the focal plane of the telescope,
  to select a field of view of 30 arcseconds.  The aperture is
  positioned over the target of interest, and all light passing
  through is recorded by the photomultiplier tube and electronics
  as a function of time.
 
 
Detector
========
 
  The detector is an EMI 9892B/350 bi-alkali, borosilicate
  photomultiplier tube with end-on illumination.  For observations
  made without filters, the responsivity is determined mainly by
  the combination of the photocathode response with the borosilicate
  transmission curve:  peak response occurs near 375 nm and
  half-quantum-efficiency points occur near 310 nm and 520 nm.
  The resultant bandpass of the telescope and photometer system
  ranges from 312 to 615 nanometers with an effective wavelength of
  453 nanometers.
 
 
Electronics
===========
 
  The electronics package first converts signal (from the target) and
  reference currents to voltages, then to audio signals using a
  voltage-to-frequency converter.  The electronics combine the
  audio signal with an audio timing broadcast and voice comments,
  then record these data on a four-track audiotape recorder.
 
  The audio timing track is typically time and frequency information
  broadcast by the WWV radio station operated by the National Institute
  of Standards and Technology (NIST).  Information about WWV is available
  at the NIST Time and Frequency web site:
 
    http://tf.nist.gov/timefreq/index.html
 
  During data collection, the observers record the UTC time associated
  with selected WWV seconds ticks.  Later, the four-track audiotapes
  are digitized, and the recorded UTC times are used to synchronize
  the data.  The resulting digitized data are considered to be raw.
 
  Before the D/Shoemaker-Levy 9 impact expedition to Mt. Singleton,
  the UMD high-speed digital electronics were inoperable.  A similar
  occultation timing system with the same high-speed analog electronics
  was borrowed from Lowell Observatory and used on this expedition.
 
 
Measured Parameters
===================
 
  For the D/Shoemaker-Levy 9 expedition to Mt. Singleton, the goal
  was to measure the light curves of Io and Europa during the impacts
  of several fragments of the comet with Jupiter.  The following data
  were recorded directly onto a four-track audiotape:
 
    1. Data counts produced the photometer, recorded as a frequency
    2. WWV time signals
    3. A 60Hz reference signal
    4. Voice comments of the observers
 
 
Operational Considerations
==========================
 
  To perform tracking, the target should first be centered in the field
  of view.  Then, an observer looks through the five-inch finder scope
  attached to the telescope and uses a hand paddle to guide on the target.
  Wind may interfere with tracking if the system is unprotected.

        </instrument_desc>
        <instrument_id>HSOTP</instrument_id>
        <instrument_serial_number>not applicable</instrument_serial_number>
        <instrument_type>Photometer</instrument_type>
        <instrument_version_id>not applicable</instrument_version_id>
    </Instrument_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_PDS3>
