<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:irphot.lspn</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>IHW INFRARED PHOTOMETRY DATA for LSPN</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.lspn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_PDS3>
        <instrument_name>IHW INFRARED PHOTOMETRY DATA</instrument_name>
        <instrument_desc>
 
  Instrument Overview
  ===================
In early discussions about plans for comet Halley observations, many
observers put a high priority on systematic measurements of the infrared
fluxes.  Objectives included study of the evolution of the coma and
tail, and of spectral features such as the silicate emission near 10
microns. Several groups organized monitoring programs at major
observatories.  The larger ones were at the European Southern
Observatory (ESO), the Gornergrat Infrared Observatory (TIRGO), the NASA
Infrared Telescope Facility (IRTF), the O&apos;Brien Observatory (Minnesota),
the South African Astrophysical Observatory (SAAO), and the United
Kingdom Infrared Telescope (UKIRT). Additional programs were organized
at Beijing Astronomical Observatory, Cerro Tololo Inter-American
Observatory (CTIO), Haute-Provence Observatory (OHP), Kitt Peak National
Observatory (KPNO), Sternberg State Astronomical Institute, and Yunnan
Observatory.  Individual contributions by a number of observers added to
the total.
 
Infrared filters were a difficult issue.  Discussions with observers led
us to conclude that for several reasons it was impractical to arrange
for a dedicated infrared filter set for the comet Halley observations.
First, the observatories had their own filters in multipurpose
instruments that could not be modified for comet observations. Second,
emission lines do not dominate the comet infrared spectrum so that
filter passband locations are less critical than in the visible spectral
region.  Third., sub-percent precision infrared photometry of comets is
currently not a high priority, and fourth, the standard (JHKL, etc.)
system had been used in previous comet observations.  Consequently, we
recommended that the standard system be used in the near infrared
observations.  Unfortunately, in some instances filters in the JHKL set
differ among observatories, and transformations must be worked out (cf.
Tokunaga 1987, Hanner and Tokunaga 1990).  On the other hand, several
observatories used nearly identical filters from a set manufactured by
the Optical Coating Company and described in the Infrared Stock Filter
Catalog (1987).  To try to ameliorate the problems caused by non-
standard filters, we put information, including transmission curves,
into the archive
 
A related problem is that of standard stars in the infrared.  Here, too,
we need more standardization and precision.  Hanner and Tokunaga (1990)
discuss these issues in a review paper about infrared techniques and
comets.
 
The Infrared Studies Network purchased and distributed long wavelength
filters centered at 18.0, 20.0, and 22.0 microns because bandpass
filters at these wavelengths were not available. Sets were sent to CTIO,
IRTF, KPNO, MSFC, and the University of Minnesota.  Unfortunately,
purchasing delays held up the filters until after Halley&apos;s perihelion.
As far as we are aware, only observers at the IRTF used them to observe
comet Halley.  We hape that the filters will be useful in future comet
observations.
 
When requested to or when it appeared useful, we supplied ephemerides,
comet news, or information on parallel observing programs to the
observers. We used the electronic mail networks, the Arizona State
message board, and written communications, but telephone calls had the
most impact.
 
There was less interest in coordinating observations with different
techniques and at different wavelengths than we expected.  For example,
there was not, as far as we can tell, much coordinated visual and
infrared monitoring.  It is not clear how much of scientific value was
actually lost by this.  On the other hand, there was extensive infrared
coverage on the Halley Watch days and near the encounter times of the
Giotto and VEGA spacecraft.
 
 
Scientific Objectives Summary
=============================
In the early 1980&apos;s, infrared studies of comets were still a relatively
young field although observations had been made in the previous one and
a half decades.  These included broad-band photometric measurements,
selected intermediate-resolution spectroscopy (resolving powers of 50-
100), and some spatial measurements of infrared emission from the coma
and tails (Wilkening 1982).  The observations had established a base of
information on the infra- red properties of comets (primarily dust) by
1982 when the IHW was organized. The number of telescopes with infrared
capability and the number of infrared astronomers had increased about
tenfold in the previous decade, and infrared instrumentation had
dramatically advanced.  Thus it was clear that a concerted effort of
infrared observations of comet Halley could help us learn much about
comets.
 
The IHW assigned all infrared (loosely defined as 1-1000 microns) obser-
vations to the Infrared Studies Network.  This meant that the IR Network
had to deal with photometry, spectroscopy, polarimetry, and imaging.
Obviously, these areas had somewhat different goals and problems, which
were reflected in the organization of the observations and the data
archiving.
 
Relatively few infrared astronomers had observed comets extensively be-
fore the IHW.  This put demands on them to become familiar with the
issues and methods of cometary science, and sometimes raised questions
about observing techniques (fortunately only rarely after the fact).  Of
course, it was an objective of the IHW to advocate and encourage comet
science, and maybe we succeeded.  Probably, however, comet Halley itself
and the accompanying excitement deserve most of the credit for the
present interest in comets.
 
Some of the data will probably not appear elsewhere, but much of the
material has been published in some form in the scientific literature.
However, even for published material, the archive often contains unique
data or information.  For example, some observers chose to publish
averaged magnitudes or fluxes of several observations taken in a night.
When the data were available, the archive includes all the measurements
rather than just the averaged values.  The archive also provides
information about apertures, filters, air masses, and miscellaneous
material that might not be published.
 
When photometry data appeared in the literature and the authors
submitted nothing to the IHW (a few cases), we entered the published
data to make the archive as complete as possible.  In all these cases,
the archive files contain the references.
 
Polarimetry files follow the same format as photometry, that is, ASCII
tables with wavelength (filter), polarization magnitude, polarization
direction, and ancillary information.  Most of the data do not appear in
digital form in the published literature.
 
The spectroscopy and imaging files are usually in the STANDARD format
FITS files. Since published spectroscopy and image data appear largely
in graphical form, the digital data in the archive are the unique
resource in most cases. Many image data sets contain calibration images
and comparison- star information.
 
To make the archive as complete as possible, we created files for those
dates when we knew of scheduled observations, even if we could not get
the data. These files contain keyword information and references to
assist archive users in tracking down material. The amount of missing
material known to us is small (a few percent of all the data taken,
including photometry, spectroscopy, and imaging).  Of course, published
material is not lost. However, the data in digital form that the archive
contains will be a resource for future researchers.  We urge those who
did not submit their data to consider publishing them in extended form
or including them in the Planetary Data System Archive.
 
The result is nearly 600 files including the filter files.  We estimate,
however, that all of it will occupy only about 1% of the space of a
compact disk.

        </instrument_desc>
        <instrument_id>IRPHOT</instrument_id>
        <instrument_serial_number>not applicable</instrument_serial_number>
        <instrument_type>Photometer</instrument_type>
        <instrument_version_id>not applicable</instrument_version_id>
    </Instrument_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_PDS3>
