<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:pfes.fexp</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>PORTABLE FIELD EMISSION SPECTROMETER for FEXP</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.fexp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hoover, G., and A.B. Kahle, A portable spectrometer for use
                   from 5 to 15 micrometers, JPL Publication 1986-19, 1986.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JPLPUB1986-19</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_PDS3>
        <instrument_name>PORTABLE FIELD EMISSION SPECTROMETER</instrument_name>
        <instrument_desc>
 
 
    INSTRUMENT: PORTABLE FIELD EMISSION SPECTROMETER
          HOST: FIELD EXPERIMENT
 
 
    Instrument Information
    ======================
      Instrument Id                  : PFES
      Instrument Host Id             : FEXP
      Instrument Name                : PORTABLE FIELD EMISSION
                                         SPECTROMETER
      Instrument Type                : SPECTROMETER
      Instrument Manufacturer Name   : JET PROPULSION LABORATORY
 
 
    Instrument Description
    ======================
      The Portable Field Emission Spectrometer (PFES) was built for
      the purpose of measuring the ambient spectral thermal emission
      of geologic materials in situ, thus avoiding the disturbance of
      the natural setting which occurs during sample collection.
      This instrument was designed and built at the Jet Propulsion
      Laboratory (JPL).  The spectral range covered is 5 to 14.5
      micrometers and the resolution is approximately 1.5% of the
      wavelength (0.1 - 0.2 micrometers).
 
      The PFES system consists of two main parts, the sensor head and
      the data recorder.  Accessories include a gas bottle, signal
      monitoring box, reference hot and cold blackbodies, and
      connecting cables.  The sensor head contains the optics, the
      detector, and the preamplifiers.  During operation, the sensor
      head is connected by a hose to a tank that supplies high
      pressure argon gas for cooling the detector.  The data recorder
      consists of a lap-top computer, signal processing circuitry,
      scan sequencing logic circuits, and the power supply.  The
      analyzing element of the spectrometer is a filter wheel
      containing three filter segments (continuously variable
      multilayer interference filters).  The detector is a MCT
      (mercury-cadmium-telluride) photoconductor.
 
      Spectral measurements of the target are made relative to the
      spectrum of a reference blackbody at ambient temperature.  The
      kinetic temperature of this blackbody is measured using an
      attached thermistor.  Usually about two to three spectra of
      each target are measured to provide a check of consistency and
      to reduce noise by averaging.  Each spectrum takes about thirty
      seconds to scan.  The instrument response function is checked
      during each operation by measuring a second blackbody at a much
      lower temperature (the cold blackbody) and comparing this
      measured radiance against calculated radiances at that
      temperature from the tables of instrument responses.
 
      Emissivity can be calculated by dividing the target radiance by
      the radiance of a blackbody at the same temperature.  Target
      kinetic temperature is determined as the lowest temperature
      which produces a calculated blackbody curve that is greater
      than the curve of the target spectral radiance and tangent to
      the target spectral radiance curve in the region between 7.0
      and 7.5 micrometers (in general, most silicates closely
      approach blackbody behavior in this wavelength region).
      However, in the case of field spectroscopy, in addition to
      radiance from the surface, the instrument is also sensitive to
      the emitted skylight radiance.  The skylight radiance is
      reflected from the surface and scattered into the instrument&apos;s
      field of view.  To correct for the reflected skylight term, the
      radiance of a texturized aluminum plate (e=0.01 to 0.05) is
      measured.
 
 
    Science Objectives
    ==================
      Measure radiance from the surface in thermal infrared
      wavelengths.
 
 
    Operational Considerations
    ==========================
      Not Applicable
 
 
    Calibration Description
    =======================
      Not Applicable
 
 
    Section &apos;PFES&apos;
    ==============
      Total Fovs                     : 1
 
 
      &apos;PFES&apos; Section Parameter &apos;RADIANCE&apos;
      -----------------------------------
        Radiance is the amount of energy per time per projected area
        per steradian.
 
        Instrument Parameter Name      : RADIANCE
        Sampling Parameter Name        : WAVELENGTH
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : 5.000000
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : 14.500000
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : 0.095000
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : MICROMETER
 
 
      Description
      -----------
        Not Applicable
 
 
      Sensitivity
      -----------
        Not Applicable
 

        </instrument_desc>
        <instrument_id>PFES</instrument_id>
        <instrument_serial_number>not applicable</instrument_serial_number>
        <instrument_type>Spectrometer</instrument_type>
        <instrument_version_id>not applicable</instrument_version_id>
    </Instrument_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_PDS3>
