<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rscn.rsn</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>VARIOUS RADIO TELESCOPES for RSN</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.rsn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Sekanina, Zdenek (ed.), &apos;The Comet Halley Archive Summary Volume&apos;, Jet
                   Propulsion Laboratory, California Institute of Technology, Pasadena,
                   California, JPL D-400-450, August 1991.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JPL_D-400-450</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_PDS3>
        <instrument_name>VARIOUS RADIO TELESCOPES</instrument_name>
        <instrument_desc>
 
 
    Instrument Overview
    ===================
    The data in the continuum subnetwork are fundamentally
    different from the spectral line observations since they
    represent a total power. In the archive, all continuum
    observations also use Janskys to express their results
    regardless of how the data are actually internally
    calibrated. Thus, a grid of data or upper limit is the final
    observation. Upper limits are reported in the HISTORY
    section of the FITS header in the HISTORY LIMIT keyword. The
    detection status of a particular observation is summarized
    in the third character of the DAT-TYPE keyword. An S implies
    that the observation did not yield a detection and is
    reported as a limit. However, in some cases marginal
    results, designated by M in the DAT-TYPE keyword have also
    been reported as limits.
 
          Details on the instrument system are given in the
    table below:
 
                   CONTINUUM (RSCN)
 
    ___________________________________________________________
    SYSTEM  OBSERV. LOCATION         INSTRUMENT  TELESC.
    ___________________________________________________________
    65001401 IRAM     PICO VELETA SPAIN S940058C314F    30M
    65001901 MPI      EFFELSBERG GFR    S240047C413F   100M
    65000701 BOLOGNA  BOLOGNA ITALY     S140057C223T    32M
    65001001 YUNNAN   KUNMING CHINA     S130028C536T    10M
    65002601 CSIRO    PARKES NSW        S530000C223T    64M
    65002604 MOLONGLO HOSKINSTOWN NSW   I820000E513T   MOST
    65001609 NRAO-VLA SOCORRO NM        I230000E000T    VLA
    65000201 ROI      ATIBAIA BRAZIL    S241558C326T    14M
    ___________________________________________________________
 
 
    Scientific Objectives
    =====================
         Radio Astronomy is a developing new technique for the
    study of comets. In some areas, such as observations of the
    OH radical via its 18 cm transitions, the observational
    procedures and analysis are well developed. Studies in these
    areas have proved their value since they both provide new
    probes of important physical processes as well as a window
    on physical processes which are less well-known and less
    accessible to study by other techniques. In many other areas,
    however, the study of comets at radio wavelengths continues
    to be primarily an exploratory endeavor. In recognition of
    this fact, the IHW Radio Science Discipline Specialist team
    felt that it was important to attempt many different kinds of
    observations during this campaign on Halley&apos;s Comet, since each
    observation has scientific merit as an exploration. Thus, we
    have been careful to document and include all data submitted
    to this archive by radio observers.
 
         The P/Halley Archive contains data from 36 different
    observing groups, representing a range of techniques. The
    majority of the observational data comes in the well
    developed area of 18cm OH observations. However, many other
    projects were attempted as well. Approximately 75% of the
    groups who are known to have obtained useful data on the
    comet have submitted it to the archive, and we are grateful
    to them for their contributions.
 
 

        </instrument_desc>
        <instrument_id>RSCN</instrument_id>
        <instrument_serial_number>not applicable</instrument_serial_number>
        <instrument_type>Radio</instrument_type>
        <instrument_version_id>not applicable</instrument_version_id>
    </Instrument_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_PDS3>
