<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:tims.c130</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>THERMAL INFRARED MULTISPECTRAL SCANNER for C130</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.c130::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Palluconi, F.D., and G.R. Meeks, Thermal Infrared
                   Multispectral Scanner (TIMS): An investigator&apos;s guide to
                   TIMS data, JPL Publication 1985-32, 1985.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JPLPUB1985-32</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kahle, A.B., and E. Abbott, (Eds.), The TIMS data user&apos;s
                   workshop; June 18 and 19, 1985, JPL Publication 1986-38,
                   1986.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JPLPUB1986-38</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_PDS3>
        <instrument_name>THERMAL INFRARED MULTISPECTRAL SCANNER</instrument_name>
        <instrument_desc>
 
 
    INSTRUMENT: THERMAL INFRARED MULTISPECTRAL SCANNER
          HOST: NASA C-130 AIRCRAFT
 
 
    Instrument Information
    ======================
      Instrument Id                  : TIMS
      Instrument Host Id             : C130
      Instrument Name                : THERMAL INFRARED MULTISPECTRAL
                                         SCANNER
      Instrument Type                : THERMAL INFRARED SPECTROMETER
      Build Date                     : 1981-01-01
      Instrument Mass                : 99.800000
      Instrument Length              : 0.940000
      Instrument Width               : UNK
      Instrument Height              : 0.762000
      Instrument Manufacturer Name   : DAEDALUS ENTERPRISES, INC.
 
 
    Instrument Description
    ======================
      The TIMS instrument is a six-channel thermal infrared
      spectrometer with a spectral range between 8.0 and 12.0
      micrometers.  Cross-track scanning is achieved through rotation
      of a 45 degree flat scan mirror that reflects incident energy
      to a 19 cm diameter, 33 cm focal length parabolic primary
      mirror.  The energy is then directed into the spectrometer
      section of the instrument by a flat secondary mirror.  Both the
      primary and secondary mirrors are aluminum coated with an
      overcoating of silicon oxides.  At the entrance to the
      spectrometer section and at the focal plane of the primary
      mirror is a 0.8 mm field stop aperture which defines the
      instrument&apos;s 2.5 mrad Instantaneous-Field-of-View (IFOV).
 
      After passing through the field stop the energy is collimated
      by an off-axis parabolic section mirror and directed to a
      replica grating of 12 grooves per mm with a blaze angle of 3.4
      degrees, which produces the spectral dispersion.  A germanium
      triplet image lens is used to form an image of the field stop
      in the detector plane.  The image size is 0.38 mm in this
      plane.
 
      The detector consists of a linear array of six MCT
      (mercury-cadmium-telluride) detector elements mounted on a
      cold finger from the inner flask of a liquid nitrogen dewar.
      The width of these detectors (0.43 mm) is a little larger than
      the image of the field stop aperture and the length is set by
      the desired bandwidth.  The thermal reference sources are
      mounted on the scan head so the scan mirror views one after
      scanning across the Field-of-View (FOV).  This permits line by
      line calibration of the TIMS data.
 
      The TIMS optical system consists of a 19 cm diameter Newtonian
      reflector telescope mounted behind an object-plane 45 degree
      flat scanning mirror and followed by a Czerny-Turner
      spectrometer.  The primary optical system uses a f1.9 parabolic
      primary mirror with a field determining aperture located in its
      focal plane.  An off-axis parabolic mirror is used to collimate
      the energy emerging from the aperture which is then dispersed
      by the diffraction grating and re-imaged on the detector array
      by a fast f0.6 germanium lens.
 
      All of the primary optical elements, the field stop, the
      off-axis collimator, and the detector dewar are mounted on
      sliding blocks controlled by Invar metering rods to provide the
      active thermal compensation for scan head ambient temperature
      changes.  The three element germanium imaging lens is also
      internally thermally compensated for changes in ambient
      temperature.
 
 
    Science Objectives
    ==================
      The objective of TIMS is to acquire data from which spectral
      emissivity and thermophysical property parameters could be
      extracted for selected targets.
 
 
    Operational Considerations
    ==========================
      Not Applicable
 
 
    Calibration Description
    =======================
      Two thermal references sources are mounted in the TIMS scanner
      head; thus the scan mirror views one before and one after
      scanning across the Field-of-View (FOV).  This permits
      line-by-line calibration of TIMS data.  Each reference source
      is a 20.3 cm square copper plate coated with Krylon 1602
      ultra-flat black paint (paint layer is 0.64 cm thick).
      Thermistors are mounted in slots cut into the rear of these
      plates.
 
      Reference source 1 can be heated or cooled and is used as the
      lower temperature reference source.  Reference source 2 can be
      heated only and is used for the higher temperature reference
      source.  The emissivities of the thermal reference sources are
      known (presumably emissivity=1.0 for the black paint surface).
      The temperatures of both references are set before the flight
      (usually 10 and 30 degrees C) and are measured independently
      throughout the flight using the embedded thermistors
      (temperatures of both reference sources are recorded from the
      thermistors during each scan of the instrument).  At the same
      time the thermistor temperatures are recorded, the scanner head
      records a DN value for each reference source through all of the
      six channel filters, consecutively.  Each DN value recorded for
      the reference sources for each of the six channels can then be
      related directly to a radiance value through the following
      relationship which translates the scene DNs for each scan line
      into physical units using the internal reference sources.  This
      also allows any scan to scan differences in the system
      operation to be easily detected.
 
 
    Section &apos;TIMS&apos;
    ==============
      Total Fovs                     : 1
      Scan Mode Id                   : UNK
      Sample Bits                    : 8
 
 
      &apos;TIMS&apos; Detectors
      ----------------
        TIMS
 
 
      &apos;TIMS&apos; Electronics
      ------------------
        TIMS
 
 
      In modes
      --------
        OPERATING
 
 
      &apos;TIMS&apos; Section FOV Shape &apos;LINEAR&apos;
      ---------------------------------
        Section Id                     : TIMS
        Fovs                           : 1
        Horizontal Pixel Fov           : 0.143000
        Vertical Pixel Fov             : 0.143000
        Horizontal Fov                 : 76.560000
        Vertical Fov                   : 0.143000
 
 
      &apos;TIMS&apos; Section Parameter &apos;RADIANCE&apos;
      -----------------------------------
        Radiance is the amount of energy per time per projected area
        per steradian.
 
        Instrument Parameter Name      : RADIANCE
        Sampling Parameter Name        : PIXEL
        Instrument Parameter Unit      : WATT/(METER*METER)/STERADIAN
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 0.143000
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : DEGREE
 
 
      Instrument Detector &apos;TIMS&apos;
      --------------------------
        Detector Type                  : MCT
        Minimum Wavelength             : 8.200000
        Maximum Wavelength             : 12.200000
        Nominal Operating Temperature  : 80.000000
 
 
      Description
      -----------
        The detector consists of a linear array of 6
        mercury-cadmium-telluride (MCT) detector elements mounted on
        a cold finger from the inner flask of a liquid nitrogen
        dewar.  The width of these detectors (0.43 mm) is a little
        larger than the image of the field stop aperture.  The length
        of the detectors is set by the desired bandwidth.
 
 
      Sensitivity
      -----------
        Sensitivity required to be less than 0.3 K.  All except Band
        6 are within 0.2 K.
 
 
    Instrument Electronics &apos;TIMS&apos;
    =============================
 
      Description
      -----------
        Not Applicable
 
 
    Instrument Mode &apos;OPERATING&apos;
    ===========================
      Data Path Type                 : RECORDED DATA PLAYBACK
      Instrument Power Consumption   : UNK
 
 
      In sections
      -----------
        TIMS
 
 
      Description
      -----------
        Not Applicable
 
 
    Mounted On Platform &apos;NASA C130 AIRCRAFT&apos;
    ========================================
 
      Description
      -----------
        TIMS was mounted on NASA&apos;s C-130 in a nadir-pointing
        position.
 

        </instrument_desc>
        <instrument_id>TIMS</instrument_id>
        <instrument_serial_number>not applicable</instrument_serial_number>
        <instrument_type>Thermal Infrared Spectrometer</instrument_type>
        <instrument_version_id>not applicable</instrument_version_id>
    </Instrument_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_PDS3>
