<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spec.spec</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>IHW SPECTROSCOPY AND SPECTROPHOTOMETRY for SPEC</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.spec::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Sekanina, Zdenek (ed.), &apos;The Comet Halley Archive Summary Volume&apos;, Jet
                   Propulsion Laboratory, California Institute of Technology, Pasadena,
                   California, JPL D-400-450, August 1991.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JPL_D-400-450</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_PDS3>
        <instrument_name>IHW SPECTROSCOPY AND SPECTROPHOTOMETRY</instrument_name>
        <instrument_desc>
 
 
    Instrument Overview
    ===================
    The spectroscopic archive consists of data obtained by a
    wide variety of observers, instruments, and techniques. The
    range of observation sites spans the globe and includes the
    upper atmosphere and satellites in Earth orbit. The
    spectroscopic observations of Comet Halley were monitored,
    but not coordinated, by the Spectroscopy Center at Arizona
    State University. Various individual observing programs were
    planned and executed in their entirety by the observers who
    contributed data to the archive. Occasionally the
    observations were made by observers who had no expertise in
    cometary spectroscopy. Fortunately, there was such an
    overwhelmingly universal interest in Comet Halley that
    virtually every large aperture telescope equipped with
    spectroscopic instrumentation obtained at least a few
    spectra of the comet. Thus, the spectroscopic archive
    comprises data obtained with a very diverse array of
    state-of-the-art instruments and detectors in the years
    1985-1986 and represents a unique set of observations of
    Comet Halley. These instruments include simple scanners and
    spectrographs to more complicated Fabry-Perot and echelle
    systems.
 
         The spectroscopic data in the Comet Halley archive
    consist of two basic types: one-dimensional and
    two-dimensional spectra. In the case of one- dimensional
    spectra, the data are measurements vs. wavelength of the
    flux from the comet within a solid angle determined by the
    size of the spectroscopic instrument aperture projected at
    the comet. For the two-dimensional spectra, a spatial
    dimension is added covering the length of the slit projected
    at the comet. Thus a two-dimensional spectrum contains flux
    information for a set of points, determined by the slit
    length used. The two-dimensional spectra can be treated as a
    normal image, as far as manipulation and display. The only
    difference from an image is that one dimension is wavelength
    and the other is spatial. The one-dimensional spectra might
    be displayed as a one-dimensional image, but a graphical
    display, plotting flux vs. wavelength is more conventional.
 
         Both the coma and plasma tail spectra are composite
    with an underlying continuous spectrum contributed by the
    solar radiation scattered by the comet dust. Thus when
    analyzing the gaseous component of the spectrum, the dust-
    reflected solar continuum is usually subtracted from the
    composite spectrum. The spectra of Comet Halley presented in
    this archive can be found in various forms, both with and
    without the correction for the solar background continuum.
    The state of each archive spectrum can generally be
    determined by reading its fits header. Some observers have
    submitted spectra of solar system objects or scattered
    twilight to provide a solar spectrum with the same
    instrument used to observe the comet. These spectra have
    been archived with the Halley spectra and can be used to
    subtract the background solar spectrum from the comet
    spectrum. Also included in the IHW archive as appendices are
    two high resolution spectra obtained directly of the Sun,
    which, when convolved with the appropriate instrument
    profile and corrected for the scattered light wavelength
    dependence (1/lambda), can be used to correct the composite
    comet spectra for scattered sunlight.
 
       It was requested that observers submit data to the IHW in
    reduced form (i.e., F(lambda) vs. lambda versus rho). Most
    of the data in the archive are as fully reduced, or as fully
    reduced as possible (in some instances, such as high
    spectral resolution data, flux calibration may not be
    possible). In some sets, the data are raw, essentially as
    observed. Hopefully with the raw data sets, other
    calibration data have been included as well, although this
    is not always the case. When calibration frames are
    available, their type should be clear from the OBJECT
    keyword. The type of data presented can be determined from
    DAT-TYPE. Data and calibration frames should be correlated,
    based on time and date of observation, observer, and
    observatory.
    Details in the instrument system are given in the table
    below:
 
       SPECTROSCOPY &amp; SPECTROPHOTOMETRY DISCIPLINE
 
    __________________________________________________________
    SYSTEM  OBSERVATORY            TELESCOP INSTRUMENT
    __________________________________________________________
    75110601 OBS. OF HAUTE-PROVENCE 1.52-M   ECHELLEC SPEC
    75110501 OBS. OF HAUTE-PROVENCE 1.2-M    MARLEY/PL IIaO
    75110102 OBS. OF HAUTE-PROVENCE 1.9-M    SILFID
    75000701 BOLOGNA UNIV. OBS.     1.52-M   B&amp;C/EMI TUBE
    75001301 SOUTH AFRICAN ASTRO OBS1.88-M   RET PHOT COUNT
    75002403 KR.AO AS USSR          2.6-M    SD/IC/103AG
    75002401 MAIN ASTRO OBS, TERSKO 0.6 M    UAGS/2-CHAMBIC
    75002404 MAIN ASTRO OBS, MAIDAN 0.6-M    AS
    75002402 GISSAR                 0.7-M    SPM-1/IC/103AG
    72130201 ASSA (ALMA-ATA, KASAKH)1-M RCC  UAGS/103AO
    75000501 VAINU BAPPU OBS,KAVALUR1.02-M   AUTO SCAN
    72860101 YUNNAN OBS, CHINA      1.0-M    CASS SPEC/BAKD
    75000801 OKAYAMA ASTRO OBS      1.88-M   PLATE/RCA INTN
    75000802 OKAYAMA ASTRO OBS      1.88-M   CASS IMAG TUBE
    74140101 MOUNT STROMLO OBS      74-INCH  COUDE ECHELLE
    71410102 ANGLO-AUSTRALIAN OBS.  3.9-M    AAO CCD
    71410103 ANGLO-AUSTRALIAN OBS.  3.9-M    FAINT RED SPEC
    71410101 ANGLO-AUSTRALIAN OBS.  3.9-M    RGO SPEC/IPCS
    75680401 MAUNA KEA OBSERVATORY  88-INCH  COUDE SPEC/#3
    76620102 LICK OBSERVATORY       120-INCH COUDE CCD SPEC
    76620103 LICK OBSERVATORY       120-INCH CASS SPEC/CCD
    76750101 PALOMAR OBS            200-INCH DOUBLESPEC/CAS
    76950103 KITT PEAK NATIONAL OBS 4.0-M    CRYOCAM/CCD
    76950102 KITT PEAK NATIONAL OBS 4.0-M    RC SPEC/CCD
    76950203 KITT PEAK NATIONAL OBS 2.1-M    IIDS
    76950301 KITT PEAK NATIONAL OBS MCMATH   FABRY-PEROT
    76880101 LOWELL OBSERVATORY     1.8-M    IDS
    76960101 F.L. WHIPPLE OBS       4.5-M    ECHELLE SPEC
    76930101 CATALINA OBS           61-INCH  LPL CCD/SPEC
    76930102 CATALINA OBS           61-INCH  LPL CCD/SPEC
    75001602 SOUNDING ROCKET NASA   FOT      ROWLAND CIRCL
    77110104 MCDONALD OBS.          2.7-M    LONG SLIT CCD
    77110102 MCDONALD OBS.          2.7-M    IDS BLUE CHAIN
    77110103 MCDONALD OBS.          2.7-M    IDS RED CHAIN
    75001601 BLACK MOSHANNON OBS    1.6-M    BMO GALAXY
    78070101 CERRO TOLOLO INTER OBS 4.0-M    2D-FRUTTI
    78070201 CERRO TOLOLO INTER OBS 1.5-M    HARVARD SCAN
    78090101 EUROPEAN SOUTHERN OBS  3.6-M    CASPEC/ECH/CCD
    78090301 EUROPEAN SOUTHERN OBS  1.5-M    CASS SPEC/IDS
    78090302 EUROPEAN SOUTHERN OBS  1.5-M    B&amp;C/EMI TUBE
    78090501 EUROPEAN SOUTHERN OBS  F=400MM  WIDEFIELD/LONG
    73040301 LAS CAMPANAS OBS       0.6-M    CLASS SPEC
    75009903 IUE OBSERVATORY        IUE      LONG/LOW RES
    75009901 IUE OBSERVATORY        IUE      SHORT/LOW RES
    78800101 NATIONAL OBS, BRAZIL   1.6-M    CASS SPEC/VID
    75007401 ROQUE MUCHACHOS OBS    2.5-M    FOS/DUR CCD
    _________________________________________________________
 
 
    Scientific Objectives
    =====================
         During the years 1983-88, the Spectroscopy and
    Spectrophotometry Network (SSN) of the International Halley
    Watch (IHW) was responsible for coordinating, collecting,
    and archiving a wide diversity of spectroscopic observations
    of the periodic comets Halley, Giacobini-Zinner, and
    Crommelin. The spectral domain covered the ultraviolet and
    visible regions, from about 1100 A to 10,000 A, with the
    ground-based data representing the bulk of the spectra and
    covering 3000 A to 10,000 A. Spectra of comets obtained in
    the wavelength regions longer than 10,000 A (1 micron) have
    been archived by the Infrared Network.
 
         The spectra of comet Halley taken from Earth have
    spatial resolutions of about 400 km at best. Such spectra
    obtained remotely arise from three distinct sources in the
    coma: (1) sunlight scattered by the coma dust, (2) neutral
    molecular gas fluorescing with the solar radiation, and (3)
    molecular and atomic ions also excited by resonance
    fluorescence. Solar radiation reflected directly from the
    nucleus of the comet contributes negligibly to the spectrum
    observed from Earth, except when a comet is at relatively
    large heliocentric distances (&gt;5 AU). Spectra in the IHW
    archive obtained with the instrument aperture centered on
    the brightest part of the coma are generally dominated by
    the neutral molecular spectrum of the coma. Spectra offset
    projected distances &gt;100,000 km from the brightest coma
    region toward the tail (anti-solar direction) are generally
    dominated by molecular ions which populate the plasma tail
    of the comet.
 
       Estimates were that the majority (70-80%) of the spectra
    would be recorded in digital format. In fact, virtually all
    the spectroscopic data that we received were in digital
    format. A small percentage (less than 3%) of spectra
    originally recorded on photographic plates were scanned with
    digital microphotometers by observers at their institutes
    and were submitted on magnetic tape. At the time the IHW was
    organized, photographic plates were already on their way
    out. Nearly all observatories that had instrumentation to
    record useful slit spectra of comet Halley had some kind of
    digital detector system.
 
 

        </instrument_desc>
        <instrument_id>SPEC</instrument_id>
        <instrument_serial_number>not applicable</instrument_serial_number>
        <instrument_type>Spectrometer</instrument_type>
        <instrument_version_id>not applicable</instrument_version_id>
    </Instrument_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_PDS3>
