<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:2cp.ecas</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>2 CHANNEL PHOTOMETER for ECAS</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.ecas::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tedesco, E.F., D.J. Tholen, and B. Zellner, The eight-color asteroid survey:
                   Standard stars, The Astronomical Journal, 87, 11:1585-1592, 1982.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TEDESCOETAL1982</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_PDS3>
        <instrument_name>2 CHANNEL PHOTOMETER</instrument_name>
        <instrument_desc>
 
      Instrument Overview
      ===================
      The following instrument description is extracted from Tedesco et
      al. 1982 [TEDESCOETAL1982]:
 
      This two-channel computer-controlled photometer is an adaptation
      of one of the instruments originally built for the 1977 stellar
      occultation by Uranus (Hubbard and Zellner 1980).  Light entering
      this photometer strikes a rotating segmented mirror that
      alternately directs star and sky light to a focal plane diaphragm.
      The throw of this mirror is 3.2 mm.  Hence, as normally used on
      the 61-inch and 90-inch telescopes of the University of Arizona
      Observatories, skies are taken about 32 arcseconds away from
      (generally north of) the program object.  Star-sky dwell time
      ratios of 1:1, 3:1, or 9:1 over a 4 second cycle, are selectable
      by the observer.  Following the diaphragm is a manually
      controlled, 2.5 mag neutral density filter used to observe objects
      brighter than about visual magnitude 8 at the 61-inch telescope.
      The beam next encounters a dichroic mirror that reflects
      wavelengths less than about 0.52 microns through a filter slide
      onto a blue sensitive photomultiplier tube and transmits longer
      wavelengths through a second filter slide onto a red sensitive
      photo-multiplier tube.
 
      Pulse counting electronics and Fabry imaging are employed in both
      photometric channels.  The blue photomultiplier is an uncooled EMI
      9789QB (bialkali photocathode) with quantum efficiency near 20% at
      0.38 microns.  The dark current varies from 1 to 50 counts per
      second depending on ambient temperature.  The red channel can
      accommodate either a thermoelectrically cooled RCA C31034-05 (GaAs
      photocathode) or a dry-ice cooled Varian VPM 159A.12D (InGaAsP
      photocathode).  The RCA tube has an effective quantum efficiency
      of about 22% at 0.55 microns, about 14% at 0.86 microns, and is
      essentially insensitive beyond 0.9 microns. Dark counts are
      generally between 1 and 25 per second.  The Varian detector, which
      must always be kept at a temperature of less than -20 degrees
      centigrade, is maintained at dry ice temperature even between
      observing runs.  Its effective quantum efficiency is about 18% at
      0.40 microns, about 6% at 1.0 microns, and about 0.5% at 1.1
      microns.  The response functions of the eight filters used in ECAS
      as well as that of the dichroic beam splitter are given in the
      &apos;ecasfltr.tab&apos; data table, which is included in the ECAS dataset.
       END_OBJECT = INSTRUMENT_INFORMATION

        </instrument_desc>
        <instrument_id>2CP</instrument_id>
        <instrument_serial_number>not applicable</instrument_serial_number>
        <instrument_type>Photometer</instrument_type>
        <instrument_version_id>not applicable</instrument_version_id>
    </Instrument_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_PDS3>
