<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:irspec.eso</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>INFRARED SPECTROMETER for ESO</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.eso::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_PDS3>
        <instrument_name>INFRARED SPECTROMETER</instrument_name>
        <instrument_desc>
 
 
    Instrument Overview
    ===================
      IRSPEC is a cryogenically cooled grating spectrometer equipped with
      a 58 x 62 pixel SBRC InSb array with 76 micrometer pixel size. It
      covers the 1 micrometer to 5 micrometer wavelength range at
      resolving powers of 1000 to 5000 with a nominal slit length of 2
      arcmin. The instrument is attached permanently to one of the F/11
      Nasmyth foci of the New Technology Telescope (NTT) and hence free of
      instrumental flexure effects. It employs an optical de-rotator in
      front of the slit to counter the field rotation at the telescope
      focus and to permit orientation of the slit at any position angle on
      the sky.
 
      IRSPEC is remotely controlled from the HP A900 &apos;New Technology
      Instrument&apos; (NTI) host computer via form filling and &apos;mouse&apos;
      clicking on a menu bar. An on-line display of standard instrument
      and detector status parameters is available on a RAMTEK screen.
      Data acquisition is performed through the pre-processing system
      (PPS) which receives commands from the host. Images and 1-D traces
      can be displayed in real time on a monitor connected directly to the
      pre-processor. The display can be used for infrared &apos;peaking-up&apos;.
      Brighter objects are centered using the NTT guide probes or the
      IRSPEC slit viewer.
 
      Final data are sent to the A900 where they are stored as individual
      2-D IHAP files. IHAP is available on-line on the A900 with a RAMTEK
      monitor for image display and a graphics terminal for obtaining 1D
      spectrum plots, traces, etc.
 
 
    Optics
    ======
      Light enters the spectrometer via the de-rotator which is installed
      between the NTT adapter A and IRSPEC. The de-rotator converts the
      NTT F/11 beam to F/8 at the slit. After passing through the entrance
      window, the F/8 beam is converted to F/7.4 by a field lens located
      immediately in front of the slit which also re-images the pupil onto
      a cold stop at the off-axis parabolic collimator. The latter directs
      the 10 cm diameter collimated beam towards one of the two
      &apos;back-to-back&apos; mounted diffraction gratings (12 x 15 cm ruled area)
      operated in the Littrow mode. Grating # 1 (300 lines/mm) is used in
      the middle infrared and grating # 2 (600 lines/mm) in the near
      infrared. The F/2 Pfund type camera then focuses the spectrum on the
      detector array.
 
      The gratings are supported in a cradle mount which permits their
      interchange by a 180 degree rotation about an axis parallel to the
      ruled surface and orthogonal to the rulings. Both gratings have
      blaze angles approximately 37 degrees and can be rotated through
      approximately 25 degrees.
 
      The slit is a continuously variable moving blade system.
      Magnification between the detector and the slit is 3.7 so a 76
      micrometer pixel corresponds to 280 micrometers on the slit or 2.2
      arcsec. The slit blades are polished and slightly tilted to permit
      slit viewing with a TV camera. Behind the slit is an 8 position
      wheel containing the order sorting filters.
 
      The Littrow mount is off-axis by 10 degrees and the slit is tilted
      by 15 degrees relative to horizontal coordinates. This particular
      spectrometer arrangement causes a pronounced spectrum line tilt and
      curvature. The tilt angle omega(tilt) is given by
 
        omega(tilt) = arctan(sin gamma(0) x 2 tan omega) - theta      (1)
 
      where
 
        sin omega = m x lambda / 2D x cos gamma(0)                    (2)
 
      with
 
      theta    = 15 degrees, slit tilt
      gamma(0) = 10 degrees, off-axis angle of Littrow mount
      m        grating order
      lambda   center wavelength
      D        grating constant
 
 
    Mounting
    ========
      All the cooled optical functions are supported by, but thermally
      isolated from, a rigid optical bench which remains close to room
      temperature. The optical bench supports pass through stainless steel
      vacuum bellows attached to the vacuum vessel in order to decouple
      the latter from the spectrometer.  Cooling of the optics to
      approximately 80 K is by means of silver straps or copper braids
      attached to the radiation shield which, in turn, is cooled by a
      continuous flow of liquid N2 (LN2) through a tube attached to its
      bottom plate. LN2 also passes through a heat exchanger sandwiched
      between the two gratings. The LN2 is supplied from an internal
      storage tank which is refilled twice a day. Temperature sensors
      automatically control the nitrogen flow to limit temperature
      gradients during cool down and to maintain the final steady state
      temperature. The detector array is cooled to 30K by a closed cycle
      cooler.
 
 
    Detectors
    =========
      The detector at IRSPEC is a 58 x 62 pixel array from SBRC with 62
      pixels aligned along dispersion direction. It is a hybrid type
      detector with backside illuminated InSb diodes bump-bonded to an X-Y
      addressed switched FET output multiplexer. The array has a quantum
      efficiency of 0.89 at 2.85 micrometers, 99.7% of pixels operable,
      and a well capacity of 1 x 10**6 e- .  The array is operated in DC
      mode which is possible because of its high stability. The ADU to
      electron conversion factor is 85 e-/ADU.
 
 
      Dark Current and Noise
      ----------------------
      Two major sources of dark current are present. The diffusion
      current, due to thermally generated charge carriers in the
      semiconductor, and the generation-recombination current due to
      emission of charge carriers through mid-band traps, add up to
      approximately 200 e-/sec at 30K. The internal background of the
      instrument increases the dark current to approximately 400 e-/sec.
 
      Individual pixels exhibit noise which is due to Shot (Poisson)
      noise, Johnson noise, and 1/f noise. Shot noise is associated with
      statistical variations in the arrival rates of photons (i.e. the
      rate of generation of photo current) and in the generation and drift
      of dark current carriers across the semiconductor. Johnson noise is
      thermodynamically fundamental to all resistances, including that of
      the detector. 1/f noise increases as the sampling frequency is
      lowered. Its origin is not understood. Read noise is defined as the
      RMS deviation of the signal read out of a pixel after zero
      integration time.  Spatial noise, i.e. pixel to pixel variations
      present after flat fielding, determines the ultimate S/N that can be
      achieved.
 
 
    Data Modes
    ==========
      Two read out schemes are implemented for the SBRC array. Before an
      integration, a reset switch is closed and the detector is set to an
      initial voltage Vi. This causes the detector and FET capacitances to
      be charged up.  An integration is started by opening the reset
      switch. The effective capacitances are discharged by the photon and
      dark currents. In triple correlated read out, the detector voltage
      is sampled at reset (R1), at the beginning (S1), at the end (E1),
      and at second reset (R2) after the end of the integration.  The main
      contribution to the read noise results from the video line (kTC
      noise). It varies on time scales longer than typical detector
      integration times. This allows an interpolation of the noise during
      the integration; the signal voltage is thus obtained by Vs = (E1-
      R2) - (S1- R1).  The read noise in triple correlated read out is
      approximately 680 e- RMS.
 
      The read noise is significantly reduced by non destructive read out.
      In this option, the output voltage is continuously sampled at a rate
      of 28 s**-1 without resetting the detector. The final signal voltage
      E1 is obtained by a least squares fit through the individual
      measurements. For detector integration times around 10 sec, the
      combined dark and read noise is approximately 150 e- RMS. Figure 2.2
      shows the read noise as a function of the detector integration
      time.  It increases for integration times above one minute due to
      the internal background.
 
      Detector Response
      -----------------
      Pairs of columns are read out simultaneously via two independent
      output lines.  A pronounced odd - even effect between adjacent
      columns appears in the detector response because the output lines
      have different gains. The difference is corrected to first order by
      software.
 
      There is an intrinsic non-linearity of the discharge of the total
      capacitance because both Idark and Cdet are functions of the bias
      voltage which changes during integration. The present software does
      not correct for the nonlinearity which is estimated to amount to 10%
      at maximum for this array (McCaughrean 1988).
 
      Acquisition and Storage
      -----------------------
      The central unit is the NTI A900 computer on which the IRSPEC tasks
      are implemented. Data acquisition on the SBRC array is controlled
      through the pre-processor (PPS). Commands and replies from the A900
      host system are sent via a simple RS232 connection. Final data are
      sent back to the A900 via a fast fiber link and stored as 2-D IHAP
      files. All IRSPEC commands are issued from the LU54 instrument
      console. Two RAMTEKs, LU38 and LU39, and a graphics terminal, LU72,
      are used to display final images, instrument and detector status
      parameters, and 1-D spectra.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The pre-processing system is based on VME hardware. It contains a
      MC68030/25 MHz CPU board (Eltec E6) and a RAM board with 2 x 0.5
      MBytes solid RAM disk cartridges. The software works under the OS-9
      operating system. It handles the data acquisition, the host
      communication and the real-time display. On the PPS, the interface
      program CI waits for commands from the host, checks the correctness
      and triggers one or more programs depending on the command.
 
      After initialization of the acquisition hardware at start detector
      data are continuously read out upon an interrupt of the sequencer.
      The data are stored in an input-ring-buffer as pixel values. The
      mean and standard deviation are calculated and the result is stored
      into an output-ring-buffer. Individual measurements and final
      averaged data are sent on request to the NTI A900 host system.
 
      The PPS software contains a real-time graphics display task. It
      displays data frames, 1-D plots, and various integration parameters.
      The task has facilities like autocut (median filtered), display of
      pixel values for the various data frames, &apos;keeping images&apos; for later
      display, subtract fixed pattern frame, etc.
 
      IRSPEC Software
      ---------------
      The IRSPEC software on the NTI-A900 consists of several programs:
      The observation task IRSPC executes commands from the user or
      external programs. Its main functions are to set up the instrument
      and detector, to start exposures and transfer final data to tape.
      The spectrometer control task ICTRL receives commands related to the
      setting of spectrometer parameters sent by IRSPC. The detector
      control task IDTRL executes detector commands. Commands from the
      terminal are sent to the various destination programs via the
      Terminal Handler (TH). The display of messages on the terminal
      screen is handled by the Screen Handler (SH). It divides the
      terminal screen into two parts: in lines 1 to 5 replies from any
      destination program are displayed. Scrolling is disabled because of
      the need to write asynchronous replies. The instrument control task
      IRSPC communicates with the NTT computer via an Ethernet link.  Both
      NTI and NTT computers keep the same, updated parameters in their
      respective memory (twin-pool). From IRSPC, any program, both on the
      NTI and NTT computers, can be accessed by typing its name.
 
 
    Calibrations
    ============
      Flat Fielding
      -------------
      In a procedure similar to that employed for optical CCDs, reasonable
      flat field corrections are obtained at wavelengths lambda &lt; 2.5
      micrometers using a halogen lamp. It is in general sufficient to
      obtain flat field exposures at the beginning and at the end of the
      night. To account for the non - linearity of the array, take flat
      fields at an exposure level similar to that of the objects. The
      halogen lamp is bright at wavelengths between 1 micrometer and 2.5
      micrometers and the detector saturates for DITs larger than a few
      sec.  Perform flat field measurements for the instrument settings
      used for the science exposures, including the various central
      wavelengths, grating number/orders, and filters. At wavelengths
      lambda &gt; 2.5 micrometers, the thermal emission from the calibration
      unit provides a good flat field source.
 
      The use of standard stars as flat field sources is not recommended.
      Many of the stars previously believed to have flat continua in the
      near IR do in fact show stellar absorption features which, at the
      resolution of IRSPEC, have depths of a few percent.
 
      The odd - even difference in the response of the array is corrected
      to first order by software. An odd - even effect may still be
      present at a low level after flat fielding. If your observing
      program aims to measure spectra with high S/N, obtain science
      exposures with central wavelengths shifted by one or any other odd
      number of pixels. The ultimate S/N that can be achieved is limited
      by the spatial noise of the array. It cannot be improved by the
      accuracy with which flat field corrections are carried out nor by an
      increase of the total integration time. Whenever spatial noise is
      dominant, the faintest spectral features distinguishable are defined
      only by the uniformity of the array and the intensity of the
      background.
 
 
    Operational Considerations
    ==========================
      The position angle of the slit with respect to the sky is defined in
      the usual way: North = 0 degrees, angle measured positive to East.
      The angle is set by specifying the rotator (i.e. adapter A) offset
      angle (command PRSET&gt; RTOF, see section C.1). The slit is
      conventionally set to a width of 2 pixels corresponding to 560
      micrometers, i.e. 4.4 arcsec. This ensures an adequate sampling in
      lambda.
 
      The near infrared wavelength region accessible to ground based
      observations may be divided into two regimes: the 1 - 2.5 micrometer
      wavelength region and the thermal infrared at longer wavelengths.
      The near IR is dominated by non-thermal emission by the polar
      aurora, OH and O2 emission lines, and near IR nightglow.
      Vibrationally excited OH is produced in a reaction of Ozone with
      atomic hydrogen that takes place in a thin layer (approximately 10
      km) between the mesosphere and the ionosphere (approximately 80 km
      height). The emission is highly variable on time scales of a few
      minutes. Pronounced diurnal intensity variations result from changes
      in the OH photodissociation rate which depends on the Doppler shift
      of the solar spectrum with respect to the predissociated OH
      absorption lines. Spectral variations result from changes in the
      rotational temperature of OH. Telluric O2 emission in the IR is
      limited to wavelengths around 1.27 micrometers and 1.58
      micrometers.  It arises from electronically excited O2 which is a
      photodissociation product of Ozone.
 
      The wavelength windows accessible from ground based observations are
      determined by the atmospheric absorption lines of molecular species,
      mainly H2O and CO2. Figure B.1 contains the transmittance of the
      atmosphere between wavelengths of lambda = 1 - 5 micrometers.  The
      edges of the atmospheric windows are highly variable. The
      photometric atlas of the solar spetrum (Delbouille et al. 1981) can
      be consulted if a detailed knowledge of the atmospheric
      transmittance is required.
 
      A proper flux calibration requires the observation of a standard
      star with the same instrument setting used for the science
      exposures. Hot stars have few absorption lines in the infrared, but
      can not be used if atomic hydrogen or helium features are
      investigated. For observations in bad atmospheric windows, choose a
      star as close as possible in air mass to the object in order to get
      an accurate flux calibration.
 
      If the detector gets saturated, a memory of the previous image is
      present on the array. To clean the array, perform a number of Dummy
      read outs (e.g. 5 Dummy read outs with DITs of 1 sec). The number of
      Dummy read outs is specified in the Exposure Parameters Form.
 
      Changing from one photometric band to the other results in a motion
      of the source along the slit by a few arcsec. The displacement can
      be determined by the observation of a standard star at similar
      wavelengths.
 
      As a major change compared to IRSPEC observations prior to the
      installation of the SBRC array, sky chopping and telescope beam
      switching have been removed from the observing menu. The detector is
      operated in DC mode, and FINALs up to several minutes on source.
 
      Observations in the J, H, and K Bands
      -------------------------------------
      Analogous to chopping, cancellation of bright and variable sky
      emission is achieved through observations of a reference position
      close to the source.  For compact sources, the sky observation may
      be obtained by observing the source at a different slit position.
      Total integration times per position are limited to approximately 10
      min during the night when the sky emission is stable in order to
      obtain a proper sky line subtraction. Before and after sunset and
      sunrise, significant variations in the sky emission can occur at
      time scales below 5 min.
 
      Note
      ----
      Poor cancellation of sky lines may arise from significant spectral
      and intensity variations of the emission lines at times shorter than
      the integration time. They may also result from small grating drifts
      after changing the wavelength. The stability of the grating is
      checked through the DITs stored as fixed pattern frames during
      integration. Variations in the sky emission or grating instabilities
      show up as deviations from a uniform, noisy pattern.
 
      Observations in the Thermal Infrared
      ------------------------------------
      Sky lines are no longer dominant at wavelengths longer than 2.5
      micrometers because of the large background from thermal radiation
      from the atmosphere.  As shown in Table 3.6, the detector saturates
      at small DITs. Shot noise of the thermal background photons dominate
      rather than read noise. Because of this, the sensitivity is severely
      decreased. Sources without an optical counterpart are therefore
      searched and centered at 2 micrometers where the S/N is in most
      cases higher. The stability of the thermal emission compared to the
      frequency of sky observations is the limiting factor that determines
      the sensitivity that can be achieved. Sky observations should be
      carried out at intervals of typically one minute.
 
      The actually employed detector integration time is different from
      that specified in the Exposure Parameters Form. The correct DIT is
      displayed in the status display after the form is exited. It is also
      written into the header of the IHAP file stored on the NTI-A900.
      Because of the small DITs used in the thermal infrared, the actual
      integration time may differ significantly from the DIT specified.
 
 
    System Performance
    ==================
      The resolving power R of IRSPEC at the various combinations of
      grating number and order are listed in Table 3.8 (Melnick et al.
      1989).   The filters are selected if the parameter Auto Filter
      Selection in the IRSPEC Instrument Set Up Form is set to TRUE. Note
      that the resolving power listed in Table 3.8 is given for a slit
      width corresponding to two pixels. Higher resolving powers are
      possible for narrower slit widths. (A graphical representation of R
      as a function of wavelength is illustrated in Figure 3.1 of Melnick
      et al 1989.)
 
      Table 3.8 contains preliminary results of sensitivity measurements
      at the centres of the standard photometric bands. The listed
      limiting magnitudes and fluxes per pixel correspond to 1 sigma
      noises derived from observations of a standard star using 60 sec of
      integration time on the star and 60 sec on the sky. For point like
      sources, explicit sky observations are avoided by observing the
      source at two different slit positions. It is thus possible to gain
      a further factor of root 2 in S/N.
 
 
    Bibliography
    ============
      Wallander A.: 1993, Remote Control of the 3.5m NTT User Guide, ESO
      Operating Manual No 17.
 
      D&apos;Odorico, S., Ghigo, M., Ponz, D.: 1987, An atlas of the
      Thorium-Argon Spectrum for CASPEC in the 3400-9000 Angstrom region,
      ESO Scientific Report No. 6
 
      Dekker. H., Delabre, B.: 1987, Applied Optics, 26, 8, 1375
 
      Dekker, H., Delabre, B., D&apos;Odorico, S.: 1986, SPIE, 627, 339
 
      Gilliotte, A.: 1992, Image Quality Filters Catalogue, Internal ESO
      publication
 
      Melnick, J., Dekker, H., D&apos;Odolico, S.: 1989, ESO Operating Manual
      #4
 
      Prieur, J.-L., Rupprecht, G.: 1990, Efficiencies of EMMI, ESO
      internal report
 
      Wilson, R. N., Franza F., Noethe L., Andreoni G.: 1991, Journal of
      Modern Optics, 38, 219.
 

        </instrument_desc>
        <instrument_id>IRSPEC</instrument_id>
        <instrument_serial_number>not applicable</instrument_serial_number>
        <instrument_type>Spectrograph</instrument_type>
        <instrument_version_id>not applicable</instrument_version_id>
    </Instrument_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_PDS3>
