<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rsuv.rsn</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>VERY LARGE ARRAY for RSN</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.rsn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Sekanina, Zdenek (ed.), &apos;The Comet Halley Archive Summary Volume&apos;, Jet
                   Propulsion Laboratory, California Institute of Technology, Pasadena,
                   California, JPL D-400-450, August 1991.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JPL_D-400-450</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_PDS3>
        <instrument_name>VERY LARGE ARRAY</instrument_name>
        <instrument_desc>
 
 
    Instrument Overview
    ===================
    Radio interferometers measure a source&apos;s visibility
    function, which is the Fourier transform of the source
    brightness distribution. In aperture synthesis imaging, a
    set of measurements of the visibility function are Fourier
    transformed to obtain an image of the source brightness
    distribution. Unfortunately, the processing steps required
    to make a map force the observer to specify many parameters
    that determine how the visibility data will be transformed
    to make the image. The specification of these parameters and
    the Fourier transformation of the data, in our view,
    constitutes an interpretation of the data, and runs counter
    to the philosophy of a data archive. Thus, we have preserved
    the actual visibility data in this archive.
 
         The visibility data are presented in the extended FITS
    GROUP data format. This is the format currently used for
    visibility data by many of the world&apos;s interferometers, and
    FITS readers for visibility data should be able to read the
    files prepared for the IHW archive directly. We have tested
    the files in the data reduction program for the U.S.
    National Radio Astronomy Observatory (Astronomical Image
    Processing System = AIPS), and in fact the files are quite
    similar to the UVFITS format of AIPS. For spectral line
    data, AIPS cannot Fourier transform more than eight spectral
    line channels at a time. Therefore, following the style of
    the NRAO VLA, we have archived the 32 channel data that were
    typically obtained in 4 separate FITS files with 8 channels
    in each file. A fifth file usually accompanies this data and
    contains the broadband continuum data recorded at the same
    time as the spectral line data.
 
 
    Scientific Objectives
    =====================
         Radio Astronomy is a developing new technique for the
    study of comets. In some areas, such as observations of the
    OH radical via its 18 cm transitions, the observational
    procedures and analysis are well developed. Studies in these
    areas have proved their value since they both provide new
    probes of important physical processes as well as a window
    on physical processes which are less well-known and less
    accessible to study by other techniques. In many other areas,
    however, the study of comets at radio wavelengths continues
    to be primarily an exploratory endeavor. In recognition of
    this fact, the IHW Radio Science Discipline Specialist team
    felt that it was important to attempt many different kinds of
    observations during this campaign on Halley&apos;s Comet, since each
    observation has scientific merit as an exploration. Thus, we
    have been careful to document and include all data submitted
    to this archive by radio observers.
 
         The P/Halley Archive contains data from 36 different
    observing groups, representing a range of techniques. The
    majority of the observational data comes in the well
    developed area of 18cm OH observations. However, many other
    projects were attempted as well. Approximately 75% of the
    groups who are known to have obtained useful data on the
    comet have submitted it to the archive, and we are grateful
    to them for their contributions.
 
 

        </instrument_desc>
        <instrument_id>RSUV</instrument_id>
        <instrument_serial_number>not applicable</instrument_serial_number>
        <instrument_type>Radio</instrument_type>
        <instrument_version_id>not applicable</instrument_version_id>
    </Instrument_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_PDS3>
