<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:quirc.cfht</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>QUICK INFRARED CAMERA for CFHT</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.cfht::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hodapp,K.-W., J. L. Hora, D.N.B. Hall, L.L. Cowie, M. Metzger, E.M. Irwin, T.J.
                   Keller, K. Vural, L. J. Kozlowski, and W. E. Kleinhans, Astronomical
                   Characterization of 1024x1024 HgCdTe HAWAII Detector Arrays, Proc. SPIE Int.
                   Soc. Opt. Eng. 2475, 8-14, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HODAPPETAL1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_PDS3>
        <instrument_name>QUICK INFRARED CAMERA</instrument_name>
        <instrument_desc>
 
        Instrument overview
        ===================
           The first prototype of a HgCdTe infrared detector array
           with 1024x1024 pixels developed by the Rockwell
           International Science Center has been tested in a new
           infrared camera at UH 2.2 m telescope, the 0.6 m telescope,
           and the CFHT. At the UH 2.2 m tests were conducted both at
           f/31, where images of very high resolution were obtained
           using tip-tilt corrections, and at f/10 for a wide field
           of view. At the CFHT both wide field imaging (f/8) and
           adaptive optics work was done. The HAWAII
           ( HgCdTe Astronomical Wide Area Infrared Images) prototype
           device achieved very good performance. In the camera system,
           a double correlated readnoise of 15 e- rms was achieved.
           the dark current at 1 V bias could be confirmed to be
           below 1 e-, even though the device was operated above 77 K.
           The quantum efficency is slightly below 50% and shows the
           wavy pattern characteristic of LPE-grown HgCdTe. The full
           well capacity is above 10^5 e- at 1 V bias, limited in the
           system by the dynamic range of A/D converter. Data reduction
           is practically identical to what is used for NICMOS3 256x256
           devices. Combined integration times of more than 1 hour
           have been used and demonstrate that the HAWAII devices
           are suitable for very deep imaging. The residual excess
           dark current problem known has not been resolved. However,
           it seems less serious then in the first HAWAII prototype
           device.
 
 
        Electronics
        ===========
           The HAWAII arrays are operated by a controller system
           intended to combine the best features of the older
           controlers at the Institute of Astronomy with the more
           flexible device operation allowed by a DSP based system.
           The digital side of the system is based on the CCD
           controller developed by R. Leach. The analog input and
           D/A pulse shaping capabilities of Leach&apos;s system were not
           used. It was decided to optically decouple digital
           clocking and data processing from any analog signal going
           into and coming out of the infrared array. To do this, a
           digital interface board was developed that resides on the
           Leach controller backpane and uses the same addresses as
           the Leach Analog Board for the output of A/D values onto
           the backpane. Some of the addresses used by Leach to
           control the D/A converters for pulse shaping are used to
           control the clocks. All signals are transmitted to the
           device drivers and recieved from the analog board through
           optocouplers. For the initial tests, the same device driver
           board as in our NICMOS3 camera was used. The board switches
           between two constant but manually adjustable voltage levels.
           The analog signal from the devices is preamplified, shifted
           by manually adjustable offset voltages, and sampled by a
           1 MHz Analogic A/D converter. The signals from the 4
           independant quadrants of the HAWAII detector array are
           routed to the same A/D converter by an analog switch.
 
           The DSP 56001 used in the Leach system is not used for
           signal processing due to its limited memory space. All raw
           data values are transmitted to the host computer (a SPARC LX
           or SPARC 2) via fiber optics, a fiber optics interface
           system, and a S-bus interface card, and are processed there.
           The online data processing requirements for the long
           integration times typically used with the HAWAII arrays are
           not very demanding so this arrangement is adequete.
 
        Detector
        ========
           The acronym QUIRC (Quick Infrared Camera) was chosen to
           describe the purpose and design philosophy of this system.
           The goal was to build a camera in a very short time
           (7 months) to keep up with Rockwell&apos;s aggressive development
           schedule for HAWAII devices. Similar to the camera used for
           the NICMOS3 device the new camera is a simple refractive
           optical system consisting of a field lens and an achromatic
           reimaging system with approximately 1:1 reimaging ratio.
           In fact, the reimaging system is the same as the Institute
           for Astronomy&apos;s(IfA) NICMOS3 camera and only the field lens
           needed to be changed to one with a higher index of
           refraction, to keep spherical aberation in the pupil plane
           within acceptable limits. QUIRC is equipped with a single
           filter wheel operated by a cryogenic stepper motor.
           Further, and different from the older camera, a cryogenic
           pupil mask slide was installed to adapt the camera to
           different f-ratios. The dewars is an up looking design
           with a single large liquid nitrogen can (91 volume) of
           a design similar to that of the CCD dewars used at the IfA.
           The dewar was designed for long periods of cold operation
           of the device, its vacuum stability is excelent, having
           demonstrated in excess of 10 weeks of continuous operation
           without pumping. The cryogenic hold time is in excess of
           24 hours.
 
           The very first HAWAII device produced by Rockwell was
           tested in their laboratory through a number of thermocycles.
           In Rockwell&apos;s dewar, the hybrid device was thermally
           tightly coupled to the cryogen, and the cooldown time was
           short. Under those testing conditions, hybrid #1
           deteriorated rapidly from thermocycle to thermocycle.
           Since the intention was to use the device for astronomical
           observations for an extended period of time, the mechanical
           forces exerted by the device mount on the chip were
           minimized, and increased the thermal resistance between the
           cold surface and the device. While this succeeded in
           avoiding the rapid deterioration of the device (hybrid #3),
           it led to such poor thermal contact that our device in QUIRC
           does not achieve the same low dark currents that Rockwell
           had measured for it. This higher than expected dark current
           is clearly understood to be only due to higher than expected
           operating temperature of the HAWAII array in QUIRC.
 
 
       Performance
       ===========
 
           The HAWAII array used in QUIRC ( hybrid #3) performs very
           well. However, the IfA was not was not able to fully
           verify the dark current performance of the array. The
           dark current values are around 1 electron per second and
           are clearly caused by the detector array operating a few
           degrees warmer than expected. The same array, when tested
           in a dewar better suited for that purpose at Rockwell,
           achieved dark-currents of less than 0.1 e-/s.
 
           The read-noise at the telescope was measured to be 15 e- rms
           with a filter time constant 0.8 microseconds, while
           Rockwell, in a loboratory set up, measured 9 e- rms for the
           same array. These noise values were achieved with simple
           double correlated reading. It is expected that
           multi-sampling techniques (Fowler sampling) can lead to
           substantial further reductions in noise.
 
           The Quantum efficency still leaves some room for
           improvement. The efficency measured was about 42% in K,
           45% in H, and 27% in J. Very similar values have in the past
           been measured on a NICMOS3 device at the same telescope. It
           should be noted that Rockwell has measured higher quantum
           efficiencies on the same devices in their lab, and the
           reason for the discrepency is not known to date.
 
           The residual excess dark current, i.e., the fact pixels
           previously exposed to radiation show an increased dark
           current in subsequent exposures, had been a signifigant
           problem in NICMOS3 devices. Several tests were conducted
           with the HAWAII arrays to determine to which degree this
           problem still persists. Saturated exposures of the device
           were found to still leave a substantial level of residual
           excess dark current that decays with a time constant of
           about 150 seconds. A nonsaturated exposure (60%) leaves a
           much smaller residual excess dark current that becomes
           undetectable in about one minute.
 
           Astronomical images taken through a narrow band filter
           2.12 microns, i.e., under low background conditions, did
           not leave a detectable residual image up to about 40% of
           full-well exposure level in the preceeding exposure.
 
 
        Filters
        =======
           In the current application this instrument uses three
           filters. The following table lists the filters and
           their characteristics:
 
           filter name      central wavelength    FWHM
                              (microns)         (microns)
           ------------------------------------------------
               H                1.65              2.96
               J                1.22              1.64
               K                2.20              3.36

        </instrument_desc>
        <instrument_id>QUIRC</instrument_id>
        <instrument_serial_number>not applicable</instrument_serial_number>
        <instrument_type>Camera</instrument_type>
        <instrument_version_id>not applicable</instrument_version_id>
    </Instrument_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_PDS3>
