<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:b-c.eso</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>BOLLER &amp; CHIVENS SPECTROGRAPH for ESO</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.eso::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_PDS3>
        <instrument_name>BOLLER &amp; CHIVENS SPECTROGRAPH</instrument_name>
        <instrument_desc>
 
 
  Instrument Overview
  ===================
    In the Boller &amp; Chivens (B &amp; C) spectrograph, the converging
    light beam from the telescope passes through the spectrograph
    entrance slit in the telescope focal plane to the collimator,
    an off-axis parabolic mirror.  The reflected parallel beam then
    falls on the grating surface.  The diffracted light passes
    through a Schmidt camera which images the spectrum on the CCD
    detector.  The instrument and thus the slit orientation can be
    rotated fully within a 180 degree range and a readout accuracy
    of 0.1 degree.  The slit width is set by a motor to a specified
    value between 50 and 890 micrometers.
 
    The front surface of the spectrograph slits are aluminised and
    tilted slightly with respect to the incoming beam to allow the
    use of an integrating TV acquisition and guiding system.
    Guiding must be done by hand.  Tracking rates for planetary
    motion can set.
 
    In each exposure, spectra of 2048 pixel length are recorded for
    100 or more spatial resolution points along the slit at 0.81
    arcsec/pixel.  The spectral scale can be changed by exchanging
    gratings.  Although each spectrum is 2048 pixels long, the
    usable length is at least 10 % less since both ends of each
    spectrum are of degraded quality due to vignetting.
 
 
  Scientific Objectives
  =====================
    The objective was to determine the absolute albedo of the
    jovian planets and Titan at 1 nm or better spectral resolution
    throughout the spectral range accessible by CCDs.  For small
    objects, Uranus, Neptune, Titan, and calibration stars, the
    total light at each wavelength was the only requested datum.
    For Jupiter and Saturn, the spatial distribution of light at
    each wavelength was of interest.
 
 
  Calibration
  ===========
    Wavelength calibration is performed by an He-Ar lamp.
 
    Flat-fields are taken at the dome illuminated by floodlights.
 
 
  Operational Considerations
  ==========================
    At the beginning of each night, the grating is installed and
    tilted to achieve the desired spectral range, and the
    spectrograph is focused by staff members.
 
 
  Detectors
  =========
    The detector is a CCD: Ford Aerospace FA 2048 L, front
    illuminated, UV coated by EEV.  It has 2048x2048 pixels of
    15x15 micrometer size.  The gain is 2.9 electrons/ADU.  The
    noise level is 8 electrons RMS.  Linearity is better than 0.2 %
    up to 85,000 electrons/pixel.  The mean dark current is 2
    electrons/pixel/hour.  About 1.3 cosmic ray events occur per
    minute on the whole chip.
 
 
  Filters
  =======
    Order separating filters:
 
       WG345:  cuts off light below 345 nm
       GG475:  cuts off light below 475 nm
       OG530:  cuts off light below 530 nm
       OG550:  cuts off light below 550 nm
       OG570:  cuts off light below 570 nm
 
    Other filter:
 
       BG24:   lowers light in the 500-650 nm region where the CCD
               is much more sensitive than in the blue.
 
 
  Optics
  ======
    Collimator:      off-axis paraboloid of 750 mm focal length.
 
    Schmidt Camera:  focal length 143.5 mm.
 
    Gratings:
 
           Name  grooves  blaze     blaze     dispersion
                   /mm    angle   wavelength
           ------------------------------------------------
           # 5:    900    21o 10&apos;    724 nm   0.13 nm/pixel
           #17:    400     9  44     770      0.28
           #19:    600    17  27     910      0.19
           #23:    600     8  38     455      0.19
           #29:    600     5  10     300      0.19
 
 
  Location
  ========
       Latitude:  29 degrees, 15 minutes S
       Longitude: 70 degrees, 44 minutes W
       Altitude:  2400 meters
 
 
  Measured Parameters
  ===================
    The instrument measures the brightness of the area of the sky
    the telescope is pointed to for a wide range of wavelengths.
    The spectra are generated by directing the light from the
    target onto a grating which differentiates the incoming light
    into its components.
 

        </instrument_desc>
        <instrument_id>B&amp;C</instrument_id>
        <instrument_serial_number>not applicable</instrument_serial_number>
        <instrument_type>Spectrometer</instrument_type>
        <instrument_version_id>not applicable</instrument_version_id>
    </Instrument_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_PDS3>
