<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:avir.er-2</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>AIRBORNE VISIBLE/IR IMAGING SPECTROMETER for ER-2</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.er-2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   G. Vane (Ed.), Airborne Visible/Infrared Imaging
                   Spectrometer (AVIRIS). A description of the sensor, ground
                   data processing facility, laboratory calibration, and first
                   results, JPL Publication 1987-38, 1987.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JPLPUB1987-38</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Macenka, S.A., and M.P. Chrisp, AVIRIS spectrometer design
                   and performance, Int. Soc. Opt. Eng., 834, 1987.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MACENKA-CHRISP1987</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_PDS3>
        <instrument_name>AIRBORNE VISIBLE/IR IMAGING SPECTROMETER</instrument_name>
        <instrument_desc>
 
 
    INSTRUMENT: AIRBORNE VISIBLE/IR IMAGING SPECTROMETER
          HOST: NASA ER-2 AIRCRAFT
 
 
    Instrument Information
    ======================
      Instrument Id                  : AVIR
      Instrument Host Id             : ER-2
      Pi Pds User Id                 : GVANE
      Instrument Name                : AIRBORNE VISIBLE/IR IMAGING
                                       SPECTROMETER
      Instrument Type                : IMAGING SPECTROMETER
      Instrument Mass                : 326.600000
      Instrument Length              : 1.600000
      Instrument Width               : 0.838000
      Instrument Height              : 1.170000
      Instrument Serial Number       : 1
      Instrument Manufacturer Name   : JET PROPULSION LABORATORY
 
 
    Instrument Description
    ======================
      The AVIRIS instrument is a group of four spectrometers that
      view the ground through a scanner while being carried over the
      test site in an aircraft.  Blocking filters help partition
      reflected light among the spectrometers.  At any one moment the
      spectrometers are viewing a spot on the ground that is 20 by 20
      meters.  This spot is viewed simultaneously in 224 spectral
      bands.  An image is built up through the scanner motion, which
      defines an image line 614 pixels wide perpendicular to the
      aircraft direction, and through the aircraft motion, which
      defines the length of the image frame.
 
      The AVIRIS foreoptics determine the spatial performance of the
      optical system.  The foreoptics system is based on a modified
      Kennedy scanner, which was converted to provide the correct
      instantaneous field of view (IFOV) and to make efficient use of
      the limited field of view required.  The scanner was initially
      designed with a four sided rotating mirror to scan an field of
      view (FOV) of approximately 160 degrees.  To efficiently use
      the required 30 degrees FOV, the rotating mirror was replaced
      by an oscillating two sided triangular mirror, giving a scan
      efficiency of 70%.
 
      Scans are taken in only one direction and the flyback speed is
      approximately twice as great as the scan speed.  The large
      facets on the 2 sided mirror also removed the vignetting in the
      system, resulting in an aperture increase by a factor of about
      1.3.  In the initial system the detectors had been placed at
      the focus of the paraboloid mirror.  To provide the correct
      IFOV of 1 mrad this image is magnified 1.3 times by an
      ellipsoidal mirror, which relays the image to the fiber optics
      focal plane.  The fibers are placed very close together so the
      total image field angle required from the foreoptics is only 5
      mrad.  The reduced field of view (30 degrees) for the system
      enabled the baffling of the original design to be improved.
 
      The foreoptics looks out of the aircraft through a window of
      fused silica, which improves the thermal environment for the
      instrument.  The fused silica is water free, to avoid the
      absorption bands present in the infrared region.  Fiber optics
      are used to transmit the light from the fore optics to the
      actual spectrometers.
 
 
    Science Objectives
    ==================
      AVIRIS is used to acquire high spectral resolution radiance
      measurements in visible and near infrared wavelengths for
      analysis of surface composition and texture.
 
 
    Operational Considerations
    ==========================
      See INSTRUMENT_DESC
 
 
    Calibration Description
    =======================
      Light from a filament lamp is imaged by a concave metal mirror
      through a filter wheel onto the fiber optics leading to the
      spectrometers.  The fibers are at the meridional focus so the
      astigmatism of the mirror blurs the filament image, reducing
      the sensitivity of the system to movement.  The mirror and
      structure are monometallic so thermal effects are minimized.
 
      The rotating shutter in the foreoptics enables the light from
      the foreoptics to be shut off during calibration.  The filter
      wheel in the calibrator has four positions, one of which cuts
      the light off.  Two of the positions are used for neutral
      density filters to provide two radiometric levels, and the
      other position is used for a didymium rare earth filter to
      provide a reference spectrum.  This spectrum is relatively
      independent of the operating temperature.
 
 
    Section &apos;AVIR&apos;
    ==============
      Total Fovs                     : 1
      Data Rate                      : 7692308.000000
      Scan Mode Id                   : UNK
      Sample Bits                    : 10
 
 
      &apos;AVIR&apos; Detectors
      ----------------
        SPECTROMETER A
        SPECTROMETER B
        SPECTROMETER C
        SPECTROMETER D
 
      &apos;AVIR&apos; Electronics
      ------------------
        AVIR
 
 
      In modes
      --------
        OPERATING
 
 
      &apos;AVIR&apos; Section FOV Shape &apos;LINEAR&apos;
      ---------------------------------
        Section Id                     : AVIR
        Fovs                           : 1
        Horizontal Pixel Fov           : 0.050000
        Vertical Pixel Fov             : 0.050000
        Horizontal Fov                 : 30.000000
        Vertical Fov                   : 0.050000
 
 
      &apos;AVIR&apos; Section Parameter &apos;RADIANCE&apos;
      -----------------------------------
        Radiance is the amount of energy per time per projected area
        per steradian.
 
        Instrument Parameter Name      : RADIANCE
        Sampling Parameter Name        : PIXEL
        Instrument Parameter Unit      : WATT/(METER*METER)/STERADIAN
        Minimum Instrument Parameter   : 0.000000
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 0.050000
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : DEGREE
 
 
      Instrument Detector &apos;SPECTROMETER A&apos;
      ------------------------------------
        Detector Type                  : LINE ARRAY
        Detector Aspect Ratio          : UNK
        Minimum Wavelength             : 0.410000
        Maximum Wavelength             : 0.700000
        Nominal Operating Temperature  : 80.000000
 
 
      Description
      -----------
        The design is a double-pass Schmitt detector with a sampling
        interval 9.7 nm.  There are 31 channels.  The grating is
        117.65 l/mm.  There are 32 elements made of silicon, with 30
        micrometers of dead space between elements.  The detector has
        an integration time of 87 microseconds.  The active area of
        the detector is 200 X 200 micrometers.
 
 
      Sensitivity
      -----------
        See DETECTOR_DESC
 
 
      Instrument Detector &apos;SPECTROMETER B&apos;
      ------------------------------------
        Detector Type                  : LINE ARRAY
        Detector Aspect Ratio          : UNK
        Minimum Wavelength             : 0.680000
        Maximum Wavelength             : 1.270000
        Nominal Operating Temperature  : 80.000000
 
 
      Description
      -----------
        The detector is of a double-pass Schmitt design with a
        sampling interval of 9.5 nm and 63 channels.  The grating is
        128.205 l/mm.  There are 32 silicon elements with 30
        micrometers of dead space between them.  The integration time
        is 87 microseconds.  The detector active area is 200 x 200
        micrometers.
 
 
      Sensitivity
      -----------
        See DETECTOR_DESC
 
 
      Instrument Detector &apos;SPECTROMETER C&apos;
      ------------------------------------
        Detector Type                  : LINE ARRAY
        Detector Aspect Ratio          : UNK
        Minimum Wavelength             : 1.250000
        Maximum Wavelength             : 1.860000
        Nominal Operating Temperature  : 80.000000
 
 
      Description
      -----------
        The detector design is a double-pass Schmitt with a sampling
        interval of 9.8 nm.  There are 63 channels.  The grating is
        124.2236 l/mm.  There are 64 elements made of indium
        antimonide with a deadspace between elements of 30
        micrometers.  The integration time is 87 microseconds and the
        detector active area 200 x 200 micrometers.
 
 
      Sensitivity
      -----------
        See DETECTOR_DESC
 
 
      Instrument Detector &apos;SPECTROMETER D&apos;
      ------------------------------------
        Detector Type                  : LINE ARRAY
        Detector Aspect Ratio          : UNK
        Minimum Wavelength             : 1.840000
        Maximum Wavelength             : 2.450000
        Nominal Operating Temperature  : 80.000000
 
 
      Description
      -----------
        The design of the detector is a double-pass Schmitt having a
        sampling interval of 9.8 nm.  There are 63 of channels.  The
        grating is 128.6 l/mm.  There are 64 of elements made of
        indium antimonide having a dead space of 30 micrometers.  The
        detector has an integration time of 87 microseconds.  The
        detector active area is 200 x 200 micrometers.
 
 
      Sensitivity
      -----------
        See DETECTOR_DESC
 
 
    Instrument Electronics &apos;AVIR&apos;
    =============================
 
      Description
      -----------
        The AVIRIS instrument has a separate dedicated analog signal
        processing chain for each of its four spectrometers.  The
        signal chains amplify low-level focal-plane line array
        signals (5-10 mV full-scale span) in the presence of larger
        multiplexing signals (~ 150 mV) providing the data handling
        system a ten-bit digital word (for each spectrometer) each
        1.3 microseconds.  This signal chain provides automatic
        correction for the line array dark signal nonuniformity
        (which can approach the full-scale signal span).
 
 
    Instrument Mode &apos;OPERATING&apos;
    ===========================
 
      In sections
      -----------
        AVIR
 
 
      Description
      -----------
        There is only one section and mode for AVIRIS.
 
 
    Mounted On Platform &apos;NASA ER-2 AIRCRAFT&apos;
    ========================================
 
      Description
      -----------
        AVIRIS is mounted in a nadir-pointing position on an ER-2
        aircraft.  The foreoptics look out of the aircraft through a
        window of fused silica, which improves the thermal
        environment for the instrument.  The fused silica is water
        free, to avoid the absorption bands present in the infrared
        region.
 

        </instrument_desc>
        <instrument_id>AVIR</instrument_id>
        <instrument_serial_number>not applicable</instrument_serial_number>
        <instrument_type>Imaging Spectrometer</instrument_type>
        <instrument_version_id>not applicable</instrument_version_id>
    </Instrument_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_PDS3>
