<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:msnvis.msn</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>METEOR COUNTS - VISUAL for MSN</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.msn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hajduk, A., Bulletin of the Astronomical Institute of
                   Czechoslavakia, Number 21, pp. 37, 1970.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAJDUK1970</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Sekanina, Zdenek (ed.), &apos;The Comet Halley Archive Summary Volume&apos;, Jet
                   Propulsion Laboratory, California Institute of Technology, Pasadena,
                   California, JPL D-400-450, August 1991.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JPL_D-400-450</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   McIntosh, B.A., and A. Hajduk, &apos;Comet Halley meteor
                   stream - A new model&apos;, Monthly Notes of the Royal
                   Astronomical Society, Vol. 205, 931, 1983.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MCINTOSH-HAJDUK1983</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   McIntosh, B.A., and J. Jones, &apos;The Halley Comet meteor
                   stream - Numerical modeling of its dynamic evolution&apos;,
                   Monthly Notes of the Royal Astronomical Society, Vol. 235,
                   673, 1988.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MCINTOSH-JONES1988</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_PDS3>
        <instrument_name>METEOR COUNTS - VISUAL</instrument_name>
        <instrument_desc>
 
 
    Instrument Overview
    ===================
    The disintegration of a meteoroid in the Earth&apos;s atmosphere
    produces light and ionization, both of which have a complex
    relation to the energy (mass and velocity) of the particle.
    A meteor trail can reflect radio waves, producing &apos;echoes&apos;
    having measurable parameters such as amplitude and duration
    which can be related to the properties and energy of the
    particle. Some radars are able to determine meteor velocity.
 
         The luminous meteor is a point source moving with
    sufficiently high angular velocity that the human eye is a
    more sensitive detector than typical lenses and photographic
    emulsions. However, the eye is not a particularly
    satisfactory quantitative recorder of brightness and
    position. The current sensitivity of electronic imaging
    devices much exceeds that of the human eye.
 
         In order to cover as wide a mass range of meteors as
    possible, a variety of ground-based techniques is required.
    The resulting data are of many types and in many formats. In
    general the data occur in two basic forms -- statistical
    counts and single events. It was established that all
    statistical counts would be for one-hour intervals. These
    observations range from a simple count of meteors seen, to
    diversified radar echo counts in multiple interval classes
    of range (distance) and/or echo duration or echo amplitude.
 
         It was stressed to all observers that it was important
    to distinguish carefully between meteors belonging to the
    Halley showers and those that are background or other shower
    meteors. Shower counts are at best slightly higher than
    background counts. Some radars are able to distinguish on
    the basis of velocity and/or the geometry of the trail, but
    for others, shower counts are obtained only by subtraction
    of an assumed background rate.
 
         It was required that radar meteor echo counts be made
    in standardized class intervals of echo duration and
    amplitude.
 
         Major activity takes place at solar longitudes 42.5-47
    deg (May 3-8) for the Eta Aquarid shower and 206-210 deg
    (Oct 19-24). At least two other relatively stable secondary
    maxima have been observed in both showers. They are
    distinctly separated from the main zones at longitudes 38
    deg and 50 deg (Apr 28/29 and May 10/11) and at 203 deg and
    215 deg (Oct 16/17 and 28/29). The maximum at the beginning
    of each shower is of particular interest since it is thought
    to contain particles of most recent vintage.
 
         As noted earlier, activity extends over as much as
    fourteen days-- between solar longitudes 37 and 51 deg
    (April 27-May 11) and between 202 and 216 deg (October
    15-30), with priority given to the central interval. The
    lunar phase is significant for visual observations and was
    reasonably good for the two years: the new moon occurred on
    1985 28 October and 1986 9 May.
 
         The suite of data that has been archived consists of
    radar meteor counts and visual observations. The radar
    stations which provided data are listed in the Meteor
    Studies Network chapter of &apos;The Comet halley Archive Summary
    Volume&apos; (Sekanina, Z., 1991). They range from latitude +54
    deg to -33 deg, longitude 75 deg W (285 deg) to 69 deg E.
    Observations of both the Eta Aquarid and Orionid meteor
    showers from 1984 through 1988 are included--a total of 5662
    hours of data.
 
    Details on the instrument system are given in the table
    below:
 
                  VISUAL (MSNVIS)
 
    ___________________________________________________________
    SITE                   NO.       LONG.   LAT.  ELEV.
                                                  (meter)
    ___________________________________________________________
 
    COMO                   152        9.05  45.82
    KLOVBORG               119        9.47  55.92
    HADERSLEV              120        9.58  55.28
    KONGSBERG              140        9.60  59.70
    AROSIO                 111        9.63  46.70  1500
    ULM                    144       10.03  48.45
    NEAR FISCHEN           145       10.22  47.48
    HEGGEDAL               139       10.40  59.78
    VIBY                   141       10.70  55.50
    ARNSTADT               104       10.90  50.80
    DEMEN                  112       11.43  53.38
    HAVDRUP                118       12.12  55.53
    GUSTROW                149       12.15  53.78
    BRONDBY                143       12.42  55.65
    GROSS WOKERN           146       12.48  53.75
    CARLSFELD              105       12.58  50.43
    SCHNEEBERG             116       12.63  50.60
    LIMBACH                107       12.77  50.83
    KARL-MARX-STADT 2      115       12.90  50.80   250
    GOLM                   114       12.95  52.40    35
    KARL-MARX-STADT 1      108       12.95  50.87
    POTSDAM                102       13.02  52.38    34
    BASDORF                150       13.45  52.72    50
    BERLIN                 106       13.57  52.42
    RADEBEUL               103       13.63  51.10   180
    DRESDEN                113       13.80  50.97
    ZURRIEG                154       14.42  35.85    30
    SOHLAND                117       14.42  51.02
    MOSTA                  155       14.43  35.90
    FGURA                  153       14.52  35.87    47
    MARSASCALA             110       14.57  35.87    56
    WEISSWASSER            109       14.63  51.48   160
    RONNE                  142       14.72  52.15
    MSIDA                  156       14.83  35.90
    CATANZARO              151       16.60  38.90
    VASAS                  131       16.77  47.08
    ZALAEGERSZEG           132       16.83  46.83
    PAPA                   147       17.45  47.37
    TATA                   127       18.40  47.67   200
    BOLY                   122       18.53  45.87   128
    KAJDACS                128       18.62  46.57
    BAJA                   123       18.95  46.18
    LAJOS FORRAS           125       19.00  47.75   550
    VARTOVKA               158       19.15  48.72
    FOT                    124       19.20  47.65
    SULYSAP                126       19.53  47.45   200
    ZAVADA                 157       19.73  48.53
    OROSHAZA               130       20.68  46.57
    MEZOBERENY             129       21.00  46.80
    RAUMA                  136       21.48  61.13
    TAMPERE                135       23.62  61.50   150
    SATU-NOU               133       24.63  47.13
    PARTALANKOSKI          137       25.08  61.88
    HELSINKI               138       25.18  60.18     2
    DELHI                  201       77.33  28.67
    BALLAJURA              318      115.83 -31.82
    RIVERVALE              319      115.93 -31.93
    THORNLIE               309      115.97 -32.03
    PERTH                  330      116.00 -32.00
    BYFORD                 310      116.02 -32.25
    KALAMUNDA              315      116.07 -31.98
    KARNET                 308      116.08 -32.52
    ROLEYSTONE             320      116.08 -32.12
    JARRAHDALE             326      116.08 -32.33
    GIDGEGANUP             321      116.28 -31.70
    GLENEAGLE              304      116.42 -32.33
    TOODYAY                325      116.47 -31.58
    DRYANDRA               305      117.18 -32.82
    YORKRAKINE             316      117.58 -31.43
    BROOME                 329      122.20 -18.00
    HIGASHI-SON, OKINAWA   218      128.22  26.63   100
    KAWATANA               214      129.83  33.07    10
    OHCHI-GUN              212      132.45  34.88
    KINOE-CHO HIROSHIMA    205      132.92  34.22     2
    MATSUE                 211      133.12  35.43
    KITAJIMA TAINOHAMA     208      134.55  34.12     2
    KAMI TOWN              215      134.88  35.10
    KAWASAKI OBS.          213      135.38  34.38    75
    KITAOJI OTSU           217      135.88  34.97   233
    MUROH-NARA             204      136.02  34.57   400
    ARUYAMA                202      136.10  35.15   100
    FUKUMITMACHI TOYA      216      136.90  36.55    72
    KANAYA TOYAMASHI       207      137.17  36.68    15
    SHIROYAMA              219      137.23  34.90   136
    GAWLER                 314      138.75 -34.60
    NEAR FUJINOMIYA        220      138.80  35.33  1455
    BAROSSA VALLEY         322      138.93 -34.57
    KAWAUCHI KIRYU         210      139.33  36.17    55
    SAYAMA OBS.            209      139.47  35.85    46
    MT. TSUKUBA            206      140.13  36.20   360
    HOSHINOKITSUSASHITSU   203      141.13  39.47    71
    COOTAMUNDRA            323      148.05 -34.68
    COONABARRAN            328      149.50 -31.10
    COLO                   327      149.60 -31.92
    DARKES FOREST          306      150.83 -34.22
    BELMONT                317      151.58 -33.00
    BUNDABERG              307      152.35 -24.83
    BLACK BIRCH            311      173.80 -41.80
    CARTER OBS.            301      174.77 -41.28
    AUCKLAND               312      174.78 -36.85
    MANA OBS.              303      174.87 -41.08
    PAVAVTANANUI FIELD S   324      174.93 -41.13
    BROWN OWL OBS.         302      175.10 -41.10   140
    BARBERS POINT          402      201.95  21.33
    EWA BEACH              401      201.98  21.33
    KIPAPA GULOH           403      201.98  21.43
    LAIE                   427      202.07  21.65
    PEARL HARBOUR          404      202.08  21.42
    ROSEBURG               407      237.22  43.37
    HERB&apos;S FIELD           431      237.73  37.28   167
    WHITTAKER PEAK         408      241.30  34.57   914
    SAN DIEGO              409      242.98  32.70
    ALPINE                 424      243.37  32.83   885
    MIQUELON               422      247.08  53.23
    ELK ISLE               414      247.15  53.52
    POLISH SETTLEMENT      413      247.18  53.88
    NUGGET                 411      247.43  53.13
    WEAVERS NEEDLE         419      248.57  33.40
    U.P.N.                 426      249.03  31.33  1240
    CABRERA                425      249.05  31.32  1220
    FT. DAVIS              429      256.05  30.60
    WINNIPEG               423      262.60  49.90   232
    DALLAS                 405      263.35  32.72
    LA SALLE STATE PARK    430      272.53  41.07
    PUNTA ARENAS           428      275.10   9.90
    SEBRING                417      278.67  27.33
    CLARION PA             421      280.62  42.20   460
    NEAR BELLEFONTE        410      282.08  40.92
    MC KENDREE             406      283.37  38.78
    PHILADELPHIA           420      284.85  39.93
    WORCESTER              418      285.27  42.58   640
    LA PAZ 1               507      291.87 -16.52  3580
    LA PAZ 2               506      291.92 -16.53  3360
    SANTA ANA, TARIJA      518      295.48 -21.62  1900
    HALIFAX                415      296.38  44.65
    VALSAYN                416      298.60  10.63
    ABAGAZA, ZARATE        520      300.97 -34.12    26
    VILLA ELISA            519      301.95 -34.83    20
    IRAI                   513      306.62 -27.35   522
    ARAMBARE               509      308.50 -30.92
    PORTO ALEGRE 3         504      308.50 -30.23   200
    PORTO ALEGRE 4         510      308.55 -30.92
    PORTO ALEGRE 2         503      308.80 -30.05     4
    PORTO ALEGRE 12        523      308.82 -30.08
    PORTO ALEGRE 7         514      308.82 -30.08   295
    PORTO ALEGRE 1         502      308.83 -29.92     4
    PORTO ALEGRE 6         512      308.85 -30.07
    PORTO ALEGRE 5         511      309.00 -30.38     4
    PORTO ALEGRE 8         515      309.10 -29.85    30
    PORTO ALEGRE 9         516      309.28 -30.20    15
    PORTO ALEGRE 10        521      309.87 -29.80
    BRAZILIA               508      312.33 -15.92  1100
    SAO PAOLO              524      313.28 -23.53   780
    BELO HORIZONTE         501      315.17 -20.72   997
    FORTALEZA              517      321.00  -3.57
    PORTO ALEGRE 11        522      350.83 -30.05     6
    CAMBRIDGE              121      357.65  51.75
    ___________________________________________________________
 
 
    Scientific Objectives
    =====================
         Meteor observations are specifically oriented toward
    studies of comet-meteor relationships. They contribute to
    comet science mainly in the areas of dust production and
    the dust-particle dynamics. These aspects can be enhanced by:
 
         o determination of the number density and mass
            distribution of particles in the showers,
 
         o determination of the properties and composition of
            the particles,
 
         o study of the evolution of the Halley meteor stream,
 
         o study of the spatial structure of the stream,
            especially as a function of particle mass.
 
         The IHW program provided an opportunity to coordinate
    and combine many different observations to determine the
    stream structure with high resolution and to infer from this
    the production and dynamical evolution of the larger dust
    particles.
 
         This goal is independent of the current comet passage.
    No increase in normal meteor shower rates was expected, and
    none was observed. It was thought that the more rapid and
    wider dispersal of fine particles might contribute fresh
    meteors observable on sensitive instruments. These were
    searched for with the Canadian High-Power Meteor Radar,
    particularly at the time of the Earth&apos;s passage through the
    comet orbit plane, but results were negative.
 
         The Earth makes two close approaches to the comet
    orbit, once in early May, and again in late October. In
    common with other comet-produced meteor streams, the dust
    ejected from Halley is dispersed along the orbit and
    laterally from the orbit; but, uncommonly in meteor
    astronomy, the Earth passes twice every year through the
    band of Halley particles, thus producing the long-known
    Eta-Aquarid (May) and Orionid (October) meteor showers. Most
    of the meteor activity is confined to a period of about five
    days in each case. However, this period is not well defined;
    shower meteors have been observed over as long as fourteen
    days. Furthermore the activity is not consistent from year
    to year -- the position in time of maximum flux shifts
    significantly and there are secondary maxima. Hence an
    activity curve for one year is not a reliable predictor for
    the activity in another year. If averaged over many years, a
    broad flat curve results, which again is not indicative of
    annual activity.
 
         Traditional visual observations have never been carried
    out over sufficiently long intervals of time to define
    clearly the structure of the stream. Radar observations have
    contributed to our understanding of the structure, but they
    are also not without problems. A paper by Hajduk (1970)
    summarizes visual and radar observations from 1900 to 1969.
    There are also some earlier, medieval and ancient
    observations.
 
         The geometric relation between the Earth&apos;s orbit and
    the comet&apos;s current orbit suggests that the two showers
    should not be of equal strength or equal duration, which is
    contrary to actual observations. A recent theory (McIntosh
    and Hajduk 1983; McIntosh and Jones 1988) proposes that the
    long-term evolution of comet and dust results in a flat
    ribbon of particles so that the Earth&apos;s two crossings yield
    approximately equal-activity, equal-duration showers.
 
         Observationally the meteors are very fast (V &gt; 65 km/s
    for both showers), with persistent trains being common.
    Studies of the physical characteristics and composition of
    the particles are sparse, but there is no evidence that they
    are unusual.
 
         The visual rates for the showers may be as high as 30
    per hour depending on the latitude of the observer. The
    low-declination radiant of the May shower (in Aquarius, at
    R.A. = 335.5 deg, Dec = -1.9 deg) rises only a little before
    sunrise, particularly at high northern latitudes, providing
    a very limited period for visual or optical observations.
    More extensive coverage by Southern Hemisphere observers was
    needed.
 
         The observing period for the Orionids extends through
    nearly the entire night because of the radiant&apos;s much
    greater elongation from the Sun (R.A. = 94.5 deg, Dec =
    +15.8 deg). The higher declination and time of the year
    favor Northern Hemisphere observers.
 
         Studies benefit also from observations at many
    longitudes around the Earth. This is true of the
    Eta-Aquarids in particular.
 
 

        </instrument_desc>
        <instrument_id>MSNVIS</instrument_id>
        <instrument_serial_number>not applicable</instrument_serial_number>
        <instrument_type>Visual Count</instrument_type>
        <instrument_version_id>not applicable</instrument_version_id>
    </Instrument_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_PDS3>
