<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:nsfcam.irtf</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>NSF CAMERA for IRTF</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.irtf::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Leggett, S., and T. Denault, NSFCAM User&apos;s Guide, Jan 3, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEGGETT-DENAULT1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_PDS3>
        <instrument_name>NSF CAMERA</instrument_name>
        <instrument_desc>
 
 
    Instrument Overview
    ===================
      NSFCAM is a 1-5 um imager with a 256x256 InSb detector. Simultaneous
      optical imaging is possible via an optical port. Three different
      magnifications can be selected by rotating different cold lens
      assemblies into the beam. These give plate scales of
      0.3arcsec/pixel, 0.15arcsec/pixel and 0.06arcsec/pixel, with
      corresponding fields of view of 76.8 arcmin, 37.9 arcmin and 14.1
      arcmin respectively. Images can be obtained through a variety of
      broad- and narrow-band filters, and low-resolution spectroscopy can
      also be carried out using the circular variable filters (CVFs) or
      grisms. Polarizing waveplates or grids can be inserted into the
      beam. Two cold coronograph masks are also available.
 
      Images are recorded onto a Sun workstation in FITS format. These are
      taken in basic stare mode using the main (object) and offset (sky)
      telescope beam positions; software is available to shift-and-add
      series of images together to study fine image structure. It is also
      possible to take frames rapidly in movie mode, storing them directly
      to the instrument computer and saving overheads in time-critical
      observations.
 
 
    Electronics
    ===========
      Instrument start-up
      -------------------
      The camera is run from a PC which is located out at the telescope.
      You can communicate with this PC, called NSFPC, via a monitor and
      keyboard in the control room (to the right of the Planck
      workstation), or by logging on to NSFPC from a workstation. Often
      both the computer and the software which runs the camera are
      referred to as the &apos;IC&apos;, for Instrument Computer.
 
      The default Voltage (DETector) of -3.4 implies a 300mV bias across
      the array (-3.4 - -3.7). This works well in the non-thermal regime
      and where the background is not high, i.e. through narrow filters or
      for the CVF.  Increasing the bias across the array, i.e. increasing
      VDET, will increase the well depth allowing you to reach higher
      counts before entering the non-linear regime, but it will also
      rapidly increase the number of bad pixels and the dark current.
      Hence the best value of VDET is a compromise between well depth and
      increasing bad pixels, and it may vary from night to night; getting
      the correct value will probably require some experimentation at the
      telescope. You can reduce the number of counts per pixel and the
      non-linearity problem by using a smaller pixel scale, if your
      program will allow this.
 
      A non-destructive read consists of reading each pixel without
      resetting its value. Increasing the number of reads per image
      reduces the read noise and for this reason the default value of NDR
      is set to 8. For the CSHELL array (also a SBRC 256x256 InSb) it was
      found that the read noise was 55 electrons (or 5 DN) for NDR=1, and
      22 electrons (2 DN) for NDR=6. For NSFCAM the gain has been measured
      to be 10 electrons/DN.
 
      The higher the number of NDR the longer the minimum integration
      time, as each read requires about 0.077 seconds. The number of NDR
      will be set automatically to the maximum number possible (up to 8)
      for your requested integration time (see following Section). The
      maximum possible value of NDR (currently 8) as well as the number
      used on the last &apos;Go&apos; is displayed on the top User Interface
      window.
 
 
    Data Modes
    ==========
      Readout Modes
      -------------
      &apos;ARC_D&apos; stands for &apos;array reset clocking, double sample&apos;. The entire
      array is readout once (called pedestal sampling) and then after the
      requested integration time has elapsed the array is readout again
      (sampled). The difference between these two reads is displayed in VF
      and saved to disk if Autosave is selected. The minimum integration
      time is a function of array size.
 
      If more than one NDR is done, the pedestal value is read out many
      times (set by the value of NDR) and the final sample value is read
      many times. The integration time is the time from the first read of
      the pedestal to the first read of the sample. The frame that is
      stored is the difference between the sum of the pedestal read and
      the sum of the sample reads. Hence the number of counts in the frame
      will be increased by a factor equal to the number of NDR. If more
      than one coadd has been requested then this entire process is
      repeated for the number of coadds, and the frame that is stored is
      the sum of the frames. Hence when reducing your data the counts in
      each frame need to be divided by the number of NDR and the number of
      coadds. This value is given in the FITS header as &apos;Divisor&apos;. The
      quick-look utility VF will automatically divide the counts in the
      image by this value.
 
      As described above, read noise decreases with increasing NDR. Hence
      the maximum number of NDR possible within your requested integration
      time (up to 8) will be carried out. For full arrays this means for
      example that the value of NDR will be equal to the integer value
      of:  (integration time) / 0.0768.
 
      The other readout modes are not operational however briefly they
      work as follows. ARC_S (Array Reset Clocking Single Sample) follows
      the same procedure as ARC_D however no pedestal value is
      subtracted.  PRC (Pixel Reset Clocking) mode is similar to ARC_S
      however instead of reading the entire array every integration
      interval, the pixels are read out on an individual basis. Similarly
      CDS (Correlated Double Sample) reads the pixels on an individual
      basis but subtracts a pedestal value for each pixel. These last two
      modes effectively increase the well depth of the pixels as each
      pixel is not left integrating up in counts while the entire array is
      being sampled.  They will be useful modes for observing in the
      thermal regime when they are operational.
 
 
    Optics
    ======
      NSFCAM -- A U. Hawaii 256x256 Infrared Array Camera with an In-Sb
      based chip, with each pixel individually addressable.  The camera
      can be used in many modes including imaging and grism-based,
      low-resolution spectroscopy.  The Observing Parameters are array,
      filter, lens, dichroic and waveplate.
 
      Waveplate
      ---------
      A half-wave plate is available for polarizing work with NSFCAM.
      Polarizing grids are also available in both the CVF and filter
      wheels.
 
      Dichroic
      --------
      The first cold optical element in the light path is the dichroic
      assembly.  There are four turrets currently containing: an open
      aperture (default position), a visual/infrared dichroic, and two
      lenses for the cold coronograph instrument CoCo.
 
      Lens (&amp; Grism Slit &amp; Coronograph Masks)
      ---------------------------------------
      The optical element below the dichroic is the lens turret assembly.
      There are three plate scales available chosen by selecting the
      appropriate lenses; the focus position for each scale is different.
      The three scales are: 0.055arcsec/pixel, 0.148arcsec/pixel and
      0.300arcsec/pixel, giving fields of view of 13 arcsec, 35 arcsec and
      72 arcsec (allowing for bad edges to the array). There are
      coronograph masks available for the two smaller scales and a grism
      slit available with the largest plate scale. The coronograph masks
      are centrally located on the array and have diameters of 4 arcsec
      (for the 0.055 arcsec scale) and 6 arcsec (for the 0.148 arcsec
      scale).
 
      Filter and CVF Wheels
      ---------------------
      The last optical elements before the detector are the filter and CVF
      wheels.
 
      The software will automatically select the blocking filter or open
      position in the CVF wheel as appropriate for the filter wheel
      selection. Similarly the blocker in the filter wheel will be
      automatically selected for the CVF.  (The blockers are necessary in
      some cases to prevent long-wavelength light leaks). All you need do
      is select your filter or the CVF and type in the required CVF
      wavelength with the latter. After making your selection from the
      filter and CVF menus you must click on the &apos;move&apos; button before the
      wheels will be moved.  The table below lists the filters in this
      project.
 
      Index Name                      Step   Deg  Central Wavelngth   FWHM
                                                           microns
 
      1     J                         2500   125    1.26              0.28
      3     K&apos;                        2020   101    2.12              0.34
      8     Spencer 2.3                740    37    2.28              0.17
      10    VIS ND=20.                7180   359
      16    Brackett ki 2.166         5620   281    2.16              0.02
      17    H2 v=2-1 s1 2.248         5380   269    2.25              0.02
      18    CO headband 2.295         5140   257    2.30              0.03
      19    CO continuum K            4900   245    2.26              0.05
      23    .945 micron               3940   197
      24    IR ND=2.0                 3580   179
      27    Open                      2740   137
 
      Array (and Subarrays)
      ---------------------
      You are not constrained to reading out the full array of the camera
      - smaller subarrays can be used. You can also store an image made up
      of up to three non-overlapping subarrays. There are various ways of
      defining which regions of the array you want read out.
 
      In the Observing Parameters window you can use the Array 1/2/3 lines
      to explicitly define the subarrays. You would enter the x,y
      coordinates of the top left of the region (the top left corner of
      the full array is 0,0), followed by the width and height of the
      region in pixels. The width and height must be divisible by 8, and
      the software should round off your numbers to the nearest
      permissible value. In this window &apos;num array&apos; is the value of the
      total number of regions you want read out in a single frame.
 
 
    Operational Considerations
    ==========================
      Integration Times, Coadds, Cycles
      ---------------------------------
      The integration time is specified in seconds on the &apos;itime&apos; line in
      the window. The minimum integration time is about 0.077 seconds for
      a full array.  Software will automatically go to the smallest
      possible value if your value is below this limit. The actual
      integration time will be displayed and written in the FITS header.
 
      The longest possible integration time will be set by the
      requirements of:  not getting the counts up to the non-linear
      regime  and not sitting on any science target for longer than the
      sky stability period.
 
      Setting the number of coadds greater than one will result in
      repeated reads with your selected integration time, added together,
      with the sum written out as a single image. This was also described
      earlier where the connection between integration time, number of
      NDRs, and coadds was discussed. VF automatically divides the counts
      in your image by the number of NDR and coadds, so that you can
      easily check for non-linearity.
 
      Typically you will set your integration time to the maximum value
      possible to still remain safely in the linear regime, using either a
      bright science object in the field or the sky background if your
      objects are faint. Then you will set your coadds so that the total
      time is about equal to sky stability time (one or two minutes at
      JHK, 20 seconds at longer wavelengths). Keep your counts greater
      than ~100 to avoid being limited by read noise.
 
      Selecting more than one &apos;cycle&apos; just means that the entire process
      will be repeated many times with many images being written out (as
      opposed to a single image if coadds &gt;1). If &apos;pair&apos; is selected as
      the &apos;Obs Mode&apos; then cycles will repeat in a ABBA... pattern.
 
 
    System Performance
    ==================
      The focus of the telescope is controlled from the operator&apos;s console
      so that the observer needs to request any focus changes (this will
      be changed in the future). The focus of the telescope gets more
      negative with decreasing temperature, and so has to be reduced
      during the night, usually stabilising by the early hours of the
      morning.
 
      The NSFCAM plate scales have different focus positions. The values
      depend on the ambient temperature and can change by 20 units (0.20)
      but typical values (for the non-tiptilt top end) are:
 
      Instrument Sensitivity Assuming a 2 arcsec x 2 arcsec Image is as
      follows:
 
      Filter   Background per square arcsec    3 sigma mag in min on target
                   with gain of 10 e/ADU           and 1 min on sky
 
      J         6.9 x 10**3 e/s  15.9  mag             20.6
      K&apos;        1.2 x 10**4      14.0                  18.9
      K         1.7 x 10**4      13.7                  18.8
 
 
      Other magnitudes or signal-to-noise values can be calculated
      assuming background limited performance:
 
                               S/N = signal x (sqrt time)
 
      So that for example to increase signal-to-noise from 3[[sigma]] to
      30[[sigma]], the signal would have to be increased by a factor of
      10, implying that the object would have to be 2.5 magnitudes
      brighter than the values given above, or the integration time would
      have to be increased by a factor of 100.
 
      For the narrow band filters or CVFs S/N can be estimated using the
      above numbers and the difference in bandwidth. For example, the
      signal through the CVF is down by about a factor of 10 compared to
      the corresponding broadband filter and the noise is down by the
      square root of 10; therefore objects would have to be 1.25
      magnitudes brighter than the values listed above for the same
      signal-to-noise.
 
      Note that often systematic effects will limit the accuracy
      achieved.  In particular sky variations will be the limiting factor
      unless you are careful to limit the exposure time for each image to
      less than the likely sky variation time. This translates into
      maximum integration times of about one or two minutes at JHK, and
      about 20 seconds at longer wavelengths. Keep your counts greater
      than ~100 to avoid being read noise limited. The minimum number of
      counts to be background limited is equal to the square of the read
      noise in electrons divided by the gain.
 
 
    Calibrations and Photometric Color Transformations
    ==================================================
      Non-Linearity
      -------------
      The array behaves in a similar manner to the CSHELL SBRC InSb
      array.  The plots shown in the back of the CSHELL manual of counts
      versus integration time, as a function of bias voltage, can be used
      as a guide for the camera.
 
      Observations of photometric standards with a 300mV bias show that
      counts around the 2500 level result in a 5% non-linear effect.
 
      Standard Stars
      --------------
      For JHK work the UKIRT Faint Standards list provides an excellent
      source of standard stars. This list is posted on paper in the
      control room and is also available to the operators and observers
      via the xstarcat utility. The natural system of NSFCAM is extremely
      similar to the UKIRT photometric system. The systems appear
      identical at H and K with a small difference at J described
      (provisionally) by the color relation:
 
                       (J-K)nsfcam = 0.95 (J-K)ukirt
 
      Using the UKIRT to CIT relationships from Krisciunas (private
      communication) this implies that the relationship between the NSFCAM
      natural system and the CIT system (as defined by the Elias
      standards) is:
 
                          Kcit     = Knsfcam
                          (H-K)cit = 0.854(H-K)nsfcam
                          (J-K)cit = 0.974(J-K)nsfcam
 
      Photometric zeropoints for NSFCAM (i.e. the magnitude that is added
      to the instrumental magnitude to obtain true magnitude) are
      typically:
 
      Filter                      J            H             K        L&apos;
 
      Plate Scale(arcsec)    0.30  0.15   0.30   0.15   0.30   0.15   0.15
      Zero Point            22.54 22.44  22.06  21.94  21.43  21.32  20.0
 
 
      These values are for an airmass of 1.0 and were measured over the
      time period December 1994 to November 1995. They are a measure of
      instrument throughput and should not vary by more than about 0.10mag
      from the above values. Atmospheric extinction is typically in the
      range 0.05 to 0.20 magnitudes per airmass at JHKL&apos;. When reducing
      your data don&apos;t forget to divide your FITS images by the number of
      coadds and NDR (DIVISOR parameter value in the header); this is done
      automatically in VF.
 
      The maximum time between successive images, i.e. the number of
      coadds, should be constrained by sky variability. At JHK sitting on
      one position for a minute or two should be OK, but in the thermal
      regime shorter observations are recommended, such as 200 coadds at
      0.08 seconds.
 
      Flat Fields
      -----------
      At J,H,K good flats can be obtained either from the dome or from the
      sky.  Night to night variations at the level of 2% have been seen so
      taking flats each night is recommended (this situation may have been
      improved with the new array temperature controller). All the lights
      should be on in the dome and the telescope pointed at the usual flat
      position (which is not the white spot). Taking two sets of data with
      the lights on, where one set has half the integration time of the
      other, and subtracting the results, works well.
 
      In the thermal regime dome flats require a long integration to get
      sufficient counts and usually sky flats are used, or flat fielding
      is not done and the object and calibrator are placed in the same
      region of the array.
 
      The array is flat to about 7%. The usual structure is a gradient
      across the array with the right brighter than the left, and what
      Mark Shure refers to as the Starship Enterprise pattern in the
      center. If you do not see this kind of pattern then it is possible
      that there is a problem with the array and you should report this to
      the operator and your support astronomer.
 

        </instrument_desc>
        <instrument_id>NSFCAM</instrument_id>
        <instrument_serial_number>not applicable</instrument_serial_number>
        <instrument_type>Camera</instrument_type>
        <instrument_version_id>not applicable</instrument_version_id>
    </Instrument_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_PDS3>
