<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:parb.fexp</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>PARABOLA for FEXP</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.fexp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Deering, D.W., and P. Leone, A sphere-scanning radiometer
                   for rapid directional measurements of sky and ground
                   radiance, Remote Sensing of the Environment, 19, 1-24,
                   1986.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DEERING-LEONE1986</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_PDS3>
        <instrument_name>PARABOLA</instrument_name>
        <instrument_desc>
 
 
    INSTRUMENT: PARABOLA
          HOST: FIELD EXPERIMENT
 
 
    Instrument Information
    ======================
      Instrument Id                  : PARB
      Instrument Host Id             : FEXP
      Pi Pds User Id                 : DDEERING
      Instrument Name                : PARABOLA
      Instrument Type                : SPECTROMETER
 
 
    Instrument Description
    ======================
      The Portable Apparatus for Rapid Acquisition of Bidirectional
      Observations of the Land and Atmosphere, or PARABOLA instrument
      was designed to overcome important limitations of previously
      existing field instruments for obtaining the adequate sampling
      needed to analyze the bidirectional reflectance angular
      distributions of earth surface targets and the sky.
 
      PARABOLA is a battery-powered, two-axis scanning head
      three-channel (visible, near infrared, and mid-infrared;
      0.650-0.670, 0.810-0.840, and 1.620-1.690 micrometers,
      respectively), motor-driven radiometer that enables the
      acquisition of radiance data for almost the complete (4 pi)
      sky- and ground-looking hemispheres in 15 degree instantaneous
      field-of-view sectors in only 11 s.  The detectors, two silicon
      and one germanium, are temperature regulated (by cooling or
      heating) through thermoelectric proportional control circuits.
      Due to the tremendous range in target brightness that can be
      expected in scanning a 4 pi sr field of view, an auto-ranging
      amplifier is used to switch the gain levels back-and-forth by
      factors of 1, 10 and 100 to maintain maximum radiometric
      sensitivity.
 
      The direct solar beam saturates PARABOLA detectors for the
      pixel at that view angle, and therefore a separate measurement
      of the sun is required for computations of direct and total
      irradiant flux.  Neutral density filters have been designed for
      mounting over the detector cones of PARABOLA for this purpose
      to obtain periodic measurements when the instrument is placed
      in its manual (or calibration, as opposed to scanning) mode.
      The radiometer is then pointed directly at the solar disk to
      acquire the measurement.  PARABOLA data system was originally
      designed to transform the analog data and record the records
      onto digital cassette tapes, providing a rugged recording
      medium with unlimited data storage capability.  The data were
      then transferred to computer diskettes via a microcomputer and
      serially linked tape reader.
 
      The original data system has been upgraded to enable direct
      transmittal of the data onto computer disks via a field-hardy
      portable computer.  The original cassette recording system is
      maintained as a redundant backup.  Specially developed software
      programs are then used to apply geometric computations and
      system calibration coefficients to the data to generate an
      output file that can be handled by a variety of commercial
      software packages, as well as those designed in-house.
 
      The primary mounting device is a lightweight, collapsible boom
      apparatus, called the Transportable Pickup Mount System or
      TPMS, whose primary unit consists of an aluminum triangular
      truss that decouples as four 2-m long sections.  At the top end
      resides a detachable, two-axis motorized PARABOLA radiometer
      head mounting and leveling head with a camera mounting
      attachment.  All operations of the PARABOLA/TPMS, except for
      raising and lowering the boom, are controlled from the PARABOLA
      data system control panel.  For the GRSFE study the complete
      PARABOLA/TPMS system was mounted on a large tripod.
 
      The PARABOLA design provides multidirectional viewing, but the
      geometry of the systems does not allow the same spot on the
      ground to be measured at each view direction.  Thus,
      considerable care must be taken in locating the instrument at a
      field site to ensure that the data acquired will actually
      represent the kind of surface that is desired; and some
      assumptions about the homogeneity of the area must be made.
      One approach to increasing the sampling density, which has been
      found to particularly effective, was employed at the GRSFE
      site.  This involves the rotation of the radiometer boom by +
      and -7.5 degrees from the solar principal plane axis and
      acquiring two additional complete scans.
 
      The three scans are combined in a special program that has been
      written to analyze the bidirectional reflectance distribution
      characteristics of a site.  This procedure also enables more
      accurate sampling of the hot spot effects and the aureole
      surrounding the solar disk.  In more spatially heterogeneous
      sites three or more (n) complete PARABOLA replicate scans are
      occasionally acquired by moving the instrument within the site.
      The replicates are then averaged for each viewing angle
      position to minimize the within-field inhomogeneity effects.
      Directional reflectances are normally computed as
      hemispherical-directional reflectance factors using the
      PARABOLA directional radiance measurements from the
      ground-looking hemisphere divided by the PARABOLA-derived
      incident irradiance as computed from the PARABOLA sky
      irradiance data or from a calibrated painted BaSO4 reference
      standard panel.
 
      A pair of Eppley Pyranometers was used to obtain broad-band
      (visible, reflected IR) sky irradiance and the irradiance
      reflected from the ground.  The instrument was deployed at
      PARABOLA height.
 
 
    Science Objectives
    ==================
      Measure the bi-directional reflectance function for field
      targets.
 
 
    Operational Considerations
    ==========================
      N/A
 
 
    Calibration Description
    =======================
      Radiometric laboratory calibration of PARABOLA is performed at
      GSFC on a 1.8 m spherical integrator employing 12 200-W quartz
      halogen lamps (2950K at 6.5A).  The number of lamps is varied
      to produce 12 radiance levels for calibration.  Three separate
      calibration runs are made to fully calibrate PARABOLA at the
      three gain levels of the instrument.  Neutral density filters
      (0.1 and 0.01 density levels; precisely calibrated) are used
      for the two lowest gain settings.  The voltage response to the
      radiance level is linear in all three spectral channels for
      each gain setting with linear correlation coefficients of
      0.999, and has been found to be very stable from year to year.
      Calibrations are typically performed at the beginning and at
      the end of each seasonal field campaign.
 
 
    Section &apos;PARB&apos;
    ==============
 
      &apos;PARB&apos; Section Parameter &apos;RADIANCE&apos;
      -----------------------------------
        Radiance is the amount of energy per time per projected area
        per steradian.
 
        Instrument Parameter Name      : RADIANCE
        Sampling Parameter Name        : WAVELENGTH
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : 0.650000
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : 1.690000
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : MICROMETER
 
 
      Description
      -----------
        N/A
 
 
      Sensitivity
      -----------
        N/A
 

        </instrument_desc>
        <instrument_id>PARB</instrument_id>
        <instrument_serial_number>not applicable</instrument_serial_number>
        <instrument_type>Spectrometer</instrument_type>
        <instrument_version_id>not applicable</instrument_version_id>
    </Instrument_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_PDS3>
