<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:caspir.mssso</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CRYOGENIC ARRAY SPECTROMETER/IMAGER for MSSSO</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.mssso::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   McGregor, P.J., P.D. Nicholson, M.G. Allen, near-infrared observations of
                   the impacts of fragments C, D, G, K, N, R, V, and W of Comet
                   P/Shoemaker-Levy 9 with Jupiter from the ground, Icarus, 121 361-388,
                   1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MCGREGORETAL1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_PDS3>
        <instrument_name>CRYOGENIC ARRAY SPECTROMETER/IMAGER</instrument_name>
        <instrument_desc>
 
 
    Instrument Overview
    ===================
      This manual describes the operation of CASPIR, the Cryogenic Array
      Spectrometer/Imager on the ANU 2.3 m telescope at Siding Spring
      Observatory.  CASPIR uses a Santa Barbara Research Center (SBRC)
      CRC463 256 x 256 InSb detector array to provide direct imaging and
      spectroscopic capabilities in the 1-5 micrometer wavelength range.
      Two direct imaging focal plane scales of 0.5 arcsec/pixel and 0.25
      arcsec/pixel are available, as well as long slit J, H, and K grisms
      giving two pixel resolving powers of ~500 through a 1 arcsec x 128
      arcsec slit, and IJ, JH, and HK cross-dispersed grisms giving two
      pixel resolving powers of ~1100 through a 1 arcsec x 15 arcsec
      slit.  Coronograph and imaging polarimetry functions are also
      available.
 
 
    Operational Considerations
    ==========================
      CASPIR operates within the environment common to all infrared
      instrumentation on the 2.3 m telescope. All mechanical functions are
      controlled from MOPRA to the LSI-11/23 located in the Cassegrain
      Instrumentation Rack in the Nasmyth Lab, and from this to the
      instrument control subrack mounted on the Instrument Mounting Box
      (IMB).  The detector array clocks, biases, and signal processing are
      performed by the SBRC Array Control Electronics (ACE2) also mounted
      on the IMB, close to the CASPIR dewar.  The ACE2 is controlled
      directly by MOPRA through a 9600 baud RS-232 connection.  Data from
      the four detector output channels are digitised in the ACE2 using
      four 16-bit, 500 kHz Burr-Brown ADCS, and serialised using four
      transputer Link Adaptors.  The serial data are transmitted from the
      Cassegrain focus to the Nasmyth Lab where four T800 transputers
      receive the data and process it as necessary.  When the requested
      integration sequence completes, the data are transferred to MOPRA
      through a transputer link to Q-bus interface and are displayed on
      the workstation screen and stored on disk.  The detector array
      temperature is controlled by a commercial controller located in the
      Nasmyth Lab.  MOPRA communicates with this controller through an
      RS-232 line.
 
 
    Optics
    ======
      CASPIR is a cryogenic reimaging camera with a 50 mm long, 10.4 mm
      diameter collimated beam section.  The camera body is cooled to ~60
      K by the first stage of a closed cycle helium refrigerator, and the
      detector array cooled detector array cooled to ~32 K by the second
      stage of the cooler.  The dewar incorporates a novel design which
      uses five 16-position annular wheels mounted coaxially around the
      cooler to produce a compact vacuum system.  The wheels are driven by
      motors located on the dewar base plate.
 
      The CASPIR dewar mounts on port A of the IMB.  The rotatable
      dichroic mirror in the IMB directs the f/18 telescope beam to the
      dewar.  The dewar window is a Sapphire/CaF2 doublet which acts as
      field lens to image the telescope exit pupil (the secondary mirror)
      onto an internal cold stop.  A cold gold-coated mirror then directs
      the beam down, parallel to the dewar axis.  The telescope focus is
      located immediately below this mirror at the Aperture Wheel.  The
      Aperture Wheel contains baffles for the 0.5 arcsec/pixel and 0.25
      arcsec/pixel focal plane scales, a range of slits for the grisms,
      coronograph masks, and the field mask used for imaging polarimetry
      (Table 12).  The diverging beam then passes to a fixed MgO/CaF2
      doublet, collimator lens which produces the collimated beam
      section.  Immediately below this, in the collimated beam, is the
      Upper Filter Wheel which contains the filters listed in Table 13.
      Next is the Utility Wheel which is located at the pupil plane.  This
      wheel contains the direct imaging cold stop, the MgO/CaF2 doublet
      slow camera lens for the 0.25 arcsec/pixel focal plane scale, the
      six grisms, and the Wollaston prism polarimeter analysers (Table
      14).  Below the Utility Wheel is the Lower Filter Wheel which
      contains the filters listed in Table 15. Note that some of the
      broadband filters require blocking filters located in the Lower
      Filter Wheel.  Both filter wheels contain clear positions.  The
      detector array should not be exposed to optical light while cold, so
      the software prevents both clear positions being selected at the
      same time. Note also that the Lower Filter Wheel is located in an
      f/10.4 converging beam when the slow camera is used, so some
      refocusing between filters may be required.  The final wheel is the
      Lens Wheel which contains the MgO/BaF2 fast camera lenses for the
      0.5 arcsec/pixel focal plane scale.  These are rotated out of the
      beam when the slow camera is used. The detector array is located at
      the lower end of the dewar at the camera focus.
 
 
    Detectors
    =========
      The detector is an SBRC CRC463 256x256 InSb array which is sensitive
      from ~0.9 micrometers to 5.5 micrometers.  The array has four output
      channels corresponding to four interlaced columns (12341234...) The
      array is controlled by the SBRC ACE2 drive electronics which is
      mounted close to the CASPIR dewar.  Communications with the ACE2 is
      through an RS-232 connection to MOPRA.
 
 
      The CRC463 is a hybrid device in which the InSb detector material is
      bump-bonded to a silicon multiplexer through indium bumps.  The
      multiplexer is a switched FET read-out device, which operates
      differently than a CCD.  Each pixel (or unit cell) contains four
      FETS; the two row select FETs and the reset FET are switches which
      can be thought of as closed when activated.  The fourth FET  acts as
      a source-follower amplifier which continuously samples the voltage
      on the detector node without affecting its value.  A load is
      provided for the unit cell source-follower FET.  This load FET  is
      located in the column biasing circuitry.  The output FET acts as a
      second source-follower amplifier with its external 10 KOhm load
      resistor in the ACE2 electronics rack.  The two column select FETs
      also act as switches.
 
      Pixels in the array are sequentially addressed by pulsing column and
      row shift registers which activate the column and row select FET
      switches.  Once a pixel is selected, the voltage of the detector
      node can be non-destructively read via the source-follower amplifier
      signal train, and the detector node voltage can then be optionally
      reset to Vdduc by activating the reset FET switch by pulsing the
      Phibrst clock line.  Note that the stored charge is not transferred
      across the array like a CCD.  Instead each pixel is sequentially
      reset and read.  This results in a time delay in the integration
      window across the array of one frame readout time between the first
      and last pixels.
 
      The array readout scheme permits the use of a variety of readout
      methods which are now described.
 
 
    Data Modes
    ==========
      Readout Method 1: Fast Sampling
      -------------------------------
      In the fastest readout method, speed is considered more important
      than accuracy so we take only one sample per pixel and reference
      this voltage to electrical ground (Vss).  The detector node voltage
      is applicable in readout method I. The unit cell is reset,
      integrated, and sampled once at the end of the integration ramp.
 
      This method should be used for imaging in the 3-4 micrometer band
      and at M where the high thermal background flux significantly fills
      the detector wells in of order the frame readout time.  In this
      situation, the dominant noise source is photon shot noise from the
      background flux, so readout noise is not an issue.
 
      The minimum readout time for this method is 0.2 sec.
 
      Readout Method 2: Relative Sampling
      -----------------------------------
      Under less extreme background conditions, significant improvement in
      stability can be made by referencing the signal level to the reset
      level, instead of electrical ground.  This is done in readout method
      2.
 
      Note that the detector node voltage jumps when the reset FET is
      switched off, and this pedestal level is not removed in readout
      method 2. The pedestal level is different for each pixel in the
      array so this imprints a pedestal structure on the image, which is
      difficult to remove completely.  The uncertainty in the value of
      this pedestal is known as kTC noise.
 
      For direct imaging through broad band filters with high sky levels,
      the dominant noise source is still the photon shot noise of the
      background flux so readout method 2 gives acceptable performance.
 
      The minimum readout time for this method is 0.3 sec.
 
      Readout Method 3: Double-Correlated Sampling
      --------------------------------------------
      The pedestal structure can be removed using a readout method which
      references the detector node voltage at the end of the integration
      to the voltage at the beginning of the integration.
 
      In principle, this readout method is susceptible to electrical 1/f
      noise since it differences two samples separated in time by the
      duration of the integration.  In practice, this is unlikely to be an
      important noise source.
 
      This is the preferred readout method for broad band imaging because
      it does not imprint the pedestal pattern on the data.
 
      The minimum readout time for this method is 0.4 sec.
 
      Readout Method 4: Triple Correlated Sampling
      --------------------------------------------
      The potential 1/f noise problem with readout method 3 can be
      overcome, at the expense of two more reads, by referring both the
      start and end reads to their respective reset levels.
 
      Naively, this should be the most accurate readout method to adopt.
      However, we must now delve into the more obscure operating
      characteristics of the CRC463 array to see why other effects
      dominate.
 
      Readout Method 5: Fowler Sampling
      ---------------------------------
      The FET switches in the CRC463 multiplexer are not perfect switches
      as assumed above, but instead have finite gate capacitances that act
      as sinks of charge that would otherwise remain on the detector node
      capacitance.  The reset pedestal (i.e., the amount the detector node
      voltage jumps by when the reset is taken off) is due to a
      redistribution of charge from the detector node capacitance to the
      reset FET gate capacitance that occurs when the reset FET gate
      voltage (i.e., the reset clock voltage) moves positive to switch the
      reset FET off.  This amounts to ~100 mV of lost detector reverse
      bias (or well depth).  Similarly, a further ~400 mV of detector bias
      is lost when the row and column select FETs  are switched off to
      deselect the pixel.  This constitutes a movement of ~500 mV of
      charge off the detector node compared to the normal operating
      detector reverse bias that remains of only ~200 mV.  The true
      pedestal is therefore significantly larger than the reset pedestal
      seen if each pixel is reset and read on one pass through the array.
 
      Fowler &amp; Gatley (1990, ApJ, 353, L33) show that the read noise can
      be reduced by performing multiple nondestructive passes through the
      array at the beginning and end of the integration ramp.  By
      resetting each pixel on one pass through the array, and sampling the
      detector node voltage on subsequent passes through the array, the
      true pedestal is removed from the data.  Each time a pixel is
      selected charge is redistributed from the row and column select FETs
      back onto the detector node capacitance.  Fowler claims that the
      read noise is predominantly due to the kTC noise associated with
      this charge redistribution.  By performing multiple non-destructive
      passes through the array at the beginning and end of the
      integration, the read noise is reduced by the square root of the
      number of passes.
 
      Readout Method 5 implements Fowler sampling in this way.  The number
      of reads at each end of the integration is set by the FNDR parameter
      (CASPIR/FNDR=...).  For applications where low read noise is
      required, at the expense of increased frame readout time, method 5
      is the preferred readout method.  This is likely to be the case when
      using the grisms.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      Well Depth Considerations
      -------------------------
      The detector node capacitance for the CRC463 array is ~0.06 pF.  The
      well depth is then proportional to the actual reverse bias voltage
      across the detector; q = CV.  Consequently, a detector reverse bias
      of ~160 mV is required for a well depth of 60,000 e. Our array has
      an odd-even column effect which causes the applied detector reverse
      bias on even columns to be lower than that on odd columns.  This
      means that even columns have well depths ~80% smaller than odd
      columns.
 
      Linearity Correction
      --------------------
      When the bias-subtracted linearity data are plotted as signal rates,
      it is apparent that the CASPIR array has a quadratic non-linearity
      that must be allowed for during data reduction. The best description
      of this non-linearity is currently given by the equation:
 
      Linear Counts = Raw Counts + 6.4 * 10^-6 * (Raw Counts)^2
 
      It is possible that different quadratic coefficients apply to
      different pixels.  Further investigation of this effect is
      required.
 
      Transputer Preprocessor
      -----------------------
      CASPIR is designed to operate in the high background conditions
      encountered at long wavelengths.  It uses four 16-bit 500 kHz
      analog-to-digital converters to digitize the data, with the rest of
      the data train being capable of sustained data rates of at least 2
      microsec/pixel.  The requirement that individual frames be coadded
      at this data rate to build up the image means that the data cannot
      be input directly into MOPRA.  Instead a transputer-based
      preprocessor is used.
 
      A transputer is a fast microprocessor chip with considerable
      in-built parallelism and which uses four fast serial &apos;links&apos; for
      I/0.  Each link can be connected to another transputer, or to an
      external device through a &apos;Link Adaptor&apos;, which is essentially a
      bidirectional serial to parallel converter.  This architecture has
      made transputers popular in parallel computing applications.
 
      The CASPIR system uses four transputer link adaptors on the ADC
      cards to serialise the data at the Cassegrain focus.  Four serial
      lines then bring the signals to the Nasmyth Lab where the transputer
      preprocessor is located.  This consists of four T800 transputer
      boards which each have 1 Mbyte of memory and each are responsible
      for processing the data from one serial line.  The current frame is
      DMAD into transputer memory at the same time that the previous frame
      is being coadded to an accumulation array where the summed image is
      stored.  After the requested number of coadd cycles, the accumulated
      image is divided by the number of coadd cycles, optionally has a
      bias frame subtracted and is divided by flatfield frame, and is
      copied to MOPRA via a transputer link to Q-bus interface with the
      four separate data channels correctly interlaced to form the final
      image.
 
      The result of each sequence of coadd cycles is displayed on MOPRA&apos;s
      workstation screen and is stored on MOPRA&apos;s disk.  The individual
      frames from each cycle are not normally saved (this only occurs in
      the occultation observing mode).
 
 
    Mounting
    ========
      Instrument Mounting Box
      -----------------------
      All infrared dewars mount on a box attached to the Cassegrain focus
      of the 2.3 m telescope that is known as the Instrument Mounting Box
      (IMB).  Two dewars can mount on the IMB at the same time and a
      dichroic mirror in the IMB can be positioned to direct infrared
      light from the telescope to either dewar.  The IMB output ports are
      identified by the labels A-D.  From the Cassegrain Access Platform,
      with the control electronics racks on your left, the port position
      facing you is &apos;A&apos;, the one to your right (not used) is &apos;B&apos;, the back
      position is &apos;C&apos;, and the control electronics mount on face &apos;D&apos;.  A
      dichroic reflexer directs the infrared beam to the selected IMB port
      while an acquisition system views the same field in optical light.
      Auxiliary modules can be mounted above the dichroic reflexer in the
      IMB.  A calibration lamp module is available, and a polarimetry
      module is under construction.
 
      A manual dust cover is located in the mounting flange at the top of
      the IMB.  The open and close positions are clearly marked on the
      flange, and it should be used.
 
 
    Calibrations
    ============
      Calibration Module
      ------------------
      The calibration lamp module can be used to obtain wavelength
      calibration arc spectra.  The module contains Xenon and Argon lamps
      as well as an incandescent lamp which may be useful for
      flatfielding.  A rotary mirror is used to select one of the three
      lamps and a flip mirror is placed in the telescope beam to direct
      the lamp light to the detector.
 
      Polarimetry Module
      ------------------
      The polarimetry module contains an achromatic half-wave plate
      borrowed from the polarimetry module used at the AAT with IRIS, and
      a 50 mm diameter wire grid for position angle and efficiency
      calibration.  The warm half-wave plate is rotated in the infrared
      beam to rotate the intrinsic plane of polarization of an
      astronomical source with respect to a cold analyser mounted within
      CASPIR.  The analyser is either a Wollaston prism mounted in the
      Utility wheel, or a wire grid mounted in the Upper Filter wheel.
      The Wollaston prism separates the parallel and perpendicular
      polarization components equally on the array, so is a dual beam
      system.  The wire passes only one polarization, but it does allow
      the grisms mounted in the Utility wheel to be used for single beam
      spectropolarimetry.
 
 
    Field of View
    =============
      Sky Subtraction
      ---------------
      The strong and variable near-infrared background has contributions
      from OH airglow in the J, H, and K bands, moonlight (either directly
      or reflected off clouds) especially in the J band, and from thermal
      emission from the telescope and sky in the K and L bands which
      varies with temperature and humidity.  Although the 10-30%
      variations in background caused by these factors do not strongly
      limit the S/N of observations (except at K and L for large changes
      in temperature), they greatly complicate both the creation of
      mosaics of large regions and accurate surface photometry of objects
      with extents comparable to CASPIR&apos;s field of view.  For such
      observing programs, it is best to obtain sufficient object exposures
      (and intermixed sky exposures if necessary) to create a SKY frame
      for each dataset.  For programs with single or a few observations of
      many objects, a sky calibration based on observations of several
      objects, possibly combined with subtracting a fitted surface from
      the final image, is the best that can be accomplished.  These
      grouped observations could be treated as one dataset for the
      purposes of sky subtraction.  It is useful to remember that variable
      airglow can cause the sky background to vary at H by a factor of 2
      and at J by 40% on hour timescales.
 
      SKY frames for a dataset are created using the redimage task by
      setting the subsky flag, and supplying values to the obstype,
      subtype, nrun, and destripe parameters, obstype defines the type of
      sky observations in the dataset.  obstype=all indicates that all
      images in the dataset are to be included in the creation of SKY
      frames. obstype=objskyobj indicates that the first image in the
      dataset is an object image, and this is followed by a sequence of an
      off-source sky image and an object image, ending with an object
      image.  Only the off-source sky images will be included in the
      creation of SKY frames.  obstype=skyobjsky indicates that the first
      image in the dataset is an off-source sky image, and this is
      followed by object and off-source sky image pairs, ending with a sky
      image.  Only the off-source sky images will be included in the
      creation of SKY frames. obstype=skyobjobjsky indicates that the
      dataset consists of sequences of sky, object, object, sky frames.
      Only the off-source sky images will be included in the creation of
      SKY frames. obstype=radio is a special pattern used for nbL band
      observations, initially of radio galaxies.  Sets of ten dithered nbL
      frames are separated by Kn sky and object frames that (hopefully)
      allow drifts in telescope pointing to be corrected in the final
      mosaicing.  It is likely that, these patterns will include most
      observing sequences in user defined DO files.  redimage can be
      extended to include other sky types if this proves necessary.
 
      Standard star measurements recorded in pairs with the star displaced
      on the array can be processed by selecting obstype=standard.  This
      is a special type requiring exactly two input images.  An output
      image is formed by subtracting the second (sky) image of the
      standard star from the first (object) image of the standard star.  A
      permanent output file is produced with the name stdnnn_mmm where nnn
      is the number of the first standard star image and mmm is the number
      of the second standard star image.  This sky- subtracted standard
      star image can be automatically processed in each of the following
      steps except that mosaicing and creating a coordinate grid will be
      ignored.  These steps are not applicable to this image.  It is most
      likely that users will fix bad pixels and then measure aperture
      photometry on the standard star image after sky subtracting.
 
      The subtype parameter in redimage defines the type of sky
      subtraction that is performed. subtype=all defines that all sky
      images in the dataset will be included in the creation of a single
      SKY frame, which is then scaled to the median pixel value of each
      object image and subtracted from them.  This is adequate for small
      datasets where the total time span of the observation is less than
      about 20 minutes.  Larger datasets need to be subdivided into
      smaller units, with individual SKY frames.  This is achieved by
      setting subtype=running.  This causes a SKY frame to be formed for
      each object image in the dataset from the median of nrun sky images
      taken immediately before and after the object image.  The object
      image itself is not included in the running median.  The SKY frame
      created for each object image is then scaled to the median pixel
      value of the object image and subtracted from it.
 
      The destripe parameter in redimage determines whether a residual
      column bias pattern is to be defined and subtracted from each image
      after normal sky subtraction.  Usually this will not be necessary.
      However, nbL images obtained with readout method 1 suffer from DC
      drifts in the bias levels of the four output amplifiers between the
      object and sky frames that are manifest as a residual column bias
      pattern with four pixel period that is often not removed by normal
      sky subtraction.  When the destripe parameter is set, redimage
      determines the shape of this bias pattern by projecting the image in
      the column direction to a 1D spectrum, and then subtracting this
      spectrum off each row in the image.
 
 
    System Performance
    ==================
      The best empirical estimate of the system performance is the
      observation that for imaging with 0.5 arcsec pixels after 6 hr of
      on-source integration, objects spread over ~2 arcsec with Kn ~19.5
      mag are detectable with a signal- to-noise ratio of ~5, depending on
      how they are measured.  This is confirmed by similar observations
      with 4 min on-source integration times reaching Kn ~17.0 mag with
      similar signal-to-noise ratio.
 
      The following describes measurements of basic system parameters, and
      then calculations of the theoretical performance based on these
      parameters.  These calculations can be used to estimate system
      performance in other configurations, but should be normalized by
      comparison with the above observed sensitivities.
 
      System zero point offsets are based on the total ADUs in a
      sky-subtracted stellar image after correction for airmass effects
      and are defined by the equation ZP = M_std + 2.5*log(ADU/sec).
      Typical values of the zero point offsets for each filter (mainly
      with the 0.5 arcsec pixel scale) are listed in Table 3. These can be
      used to calculate the total signal expected on an object of a given
      brightness or the signal/pixel on an object of a given surface
      brightness.
 
      Table 3: Typical Zero Points
 
      Filter                     Zero Point
      --------------------------------------
      J                              21.6
      H                              21.6
      K                              20.8
      K&apos;                             20.6
      Kn                             20.5
      M                              11.7
      MSO [Fe II]                    18.6
      H_2 1-0 S(1)                   18.0
      H I Br_gamma                   17.6
      2.21 micrometer Continuum      19.1
      CO (delta_v=2)                 18.5
      3.28 micrometer Dust           16.6
      3.60 micrometer Continuum      17.3
      4.00 micrometer Continuum      16.6
      H I Br_alpha                   16.3
 
      Typical background brightnesses measured with CASPIR are listed in
      Table 4.  The expected background photon fluxes can be calculated
      from the tabulated background brightnesses and the system zero point
      offsets.
 
      Table 4: Background Brightnesses (mag/arcsec^2)
 
      Filter                     IRPS  IRIS   CASPIR   CASPIR   PICNIC
                                 1984  1993  Nov 1993 Mar 1993 Aug 1994
      ------------------------------------------------------------------
      J                          15.5  15.0    18.7     ....    ....
      H                          14.5  13.7    14.6     ....    ....
      K                          11.5  12.5    11.6     11.7    ....
      K&apos;                         ....  13.7    12.5     12.6    ....
      Kn                         ....  13.2    12.4     12.5   13.1-13.9
      2.21 micrometer Continuum  ....  ....    12.9     ....    ....
      CO (delta_v=2)             ....  ....    10.7     ....    ....
      3.28 micrometer Dust       ....  ....     3.1     ....    ....
      3.60 micrometer Continuum  ....  ....     3.8     ....    ....
      4.00 micrometer Continuum  ....  ....     2.6     ....    ....
      H I Br_alpha               ....  ....     2.0     ....    ....
 
      The noise in an image is a combination of photon shot noise from the
      sky and telescope, photon shot noise from the object, shot noise
      from the dark current, read noise, and other systematic noise
      sources that are difficult to quantify. For small signals, the noise
      per pixel can be estimated from the equation:
 
                Noise = [RN^2 + T*(i_b + i_d)]^1/2
 
      where RN is the read noise in e-, T is the integration time in sec,
      i_b is the background signal in e-/sec, and i_d is the dark current
      in e-/sec.  The read noise for the double sample readout methods
      (methods 2-4, and method 5 with FNDR=1) is ~50 e-.  The dark current
      is typically 10 e-/s/pixel for most of the array, but there are a
      significant number of detectors with dark currents of 100
      e-/s/pixel, and some with 1000 e-/s/pixel.
 
      With these data, theoretical performance figures for CASPIR can be
      calculated from the measured background brightness and the camera
      throughput as quantified by the system zero point.
 
      For example, for a Kn background brightness of 12.4 mag/arcsec^2 and
      a Kn zero point offset of 20.5 mag, the Kn background flux for 0.5
      arcsec pixels is
 
          (10^[(Z*P-m_std)/2.5])/4 = 434 ADU/sec/pixel
 
      In a 5 sec integration, the background count is ~2170 ADU/pixel, or
      19550 e-/pixel (1 ADU = 9 e-). The shot noise of this background
      signal is (19550)^(1/2) = 140 e- which dominates the typical readout
      noise of 40-60 e-.  Consequently, Kn images with 0.5 arcsec pixels
      and an integration time of 5 sec should be background limited.  The
      total noise per cycle is ~(50^2 + 19550)^.5 ~148 e-/pixel or 148/9 =
      16.5.  ADU/pixel which is reduced to 4.8 ADU/pixel when 12 cycles
      are averaged.  The measured value is ~5 ADU/pixel.  We assume here
      that sufficient sky frames are averaged so that sky subtraction is
      essentially noiseless.
 
      For a 5*sigma detection of an object spread over n x n pixels, we
      require an average signal in each of these n^2 pixels of five times
      the noise per pixel.  The total object signal is then n^2 x 5 x 4.8
      ADU.  This can be converted to a Kn magnitude after dividing by the
      integration time of 5 sec and using the Kn zero point offset of 20.5
      mag.  In this way, we can estimate limiting magnitudes at Kn for a
      range of seeing or object sizes.  The results of these calculations
      are shown in detail in Table 5.
 
      Table 5: Performance at Kn (0.5 arcsec/pixel)
 
          Image Size       5*sigma Total Signal     Mag      Time to 20 mag
      (arcsec)   (pixels)     (ADU/5 sec)       (1 min, 5:1)     (min)
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------
       1 x 1     2 x 2           96                17.3           145
      1.5 x 1.5  3 x 3          215                16.4           760
       2 x 2     4 x 4          382                15.8          2290
       5 x 5    10 x 10        2384                13.8         91200
 
      Predicted performance figures for 5*sigma detections in 1 min of
      on-source integration in different seeing conditions for various
      filters are listed in Table 6 for the 0.5 arcsec/pixel scale and in
      Table 7 for the 0.25 arcsec/pixel scale.  The 1 min integration time
      does not include time for sky measurements and the dead time between
      frames of ~20 sec.  It is recommended to limit individual frames to
      1 min exposures, effectively making the elapsed time ~80 sec, so
      that an adequate number of sky frames can be obtained in the time
      scale of 15 min on which the sky level is observed to change
      significantly.  If off-source sky measurements are necessary, it is
      recommended that equal time be spent on the object, and sky
      positions.
 
      Relative performance figures for each filter are of interest in
      deciding which passband is most sensitive for a particular
      observation.  These calculations for the 0.5 arcsec/pixel scale in
      1.5 arcsec seeing and an integration time of 5 sec with 12 cycles
      are listed in Table 8 for a 15.0 mag star with zero color
      (S/N_HotStar), a typical unreddened late-type star with K = 15.0
      mag, J - K = 1.0, and H - K = 0.2 (S/N_CoolStar), and a typical AGN
      power law spectrum (S/N_AGN).
 
      Performance figures for the grisms can be estimated assuming a slit
      transmission Tau_Slit = 0.5 and a grism transmission Tau_Grism =
      0.5. For example, consider an observation using the HK grism and a 1
      arcsec (2 pixel) wide slit of an object spread over 2 arcsec (n_y =
      4 pixels) along the slit and recorded in two frames.
 
      Table 6: System Performance (0.5 arcsec/pixel)
 
      Filter  Time Cycles  RN^2  Background  Dark  5*sigma, 1 min Magnitude
                                   Signal   Signal   1x1 1.5x1.5  2x2   5x5
             (sec)        (e-)^2    (e-)     (e-)          (arcsec)
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------
      J       5.0    12    2500     3100      50     19.1  18.3  17.6  15.6
      H       5.0    12    2500     7100      50     18.8  18.0  17.3  15.4
      K       5.0    12    2500    53850      50     17.1  16.2  15.6  13.6
      K&apos;      5.0    12    2500    19550      50     17.4  16.5  15.9  13.9
      Kn      5.0    12    2500    19550      50     17.3  16.4  15.8  13.8
      [Fe II] 10.0    6    2500      900     100     16.8  15.9  15.3  13.3
      H2O     10.0    6    2500     3810     100     15.8  15.0  14.3  12.3
      Cont2.2 10.0    6    2500     6800     100     16.7  15.9  15.2  13.2
      CO      10.0    6    2500    29660     100     15.5  14.6  14.0  12.0
 
      Table 7: System Performance (0.25 arcsec/pixel)
 
      Filter  Time Cycles  RN^2  Background  Dark  5*sigma, 1 min Magnitude
                                   Signal   Signal   1x1 1.5x1.5  2x2   5x5
             (sec)        (e-)^2    (e-)     (e-)          (arcsec)
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------
      J        5.0    12   2500      775      50     17.9  17.0  16.4  14.4
      H        5.0    12   2500     1775      50     17.8  16.9  16.3  14.3
      K        5.0    12   2500    13460      50     16.3  15.4  14.8  12.8
      K&apos;       5.0    12   2500     4890      50     16.5  15.6  15.0  13.0
      Kn       5.0    12   2500     4890      50     16.4  15.5  14.9  12.9
      [Fe 11] 10.0     6   2500      224     100     15.4  14.5  13.9  11.9
      H20     10.0     6   2500      978     100     14.7  13.8  13.2  11.2
      Cont2.2 10.0     6   2500     1700     100     15.7  14.8  14.2  12.2
      CO      10.0     6   2500     7420     100     14.6  13.7  13.1  11.1
      Cont3.28 0.3   200   2500   706500       3     10.0  9.1    8.5   6.5
      nbL      0.3   200   2500   706500       3     10.7  9.8    9.2   7.2
 
      (n_frames = 2) each with an integration time T = 180 sec and with
      the object placed at different positions along the slit in both
      images.  The spectral resolution at 2.2 micrometers is 2.2/2200 =
      0.001 micrometers/pixel, or a factor of Lambda = 0.33/0.001 = 330
      lower than for Kn.  In the spectral direction, each pixel sees
      signal from an area of sky A_Sky = 1 arcsec x 0.5 arcsec = 0.5
      arcsec^2, dispersed by a factor of Lambda more than for Kn, but
      reduced in flux by Tau_Grism.  The background current per pixel
      (averaged over features in the sky emission spectrum) is therefore:
 
      10^((Z.P.-m_Bkg)/2.5) * A_sky * Tau_Grism * Gain/Lambda =
                                                       11.8 e-/sec/pixel
 
      Here we have used the observed Kn background brightness, M_Bkg, of
      12.4 mag/arcsec^2 , and zero point offset, Z.P., of 20.5 mag, and
      conversion between electrons and ADU, Gain, of 9 e-/ADU.  The noise
      per pixel is then
 
      Noise = (50^2 + 180*(11.8+10))^1/2 = (2500 + 3933)^1/2 = 80 e-/pixel
 
      We see from this that shot noise from the dark current makes a
      significant contribution to the total noise, and that integration
      times of order 180 sec are required to minimize the read noise
      contribution.  Integration times significantly longer than this are
      not recommended because sky intensity variation make accurate sky
      subtraction increasingly difficult, and significant numbers of hot
      pixels saturate as the integration time is increased further.
      Normally, spectra are recorded as a nodded pair to allow sky
      subtraction, and preferably as an ABBA sequence.  In the case where
      a single sky frame is subtracted from an object frame to perform the
      sky subtraction, the total noise per pixel is increased by (2)^1/2
      because the sky frame has the same noise per pixel as the object
      frame.  For our example, the final noise becomes 113 e-/pixel.
 
      We define a 5*sigma detection per pixel by requiring a
      signal-to-noise ratio of 5 per pixel after averaging n_y pixels
      along the slit and averaging the n_frames object frames.  The
      average object signal per pixel in the dispersion direction is then
 
      Signal = 5 * Noise / (n_y)^1/2 /(n_frames)^1/2 = 200 e-/pixel
 
      The equivalent Kn imaging signal would be
 
      Kn Signal =
        200 / Gain / Tau_Grism / Tau_Slit * Lambda * n_y^2
                = 470000 ADU
 
      which corresponds to a Kn brightness of
 
      Kn = 20.5 - 2.5 * log (470000/180) = 12.0 mag
 
      From this we predict that a signal-to-noise ratio of 5:1 can be
      achieved with the HK grism on a Kn 12.0 mag object in the continuum
      in 6 min of on-source integration.  The 5*sigma line detection
      sensitivity in the same time can be estimated by assuming the line
      occupies two pixels in the dispersion direction. The line flux is
      then
 
      3.84 * 10^-14 * 10^(-12.0/2.5) * 0.001 * 2 = 1.2 * 10^-21 W cm^-2
 
 
    Filters
    =======
      Acquisition System
      ------------------
      The IMB   acquisition system contains either the ICCD acquisition
      TV, SBIG autoguider, or tip-tilt sensor mounted on an X-Y stage at
      the bottom of the IMB.  These systems view the telescope field in
      optical light through the dichroic reflexer, and allow offset
      guiding or selection of bright tip-tilt reference stars.  The travel
      of the X-Y stage is ~ +/-31.2mm in each direction in the f/18 (5
      arcsec/mm) telescope beam.  A TV filter/focusser unit mounted on the
      X-Y stage directly in front of the TV camera converts the f/18
      telescope beam to f/5.76, provides a pupil mask that acts as an
      optical sky baffle, allows for focussing of the optical image
      independent of the infrared image, and contains B, V, R, I, and
      RG630 filters as well as a clear position.
 
      F Wheel Contents
      ----------------
      The contents of the five wheels are listed below.
 
      Note that as of Oct 1994, it is necessary to set the Utility Wheel
      to increasing numbers in order to ensure that it is latched
      correctly.  The Lens Wheel should also be set to increasing
      numbers.  These details will be fixed as soon as convenient.
 
      Table 12: Aperture Wheel Contents
 
      Position    Keyword      Content
      ----------------------------------------------------------------
      1            Blank        Blank
      2            Lslit1      1.0 arcsec x 128 arcsec slit
      3            Disk5       5.0 arcsec occulting disk
      4            Lslit1.5    1.5 arcsec x 128 arcsec slit
      5            Lslit2      2.0 arcsec x 128 arcsec slit
      6            SlowClr     0.25 arcsec/pixel baffle
      7            Lslit5      5.0 arcsec x 128 arcsec slit
      8            Lslitl0     10.0 arcsec x 128 arcsec slit
      9            Polar       Three 20 arcsec x 120 arcsec
                                 slits (for polarimetry)
      10           Sslit10     10.0 arcsec x 15 arcsec slit
      11           Sslit5      5.0 arcsec x 15 arcsec slit
      12           FastClr     0.5 arcsec/pixel baffle
      13           Sslit2      2.0 arcsec x 15 arcsec slit,
      14           Sslit1.5    1.5 arcsec x 15 arcsec slit
      15           Disk2       2.0 arcsec occulting disk
      16           Sslit1      1.0 arcsecx 15 arcsec slit
 
      Table 13: Upper Filter Wheel Contents
 
      Position   Keyword   Filter             lambda_c         delta lambda
                                            (micrometer)       (micrometer)
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------
      1          Blank     Blank                 ...               ...
      2          Clear     Clear                 ...               ...
      3          Helium    He I 10830           1.082             0.011
      4          PGamma    H I P_gamma          1.093             0.010
      5          PBeta     H I P_beta           1.282             0.015
      6          FeII      MSO [Fe II] + PK50   1.647             0.018
      7          AAOFeII   AAO [Fe II]          1.650             0.015
      8          H2O       H2O                  1.996             0.050
      9          H2_1_0    H2 1-0 S(1)          2.120             0.027
      10         BrGamma   H I Br_gamma         2.170             0.022
      11         Cont2.2   Continuum            2.210             0.094
      12         H2_2_1    H2 2-1 S(1)          2.249             0.024
      13         CO        CO (delta v = 2)     2.343             0.088
      14         Cont1.6   Continuum            1.580             0.012
      15         Grid      Wire Grid Analyser    ...               ...
      16         Mirror    IR85                  ...               ...
 
      Table 14: Utility Wheel Contents
 
      Position      Keyword    Content
      --------------------------------------------------------
      1              Blank      Blank
      2              Clear      Direct imaging cold stop
      3              IJ-grism   IJ cross-dispersed grism
      4              Blank4     Blank
      5              Blank5     Blank
      6              H-grism    H grism
      7              SlowCam    Slow camera lens (0.25 arcsec/pixel)
      8              JH-grism   JH cross-dispersed grism
      9              Blank9     Blank
      10             Blankl0    Blank
      11             J-grism    J grism
      12             Mask       Coronograph pupil mask
      13             Blank13    Blank
      14             HK-grism   HK cross-dispersed grism
      15             Wollaston  Wollaston polarimeter analyser
      16             K-grism    K grism
 
      Table 15: Lower Filter Wheel Contents
 
      Position Keyword   Filter                     lambda_c   delta lambda
                                                  (micrometer) (micrometer)
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------
      1       Blank     Blank                          ...          ...
      2       Clear     Clear                          ...          ...
      3       J         J                             1.275        0.282
      4       H         H                             1.672        0.274
      5       KP        K&apos; + PK50                     2.124        0.337
      6       KN        Kn + PK50                     2.165        0.330
      7       K         K                             2.224        0.394
      8       L         L&apos;                            3.821        0.602
      9       Ice       3.08 micrometer H2O ice       3.077        0.102
      10      Dust3.28  3.28 micrometer Dust emission 3.299        0.074
      11      Dust3.4   3.4 micrometer Dust emission  3.415        0.072
      12      Cont3.6   3.6 micrometer Continuum      3.592        0.078
      13      Cont4.0   4.0 micrometer Continuum      3.990        0.052
      14      BrAlpha   H I Br_alpha                  4.051        0.054
      15      M         M                             4.777        0.650
      16      PK50      2 mm PK50                      ...          ...
 
 
      Table 16:  Lens Wheel Contents
      Position   Keyword     Content
      ---------------------------------------------------
      1          Blank       Blank
      2          FastCam     Fast Camera Lens (0.5 arcsec/pixel)
      3          Blank3      Blank
      4          Clear       Clear
 
      (Note K Filter Curve Functions can be found in the CASPIR User&apos;s
      Guide)
 

        </instrument_desc>
        <instrument_id>CASPIR</instrument_id>
        <instrument_serial_number>not applicable</instrument_serial_number>
        <instrument_type>Infrared Imaging Spectrometer</instrument_type>
        <instrument_version_id>not applicable</instrument_version_id>
    </Instrument_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_PDS3>
