<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:wi.wiyn</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>WIYN IMAGER for WIYN</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.wiyn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Dones, L., M.R. Showalter, R.H. Durisen, R.K. Honeycutt, J.S. Jurcevic, R.
                   Tripoli, and C. Strom, A Search for Saturnian Moonlets Using the WIYN
                   Telescope, Unpublished, 2004
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DONESETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Johns, M. W., and D. R. Blanco, WIYN 3.5-meter telescope project, Proc. SPIE
                   Vol. 2199, Advanced Technology Optical Telescopes V Stepp, L. M. (Ed), pp 2-9,
                   1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JOHNS-BLANCO1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_PDS3>
        <instrument_name>WIYN IMAGER</instrument_name>
        <instrument_desc>
 
        Instrument Overview
        ===================
        The 3.5-m WIYN telescope (JOHNS&amp;BLANCO1994) at Kitt Peak
        incorporates a number of features to ensure high image quality.
        The temperatures in the dome, telescope, and mirrors are
        maintained at very near ambient by a combination of passive
        ventilation and active heating and cooling. The secondary
        mirror is actively aligned using wavefront sensing, and the
        figure of the primary mirror is similarly controlled.
        The telescope has an altitude-azimuth mount, so the pupil
        and diffraction spikes from the secondary mirror rotate during
        the night. For our observations, the diffraction spikes did not
        interfere with the ring and moons and in fact rotated further
        away from the ring plane over the course of the night.
 
        The instrument used for this work was a special adaptation
        of the WIYN Imager (WI). The WI consists of a Filter/Shutter
        Assembly (FSA) that mounts on the Instrument Adapter
        Subassembly (IAS) at the Nasmyth focus of the WIYN telescope,
        plus the CCD detector. The IAS provides for target
        acquisition, autoguiding, and for the wavefront sensing that
        is used to adjust the active optics of the WIYN telescope.
        The CCD used in this work was a backside-illuminated STIS
        2048 x 2048 pixel detector with 21-micron square pixels.
 
        Data Modes
        ==========
        In normal non-coronagraphic mode, modules of the WI are mounted
        at the WIYN focus in the order IAS/FSA/CCD. For this work two
        new modules were provided, the Coronagraphic Spacer (CSP) and
        the Re-Imaging Module (RIM). The CSP is inserted between the
        IAS and the FSA so that the telescope is brought to focus at
        the filter position inside the FSA, where coronagraphic masks
        can be placed. The RIM is then inserted between the FSA and
        the detector to form a new image of the telescope focal plane
        at the CCD, forming the new sequence IAS/CSP/FSA/RIM/CCD.
        The RIM incorporates its own filter wheel. Therefore, in the
        coronagraphic configuration, the original filter wheel becomes
        the mask wheel and a new filter wheel is provided in the RIM.
 
 
        Optics
        ======
        The RIM uses two commercial lenses to collimate and re-image
        (at 1:1) the mask focal plane located in the FSA. These
        process lenses are 4-element Cooke type, 100 mm focal length,
        F/1.9, marketed under the brand name S-CORONAR. The pixel scale
        is 0.195 arcsec/pixel, corresponding to 1300 km at Saturn during
        the observations.
 
          Filters
          -------
 
          Two filter wheels were used, one integral to the RIM and one
          integral to the coronagraph.
 
          The usable wavelength range (set by the lenses) is 390-900
          nm. The RIM filter wheel is located between these two
          lenses, where parallel light facilitates the use of
          narrowband filters. The RIM filter wheel accommodates 2-inch
          square filters. For this study, the team used broadband Harris B,
          V, R, and I filters, plus a narrowband (12 nm FWHM) methane
          filter centered at 889 nm.
 
          Array (and Subarrays)
          ---------------------
          The coronagraphic field-of-view is limited to approximately
          200 arcsec on a side, corresponding to ~1000 pixels in the
          CCD. There is about 7% vignetting at the edges of this field,
          due mostly to the finite separation of the two lenses. The
          FSA filter wheel accommodates 4-inch masks, including wires of
          various diameters, straight edges in various orientations,
          wedge masks, and wedge windows. Because we knew that bright
          Dione would be present on several of our observing nights, we
          created a special mask consisted of a blocking edge overhalf
          the field with an angled wire in the open half. This could be
          positioned to block Saturn behind the edge and Dione behind
          the wire, leaving most of one ring ansa unobscured.
 
 
        Operational Considerations
        ==========================
          At the time of these observations, the detector used for
          active optics wavefront sensing at WIYN was the WI CCD.
          Therefore wavefront sensing could be done through the
          coronagraph, making available not only the best settings for
          the active optics but also accounting (to first order) for
          aberrations introduced by the coronagraphic re-imaging
          lenses. When the atmosphere permitted, this procedure
          resulted in 0.45 arcsec FWHM images through the coronagraph
          in V and R, and 0.65 arcsec in B and I. Our median seeing of
          0.8 was typical for WIYN.

        </instrument_desc>
        <instrument_id>WI</instrument_id>
        <instrument_serial_number>not applicable</instrument_serial_number>
        <instrument_type>Camera</instrument_type>
        <instrument_version_id>not applicable</instrument_version_id>
    </Instrument_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_PDS3>
