<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:susi.eso</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>SUPERB SEEING IMAGER for ESO</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.eso::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_PDS3>
        <instrument_name>SUPERB SEEING IMAGER</instrument_name>
        <instrument_desc>
 
 
    Instrument Overview
    ===================
      EMMI is a flexible instrument which allows a wide range of observing
      modes, from wide-field imaging to high-dispersion echelle
      spectroscopy, including long-slit and multi-object spectroscopy.
      This manual also describes SUSI (SUperb Seeing Imager) which is
      mounted in the other Nasmyth focus of the NTT and complements the
      imaging capabilities of EMMI.  A brief description of the active
      optics system of the NTT and its basic operational principles are
      also provided in this manual.
 
      The driving concepts in the instrument definition were the high
      image quality foreseen for the NTT, the need to complement or
      improve on the instrumentation on the 3.6m telescope, and the need
      to minimize instrument change-overs.  The concept which was adopted
      is that of a dual-beam instrument, fully dioptric, and based on the
      white pupil principle.  CCD detectors were foreseen for the two arms
      with the possibility to adapt to the geometric characteristics of
      future detectors by changing the cameras only.  The main advantages
      of this type of design are the high efficiency in both channels and
      the easy conversion from wide field imaging to grism and grating
      spectroscopy.
 
      After the first observations with the NTT, it became clear that the
      telescope and the atmosphere at La Silla could provide stellar
      images with diameters as good as 0.3 arc sec.  Images of this
      quality could not be sampled adequately with EMMI, which scale had
      also to be adapted to the spectroscopic modes of observation.  Thus,
      SUSI was designed and built for the other Nasmyth arm of the NTT.
      The design is such that switching between EMMI and SUSI is done in a
      matter of minutes, so that they can be considered as different parts
      of the same instrument.
 
      The Superb Seeing Imager (SUSI) is physically distinct from EMMI but
      complements its observing capabilities.  A supporting plate is
      mounted on the adapter of the Nasmyth A focus of the NTT. On the
      plate, a mirror with 3 positions is mounted. The first position
      sends the light to SUSI, the second feeds an IR camera (not
      available), and the third position is free for the operation of
      IRSPEC. Between the diagonal mirror and the CCD is a filter wheel
      with 8 positions.  In the control software, SUSI is also referred to
      as DIFA: the Direct Imaging FAcility.
 
      SUSI has two advantages over EMMI. First, the small pixel scale
      which gives a much better sampling of the point-spread function.
      Second, the lack of optics which gives better throughput. It also
      has two disadvantages: the CCD is much less efficient in the blue
      than the one in th blue arm of EMMI, and the field is small. SUSI is
      therefore well suited for either periods of good to very good
      seeing.
 
      Switching from EMMI to SUSI only takes a few minutes. However, it is
      necessary to move the telescope to point at the zenith: only in that
      position can M3 be turned, to move the beam from one Nasmyth
      platform to the other. The EMMI control software should be
      terminated, and SUSI started up as above. You will have to
      redetermine the focus, and if you are switching because of
      significant improvements in the seeing, a new image analysis should
      also be done to take advantage of the new situation.
 
 
    System Performance
    ==================
      Telescope focus is critical to obtain good images. The slow angle of
      the NTT beam at the Nasmyth focus (F/11) facilitates focusing the
      telescope with SUSI, which must be done using through-focus
      sequences. The parameters for these sequences are entered in the
      SUSI Exposures form.  Tests done on reasonably good seeing (0.75-1.0
      arc sec) showed that the optimal focus step is 30 microns.  Step the
      telescope by 10 arc sec in the most convenient direction depending
      on the field.  7-9 focus exposures give the best results.
 
      The following table gives approximate focus values for SUSI
      filters.
 
         U  -3.48mm
         B  -3.47
         V  -3.50
         R  -3.47
         I  -3.43
         Z  -3.43
 
 
    Calibrations
    ============
      As with all CCDs, the afternoon should be used to check that the CCD
      is in good working condition. Because SUSI is not used as often as
      EMMI, faults can go unnoticed for some time and the night is not the
      time to find out about those! Take a few biases and check the
      read-out noise and check for the presence of patterns. The CCD is
      normally used in the slow mode, especially when used with binning:
      the time gained in reading out in fast mode is 25 sec in slow mode
      and 5 sec with 2 by 2 binning CCD is linear up to 150000
      electrons/pixel.
 
      Dome flats have been found to flatten images to about 3 %. Sky flats
      are generally more accurate: SUSI shows some vignetting which is not
      well removed with dome flats.  For twilight flats Tyson sequences
      have been used with good succes: the program to calculate these is
      available on the off-line computersystem (lw0--lw10) under the
      directory { /astro/progr1/twilight}. Twilight flats should
      preferably be taken in the evening.  If the background in your
      science images is bright enough, you can also create flats out of
      these.
 
      A photometric system for SUSI has not been established. The normal
      calibrations using the Landholt standards or other CCD standards can
      be used, but due to the small field size it is difficult to get more
      than one star on the CCD. If you have determined colour terms for
      SUSI, please let us know!
 
 
    Cameras and Detectors
    =====================
      Image scale for EMMI and SUSI
 
    EMMI BIMG   #31 TEK 1024  F/4   24 micron/0.37 arc sec
 
      CCD characteristics for EMMI and SUSI
 
    # 31 slow mode  1.7e/ADU conversion  2.5ADU RON  280.2ADU BIAS 8e DARK
             fast       3.4                  1.6         275.2         8
 
      Saturation is in most cases defined by the ADU converter, at 65
      kADU. The actual well depth is around 2 x 10^6 e so that the
      linearity is good up to digital saturation. The exceptions are EMMI
      red and SUSI when read out in fast mode. For EMMI red in the fast
      mode, exposure levels should be kept below 40 kADU, and for SUSI
      below 24kADU. Otherwise, the linearity of the CCD is better than
      0.5%. The measured linearity curves can be found in the CCD test
      reports.
 
      The fast readout mode has as main advantage a reduced readout time.
      This becomes important on EMMI red where fast readout saves two
      minutes. It is much less important in SUSI. The disadvantage is
      increased readout noise and digitization noise, and sometimes
      increased electric interference. For broadband imaging and many
      spectroscopic programmes, the readout noise is not important
      compared to the photon background, and the fast readout mode would
      be recommended.  Electronic interference could be larger in fast
      readout:  when in doubt, it is worthwile to take a few biases in the
      afternoon to check on the readout noise and on the presence of
      pattern noise.  Remember that, in general, calibration frames such
      as bias, flat fields, and darks taken with slow readout cannot be
      used for correcting fast exposures, and vice versa.
 
      CCDs have an electronic bias that can be evaluated by averaging
      several 0s dark exposures and subtracted from the science images to
      take it out. By using these exposures the observer can check the CCD
      readout noise and possible pick-up patterns in the electronic
      background.  At least one, but if possible more, long (at least 1
      hour) dark exposures are important to monitor the dark current of
      the CCD (if possible, take a dark longer than the longest science
      exposure).
 
 
    Filters
    =======
      The SUSI filterwheel has 8 positions of which 7 are available for
      filters.  In contrast to EMMI, SUSI uses 60-mm filters which are the
      same size as the ones used for EFOSC. EFOSC filters can therefore
      also be mounted in SUSI (if they are not required by the EFOSC
      observer!).  There are also a large number of 60-mm filters which
      are not allocated to a particular instrument and which can be
      requested.
 
      The ESO Image Quality Filters Catalogue (Gilliotte, 1992) contains a
      list of available filters and transmission curves.  More recently
      (1995), a number of new filters have been acquired and all
      transmission curves re-measured.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The data from the EMMI and SUSI detectors are simultaneously
      transmitted to IHAP and MIDAS databases.  MIDAS runs on a Unix
      workstation equipped with a DAT tape unit. IHAP uses standard
      1/2~inch 2400~foot tapes at 6250 BPI.
 
      The FITS headers of CCD files contain all the information necessary
      for the scientific use of the data, that is all the telescope,
      instrument, and detector parameters. Most of these parameters are
      stored in so-called hierarchical keywords. MIDAS can read these
      keywords, but some other packages may not since these are an
      extension of the FITS standard. If you are not using MIDAS, it is
      worth to check the actual FITS header for further information which
      may be useful.
 
 
    Electronics
    ===========
      The NTT is controlled by two HP1000/A900 computers, one for the
      telescope (called NTT) and one for the instruments (called NTI).
      The control software of EMMI is organized in such a way that EMMI is
      presented as five sub-instruments called RILD, REMD, BIMG, BLMD, and
      DIMD.  Depending on the type of observations, the user selects one
      of these modes and the control software automatically moves the
      functions to be set for this mode.  This leaves only the parameters
      of the particular type of observation to be defined.  For instance,
      when setting up an exposure in RILD, the required mirror unit and
      the upper red folding mirror are automatically set. The observer
      must only specify the camera focus, the choice of slit, filter
      and/or grism, and exposure parameters (see section Getting
      started).
 
      The user interface (UIF) consists of a RAMTEK monitor where mouse
      driven menus and forms are displayed, and a CRT (LU:53) monitor
      where messages from the system about the instrument are given and
      commands may be entered.  Parameters are entered by filling in forms
      on the RAMTEK screen.
 
      Once all optional optical elements are installed by the operation
      group, according to the observer&apos;s request, a setup form is
      produced. A printout of this form is left in the control room so
      that the observer can verify the setup and can use it as reference
      during the night.  The positions in the wheels of filters,
      grisms,and slits, and the gratings in the housing will be displayed,
      on the RAMTEK UIF in sofar as it is used in the chosen mode,
      whenever a setup in that mode is defined.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      Bias and darks
      --------------
      It is not safe to assume the bias to be always a scalar and
      therefore it is recommended to take many bias exposures.
 
      It has proven to be extremely difficult to isolate the CCD
      electronics from electrical interference from components in the NTT
      adapters/rotators. Therefore to some extent, the EMMI CCDs show
      pick-up patterns in the electronic background (the bias).  This
      noise is minimized in  SLOW readout mode, but may be rather strong
      in FAST readout frames. The patterns are not stable, but change from
      one exposure to the next, so it is difficult to remove them
      completely by substracting bias frames.  However, some reduction can
      be achieved and, therefore, it is recommended to take a good number
      of bias frames throughout the observing run.  Should strong patterns
      (i.e. more than a few ADUs) appear on  SLOW readout bias frames,
      call the NTT coordinator (93-50).  Note that spurious patterns are
      introduced if images are displayed with demagnification factors.
 
      At least one, but preferably more, long (1 hour) dark exposures
      should be taken to monitor the dark current and any exposure
      dependent features.
 
      Flat fields
      -----------
      The linearity of CCD No 31 is very good up to 160,000
      electrons/pixel.  The most accurate results for flat fields in broad
      band imaging are obtained using sky flats. This may be achieved by
      median filtering of science images, if they are not too densely
      populated with stars and do not contain very extended objects, or by
      doing multiple exposures of sparsely populated fields, using spatial
      offsets. A list of such fields is available in the control room.
      Another approach is to use morning and evening twilight.
 
      Shutter timing
      --------------
      A time delay of 0.80 seconds has been measured for the shutter in
      the blue F/4 camera.  Because of the location of the shutter in the
      optical path, the exposure time over the field is constant and equal
      to the chosen time plus the average shutter delay.  If critical for
      your application, it is recommended that you check the shutter
      timing by either taking exposures of increasing duration on a star,
      or using one of the internal lamps and a pinhole in the aperture
      wheel.
 
      Typical count rates
      -------------------
      In blue imaging the efficiency of EMMI is the product of the
      transmission of the atmosphere, three reflections in the telescope,
      the transmission of the blue coated optics of mode BIMG, filter, and
      quantum efficiency of the CCD. The efficiency in B and U was checked
      for the F/4 camera and TEK CCD No 31 in 1993.  The count rates in
      e/sec deduced for a 15th magnitude A star with approximately zero
      colour are U: 2200, B: 16,900 at unit airmass.
 
      Wallander A.:  1993, Remote Control of the 3.5m NTT User Guide, ESO
      Operating Manual No 17.
 
      Dekker. H.,  Delabre, B.:  1987, Applied Optics, 26, 8, 1375
 
      Dekker, H.,  Delabre, B.,  D&apos;Odorico, S.:  1986, SPIE, 627, 339
 
      Gilliotte, A.:  1992, Image Quality Filters Catalogue, Internal ESO
      publication
 
      Melnick, J.,  Dekker, H.,  D&apos;Odorico, S.:  1989, ESO Operating
      Manual #4
 

        </instrument_desc>
        <instrument_id>SUSI</instrument_id>
        <instrument_serial_number>not applicable</instrument_serial_number>
        <instrument_type>Imager</instrument_type>
        <instrument_version_id>not applicable</instrument_version_id>
    </Instrument_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_PDS3>
