<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Instrument_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.mex</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>SPICE KERNELS for MEX</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Instrument_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mex::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Instrument_PDS3>
        <instrument_name>SPICE KERNELS</instrument_name>
        <instrument_desc>
 
 
1. SPICE Overview
   ==============
 
   NOTE TO THE USER - there is no instrument directly associated
   with SPICE data.  However, this template ensures that
   referential integrity is maintained in the PDS Catalog. The
   information contained in this catalog aims to give a brief
   introduction to the basic concepts related with SPICE and its
   production. For a more detailed description of the Mars Express
   SPICE dataset implementation, please refer to the SPICEDS.CAT
   in this archive.
 
 
   SPICE deals with ancillary data in order to support the planning
   for, and analysis of, science instrument data.
 
 
   Ancillary data is made up of spacecraft and planetary
   ephemerides, spacecraft orientation, instrument mounting
   alignments and field of view geometry, reference frame
   specifications and data needed for conversion between various
   time systems. They help scientists and engineers to determine:
 
      *  when and how an instrument was acquiring data.
 
      *  where the spacecraft was located.
 
      *  how the spacecraft and instruments were oriented (pointed).
 
      *  what was the location, size, shape and orientation of the
         target being observed.
 
      *  what events were occurring on the spacecraft or ground that
         might affect interpretation of:
 
          -  science observations.
 
          -  spacecraft systems performance.
 
 
   The principal SPICE system components are two:
 
      *  Data files, often called &apos;kernels&apos; or &apos;kernel files&apos;. They
         are composed of ancillary information which has been
         created in such a way as to allow easy access and correct
         usage by the space science and engineering communities.
 
      *  Software, known as the SPICE toolkit.
 
            -  The principal component is an extensive subroutine
               library.
 
            -  Also included are some:
 
                  &gt; broadly useful application programs.
                  &gt; utility programs.
                  &gt; examples of how to use SPICE toolkit
                    subroutines.
 
 
   Also part of SPICE are:
 
      *  standards
      *  documentation
      *  customer support
      *  system maintenance and continuing development.
 
 
   SPICE is used on a number of space missions, such as ESA&apos;s
   SMART-1, Venus Express and Mars Express missions, and all
   of NASA&apos;s solar system exploration missions. The SPICE system has
   been produced and is maintained by Caltech&apos;s Jet Propulsion
   Laboratory under contract to the U.S. National Aeronautics and
   Space Administration.
 
 
2. SPICE Objectives
   ================
 
   SPICE has the following objectives:
 
      *  to aid scientists in planning and interpreting scientific
         observations made by instruments flown on spacecraft;
      *  to assist with the correlation of individual data sets with
         those from other instruments on the same, or different,
         spacecraft.
 
 
3. SPICE kernels
   =============
 
   The logical contents of the SPICE system are outlined below:
 
      S - Spacecraft ephemeris, given as a function of time.
 
      P - Planet, satellite, comet, or asteroid ephemerides.  I.e.
          the location and velocity of any target body as a function
          of time. Also the associated physical and cartographic
          constants.
 
      I - Instrument description, containing descriptive data that
          describes a particular scientific instrument, such as
          field-of-view size, shape and orientation parameters.
 
      C - Pointing information, containing a transformation,
          traditionally called the C-matrix, which provides
          time-tagged pointing (orientation) angles for a spacecraft
          structure upon which science instruments are mounted. May
          also include angular rate data.
 
      E - Events, summarizing mission activities - both planned and
          unanticipated. Events data are contained in the SPICE EK
          file set, which consists of three components: Science
          Plans, Sequences, and Notes. It should be noted that the EK
          system is not used in Mars Express, and therefore no data
          are available
 
 
   Additional SPICE data products are:
 
      *  The &apos;Frame definitions Kernel&apos; (FK file) contains reference
         frame specifications that are typically used by flight
         projects. This file also includes mounting alignment
         information for instruments antennas and other structures
         of interest.
 
      *  Spacecraft clock (SCLK) and leapseconds (LSK) files are
         also part of SPICE and are used in converting time tags
         between various time measurement systems.
 
 
   Below is an outline of the SPICE logical components (left) and
   how they relate to the SPICE physical kernel files (right).
 
     ____________
   |            |              _____
   |     S      |             |     |        Space vehicle or
   |            |   -------&gt;  | SPK |        target body
   | spacecraft |         /   |_____|        trajectory
   |____________|        /                   (ephemeris).
                        /
    ____________       /
   |            |     /        _____
   |     P      |    /        |     |        Target body size,
   |            |   -------&gt;  | PcK |        shape and
   |   planet   |             |_____|        orientation.
   |____________|
 
    ____________
   |            |              _____
   |     I      |             |     |        Instrument field-
   |            |   -------&gt;  | IK  |        of-view size, shape
   | instrument |             |_____|        and orientation.
   |____________|
 
    ____________
   |            |              _____
   |     C      |             |     |        Orientation of space
   |   camera   |   -------&gt;  | CK  |        vehicle or any
   |   matrix   |             |_____|        articulating
   |____________|                            structure on it.
 
    ____________
   |            |              _____         Events information for
   |     E (*)  |             |     |        - science plan(ESP)
   |            |   -------&gt;  | EK  |        - sequence of events
   |   events   |             |_____|          (ESQ)
   |____________|                            - experimenters&apos;   .
                                               notebook (ENB).
                              ________       ______
                             |        | --&gt; |__FK__|  Reference
                             |        |      ______     Frame spec.
                             | Others | --&gt; |_LSK__|  Leapsecond
                             |        |      ______     tabulation.
                             |________| --&gt; |_SCLK_|  Spacecraft
                                                        clock
                                                        coefficient
 
    ____________
   |            |
   |     S      |                            Fortran, C and IDL
   |            |   -------&gt;   SPICE         libraries, plus a
   |  software  |             Toolkit        few utilities and
   |____________|                            example programs.
 
 
 
 
4. SPICE toolkit and documentation
   ===============================
 
   The SPICE system also includes a large collection of software
   known as the NAIF Toolkit. The principal component of this
   toolkit is a library of portable subroutines, needed to read
   the kernel files and to then calculate observation geometry
   parameters of interest. Users integrate these SPICE &apos;Toolkit&apos;
   subroutines into their own application programs to compute
   observation geometry parameters and related information, as
   needed. The NAIF Toolkit, originally implemented in ANSI
   FORTRAN 77, is also available in the C language and as a set
   of Interactive Data Language (IDL) and MATLAB interfaces.
 
 
   Also a comprehensive set of documents on SPICE is available,
   made up of:
 
      *  user manuals for the utility programs.
      *  tutorials.
      *  required readings on the several parts of SPICE as well
         as on different mathematical concepts used by SPICE.
 
 
   The SPICE toolkit and documentation can be found on:
 
      http://naif.jpl.nasa.gov/naif/
 
 
   The SPICE Toolkit is freely offered to the worldwide space
   science and space mission engineering communities at the time
   this data set was released. The few rules governing its use are
   posted on the &apos;&apos;Rules&apos;&apos; page of the NAIF website:
 
      http://naif.jpl.nasa.gov/naif/rules.html

        </instrument_desc>
        <instrument_id>SPICE</instrument_id>
        <instrument_serial_number>not applicable</instrument_serial_number>
        <instrument_type>Unknown</instrument_type>
        <instrument_version_id>not applicable</instrument_version_id>
    </Instrument_PDS3>
</Product_Instrument_PDS3>
