<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Target_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.k07s4</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>K07S4</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Target_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>

    <Target_PDS3>
        <target_name>K07S4</target_name>
        <orbit_direction>Unknown</orbit_direction>
        <primary_body_name>SATURN</primary_body_name>
        <rotation_direction>Unknown</rotation_direction>
        <target_desc>
First spotted in Cassini images taken on May 30, 2007.
S/2007 S 4 orbits Saturn between the paths of Methone
and Pallene, two small moons, about 4 kilometers (2.6 miles)
wide, also discovered in Cassini images in 2004. All three
moons orbit between much larger Mimas and Enceladus.
 
Press Release announcing the discovery below.
 
Like a hawk&amp;apos;s eyes, the high resolution cameras on
NASA&amp;apos;s Cassini spacecraft have spotted yet another
small, previously unknown moon circling giant Saturn
and one which may indicate the existence of other
small bodies in the same region.
 
The tiny world--presently thought to be only about
2 kilometers (1 mile) wide--orbits at 197,700
kilometers (122,800 miles) from Saturn. Until a
name for the moon is chosen by the International
Astronomical Union, the moon has been given the
provisional designation S/2007 S 4.
 
The moon was first spotted in Cassini images taken
on May 30, 2007. Subsequent searches through
images taken by Cassini over the previous three
years turned up additional detections of the moon
and helped researchers refine their calculations
of its orbital path.
 
S/2007 S 4 orbits Saturn between the paths of
Methone and Pallene, two small moons, about 4
kilometers (2.6 miles) wide, also discovered in
Cassini images in 2004. All three moons orbit
between much larger Mimas and Enceladus.
 
Moons surrounding the giant planets generally are
not found where they originally formed because tidal
forces from the planet can cause them to drift from
their original locations. In drifting, they may sweep
through &amp;apos;resonances&amp;apos;--i.e., locations where other
moons disturb them--and suffer orbit-changing
perturbations. The new moon, like Methone, is in
such a resonance with Mimas and appears to have
undergone such an evolution.
 
&amp;apos;The fact that both Methone and S/2007 S 4 are
dynamically locked with Mimas gives us a clue about
their orbital history,&amp;apos; said Carl Murray, a professor
at Queen Mary, University of London, and the member
of the Cassini Imaging Team leading the work on the
new moon. &amp;apos;There are numerous examples of these
resonant mechanisms between moons in the Saturn
system and they probably arise due to tides. In
the case of these two small moons, the resonance
ensures that they cannot hit Mimas, at least in
the short term.&amp;apos;
 
Because the orbits of all three small moons lie
close together, researchers think they may be
remnants of a larger population.
 
&amp;apos;This trio of objects could be remnants of a
collision or perhaps they are the lucky survivors
of a larger population of material that failed to
form a moon,&amp;apos; said Murray. &amp;apos;Either way there does
seem to be a family connection. If we could get
good data about their surfaces with Cassini, we
could begin to unravel some of these mysteries.&amp;apos;
 
Cassini imaging scientists are already busy looking
for future opportunities to zoom in on the new moon
and refine its orbit, and to search for other
companions.
 
&amp;apos;We&amp;apos;ve already identified times in the near future
when we can take some pre-planned images and re-target
them to get a closer look at this new body,&amp;apos; said
Carolyn Porco, imaging team leader and director of
CICLOPS at the Space Science Institute. &amp;apos;And of
course we&amp;apos;re always on the lookout for additional
moons. There are likely to be more of these very small
bodies out there, and we hope to find them.&amp;apos;
 
By chance, Cassini will approach the newly discovered
moon at a distance of 11,700 kilometers (7,300 miles)
at the end of December 2009, assuming the mission is
extended beyond the summer of 2008, its nominal end.
Images taken at that time could be useful for understanding
the moon&amp;apos;s shape, composition, and history.
Also known as &amp;apos;S/2007 S 4&amp;apos; on &amp;apos;Anthe&amp;apos;.
 
Named after One of the Alkyonides, the seven beautiful
daughters of the Giant Alkyoneos.
        </target_desc>
        <target_type>Satellite</target_type>
    </Target_PDS3>
</Product_Target_PDS3>
