<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ch1-orb-l-m3-2-l0-raw-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CH1-ORB MOON M3 2 L0 RAW NEAR-IR SPECTRAL IMAGES V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.chandrayaan-1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.ch1-orb::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:m3.ch1-orb::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ch1-orb-l-m3-2-l0-raw-v1.0__dvo_img_ch1-orb-l-m3-2-l0-raw-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Pieters, C.M., J.N. Goswami, R.N. Clark, M. Annadurai, J. Boardman, B. Buratti,
                   J.-P. Combe, M.D. Dyar, R. Green, J.W. Head, C. Hibbitts, M. Hicks, P.
                   Isaacson, R. Klima, G, Kramer, S. Kumar, E. Livo, S. Lundeen, E. Malaret, T.
                   McCord, J. Mustard, J. Nettles, N. Petro, C. Runyon, M. Staid, J. Sunshine,
                   L.A. Taylor, S. Tompkins, and P. Varanasi, Character and Spatial Distribution
                   of OH/H2O on the Surface of the Moon Seen by M3 on Chandrayaan-1, Science, Vol.
                   326, No. 5952, 568-572, 2009, doi:10.1126/science.1178658.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PIETERSETAL2009C</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CH1-ORB-L-M3-2-L0-RAW-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CH1-ORB MOON M3 2 L0 RAW NEAR-IR SPECTRAL IMAGES V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2010-07-19</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2008-10-22</start_time>
        <stop_time>2009-08-28</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JPL/M3 POC</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Green, R., S. Lundeen, and J. Boardman, CH1-ORB MOON M3 RAW
            NEAR-IR SPECTRAL IMAGES V1.0, CH1-ORB-L-M3-2-L0-RAW-V1.0, NASA
            Planetary Data System, 2010.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw near-IR spectral image cubes of the Moon acquired by the Moon
            Mineralogy Mapper instrument during the Chandrayaan-1 mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains raw near-IR spectral image cubes acquired
            from November 2008 through August 2009 by the Moon Mineralogy
            Mapper (M3) instrument during the Chandrayaan-1 mission to the
            Moon.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set contains uncalibrated, unprocessed, raw near-IR spectral
    image cubes acquired from November 2008 through August 2009 by the Moon
    Mineralogy Mapper (M3) instrument during the Chandrayaan-1 mission
    to the Moon.   The data were acquired while the instrument was operated
    in global or targeted mode.  The documentation in the DOCUMENT directory
    provides detailed information about the data files and their format and
    content.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The M3 Data Product SIS document located in the DOCUMENT directory
    describes how the data products in this data set were processed.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The raw near-IR data are stored as three-dimensional,
    band-interleaved image cubes in the DATA directory of this data set.
    The file naming convention is described in the M3 Data Product SIS
    located in the DOCUMENT directory.  Each data file is accompanied
    by a detached PDS label file (*.LBL) which describe the content and
    format.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The M3 Archive Volume SIS and the M3 Data Product SIS documents
    located in the DOCUMENT directory provide detailed descriptions
    of each file contained in this data set.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    M3 calibration data such as wavelength centers,
    full-width half-max values and radiometric gain factors can be found in
    the CALIB directory of the archive volume.
 
    SPICE kernels used to calculate geometric parameters for these data
    are located in the GEOMETRY directory.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    Raw data products are not dependent on definition of a coordinate
    system.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    Software is not included with this data set.  However each spectral
    image cube is accompanied an ASCII text header file compatible with
    the commercial software package known as ENVI.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    These products are delivered on a hard-drive or by ftp and
    are not formatted for a specific medium.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    Confidence level information will be provided after more thorough
    analysis of the data.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    Prior to creation of the final version of this archival data set,
    its keys elements including samples of data products, PDS labels
    and catalog files, and the Software Interface Specifications, were
    examined during a peer review held by PDS Imaging Node in January 2010.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
      The M3 image acquisition time will be divided into peak periods or
      Optical Periods (OP) when lighting is optimal for observation. The
      Optical Periods occur twice a year and are understood to have two
      central months of optimal illumination (solar beta angles -30 deg to
      +30 deg) with two optional two-week wing periods (solar beta angles
      +/-30 deg to +/-45 deg) on either side of the optimal 2 months (thus,
      one Optical Period equals 13 weeks). Each 13 week optical period is
      followed by a 13-week hiatus. The original instrument operations plan
      included the acquisition of the entire surface of the Moon in
      low-resolution Global Mode during the first Optical Period (OP1)
      while OP2, OP3, OP4 were reserved for high resolution Target Mode
      data acquisition.
 
      However, the mission was cut short, just before the halfway point, in
      August, 2009 when the spacecraft ceased operations. Despite the
      abbreviated mission and numerous technical and scientific challenges
      during the flight, M3 was able to cover more than 95% of the Moon in
      Global Mode. Only minimal high-resolution Target Mode images were
      acquired, as these were to be the focus of the second half of the
      mission. The technical challenges encountered during the mission
      have complicated the data processing and calibration. These challenges
      include thermal issues, loss of the spacecraft star trackers and a
      raising of the orbit from 100 km to 200 km on May 19, 2009. Details
      of these challenges are currently being documented and will be
      referenced and/or included in the delivery of the M3 PDS Archive
      Volume. Nonetheless, the data products released in the M3 PDS Archive
      Volume will contain optimal calibration and characterization.
      (NOTE: If these docs are included in the archive, put them in
      DOCUMENT directory, not EXTRAS.)
 
      M3 operations were sustained for two Optical Periods. (For more
      detailed information regarding the spacecraft operation schedule,
      please see the MISSION.CAT.) Please see the M3 Data Product SIS for
      more detail/information.
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    None.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

