<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dif-c-hrii-2-epoxi-hartley2-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>EPOXI 103P/HARTLEY2 ENCOUNTER - HRII RAW SPECTRA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.epoxi::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:hrii.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.103p-hartley_2_1986_e2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dif-c-hrii-2-epoxi-hartley2-v1.0__browserp_dif-c-hrii-2-epoxi-hartley2-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   A&apos;Hearn, M.F., M.J.S. Belton, W.A. Delamere, L.M. Feaga, D. Hampton, J. Kissel,
                   K.P. Klaasen, L.A. McFadden, K.J. Meech, H.J. Melosh, P.H. Schultz, J.M.
                   Sunshine, P.C. Thomas, J. Veverka, D.D. Wellnitz, D.K. Yeomans, S. Besse, D.
                   Bodewits, T.J. Bowling, B.T. Carcich, S.M. Collins, T.L. Farnham, O. Groussin,
                   B. Hermalyn, M.S. Kelley (UMD), M.S. Kelley (NASA), J.-Y. Li, D.J. Lindler,
                   C.M. Lisse, S.A. McLaughlin, F. Merlin, S. Protopapa, J.E. Richardson, and J.L.
                   Williams, EPOXI at Comet Hartley 2, Science, 332, 1396-1400, 2011,
                   doi:10.1126/science.1204054.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.AHEARNETAL2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hampton, D.L., J.W. Baer, M.A. Huisjen, C.C. Varner, A. Delamere, D.D.
                   Wellnitz, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, and K.P. Klaasen, An Overview of the Instrument Suite
                   for the Deep Impact Mission, Space Science Reviews, 117, 43-93, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3390-8.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAMPTONETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., M.F. A&apos;Hearn, M. Baca, A. Delamere, M. Desnoyer, T. Farnham, O.
                   Groussin, D. Hampton, S. Ipatov, J. Li, C. Lisse, N. Mastrodemos, S.
                   McLaughlin, J. Sunshine, P. Thomas, and D. Wellnitz, Deep Impact Instrument
                   Calibration, Rev. Sci. Instrum., 79, 091301, 2008, doi:10.1063/1.2972112.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., M. A&apos;Hearn, S. Besse, D. Bodewits, B. Carcich, T. Farnham, L.
                   Feaga, O. Groussin, D. Hampton, M. Huisjen, M.S. Kelley, S. McLaughlin, F.
                   Merlin, S. Protopapa, J. Sunshine, P. Thomas, and D. Wellnitz, EPOXI Instrument
                   Calibration, Icarus, 225(1), 643-680, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.icarus.2013.03.024.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DIF-C-HRII-2-EPOXI-HARTLEY2-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>EPOXI 103P/HARTLEY2 ENCOUNTER - HRII RAW SPECTRA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2011-06-30</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2010-10-01T16:40:32.256Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2010-11-26T03:38:03.278Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STEPHANIE MCLAUGHLIN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            McLaughlin, S.A., B. Carcich, S.E. Sackett, and K.P. Klaasen,
            EPOXI 103P/HARTLEY2 ENCOUNTER - HRII RAW SPECTRA V1.0,
            DIF-C-HRII-2-EPOXI-HARTLEY2-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2011.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw 1.05- to 4.8-micron spectral images of comet 103/P Hartley 2
            acquired by the Deep Impact High Resolution Infrared Spectrometer
            from 01 October through 26 November 2010 for the EPOXI mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset contains raw, 1.05- to 4.8-micron spectral images of
            comet 103/P Hartley 2 acquired by the High Resolution Infrared
            Spectrometer (HRII) from 01 October through 26 November 2010
            during the Hartley 2 encounter phase of the EPOXI mission.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This dataset contains raw, 1.05- to 4.8-micron spectral images
    of comet 103/P Hartley 2 acquired by the High Resolution Infrared
    Spectrometer (HRII) from 01 October through 26 November 2010
    during the Hartley 2 encounter phase of the EPOXI mission.  Initial
    results based on these data are discussed by A&apos;Hearn, et al. (2011)
    [AHEARNETAL2011].
 
    The following list summarizes the comet observations in this dataset.
    Descriptive text for each activity is included below.  Additionally,
    the HRII Hartley 2 Flyby (E-18 hours to E+2 days) Log in the DOCUMENT
    directory provides notes about each scan, such as frames containing
    the comet, that were recorded by the science team as the data arrived
    on the ground.
 
    --------------------------------------------------------------------------
    Mid-Obs         Exposure IDs      Mission Activity
    Date/DOY        Min      Max      (E = Encounter)
    --------------  -------  -------  ----------------------------------------
    2010-10-01/274  4000001  4000063  Approach imaging E-34 to E-8 days;
    to                                Coma scans every 30 minutes;
    2010-10-27/300                    Odd ExpIDs only, most repeated daily*
 
    2010-10-28/301  4000001  4000063  Approach imaging E-8 days to E-18 hours;
    to                                Coma scans every hour;
    2010-11-03/307                    Odd ExpIDs only, most repeated daily**
 
    2010-11-03/307  4000001  4000604  Flyby imaging E-18 to E-3 hours;
    to                                Scans every two hours; then reduced to
    2010-11-04/308                      one hour cadence
                                      ExpIDs are not repeated
 
    2010-11-04/308  5000000  5008002  Flyby imaging E-2 to E+1.5 hours;
                                      Near-continuous scans of coma/nucleus;
                                      Nadir imaging at closest approach;
                                      ExpIDs are not repeated
 
    2010-11-04/308  4000700  4010100  Flyby imaging E+2 hours to E+2 days;
    to                                Coma scans every 30 minutes;
    2010-11-06/310                    ExpIDs are not repeated
 
    2010-11-06/310  4100001  4500023  Departure imaging E+2 to E+12 days;
    to                                Coma scans every ~15 minutes;
    2010-11-16/320                    Odd ExpIDs only; repeated daily
 
    2010-11-16/320  4100001  4500011  Departure imaging E+12 to E+21 days;
    to                                Coma scans every 20 minutes;
    2010-11-26/330                    Odd ExpIDs only; repeated daily
    --------------------------------------------------------------------------
    *  Data acquired on 06 Oct were never downlinked due to a pointing problem
       with the Deep Space Network (DSN).
    ** First cycle of 28 Oct, only six hourly scans were taken before the
       sequence stopped and restarted at &apos;dosido&apos; section for 7 hourly
       scans.  Therefore the middle 11 scans were not acquired on
       purpose.  Some frames in a scan may be missing because they were
       scheduled for transmission after the HGA was turned off, i.e. loss
       of signal.  Any data the DSN received after this were considered
       extra credit.
 
    Hartley 2 Approach Imaging, E-34 to E-8 Days (Start HRII):  From 01
      to 28 October 2010, MRI and HRIV imaged 103P/Hartley 2 about
      every 5 minutes while the HRII spectrometer scanned for outbursts
      once every 30 minutes.  The instruments observed the comet for 16
      hours per day allowing for 8 hours of downlinking; the same sequence
      was repeated daily yielding one full cycle per day.  Data from the
      6th cycle on 06 October 2010 (DOY 279) were never downlinked because
      of a pointing problem with the Deep Space Network.  Those data had
      to be erased on board the spacecraft to make room for the next daily
      cycle and could not be recovered.
 
    Hartley 2 Approach Imaging, E-8 Days to E-18 Hours:  From 28 October
      to 03 November 2010, the MRI and HRIV imaged 103P/Hartley 2
      continuously and HRII scanned the comet about every hour for 16
      hours per day allowing for 8 hours of downlinking punctuated by
      hourly maneuvers, called dosido, to observe the comet. During this
      imaging phase there was only a single downlink of all images with
      zero margin; thus some images were occasionally lost as expected.
      The first cycle (DOY 300/301) was abbreviated such that the first
      comet-imaging session was only 6-hours long, followed by the
      standard 8-hour dosido.
 
    Hartley 2 Encounter Imaging, E-18 hours to E+2 Days:  From 03 to 06
      November 2010, the HRII, HRIV, and MRI performed high resolution
      encounter imaging of 103P/Hartley2.  The HRIV and MRI instruments
      began sampling about once every two hours until one hour before
      encounter when the cadence changed to once every 15 minutes.  At E-30
      minutes the instruments began continuously imaging of the comet.  At
      E+30 minutes simultaneous observing and data playback began with
      samples being taken every 30 minutes.  During the encounter imaging
      period, HRII infrared scans occurred every two hours until four hours
      prior to encounter when the cadence increased to hourly then more
      frequently one hour before closest approach.  About one hour after
      closest approach, regular infrared sampling at 30-minute intervals
      resumed.
 
      During this period, HRII obtained several full spectral maps of the
      coma with a scale &lt; 250 m/pixel (the exposure IDs are provided):
 
          5001000 (E-14 min, ALTFF/Mode5 scan at ~115 m/pixel)
          5001002 (E-7 min,  ALTFF/Mode5 scan at  ~60 mmpixel
          5006000 (E+7 min,  ALTFF/Mode5 scan at  ~50 m/pixel)
          5007000 (E+14 min, ALTFF/Mode5 scan at ~115 m/pixel)
 
      Also HRII obtained a full spectral map of the nucleus with a
      scale &lt; 100 m/pixel:
 
          5005001 (E+3 min, BINSF2/Mode3 scan at ~30 m/pixel)
 
      Please note the comet is in fewer frames than expected at closest
      approach because there was an error in how the spacecraft was
      commanded to point during closest approach. However this unexpected
      offset enabled serendipitous imaging of cometary debris near the
      nucleus.
 
    Hartley 2 Departure Imaging, E+2 to E+12 Days:  From 06 to 16 November
      2010, the HRII spectrometer scanned 103P/Hartley 2 every ~15 minutes
      while the MRI CCD imaged the comet every 2 minutes and HRIV once
      every hour.
 
    Hartley 2 Departure Imaging, E+12 to E+21 Days:  From 16 to 26 November
      2010, the HRII spectrometer scanned 103P/Hartley 2 every 30 minutes,
      and HRIV performed rotation sampling at the same cadence.  MRI
      performed rotation sampling every 30 minutes and imaging using gas
      filters every two to four hours.
 
 
    Data Acquisition Strategy
    -------------------------
      The data acquisition strategy for the IR scans throughout the
      Hartley 2 encounter had to balance data volume limitations with
      desired sampling.  The goal of the IR observations during approach
      and departure was to monitor the coma for any changes that occurred
      from one coma scan to another.  Therefore, the field of view covered
      by a scan was selected such that for a reasonable outflow velocity,
      the scan would cover the distance traveled by any new material
      released from the nucleus since the previous observation.  In order
      to meet the sampling and field of view criteria, the cadence of
      scans was selected and then scan rate of the spectrometer (that is,
      the slew rate of the spacecraft), perpendicular to the slit length,
      was set to be either one slit width per exposure frame or two slit
      widths per exposure frame:
 
        Mission Timeline          Scan Rate
        ------------------------  ------------------------------------------
        Approach Imaging
          E-34 to E-8 days        2 slit widths per exposure frame
          E-8 days to E-18 hours  1 slit width per exposure frame
        Flyby Imaging
          E-18 hrs to E+2 days    2 slit widths per exposure frame for these
                                  observations (exposure IDs): 4000200,
                                  4000500, 5008002, and 4000700-4010100
                                  excluding 4002700 and 4002800.  All other
                                  observations are 1 slit width per
                                  exposure frame.
        Departure Imaging
          E+2 days to E+12 days   2 slit widths per exposure frame
          E+12 days to E+21 days  1 slit width per exposure frame
 
 
    Required Reading
    ---------------
      The documents listed below are essential for the understanding and
      interpretation of this dataset.  Although a copy of each document is
      provided in the DOCUMENT directory of this dataset, the most recent
      version is archived in the Deep Impact and EPOXI documentation set,
      DI-C-HRII/HRIV/MRI/ITS-6-DOC-SET-V3.0, available online at
      http://pds.nasa.gov.
 
      EPOXI_SIS.PDF
        - The Archive Volume and Data Product Software Interface
          Specifications document (SIS) describes the EPOXI datasets, the
          science data products, and defines keywords in the PDS labels.
 
      HARTLEY2_CAL_PIPELINE_SUMM.PDF
        - The EPOXI Hartley 2 Calibration Pipeline Summary provides an
          overview the calibration pipeline as of June 2011 used for
          processing data acquired during the Hartley 2 Encounter.
          The document also discusses known limitations of the calibration
          pipeline with respect to the HRII, HRIV, and MRI instruments.
          For a thorough discussion of the pipeline refer to EPOXI
          Instrument Calibration by Klaasen, et. al. (2011, in
          preparation) [KLAASENETAL2011].
 
      INSTRUMENTS_HAMPTON.PDF
        - The Deep Impact instruments paper by Hampton, et al. (2005)
          [HAMPTONETAL2005] provides very detailed descriptions of the
          instruments.
 
      HRII_HARTLEY2_FLYBY_LOG.PDF
        - This log provides notes recorded by the science team as each
          Flyby exposure (scan) acquired from E-18 to E+48 hours was
          received on the ground.  Annotations include data quality and
          a list of frames within each scan that appeared to contain the
          comet.
 
      HRII_2_EPOXI_HARTLEY2.TAB
        - This ASCII table provides image parameters such as the mid-obs
          Julian date, exposure time, mission activity type, and
          description or purpose for each observation (i.e., data product)
          in this dataset.  This file is very useful for determining which
          data files to work with.
 
 
    Related Data Sets
    -----------------
      The following PDS datasets are related to this one and may be useful
      for calibration purposes:
 
      DIF-C-HRII-3/4-EPOXI-HARTLEY2-V1.0
        - Calibrated HRII spectral images of comet Hartley 2
 
      DIF-CAL-HRII-2-EPOXI-CALIBRATIONS-V2.0
        - Raw HRII in-flight calibrations from 2007 to 2011
 
      DIF-C-HRIV-2-EPOXI-HARTLEY2-V1.0
      DIF-C-HRIV-3/4-EPOXI-HARTLEY2-V1.0
        - Raw and calibrated HRIV images of comet Hartley 2
 
      DIF-C-MRI-2-EPOXI-HARTLEY2-V1.0
      DIF-C-MRI-3/4-EPOXI-HARTLEY2-V1.0
        - Raw and calibrated MRI images of comet Hartley 2
 
      DIF-C/E/X-SPICE-6-V1.0
        - EPOXI SPICE kernels
 
      DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV/MRI-6-EPOXI-TEMPS-V2.0
        - HRII, HRIV, and MRI instrument thermal telemetry data for EPOXI
          which may be useful for determining how temperature fluctuations
          affect the science instruments, in particular the IR spectrometer
 
      DI-C-HRII/HRIV/MRI/ITS-6-DOC-SET-V3.0
        - Deep Impact and EPOXI documentation set including a draft of the
          Deep Impact instrument calibration paper by Klaasen, et al. (2008)
          [KLAASENETAL2006]
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The raw two-dimensional (wavelength and spatial/along-slit) FITS
    spectral images and PDS labels in this dataset were generated by the
    Deep Impact/EPOXI data pipeline, maintained by the project&apos;s Science
    Data Center (SDC) at Cornell University.  The FITS data were assembled
    from raw telemetry packets sent down by the flyby spacecraft.
    Information from the embedded spacecraft header (the first 100 bytes of
    quadrant A image data) was extracted and stored in the primary FITS
    header.  Geometric parameters were computed using the best available
    SPICE kernels and the results were also stored in the FITS header.  If
    telemetry packets were missing, the corresponding pixels were flagged
    as missing in the quality map included as a FITS image extension.  The
    quadrant nomenclature and the image quality map are described in the
    EPOXI SIS document.  The SDC did not apply any type of correction or
    decompression algorithm to the raw data.
 
 
  Data
  ====
 
    FITS Images and PDS Labels
    --------------------------
      Each raw spectral image is stored as FITS.  The primary data unit
      contains the two-dimensional spectral image, with the fastest
      varying axis corresponding to increasing wavelengths from about
      1.05 to 4.8 microns and the slowest varying axis corresponding to
      the spatial or along-slit dimension.  The primary array is
      followed by one image extension that contains a two-dimensional
      pixel-by-pixel quality map.  This extension uses one byte of eight
      bit flags to indicate the quality of each pixel in the primary
      image.  The data label provides a short description of each bit.
      For more information about the FITS primary image and its
      extension or for examples of how to access and use the quality
      flags, refer to the EPOXI SIS document.
 
      Each FITS file is accompanied by a detached PDS data label.  The
      EPOXI SIS document provides definitions for the keywords found in
      a PDS data label.  Many values in a label were extracted from
      FITS image header keywords which are defined in the document
      EPOXI_FITS_KEYWORD_DESC.ASC found in the Deep Impact and EPOXI
      documentation dataset, DI-C-HRII/HRIV/MRI/ITS-6-DOC-SET-V3.0.
 
 
    File Naming Convention
    ----------------------
      The naming convention for the raw data labels and FITS files is
      HIyymmddhh_eeeeeee_nnn.LBL or FIT where &apos;HI&apos; identifies the HRII
      instrument, yymmddhh provides the UTC year, month, day, and hour at
      the mid-point of the observation, eeeeeee is the exposure ID
      (OBSERVATION_ID in data labels), and nnn provides the image number
      (IMAGE_NUMBER in the data labels) within the exposure ID.
 
      Up to 999 individual images can be commanded for one exposure ID.
      Spectral scans often had 8 or more frames for one specific exposure.
      Therefore, nnn in the file name provides the sequentially increasing
      frame number within an exposure ID and corresponds to IMAGE_NUMBER in
      the data labels.  For example, if 30 frames were commanded for a scan
      with an exposure ID of 5000000, the first FITS file name would be
      HI10110412_5000000_001.FIT and the last would be
      HI10110412_5000000_030.FIT.
 
 
    Image Compression
    -----------------
      Raw data numbers for HRII frames could be compressed on board the
      flyby spacecraft by use of a lookup table then downlinked, processed,
      and archived in the same format.  However this dataset does not
      contain compressed products because all Hartley 2 spectral images
      were never compressed.
 
 
    Image Orientation
    -----------------
      A true-sky &apos;as seen by the observer&apos; view is achieved by displaying
      the image using the standard FITS convention:  the fastest-varying
      axis (samples or wavelength) increasing to the right in the display
      window and the slowest-varying axis (lines or spatial/along-slit)
      increasing to the top.  This convention is identified in the data
      labels:  the SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION keyword is set to RIGHT and
      LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION to UP.
 
      The direction to celestial north, ecliptic north, and the Sun is
      provided in data labels by CELESTIAL_NORTH_CLOCK_ANGLE,
      ECLIPTIC_NORTH_CLOCK_ANGLE, and SUN_DIRECTION_CLOCK_ANGLE keywords
      and are measured clockwise from the top of the image when is
      displayed in the correct orientation as defined by
      SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION and LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION.  Please note
      the aspect of the North celestial pole in an image can be computed
      by adding 90 degrees to the boresight declination given by
      DECLINATION in the data labels.
 
      For a comparison of the orientation FITS image data from the three
      science instruments, see the quadrant nomenclature section of the
      the EPOXI SIS document.
 
 
    Spectral Scans
    --------------
      Each HRII scan of Hartley 2 consists of multiple frames within one
      exposure ID (OBSERVATION_ID in the data labels).  To work with these
      spectral scans, it is recommended that all frames for one exposure
      ID be stacked into a three-dimensional cube.  Then, a
      spatial-spatial map can be produced for a specific wavelength by
      selecting the appropriate spectral column from the image cube.
      Spectral wavelengths are provided by the second FITS extension, the
      spectral registration (wavelength) map.
 
 
    IR Slit Location
    ----------------
      For a comparison of the relative locations of the IR slit with
      respect to the fields of view of the Medium Resolution Instrument
      Visible CCD (MRI) and the High Resolution Instrument Visible CCD
      (HRIV), see the instrument alignment section of the EPOXI SIS
      document or Klaasen, et al. (2011) [KLAASENETAL2011].
 
      There are no visible CCD context images provided in this dataset to
      aid in orienting the IR slit location with the nucleus during a
      particular observation.  In many cases, nearly simultaneous MRI
      frames, located in the dataset DIF-C-MRI-3/4-EPOXI-HARTLEY2-V1.0,
      were acquired during the IR scans and may provide field of view
      context for the slit location.  Utilizing the infrared data scans
      themselves is currently the best way to determine the slit location
      on the nucleus.  The user can create a three-dimensional cube as
      described above then use the ~2.4-micron spatial-spatial map to
      determine where the slit was pointed during that particular scan.
      Geometry values, such as right ascension and declination, given
      in the data labels are for the instrument boresight and do not
      easily give positional information along the slit for tying a
      pixel to a specific point on the nucleus.
 
 
    Timing for Spectra
    ------------------
      It is important to note that the readout order of the IR detector
      affects the timing of the spectra.  When a HRII spectral image is
      displayed using the true-sky convention, the wavelength increases
      horizontally to the right and the spatial or along-slit direction is
      vertical.  In this orientation, the IR detector was read out from the
      left and right edges and toward the center and starting with the
      first row at the bottom and ending with the last row at the top of
      the display.  Since the detector is reset and read out on a
      pixel-by-pixel basis, the read out order affects the time at which
      each pixel is exposed although each pixel has the same exposure
      duration -- except for the ALTFF mode that has different read and
      reset causing the effective exposure time to vary with line number,
      i.e., along the slit in the spatial direction.  Additionally, the end
      of the spectrometer slit that always points roughly towards the sun
      is the first line to be readout and the last line to be read out is
      furthest from the sun, assuming the spacecraft is in its usual
      orientation with the solar panels pointing roughly toward the sun.
      For more information about the timing of the spectra, see the zero
      exposure background section of the EPOXI instrument calibration paper
      by Klaasen, et al. (2011) [KLAASENETAL2011].  A brief discussion
      about how the calibration pipeline handles the ALTFF mode is included
      in the EPOXI Hartley 2 Calibration Pipeline Summary document.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
    Data Units
    ----------
      Raw spectral image data have units of raw data numbers.
 
 
    Imaging Modes
    -------------
      A summary of the imaging modes is provided here.  For more
      information see the EPOXI SIS and EPOXI Hartley 2 Calibration
      Pipeline Summary documents, Hampton, et al. (2005) [HAMPTONETAL2005]
      and Klaasen, et al. (2011) [KLAASENETAL2011].  In the table below,
      X-Size is the spectral dimension and Y-Size is the spatial
      dimension.
 
                    X-Size  Y-Size  Bin
        Mode Name   (pix)   (pix)  Type  Comments
        ---- ------ ------  -----  ----- ------------------------------------
          1  BINFF    512     256   2x2  Binned full frame
          2  BINSF1   512     126   2x2  Binned sub-frame
          3  BINSF2   512      64   2x2  Binned sub-frame
          4  UBFF    1024     512   1x1  Unbinned full frame
          5  ALTFF    512     256   2x2  Alternate mode 1 (min. exposure
                                         time is 1/2 of mode 1)
          6  DIAG    1024     512   1x1  Diagnostic, one reset frame followed
                                         by a separate read frame such that
                                         odd IMAGE_NUMBERs are reset frames
                                         and even IMAGE_NUMBERs are read
                                         frames
          7  MEMCK   1024     512   1x1  Memory Check
 
      By utilizing the different imaging modes of the HRII instrument, the
      observational requirements for desired exposure times were met.
      Note, of the 7 modes, only modes 1-6 were used for the encounter with
      comet Hartley 2.  Subframe modes are binned (2x2), reduce the spatial
      (LINE) extent of the image FOV, and have a shorter readout time which
      reduces the exposure time for bright objects and keeps the detector
      from saturating.
 
 
    Time- and Geometry-Related Keywords
    -----------------------------------
      All time-related keywords in the data labels, except
      EARTH_OBSERVER_MID_TIME, are based on the clock on board the flyby
      spacecraft.  EARTH_OBSERVER_MID_TIME provides the UTC when an
      Earth-based observer should have been able to see an event recorded
      by the instrument.
 
      The SDC pipeline was not able to automatically determine the proper
      geometric information for the target of choice in some cases.  When
      these parameters could not be computed, the corresponding keywords
      in the data labels are set to a value of unknown, &apos;UNK&apos;.  Also if
      GEOMETRY_QUALITY_FLAG is set to &apos;BAD&apos; or GEOMETRY_TYPE is set to
      &apos;PREDICTED&apos; in the PDS labels, then this indicates the geometry
      values may not be accurate and should be used with caution.  The
      value &apos;N/A&apos; is used for some geometry-related keywords in the data
      labels because these parameters are not applicable.
 
      Observational geometry parameters provided in the data labels were
      computed at the epoch specified by the mid-obs UTC, IMAGE_MID_TIME,
      in the data labels.  The exceptions are the target-to-sun values
      evaluated at the time light left the target that reached the
      spacecraft at mid-obs time, and the earth-observer-to-target values
      evaluated at the time the light that left the target, which reached
      the spacecraft at mid-obs time, reached Earth.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    The geometric parameters included in the data labels and FITS headers
    were computed using the best available SPICE kernels at the time the
    data products were generated.  The kernels are archived in the
    EPOXI SPICE dataset, DIF-C/E/X-SPICE-6-V1.0.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    Earth Mean Equator and Vernal Equinox of J2000 (EME J2000) is the
    inertial reference system used to specify observational geometry
    parameters in the data labels.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The observations in this dataset are in standard FITS format with PDS
    labels, and can be viewed by a number of PDS-provided and commercial
    programs.  For this reason no special software is provided with this
    dataset.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The FITS files in this dataset were reviewed internally by the EPOXI
    project and were used extensively to verify the calibration of the
    instrument.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    This dataset was peer reviewed and certified for scientific use on
    15 August 2011.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    There are no unexpected gaps in this dataset, except those that
    occurred on 06 and 28 October 2011 as noted in the dataset overview.
    All science frames received on the ground were processed and included
    in this dataset.
 
    Horizontal striping through some images indicates missing data.  The
    image quality map extension identifies where pixels are missing.  If
    the second most-significant bit of a pixel in the image quality map is
    turned on, then data for the corresponding image pixel is missing.  For
    more information, refer to the EPOXI SIS document.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
 
    Timing
    ------
      The flyby spacecraft clock SPICE kernels (SCLK) used to convert to
      UTC and to calculate geometry-related parameters for this dataset
      have a known accuracy of no better than 0.5 seconds.  However the
      latest SCLK (science version 84) applied to the Hartley 2 encounter
      data is good to within 0.01 seconds for converting the spacecraft
      timestamps to ephemeris time for observations acquired around
      closest approach.  Please note that the SCLK (version 65) used to
      compute UTC values and geometry for calibration data acquired from
      January 2009 through July 2010 has known discontinuities of up to a
      second.  Those discontinuities have been corrected in the latest
      SCLK, science version 84, applied to Hartley data.
 
      The mission operations team has figured out how to correct raw clock
      correlation data for the Deep Impact flyby spacecraft to allow
      timing fits that are accurate to well under the sub-second level as
      evidenced by the 0.01-second accuracy around the time the Hartley 2
      encounter.  The EPOXI project plans to use this method to generate a
      complete and highly accurate set of UTC correlations for the flyby
      spacecraft since the launch, resulting in a future version of a SCLK
      kernel that will retroactively change correlation for **all** Deep
      Impact and EPOXI data.  When this kernel is available, it will be
      added to the SPICE datasets for the two missions and posted on the
      NAIF/SPICE web site at http://naif.jpl.nasa.gov/naif/.  The EPOXI
      project will provide more precise times for archived data as time
      and funding permit.
 
 
    HRI Telescope Focus
    -------------------
      Images of stars acquired early during the Deep Impact mission in 2005
      indicated the HRI telescope was out of focus.  However, this focus
      problem does not significantly affect the HRII instrument.  For more
      details please see the Deep Impact instrument calibration paper by
      Klaasen, et al. (2008) [KLAASENETAL2006].
 
 
    Displaying Images
    -----------------
      Flight software writes an image header over the first 100 bytes of
      quadrant A.  These image header pixels were included in the raw FITS
      images.  Since the values in these pixels vary dramatically, it is
      recommended that the values of the MINIMUM and MAXIMUM keywords in
      the data label (or the MINPVAL and MAXPVAL in the FITS header) be
      used to scale an image for display because these values exclude the
      header bytes as well as the reference rows and columns located around
      the edge of the spectral image.  For more information, see the
      quadrant nomenclature section of the EPOXI SIS document.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

