<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mer1-m-eng-6-rmc-ops-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MER 1 MARS ENGINEERING ROVER MOTION COUNTER OPS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_exploration_rover::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mer1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:eng.mer1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer1-m-eng-6-rmc-ops-v1.0__browser_mer1-m-eng-6-rmc-ops-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer1-m-eng-6-rmc-ops-v1.0__dvo_mer1-m-eng-6-rmc-ops-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer1-m-eng-6-rmc-ops-v1.0__pds.geo.mer.analysts_notebook::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mars Exploration Rover Mission, Camera Software Interface Specification, 2003
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CAMSIS2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mars Exploration Rover Mission, Rover Motion Counter Master File Software
                   Interface Specification, 2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.RMCSIS2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MER1-M-ENG-6-RMC-OPS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MER 1 MARS ENGINEERING ROVER MOTION COUNTER OPS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2005-10-18</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-01-01</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>RAFAEL ALANIS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Alanis, Rafael, &apos;MER 1 Mars Engineering Rover Motion Counter
            Ops V1.0&apos;, NASA Planetary Data System,
            MER1-M-ENG-6-RMC-OPS-V1.0, 2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains Opportunity (MER 1) Rover Motion Counter
            Operations data from the Mars Exploration Rover Mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This archive contains position and orientation information for
            various coordinate systems indexed by the Rover Motion Counter
            (RMC).
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This RDR is produced by OPGS to provide the position and
    orientation of various coordinate systems indexed by the Rover
    Motion Counter, or RMC.  An RMC file is nothing more than a
    collection of coordinate system definitions expressed in an XML
    formatted text file. Two important specializations of the file are
    described here - Site Vector Files (SVF) and Rover Vector Files
    (RVF). For an in depth discussion of all RMC files, please refer
    to the MER Project Software Interface Specification (SIS), Rover
    Motion Counter (RMC) Master File, Version 1.0, JPL D-22854,
    August 1, 2004.
 
  Processing
  ==========
    This Operations RDR is generated by OPGS/MIPL using the Mars Suite
    of VICAR image processing software at Jet Propulsion Laboratory.
    The input is a series of numbers that are used to keep track of the
    location of a rover. Any time an actuator on the rover moves, the
    RMC is incremented.  This allows ground software to keep track of
    data that was acquired from the same location.
 
  Data
  ====
    Site Vector Files
    -----------------
    A Site Vector File (SVF) is an RMC file that contains nothing but
    Site Frame definitions.  Each Site is defined relative to the
    immediately previous Site, and all Sites back to 0 must be defined
    (Site 0 has no reference and is not in the file).  Thus the file
    defines a continuous chain of Sites from 0 up to the current Site.
 
    Site Vector Files are used to determine the relationship between
    Sites.  Since EDR&apos;s do not contain any Site Frame definitions in
    their labels, and RDRs may contain at most one, an SVF is required
    any time data from more than one site is being compared or combined.
 
 
    Rover Vector Files
    ------------------
    Similar to a Site Vector File, a Rover Vector File (RVF) contains
    nothing but Rover Frame definitions.  However, instead of
    containing _all_ Rover Frame definitions, an RVF file contains only
    Rover Frame definitions within one Site.  Thus different RVF files
    will exist for each Site.
 
    RVF files will typically not contain an entry for each and every
    RMC within their Site. Instead, an RVF file contains an entry for
    every RMC at which the rover location changed.
 
    If it is subsequently determined that the rover moved between
    drives (say, the IDD moved the rover), then a solution is generated
    for that, and an entry is created in the RVF for the RMC value at
    which the move occurred.
 
    Thus, the file contains only deltas - RMC values at which the
    location of the rover changed.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    There are several types of coordinate frames in use by MER (see
    [EDR SIS]).  For the purposes of this document, the Site and Rover
    frames are the most important.
 
    Each type of frame has many different instances.  For example,
    every time the rover moves, a different instance of the Rover
    coordinate frame is created (since the Rover frame is attached to
    the rover).  A different Site frame is created whenever the project
    declares a Site.  The RMC is used to indicate which instance of a
    coordinate frame is being referred to.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The OPGS/MIPL Mars Suite of VICAR image processing was used to
    generate these RDRs.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    The data set will initially be delivered and kept online.  Upon
    Mission completion, the RMC Operations RDRs will be delivered
    to PDS on DVD.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
NULL
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

