<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.gp-j-nms-3-entry-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GALILEO PROBE NMS RAW DATA SET</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.galileo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.gp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:gpms.gp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.gp-j-nms-3-entry-v1.0__browserp_gp-j-nms-3-entry-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Niemann, H.B., S.K. Atreya, G.R. Carignan, T.M. Donahue, J.A. Haberman, D.N.
                   Harpold, R.E. Hartle, D.M. Hunten, W.T. Kasprzak, P.R. Mahaffy, T.C. Owen, N.W.
                   Spencer, and S.H. Way, The Galileo Probe Mass Spectrometer: Composition of
                   Jupiter&apos;s Atmosphere, Science 272, pp 846-849, 1996
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NIEMANNETAL1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GP-J-NMS-3-ENTRY-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GALILEO PROBE NMS RAW DATA SET</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1996-12-08</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1995-12-07T19:04:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1995-12-07T22:04:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JOHN HABERMAN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            GALILEO PROBE NMS RAW DATA SET
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This Galileo Probe Mass Spectrometer (GPMS) data set includes:
            (1) Jupiter atmospheric entry data from December 7, 1995; (2)
            Instrument characterization data; March - April, 1985; (3)
            Residual background data from Earth testing; 1985 - 1989; (4)
            Residual background data from space; 1989, 1990, 1992; (5)
            Characterization data from the refurbished Engineering Unit (NOT
            YET AVAILABLE - December, 1998); (6) Sequence and conversion
            tables necessary to process the data.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This Galileo Probe Mass Spectrometer (GPMS) data set includes:
 
    1.  Jupiter atmospheric entry data from December 7, 1995.
    2.  Instrument characterization data; March - April, 1985.
    3.  Residual background data from Earth testing; 1985 - 1989.
    4.  Residual background data from space; 1989, 1990, 1992.
    5.  Characterization data from the refurbished Engineering Unit.
        NOT YET AVAILABLE - December, 1998
    6.  Sequence and conversion tables necessary to process the data.
 
    This data set contains the Mass Spectrometer instrument data from
    the Galileo Probe mission that entered the atmosphere of Jupiter
    on December 7, 1995.  The GPMS instrument operated for
    approximately 58 minutes (7000 steps).  Approximately 50 minutes
    of the data are of high quality.  Also included are data files
    necessary to characterize the operation and behavior of this
    instrument and data files needed to demonstrate the integrity of
    the GPMS instrument over the lengthy duration of the mission.
    Additionally, the Engineering Unit was refurbished to flight
    quality and has yielded data that help understand the results
    from the mission and these data are included with this data set.
    The data tables and conversion files required to process the raw
    data are also included.  Documentation reviewing the steps
    necessary to go from telemetry to more useful (meaningful) data
    formats are included.  Finally, in the entry data set Probe time
    and Probe descent pressure data are included.  The pressure data
    are from the Atmosphere Structure Instrument.  These last two
    data items will not be detailed further in this work.
 
    In &apos;real&apos; time (i.e., on December 7, 1995) the data were
    telemetered from the Galileo Probe to the Galileo Orbiter.  These
    data were redundantly stored both in &apos;excess&apos; orbiter memory and
    on a tape recorder.  The initial data sent to Earth, beginning on
    December 10, 1995, were those stored in the Orbiter&apos;s memory.
    Following this, the data stored on the tape recorder were sent to
    Earth.  Between December 1995 and July 1996, 37 files containing
    mission data were delivered to us.  Some of these files contained
    unprocessed telemetry data (i.e., as it was received.) Other
    files contained data that had been checked and &apos;bested&apos;.  (Bested
    indicates data where error corrections have been applied.) In
    most instances each &apos;new&apos; data file contained the existing data
    plus some new data.  Effectively the data were &apos;redundantly&apos;
    telemetered to the Earth *2?* times.  The most useful (complete)
    data files are tagged with dates of February 5, April 16, and
    July 1, 1996.  The reasons for this method of data return
    include:
 
    1.  The failure of the Orbiter high gain antenna.
    2.  The problems with the Orbiter&apos;s (sticking) tape recorder.
    3.  Time use allocations with the Deep Space Antenna Network.
    4.  The fact that Jupiter and Earth were located on opposite sides
        of the Sun in early 1996 resulting in a poor signal to noise
        ratio.
 
    The Galileo Probe Mass Spectrometer instrument steps through a
    pre-programmed sampling sequence.  Each measurement results in a
    count rate related to the mass programmed for that step.  The
    nominal integration period for each step was 0.5 second.  The
    data also yield a data bit indicating a detector sensitivity mode
    (LOW or HIGH) for that measurement.  (At large count rates the
    instrument automatically switches to a LOW sensitivity mode so as
    to not overload and damage the detector.) Also returned with each
    measurement are two data bits of instrument &apos;housekeeping&apos;
    information.  Each GPMS Instrument minor frame (8 steps) yields
    two (2) housekeeping parameter values.
 
                        - - - - - - - - - -
 
    A short mass spectrometer informational interlude.  The GPMS
    instrument is also referred to as a Neutral Mass Spectrometer
    (NMS).  Such an instrument is composed of an inlet system, an
    ionizer, ion optics (lenses), a mass filter and a detector.  All
    of this is inside of a high-vacuum chamber.  The function of the
    inlet system is to channel your sample to the mass spectrometer
    (ms).  Because the ms requires a good vacuum, you must allow only
    a fraction of the incoming sample into the vacuum system.
    Calibrated leaks are used for this purpose.  The mass filter
    allows only those ions with the proper mass to charge ratio
    (generally referred to as mass or Daltons or AMU) to pass.  A
    mass filter &apos;works&apos; because in the presence of electromagnetic
    fields in a vacuum, the trajectories of ions are predictable.
    The ionizer is often a heated filament designed to emit electrons
    with a defined energy (voltage).  These electrons collide with
    gases entering the ionizer and a small fraction of the species
    acquire a charge.  The larger the ionization energy, the more
    violent the effects.  When all is working nicely, the ion
    acquires a unit charge.  When the species is a molecule, it will
    usually break up into fragments; the exact fragmentation pattern
    is determined by bond energies and the ionization energy.  Ion
    lenses are useful for directing the ions toward a specific
    target.  A good detector of ions is an electron multiplier.
 
    The GPMS Instrument:
 
    1.  Two inlets with larger leaks used on Inlet 1 than on Inlet 2.
        (Because the pressure is lower up high where Inlet 1 is used.)
        Micron sized (7 channel) capillary leaks are used.
    2.  Vacuum maintained by the use of ion and chemical getter pumps.
    3.  Quadrupole Mass Filter
    4.  Electron bombardment ionizer with 3 ionization energy options.
    5.  Several lenses are used to &apos;steer&apos; the ions.
    6.  Electron multiplier is used as the detector.
 
                        - - - - - - - - - -
 
    In order to translate the housekeeping data returned by the GPMS
    instrument, a table of conversion coefficients is required.  The
    application of these conversion coefficients yields parameters in
    meaningful units (Volts, Amperes) instead of &apos;telemetry mystery
    units&apos;.  Also needed is a table indicating the GPMS parameters
    (mass, ionizer energy) associated with each step of the sampling
    sequence.  These tables are parts of this data set.  Contained in
    the instrument&apos;s housekeeping parameters are a GPMS SYNC PATTERN.
    These parameters are necessary to &apos;lock&apos; the programmed sequence
    with the returned data.
 
    Most of the GPMS data are in the form of standard mass sweeps.
    During these sequences the mass is incremented in integral (1)
    Atomic Mass Unit (amu) steps between sample integrations.
    Typically the sweep steps over a mass range from 2 to 150 amu
    with the ionizer set to operate at 75 volts.  The circuitry
    associated with the electron multiplier (detector) normally
    starts its measurement in the HIGH sensitivity mode.  When the
    count rate exceeds a defined threshold, (excessive signal
    yielding too much current in the multiplier) the system switches
    the detector to the LOW sensitivity mode.  Occasionally
    measurements are made where the GPMS instrument is incrementing
    in 0.125 amu steps, is operating using ionization energies of 25
    or 15 Volts, is set to measure specific mass values at chosen
    ionization energies, has been forced to use the LOW sensitivity
    detection mode of operation and such.
 
    The overall GPMS sequence includes the following subsequences:
 
    1.  Instrument Background:  Selected residual gases (masses) in the
        instrument are monitored as soon as power is applied and until
        Inlet 1 and Outlet 1 are opened to the atmosphere.
 
    2.  Photochemical Region:  The molecules most likely to exist in the
        upper atmosphere probably evolved as a result of photochemical
        processes.  Masses corresponding to the anticipated molecules
        are monitored.  Selected masses are monitored at least once
        every 30 seconds.  The collection of a sample by Enrichment Cell
        1 was initiated.  The enrichment cells work by pulling a large
        volume of sample across a sorbent material (&apos;Carbosieve&apos;).  The
        hydrogen that dominates the Jovian atmosphere is pumped away
        using chemical getter pumps.
 
    3.  Below the Ammonia Clouds:  It was believed that the uppermost
        clouds visible on Jupiter were composed of Ammonia and possibly
        including Hydrogen Sulfide.  In this region a slightly modified
        sampling scheme was used.  The inlet to the Enrichment Cell was
        closed and processing of this sample started.
 
    4.  Instrument Background:  At this phase of the mission, the
        atmospheric entry models predicted the presence of a water
        cloud.  To avoid problems that can arise if a drop of water
        entered the inlet of the mass spectrometer, it was decided to
        terminate direct atmospheric measurements and prepare the GPMS
        instrument for important special sequences.  At this time, in
        the sequence, valves were closed to isolate the mass
        spectrometer from the Jovian atmosphere and instrument
        background measurements were obtained.
 
    5.  Rare Gas Measurements:  Following the charging of Enrichment
        Cell 1, a valve was opened to allow those gases not sorbed by
        the enrichment cell material to (volume expand) enter the Rare
        Gas Cell.  An additional getter pump helps remove any remaining
        hydrogen from the gas mixture.  The gases remaining were
        expected to be primarily the Rare (Noble) gases.  Following the
        completion of the instrument background measurements, valves
        were opened to allow these gases into the mass spectrometer for
        analysis.
 
    6.  Enrichment Cell 1 Measurements:  The processing of the gases in
        the enrichment cell consists of heating the cell to drive off
        those volatile materials sorbed on the &apos;Carbosieve&apos; material.
        These gases were added to those already in the Rare Gas Cell
        and analyzed by the mass spectrometer.
 
    7.  Instrument Background:  Following the evaluation of the contents
        from the special cells, additional instrument background scans
        were done.
 
    8.  Inlet 2:  Inlet and Outlet 2 were opened to monitor samples
        directly from the deeper Jovian atmosphere.  Most of the
        sequences done in this region consist of full mass scans
        because it was expected that more complicated molecules would
        exist at these higher pressures.  In a similar fashion to that
        previously noted, Enrichment Cell 2 was charged with sample.
 
    9.  Enrichment Cell 2:  Following sample processing, the contents
        from the second enrichment cell were analyzed by the mass
        spectrometer.  These samples were superposed on the sample
        entering from the direct atmosphere.
 
    10. High Resolution Scans:  A single 0.125 amu per step mass scan
        was multiplexed into the sequence.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The GPMS measurements yield a count rate for the sampling
    integration time; here nominally 0.5 second.  The resulting count
    rate as a function of mass is a measure of qualitative and
    quantitative information about the atomic and molecular species
    entering the instrument.  The actual integration period for each
    step is 0.48375 seconds.  The observed count rate must also be
    corrected for the limitations of the detector circuitry.  One
    well documented problem at higher count rates is pulse pile up
    where the events occurring at the detector are happening faster
    than the circuitry can recover.  Data corrected for this effect
    are part of the data set.
 
 
  Data - Atmospheric Entry
  ========================
    The operation of the GPMS instrument was expected to begin at an
    ambient pressure of 0.1 Bars.  As the result of a probe problem,
    the actual start of the instrument&apos;s sequence began at a pressure
    of ca.  0.5 Bars.  The data included in the file, GPMSDATA.DAT,
    include
 
    Column 1:  Sequence Step
    Column 2:  Probe Time (Seconds after Major Frame/Minor Frame 0/0.)
    Column 3:  Ambient Pressure (millibars) (from ASI measurements)
    Column 4:  Ionization (electron) Energy (electron Volts)
    Column 5:  Mass being sampled (amu)
    Column 6:  Detector Sensitivity (HI or LO)
    Column 7:  Uncorrected Count Data (counts per period)
    Column 8:  Corrected Count Data (counts per period)
    Column 9:  (Where present)  Inlet System Operation Steps
 
    The initial telemetry data forwarded by the project, in the form
    of System Data Manager (*.SDM) files, contained errors.  (Note:
    *.SDM files are not included in the PDS data set.) The GPMS data
    were redundantly sent on both the &apos;A&apos; and &apos;B&apos; telemetry data
    systems.  The Probe data were also stored both in the (excess)
    Orbiter&apos;s memory and on the Orbiter&apos;s tape recorder.  The data
    from each of these were independently telemetered to the Deep
    Space Network antennas on Earth.  As new batches of data were
    received on Earth and the Jupiter-Sun- Earth geometry improved,
    the quality of the telemetry data plus the error correction and
    besting procedures yielded a high quality raw data product.
    Eventually we identified and rejected only 2 readings from the
    final 7000+ values as being in error.
 
    The data files (*.SDM files) consist of data records sized at 100
    (8-bit) words.  (The first data word is indexed (numbered) as
    zero.) These records are recorded as BINARY data (often referred
    to as a DIRECT ACCESS format.) The first 36 of these data words
    contain data system identification plus counter and time
    information.  The remaining 64 (8-bit) words contain the
    telemetry for 1 minor frame of Galileo Probe data.  All data not
    related to the GPMS instrument were &apos;zeroed&apos; by the Galileo Probe
    Project office before we received a file.
 
    Extracting the Probe telemetry yields Probe data records.  The
    GPMS data occupy positions numbered 6, 7, 14, 15, 22, 23, 30, 31,
    38, 39, 46, 47, 54, 55, 62 and 63.  Two of the data records, from
    the data file nms0701a.sdm (July 1, 1996), are shown next.  These
    data records are tagged with the mission date 12/07/95 and the
    time tag shown.  Word 0 indicates the data system used (A or B).
    Words 36, 37 and 38 (Probe words 0, 1 and 2) show the Probe SYNC
    pattern.  Word 40 (Probe word 4) is a counter.
 
    -------------------------------------  Comments
      6   0  92   0   1   0  64   0   0    Header (36 entries)
      0   0   0   7 252  46  22 171  49    Data Stream &gt;B&lt;
      7 252  46  22 171  33   7 252  46    22:46:08.247
     22 171  33 134   5  48  22  82 227
    248 197  73   0  66 100   0  39        Probe Data (64 Entries)
      0   0   0   0   0   0   1 252
    125   7   0   0   0 167   0  32
      0   0   0   0   0   0 192  41        Multana = 3
    168 125  93 156   0   0  64  26
      0   0   0   0   0   0   0  29
     81 228 205  83   0 123   0  25
      0   0   0   0   0   0 192  24        Housekeeping = 67
 
    -------------------------------------  Comments
      5   0  92   0   1   0  64   0   0    Header (36 entries)
      0   0   0   7 252  46  22  93  36    Data Stream &gt;A&lt;
      7 252  46  22  93  36   7 252  46    22:48:09.093
     22  93  36 134   5  48  22 116 228
    248 197  73   0  65  73   0  31        Probe Data (64 Entries)
      0   0   0   0   0   0   1 252
      0   7   0   0   0 245   0  32
      0   0   0   0   0   0 192  41        Multana = 3
     14 125  93 156 122   0  64  26
      0   0   0   0   0   0   0  29
      0 228 206  83 204   7   0  25
      0   0   0   0   0   0 192  24        Housekeeping = 67
 
    Fortunately the Probe and GPMS minor frames are synchronized.
    Each Probe minor frame yields one minor frame of GPMS data.  This
    GPMS minor frame of data yields 8 count rates and associated
    detector sensitivities plus two housekeeping parameters.  These
    data are extracted from the data as indicated next.
 
    |  HIGH (Even No. Word) |   LOW (Odd No. Word)  |
    +--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+
    | 7| 6| 5| 4| 3| 2| 1| 0| 7| 6| 5| 4| 3| 2| 1| 0|   8-bit
    +--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+
    |&lt;-HK&gt;| S|&lt;Exponent-&gt;|&lt;--------Mantissa--------&gt;|
    +--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+
    |15|14|13|12|11|10| 9| 8| 7| 6| 5| 4| 3| 2| 1| 0|  16-bit
    +--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+--+
     msb                                         lsb
 
    where:
            msb = most significant bit
            lsb = least significant bit
             HK = GPMS Housekeeping bits (0 - 3)
              S = GPMS Sensitivity Bit (0 = HI, 1 = LO)
       Exponent = Count Exponent (0 - 7)
       Mantissa = Count mantissa (0 - 511)
 
    Note:  The GPMS data are log compressed.  The success of this method
           requires that the counter always starts at 1.
           The combination:  Mantissa = Exponent = 0 can NEVER occur!
 
    To determine the uncorrected count data, the following rules apply:
 
    If Exponent = 0
      COUNT = Mantissa - 1
 
    If Exponent &gt; 0
      COUNT = (512 + Mantissa) * 2 ^ (Exponent - 1) + 2 ^ (Exponent - 2)
 
    As long as the count is less than, approximately, 1. E+7, the
    CORRECTED count rate is derived from the following relationship:
 
                    OBSERVED = TRUE * exp(-TRUE / z)
    where:
        OBSERVED = Raw (Observed, Uncorrected) Count data
            TRUE = Actual (Real, Corrected) Count data
               z = Constant value determined for this specific
                   instrument
               z = 2.933 E+7
 
    The housekeeping parameter values are derived as follows:
 
          MULTANA = 64 * W(6) + 16 * W(14) + 4 * W(22) + W(30)
 
               HK = 64 * W(38) + 16 * W(46) + 4 * W(54) + W(62)
 
    where:
          MULTANA = Multiplier Analog Current:  A measure of the
                    current from the electron multiplier.
               HK = One of 32 repeating GPMS &apos;health&apos; parameters.
     W(6)...W(62) = The value from the two data bits into which
                    these housekeeping parameters are coded.
 
 
  Data - GPMS Instrument Characterization
  =======================================
    THESE DATA ARE NOT CONSIDERED TO BE QUANTITATIVE!
 
    The GPMS instrument&apos;s capabilities were tested in March and April
    of 1985 in the laboratory at GSFC.  These tests were performed
    using selected pure gases and gas mixtures to demonstrate that
    the instrument could detect these species.  These tests were NOT
    meant to be quantitative! During these tests the leaks used with
    the enrichment cells were several hundred to a thousand times
    smaller than those used during the actual Jovian atmospheric
    entry.  (This was done to prevent damage to the fragile
    components in the mass spectrometer&apos;s ionization source that
    would occur in the event of an air leak or a pressure surge.) The
    characterization gas handling system shown in the diagram
    NMSCLBR.GIF was used.  This system is a recirculating system
    where the pressures and temperatures of the gas sample can be
    controlled.
 
    The data file names indicate the GPMS instrument inlet (I1
    indicates Inlet 1 and I2 indicates Inlet 2) by which the gas
    sample was introduced as well as the identity of the gas sample.
    The data files include the following:
 
    File Name  Inlet   Gas Sample
    i1_h2s       1     Hydrogen Sulfide
    i1_hcn       1     Hydrogen Cyanide
    i1_hydr      1     Mixture of inorganic Hydrides
    i1_ph3       1     Phosphine
    i1_rg        1     Rare Gas Mixture
    i1_rgp       1     Rare Gas Mixture at selected pressures
    i2_alkan     2     Mixture of saturated alkanes
    i2_chmx      2     Mixture of saturated and unsaturated hydrocarbons
    i2_h2nh3     2     Ammonia plus hydrogen mixture
    i2_h2o       2     Water sample
    i2_h2s       2     Hydrogen Sulfide
    i2_hcn       2     Hydrogen Cyanide
    i2_hydr      2     Mixture of inorganic Hydrides
    i2_nh3       2     Ammonia
    i2_ph3       2     Phosphine
    i2_rg        2     Mixture of Rare Gases
    i2_unsat     2     Mixture of Unsaturated Hydrocarbons
    pfusim     1 &amp; 2   90% hydrogen 10% helium mixture introduced using
                       a pressure profile simulating the expected entry.
 
 
  Data - Waiting for Launch
  =========================
    NMS85183, NMS88201
    A89MY15, A89MY15A, A89JL19, A89SE14, A89SE14A
    B89MY15, B89MY15A, B89JL19, B89SE14, B89SE14A
 
    These data are an important monitors of the &apos;history&apos; and
    handling of the instrument.  The data in these files indicates
    the cleanness of the instrument and that it remained (vacuum)
    leak free.  (Note: files A89MY15A, B89MY15A and B89SE14A contain
    no data, and are not included in this archive.)
 
    The data files are included for both the &apos;A&apos; and the &apos;B&apos; data
    streams and include:
 
    July 2, 1985 instrument test at GSFC.  This test was done
      immediately after the &apos;final&apos; processing and sealing of the GPMS
      vacuum system.
 
    July 19, 1988 test at GSFC. This is the last test with the
      instrument prior to its final delivery for processing and launch.
      The GPMS was allowed to perform a full sampling sequence with the
      enrichment cell heaters operational during this test.
 
    May 15, 1989 ground MST testing at KSC (This Mission Sequence Test
      is intended to simulate the timeline and events expected at
      entry.)
 
    July 19, 1989 &apos;ground&apos; Probe Baseline testing at KSC.
 
    September 14, 1989 &apos;onboard shuttle&apos; Probe Baseline testing at KSC.
 
 
  Data - Cruising in Space
  ========================
    A89OC26, A89OC27, A90DE04, A90DE04A, A92NO20, A92NO21
    B89OC26, B89OC27, B90DE04, B90DE04A, B92NO20, B92NO21
 
    The GPMS instrument was tested three times following its launch
    from the space shuttle.  The data from both the &apos;A&apos; and &apos;B&apos; data
    streams is included with this data set.  (Note: files B89OC27 and
    B90DE04 contain no data, and are not included in this archive.)
 
    The data files include:
 
    October 26, 1989 first turn on data from space
    December 4, 1990 Probe Baseline test (SFT) from space
    November 20, 1992 MST (full sequence) test from space
 
 
  Data - Entry
  ============
    A95DE07
    B95DE07
 
    Also included are the &apos;A&apos; and &apos;B&apos; string data from the entry on
    December 7, 1995.  These data files are formatted identically to
    the files noted (above) that present the ground and space GPMS
    instrument testing results.  The instrument&apos;s housekeeping data
    is also included in these data files.
 
 
  Data - Refurbished Engineering Unit
  ===================================
    *** NOT YET AVAILABLE at the beginning of 1999.  ***
 
    The Galileo Probe Engineering Unit was refurbished to &apos;Flight
    Quality&apos; following launch.  This instrument is in the laboratory
    at GSFC and is being used in attempts to simulate the
    observations from the mission.
 
    *** NOT YET AVAILABLE at the beginning of 1999.  ***
 
 
  Data - Miscellaneous
  ====================
    NMSCOEFF, NMSSTEPS
 
    The file NMSCOEFF.TAB contains the coefficients necessary to
    convert the GPMS raw housekeeping data into real world
    Engineering units.  The file NMSSTEPS.TAB contains all of the
    details that have been programmed into the GPMS instrument&apos;s
    sampling sequence such as the mass, electron energy, and
    sensitivity conditions used for each step.  This file also
    documents the instrument&apos;s inlet system operations and other
    parameters as programmed.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The (IBM PC/Clone) executable program NMSSEQ.EXE is a
    self-extracting program that creates a set of files that display
    a cartoon of the GPMS instrument&apos;s operation.  This file will
    create 3 files in the subdirectory from which it is run.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
 
    Data Quality
    ------------
      This data set is of high quality.  The GPMS data were
      redundantly returned on the &apos;A&apos; and &apos;B&apos; data streams from the
      mission.  Where data exist from both data streams, only two (2)
      points do not agree.  The disagreements resulted at steps where
      one of the data streams was noisy or failing so it was not
      difficult to choose the correct data value.  Additionally, the
      mass spectrometer and its housekeeping parameters also yielded
      verifications with regard to the correct choice for the data
      values.
 
      CAUTIONARY NOTE: It appears that thermal problems, with either
      the Probe transmitter or the GPMS Instrument&apos;s data system or
      with both, caused the quality of the data to slowly degrade
      during the final 1000 (or so) measurements from the GPMS
      instrument.  Investigation into this problem continues.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

