<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dif-cal-hrii-hriv-2-ground-tv2-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DEEP IMPACT PREFLIGHT THERMAL-VACUUM 2 HRII/HRIV DATA</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_impact::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:hrii.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:hriv.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dif-cal-hrii-hriv-2-ground-tv2-v1.0__browserp_dif-cal-hrii-hriv-2-ground-tv2-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   A&apos;Hearn, M.F., M.J.S. Belton, A. Delamere, and W.H. Blume, Deep Impact: A
                   Large-Scale Active Experiment on a Cometary Nucleus, Space Science Reviews,
                   117, 1-21, 2005, doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3387-3.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.AHEARNETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hampton, D.L., J.W. Baer, M.A. Huisjen, C.C. Varner, A. Delamere, D.D.
                   Wellnitz, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, and K.P. Klaasen, An Overview of the Instrument Suite
                   for the Deep Impact Mission, Space Science Reviews, 117, 43-93, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3390-8.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAMPTONETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., B. Carcich, G. Carcich, E.J. Grayzeck, and S. McLaughlin, Deep
                   Impact: The Anticipated Flight Data, Space Science Reviews, 117, 335-372, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3385-5.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV-2-GROUND-TV2-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DEEP IMPACT PREFLIGHT THERMAL-VACUUM 2 HRII/HRIV DATA</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2004-10-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2002-08-15T15:39:47Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2002-09-03T08:07:39Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STEPHANIE MCLAUGHLIN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Hampton, D.L., D.D. Wellnitz, and S.A. McLaughlin, DEEP IMPACT
            PREFLIGHT THERMAL-VACUUM 2 HRII/HRIV DATA,
            DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV-2-GROUND-TV2-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Image and temperature data acquired during the preflight
            thermal-vacuum test (TV2) of the Deep Impact High Resolution
            Instrument&apos;s Infrared Spectrometer (HRII) and Visible CCD
            (HRIV)
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains image and temperature data acquired during
            the preflight thermal-vacuum test (TV2) of the High Resolution
            Instrument&apos;s Infrared Spectrometer (HRII) and Visible CCD
            (HRIV) for the Deep Impact Mission.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  This data set description was provided by Stephanie McLaughlin and
  Dennis Wellnitz (University of Maryland), who participated in
  the ground calibration tests of the Deep Impact instruments.
 
 
Data Set Overview
=================
 
  This data set contains image and temperature data acquired during
  the preflight thermal-vacuum test (TV2) of High Resolution Instrument&apos;s
  Infrared Spectrometer (HRII) and Visible CCD (HRIV) for Deep Impact.
  The experiments performed during TV2 were designed by the Ball Aerospace
  team with input from the Deep Impact science team.  TV2 was conducted
  by Don Hampton of Ball Aerospace.  Several science team members were
  present at all times to assist with the experiments and perform
  real-time analysis of the data.
 
  The main objective of TV2 was to obtain calibration data for the
  HRII instrument:
 
    - Perform tests at the 3 nominal operating temperatures of the
      optical bench:  128K, 135K, and 141K.
    - Determine best focus at the nominal operating temperatures.
    - Obtain flat fields from various blackbody sources to measure
      the response of the FPA at different wavelengths.
    - Determine the non-linearity of the FPA.
    - Activate the internal calibration lamp.
    - Check for stray light.
    - Check for spectral motion caused by motion of the HRIV filter
      wheel.
    - Check adjustments made to the FPA spectral and spatial
      registrations based on TV1 results.
    - Check the spatial and spectral dispersion of the FPA.
 
  Also, during TV2, several calibration experiments were performed
  for the HRIV instrument:
 
    - Check focus.
    - Check co-alignment and co-focus with the HRII instrument.
    - Check registration of the parallel overclock columns and
      the serial overclock rows.
    - Test the photo-response of the CCD by using several calibrated
      blackbody sources and obtain flats.
    - Measure dark current as the CCD cools.
    - Measure bias.
 
  To meet these objectives, the instruments were tested in the Ball 8
  thermal-vacuum chamber.  A test bench was setup outside the chamber
  to direct light from external sources through the window of the
  chamber.
 
  TV2 activities are summarized in the following chart.
 
                  FPA    IR Opt.
    Date/(DOY)  Temp(K)  Bench(K)    Tests
    ----------  -------  -------  ------------------------------------
    2002-08-15    N/A      N/A    HRII: Level check
    (227)                         HRIV: Level check
 
    2002-08-17    120      104    HRII: Alignment check, Darks
    (229)
 
    2002-08-18    ~88     ~136    HRII: Alignment, Focus, Internal
    (230)                               stimulator, Darks
 
    2002-08-19    ~88     ~136    HRII: Alignment, Focus, Argon and
    (231)                               Krypton sources, Blackbody sources
                                        for flats, Darks
 
    2002-08-20    ~88     ~136    HRII: Blackbody sources for flats,
    (232)                               Darks
 
    2002-08-21    ~88     ~136    HRII: Tungsten lamp with various
    (233)                               filters and integrating spheres for
                                        flats, CO and CH4 gas cells, Darks
 
    2002-08-22    ~88     ~136    HRII: Blackbody sources for flats,
    (234)                               Tungsten lamp for flats, Linearity,
                                        Various darks
 
    2002-08-23    N/A      N/A    Warmup chamber for CCD hookup,
    (235)                         No data
 
    2002-08-24    N/A      N/A    Hookup the CCD, Begin cooldown,
    (236)                         HRIV: Check CCD
 
    2002-08-25    N/A      N/A    HRIV: Check CCD dark current
    (237)                               every 5 minutes as chamber cools,
 
    2002-08-26    ~91     ~142    HRII: Alignment, Focus, Krypton
    (238)                               source, Darks
                                  HRIV: Co-alignment and co-focus
                                        with HRII
 
    2002-08-27    ~90     ~141    HRII: Argon and Krypton sources,
    (239)                               Various sources for flats, Darks
 
    2002-08-28    ~90     ~141    HRII: Linearity, Various sources
    (240)                               for flats, CH4 and N2 gas cells,
                                        Stray light, Darks
                                  HRIV: Filter wheel in motion
                                        while taking HRII darks,
                                        Begin cooldown to coldest temp
 
    2002-08-29    ~86     ~130    Could not cool to 128K as in TV1
    (241)                         HRII: Focus, Argon and Krypton
                                        sources, Various sources for flats,
                                        Darks
                                  HRIV: Focus, Darks, Co-focus
                                        with HRII
 
    2002-08-30    ~86     ~130    HRII: CO, N2 and CH4 gas cells,
    (242)                               Various sources for flats, HJLM
                                        astronomy filters, Darks
 
    2002-08-31    ~86     ~130    HRII: Linearity, Meteorite sample,
    (243)                               Various sources for flats, Stray
                                        light, Darks
                                  HRIV: Filter wheel in motion
                                        while taking HRII darks, Focus
 
    2002-09-01/02 N/A      N/A    Calibrations finished; warmup
    (244-245)
 
    2002-09-03    N/A      N/A    HRIV: Test with calibrated
    (246)                               visible source
 
 
  For more information about the mission, the HRII and HRIV instruments,
  and the anticipated flight data, see A&apos;Hearn, et al. (2005)
  [AHEARNETAL2005], Hampton, et al. (2005) [HAMPTONETAL2005], and
  Klaasen, et al. (2005) [KLAASENETAL2005].
 
 
Parameters
==========
 
  HRII
  ----
 
    The HRII spectral image data are in units of raw data numbers.
    For TV2, all seven of the HRII&apos;s image modes were tested:
 
    Image  MinExp  X-Size  Y-Size  #Images
    Mode#  (sec)   (pix)   (pix)    Output  Binning  Comments
    -----  ------  ------  ------  -------  -------  ---------------------
      1     2.862    512     256       1      2x2
      2     1.432    512     126       1      2x2
      3     0.717    512      64       1      2x2
      4     2.861   1024     512       1      1x1
      5     2.865    512     256       1      2x2
      6     1.432   1024     512       2      1x1    Reset then data frame
      7     2.864   1024     512       1      1x1    Memory check mode
 
    In this table, MinExp is the frame-to-frame minimum exposure times,
    X-Size is spectral dimension and Y-Size is spatial dimension of the
    FPA.  For all image modes except 6, the reset frame is automatically
    subtracted, on-chip, from the data frame and the result is output.
    For more information about the image modes, see Hampton, et al.
    (2005)[HAMPTONETAL2005].
 
    Spectral and spatial registrations for the IR FPA were adjusted
    after TV1.  During TV2, it was determined that the adjustments were
    correctly made.
 
  HRIV
  ----
 
    The HRIV image data are in units of raw data numbers.  The following
    image modes were defined and tested during TV2:
 
      Image  MinExp  X-Size  Y-Size
      Mode#   (ms)   (pix)   (pix)   Binning  Comments
      -----  ------  ------  ------  -------  -------------------------
        1      3.5    1024    1024     1x1    Shuttered
        2      3.5     512     512     1x1    Shuttered
        3    217.8     256     256     1x1    Not shuttered
        4     98.4     128     128     1x1    Not shuttered
        5     47.4      64      64     1x1    Not shuttered
 
    In this table, MinExp is the minimum exposure time and the term
    shuttered means the light blocker in the HRIV instrument is
    always used (opened and closed).  For all modes, additional exposure
    time can be commanded.  For unshuttered modes, a delay time (duration
    to wait before the start of the CCD readout) can also be commanded.
    For more information about the image modes, see Hampton, et al. (2005)
    [HAMPTONETAL2005].
 
    Please note that the results from TV2 indicated the need for additional
    image modes with shorter minimum exposure times or without serial and
    parallel overclock areas.  Four new image modes were defined and
    implemented for all of the Deep Impact CCDs after TV2.
 
 
Data
====
 
  Images
  ------
 
    The data are in the form of FITS files with attached FITS headers
    and detached PDS labels.  One data file contains one 2-dimensional
    HRII spectral image or HRIV visible image.  The fastest-varying
    axis is considered the X axis and the slowest-varying, the Y axis.
    TV2 data filenames have this format:  Iyymmdd_hhmmss_sss_xx.FIT
    where the &apos;yymmdd_hhmmss_sss&apos; string the date, time and subseconds
    stamp provided by the ground-support computer when it stored the
    original data file.  The clock on the ground-support computer was
    was set to local Mountain Daylight Savings time.  The &apos;xx&apos; string
    is valued with &apos;A&apos; for all HRIV data, &apos;B&apos; for HRII image modes 1-5
    and 7, or &apos;B1&apos; and &apos;B2&apos; for the reset and data frames for HRII
    image mode 6.
 
    For TV2, the ground-support computer stored data files in a native
    image format, called &apos;IMG&apos;.  The raw data numbers were 14-bit and
    and left justified.  A 100-byte image header was pre-pended to each
    data array.  The &apos;IMG&apos; data were converted to FITS at the Deep Impact
    Science Data Center (SDC) at Cornell University, using algorithms
    developed by Ball Aerospace for testing of the instruments and to
    allow real-time analysis of data during thermal-vacuum tests.
    During the conversion, raw data numbers were right justified to
    give the actual, true data numbers.  Data in the 100-byte image
    header are captured in the FITS header.
 
    For TV2, all HRIV image modes have several columns of serial
    overclocks and several rows of parallel overclocks.  However,
    during TV2, it was determined that the registrations of these
    areas on the CCD were not correct.  Thus, the Field Programmable
    Gate Array (FPGA) for the CCD was changed after TV2.
 
  Instrument Temperatures
  -----------------------
 
    Temperatures of various components of the HRII and HRIV instruments
    were automatically recorded every 5 minutes by a thermister monitor,
    a computer.  Temperature data, in fixed-width ASCII table format, are
    available in the data directory.  Time stamps in the temperature file
    are based on local Mountain Daylight Savings time and are within
    several minutes of the time stamps in the FITS filenames.
 
    It is important to note that the IR FPA temperatures recorded by the
    thermister monitor were adjusted by -3.26K before being stored in the
    temperature table.  After thermal-vacuum 4 (TV4), Ball Aerospace
    personnel analyzed all IR FPA temperatures and determined the
    temperatures recorded by the monitor needed to be adjusted by -3.26K
    because the cable connected to this temperature point included about
    18 inches of manganin wire which resulted in higher temperature
    measurements due to its higher electrical resistance.
 
         .
Ancillary Data
==============
 
  The DOCUMENT directory provides the image log recorded during TV2.
  The log contains an entry for each image acquired during TV2 and
  includes image parameters such as mode and experiment type.  The
  log includes a brief description of each type of experiment performed
  during TV2 and a summary of the experiments performed on each test date.
 
  The DOCUMENT directory also provides daily reports written by the
  test leaders and distributed to the test team and the science
  team.  The reports describe in detail the test activities as well
  problems and successes encountered during TV2.
 
  The DOCUMENT directory includes the local PDS data dictionary used
  to produce the labels as well as sample IDL code used to read
  and extract temperatures from the TV2 temperature table.
 
 
Media/Format
============
 
  This data set is released as a logical data volume.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    1) The time stamp in the FITS filename can vary by several
       tens of seconds of the actual time the image was acquired.
 
    2) Instrument temperatures should be extracted from the temperature
       table provided in this archive.  While some temperatures appear
       in the PDS labels, these values were extracted from the FITS
       headers and are not reliable because of uncertainties about
       how the measurements were being recorded by the ground-support
       equipment used during TV2.  However, temperatures recorded by
       the thermister monitor and provided in the temperature table
       are reliable according to Ball Areospace engineers and science
       team members who have used these data.
 
    3) The images in this archive were used extensively by the science
       team and Ball Aerospace engineers to verify the instruments were
       operating within requirements and to calibrate the instruments.
       These data were reviewed internally by the Deep Impact project
       before release to the planetary community.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

