<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ro-a-osinac-osiwac-5-lutetia-shape-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>PLATE SHAPE MODEL OF ASTEROID LUTETIA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.international_rosetta_mission::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.ro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:osinac.ro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.21_lutetia::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ro-a-osinac-osiwac-5-lutetia-shape-v1.0__browserp_ro-a-osinac-osiwac-5-lutetia-shape-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Carry, B., M. Kaasalainen, C. Leyrat, W.J. Merline, J.D. Drummond, A. Conrad,
                   H.A. Weaver, P.M. Tamblyn, C.R. Chapman, C. Dumas, F. Colas, J.C. Christou, E.
                   Dotto, D. Perna, S. Fornasier, L. Bernasconi, R. Behrend, F. Vachier, A.
                   Kryszczynska, M. Polinska, M. Fulchignoni, R. Roy, R. Naves, R. Poncy, and P.
                   Wiggins, Physical properties of the ESA Rosetta target asteroid (21) Lutetia.
                   II. Shape and flyby geometry, Astron &amp; Astrphys. 523, A94, 2010.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CARRYETAL2010</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Patzold, M., T.P. Andert, S.W. Asmar, J.D. Anderson, J.-P. Barriot, M.K. Bird,
                   B. Hausler, M. Hahn, S. Tellmann, H. Sierks, P. Lamy, and B.P. Weiss, Asteroid
                   21 Lutetia: Low Mass, High Density, Science 334, pp. 491-492, 2011,
                   doi:10.1126/science.1209389.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PATZOLDETAL2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Sierks, H., H.U. Keller, R. Jaumann, H. Michalik, T. Behnke, and 19 others, The
                   DAWN Framing Camera, Space Sci. Rev. 163:263-327, 2011. DOI
                   10.1007/s11214-011-9745-4.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SIERKSETAL2011B</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>RO-A-OSINAC/OSIWAC-5-LUTETIA-SHAPE-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>PLATE SHAPE MODEL OF ASTEROID LUTETIA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2013-08-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>Tony L. Farnham</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Farnham, T.L., SHAPE MODEL OF ASTEROID 21 LUTETIA,
            RO-A-OSINAC/OSIWAC-5-LUTETIA-SHAPE-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2013.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Detailed plate shape model of asteroid 21 Lutetia
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Shape model of asteroid 21 Lutetia, as derived from the Rosetta
            images obtained around the time of closest approach. Twelve
            different versions of the model, at different resolutions, are
            given.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
 
This data set presents the detailed plate shape model of asteroid 21 Lutetia,
as derived by L. Jorda, R. Gaskell, M. Kaasalainen and B. Carry from the
images that were obtained by the Rosetta spacecraft around the time of its
closest approach to the asteroid, and from lightcurve data.  Twelve different
versions are included to provide a variety of surface resolution.  Additional
information about the model can be found in Sierks et al., &apos;Images of
Asteroid 21 Lutetia: A remnant planetesimal from the early solar system&apos;,
Science 334, 487, 2011 [SIERKSETAL2011B]
 
The Rosetta spacecraft reached its closest approach to Lutetia on
10 July 2010 15:45 UT at a distance of 3168.2 km. The Optical, Spectroscopic,
and Infrared Remote Imaging System (OSIRIS) instrument (including both the
Narrow Angle Camera (NAC) and the Wide Angle Camera (WAC)) obtained
body-resolved images starting 9.5 hours before closest approach and
continuing until 18 minutes after.  Images covered more than 50% of the
surface, with spatial scales up to 60 m/pix.
 
The shape model presented here was developed by Laurent Jorda et al. from the
combination of two different techniques: Stereophotoclinometry, using 60 of
the NAC and WAC images, was used to model the surface illuminated and visible
in the Rosetta images.  The rest of the surface was constrained using the
inversion of 50 photometric lightcurves and the contours of adaptive optics
images (Carry et al., &apos;Physical properties of the ESA Rosetta target asteroid
(21) Lutetia.  II. Shape and flyby geometry&apos;, Astron &amp; Astrphys. 523, A94
2010 [CARRYETAL2010]).
 
The orientation of the spin axis, derived as part of the solution, is such
that the North (positive) pole points to a right ascension of 51.8+/-0.4 deg
and a declination of +10.8+/-0.4 deg (J2000).
 
The body&apos;s coordinate system was defined with the +Z axis in the direction of
the spin axis and the prime meridian (+X axis) is defined to pass through the
center of the crater Lauriacum, located at ~38 deg latitude (see the file
LUTETIA-ROTATION.PDF in the DOCUMENTS directory).  The +Y axis completes the
right-hand coordinate system.  The body center is not exactly coincident with
its center of gravity, but the offset is within the uncertainties derived for
the surface positions.
 
The mass of Lutetia was estimated from Radio Science Investigation (Patzold
et al., &apos;Asteroid 21 Lutetia: Low Mass, High Density&apos;, Science 334, 491, 2011
[PATZOLDETAL2011]) to be (1.700+/-0.017)e18 kg.  Combining this with the
volume computed from the shape model, gives a bulk density 3400+/-300 kg/m^3.
 
 
PLATE MODEL
 
The model is given in the standard PDS vertex/triangular plate format (see
plate_shape_definition.txt in the documents directory) with dimensions in
cartesian coordinates.  The models consist of the following
 
   LUTETIA_003M_CART.WRL - 1572866 vertices forming 3145728 triangular plates
   LUTETIA_002M_CART.WRL -  793099 vertices forming 1586194 triangular plates
   LUTETIA_780K_CART.WRL -  392257 vertices forming  784510 triangular plates
   LUTETIA_380K_CART.WRL -  191312 vertices forming  382620 triangular plates
   LUTETIA_240K_CART.WRL -  122066 vertices forming  244128 triangular plates
   LUTETIA_190K_CART.WRL -   94864 vertices forming  189724 triangular plates
   LUTETIA_098K_CART.WRL -   49142 vertices forming   98280 triangular plates
   LUTETIA_048K_CART.WRL -   23894 vertices forming   47784 triangular plates
   LUTETIA_025K_CART.WRL -   12265 vertices forming   24526 triangular plates
   LUTETIA_012K_CART.WRL -    5979 vertices forming   11954 triangular plates
   LUTETIA_006K_CART.WRL -    2914 vertices forming    5824 triangular plates
   LUTETIA_003K_CART.WRL -    1483 vertices forming    2962 triangular plates
 
The data are presented with VRML wrappers that allow the files to be
displayed with existing VRML viewers that are freely available (e.g., INSTANT
PLAYER, OCTAGA, CORTONA, etc.)  Different camera angles have been embedded in
the WRL file to display the nuclues from all of the principal axis
directions, with the &apos;headlight&apos; illumination.  Note that the capabilities of
different viewers may limit the ability to display some or all of these
viewpoints.  Look for &apos;cameras&apos; or &apos;navigation&apos; items in the menus.
 
SURFACE DISCONTINUITY
 
The shape model contains a flaw in the surface that produces a notable jump
in elevation around the body.  This discontinuity is the seam between the two
portions of the model constrained with the different derivation techniques
(stereophotoclinometry and lightcurve analysis).  There are also a few
&apos;holes&apos; in the face that are discontinuous.  These defects are illustrated in
the images LUTETIA_SEAM.PNG and LUTETIA_HOLES.PNG in the DOCUMENTS directory.
 
 
TABLE: Shape Model Characteristics
 
  Surface Area:        33331 km^2
  Volume:              5.0e5 +/- 0.4e5 km^3
  Mean diameter:       98 +/- 2 km  (diameter of sphere of equivalent volume)
  Radius range:        33.4 to 64.7 km
  Dimensions along the principal axes of inertia:
                       A: (121 +/- 1) km
                       B: (101 +/- 1) km
                       C: ( 75 +/- 13) km
  Axis orientation:    RA:   51.8 +/- 0.4 deg
                       Dec: +10.8 +/- 0.4 deg
  Rotation Period:     8.168270 +/- 0.000001 hr
 
 
Author
------
The descriptions in this file were written by Tony Farnham, based on
information from Laurent Jorda and [SIERKSETAL2011B].
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
 
Lightcurve/adaptive optics analysis, which provided the primary constraints
on the portions of the body unseen by Rosetta, was good to within 2 km of the
Stereophotoclinometry technique in regions where both techniques could be
applied. This provides confidence that the unseen portions of the model are
valid.
 
    Review
    ======
The plate model was peer reviewed on 5 March 2013.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

