<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ds1-c-pepe-2-edr-borrelly-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DEEP SPACE 1 19P/BORRELLY ENCOUNTER UNCALIBRATED PEPE V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_space_1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.ds1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:pepe.ds1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.19p-borrelly_1_1904_y2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:plasma_stream.solar_wind::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ds1-c-pepe-2-edr-borrelly-v1.0__browserp_ds1-c-pepe-2-edr-borrelly-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Rayman, M.D., The Successful Conclusion of the Deep Space 1 Mission: Important
                   Results without a Flashy Title, 53rd International Astronautical Congress/World
                   Space Congress, Houston, TX, IAC-02-Q.5.2.03, 10-19 October, 2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.RAYMAN2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Soderblom, L.A., Comet 19P/Borrelly in Three Dimensions: Coma and Nucleus,
                   AGU Fall Meeting 2002, abstract #P22D-12, 2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SODERBLOM2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DS1-C-PEPE-2-EDR-BORRELLY-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DEEP SPACE 1 19P/BORRELLY ENCOUNTER UNCALIBRATED PEPE V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2003-03-08</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2001-09-19T15:55Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2001-09-23T10:44Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. FRANK A. CRARY</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Young, D.T., F.J. Crary and J. Hanley, DEEP SPACE 1 19P/BORRELLY
            ENCOUNTER UNCALIBRATED PEPE V1.0, DS1-C-PEPE-2-EDR-BORRELLY-V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 2005.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains ion and electron flux as a function of
            energy and angle, and ion composition data acquired during the
            Deep Space 1 encounter with comet 19P/Borrelly. The data are
            uncalibrated and provided in spacecraft coordinates.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains ion and electron flux, as a function of
            energy and angle, and ion time of flight measurements of ion
            composition. These data were measured by the Plasma Instrument
            for Planetary Exploration (PEPE) on the Deep Space 1 (DS1)
            spacecraft during the DS1 encounter with comet 19P/Borrelly. PEPE
            measured particles from 8 eV to 31.5 keV and over a 2.8 pi sr
            range of angles. These data were acquired in order to
            characterize the interaction between the solar wind and a
            moderately active comet, including but not limited to the slowing
            and heating of the mass-loaded solar wind, the composition,
            abundance and velocity distribution of cometary heavy ions, the
            location and properties of boundaries such as bow shocks and the
            cometopause, and changes in the charge state of solar wind heavy
            ions caused by charge transfer reactions with the neutral coma.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
 
      *** NOTE WELL: The data supplier and producer failed to meet
      ***            his archiving obligation with these data, in
      ***            that a large number of science content problems
      *** identified in the peer review held October 2003 were still
      *** unresolved two years later, when the data were submitted
      *** for archiving.  Potential users should read the text of
      *** the CONFIDENCE_LEVEL_NOTE carefully, and see the list of
      *** unresolved problems in the &apos;liens_outstanding.txt&apos; file
      *** included in the documentation for this data set.
 
      This data set contains ion and electron flux, as a function of
      energy and angle, and ion time of flight measurements of ion
      composition. These data were measured by the Plasma Instrument
      for Planetary Exploration (PEPE) on the Deep Space 1 (DS1)
      spacecraft during the DS1 encounter with comet 19P/Borrelly.
      PEPE measured particles from 8 eV to 31.5 keV and over a 2.8 pi
      sr range of angles. These data were acquired in order to
      characterize the interaction between the solar wind and a
      moderately active comet, including but not limited to the slowing
      and heating of the mass-loaded solar wind, the composition,
      abundance and velocity distribution of cometary heavy ions, the
      location and properties of boundaries such as bow shocks and the
      cometopause, and changes in the charge state of solar wind heavy
      ions caused by charge transfer reactions with the neutral coma.
 
      19P/Borrelly is a Jupiter family comet with an orbital period of
      6.86 years. Earth-based spectra have identified Borrelly as
      depleted in C2 and C3 relative to 1P/Halley, and is the
      type-example of a class of comets which are C2 and C3 depleted,
      but not significantly depleted in CN. The DS1
      encounter occurred on September 22, 2001 (day of year 265), at
      a distance of 1.36 astronomical units from the Sun. At that time,
      Borrelly was eight days past perihelion and had, based on
      several Earth-based observations, a production rate of 3.5x10E28
      molecules per second. Compared to other comets encountered by
      spacecraft, this is a factor of 20 to 30 less than 1P/Halley,
      comparable to 21P/Giacobinni-Zinner, and four times higher than
      26P/Grigg-Skjellerup [SODERBLOM2002]
 
      The spacecraft trajectory during the encounter was nearly north-
      south due to the comet&apos;s 30.3 degree inclination. Closest
      approach occurred at 2001-265T22:29:32, spacecraft event time and
      at a range of 2171.4 km from the nucleus. Closest approach was
      near the comet-Sun line, at a phase angle of 4.2 degrees. At the
      time of closest approach, the spacecraft&apos;s position and velocity
      relative to the nucleus were (-693.6,-1866.7,-865.5) km and
      (2.40,6.17,-15.21) km/s in J2000 coordinates, and a unit vector
      pointing from the nucleus to the Sun was (-0.2535,-0.8880,
      -0.3838). The spacecraft position may be calculated by assuming
      the spacecraft velocity was constant. This approximation is
      accurate to within 150 km and 1.2E-4 time the spacecraft-comet
      range at all times within 24 hours of closest approach. More
      accurate information on the trajectory may be obtained from the
      SPICE spk kernels. During the encounter, there were numerous
      spacecraft turns, to track the nucleus, observe guide stars,
      orient the spacecraft for optimal PEPE observations on the
      outbound leg and to turn to downlink data to Earth. A more
      complete description may be found in [RAYMAN2002] and the
      exact orientation of the spacecraft may be found in the relevant
      SPICE ck kernels.
 
      Processing
      ==========
      The PEPE data have been processed by:
        (1) Extracting the raw PEPE data from the packetized telemetry
            files.
        (2) Converting data from 8-bit data numbers to 16-bit counts
            (see the Limitations section of CONFIDENCE_LEVEL_NOTE
            in this file) and conversion of housekeeping values into
            physical units.
        (3) Converting time tags from spacecraft clock time to
            spacecraft clock time, using NAIF toolkit software and
            SPICE kernels.
        (4) Reformatting data into the PDS archive format.
 
      Parameters
      ==========
 
      Data Sampling:
      PEPE data are acquired by simultaneously integrating counts in
      16 azimuthal pixels. Counts in 16 elevations and 128 energies
      are collected sequentially by stepping the voltage applied to the
      instrument&apos;s deflector plates (elevation) and electrostatic
      analyzer (ESA) plates (energy.) A complete set of elevations is
      collected at each energy, before lowering the ESA voltage to the
      next step.
 
      Offset times have been added to the data to indicate when,
      relative to the start of each measurement, a specific elevation
      and energy was sampled. However, all PEPE data products are
      collapsed by summing over a number of samples, to reduce data
      volume. The offset time gives the start of the first integration
      in the collapsed data. The following table illustrates the order
      in which samples are integrated.
 
      Table 1. PEPE Sampling Order
      -----------------------------------------------------------------
      Energy  |Elevation 0  1  2  3  4  5  6  7  8  9 10 11 12 13 14 15
      -----------------------------------------------------------------
      0       |          0  1  2  3  4  5  6  7  8  9 10 11 12 13 14 15
      1       |         16 17 18 19 20 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28 29 30 31
      2       |         32 33 34 35 36 37 38 39 40 41 42 43 44 45 46 47
      3       |         48 49 50 51 52 53 54 55 56 57 58 59 60 61 62 63
      ...     |         ...
      -----------------------------------------------------------------
 
      In, for example, the electron (ELC) data, samples are collapsed
      by summing together blocks of four elevations and two energies.
      One collapsed value would be the sum of elevations 0 to 3 and
      energies 0 and 1 are summed. I.e. the 0th, 1st, 2nd, 3rd, 16th,
      17th, 18th and 19th samples measured by the instrument. The
      offset time in the data would be the time of the start of the
      0th integration. The offsets in the ion &apos;singles&apos; and
      &apos;logicals&apos; are similarly affected by collapsing the data.
 
      Data collapse and integration times:
      The instrument&apos;s data rate is controlled by (1) changing the
      method of collapsing data and (2) varying the integration time
      at each elevation and energy. During the Borrelly encounter, only
      one collapse mode was used. PEPE was operated at two data rates
      during the encounter. From the start of the observations until
      2001-265T10:23:05, the instrument was in a 50 bps mode, with an
      integration time of 572.4 ms, requiring 1302 seconds per full
      measurement. After 2001-265T10:23:05, the PEPE was operated in a
      1 kbps mode, with an integration time of 28.62 ms, requiring 65.5
      seconds per full measurement.
 
      Energy range:
      During the Borrelly encounter, PEPE used one of two look up tables
      to determine the range of energies sampled. The number of energy
      steps per measurement was the same in both energy tables. The
      spacecraft&apos;s ion propulsion system (IPS) produces a extremely
      high flux of low energy, heavy ions. For instrument health
      reasons, PEPE did not sample energies below 15 eV when the IPS was
      on. Instead, the instrument&apos;s ESA was set to zero volts for these
      energy steps. When the IPS was off, the ESA was set to zero for
      the final 1/16 of the energy steps, providing data on energies
      down to 8 eV as well as background measurement. The following
      table gives the times at which these energy tables were used.
 
      Table 2. PEPE Energy Table Use
      ------------------------------------------------------------------
      Start time     End time       Energy Table
 
      2001-262T15:55 2001-265T10:23 IPS blocked
      2001-265T10:23 2001-265T11:27 Full range
      2001-265T11:27 2001-265T12:25 IPS blocked
      2001-265T12:25 2001-266T00:20 Full range
      2001-266T00:20 2001-266T10:44 IPS blocked
 
      Data
      ====
      The PEPE data consist of seven data products, each archived in
      separate files. These products are electron spectra, selected
      housekeeping values, ion &apos;singles&apos; spectra, ion &apos;logicals&apos;
      spectra, ion &apos;mass over charge&apos; spectra and ion time-of-flight
      mass spectra. The contents of these products is described below.
      Each file contains all measurements with a start time on the
      specified day. File names are of the form xxxyyddd.dat where
        xxx     = elc Electron data
                  hsk Housekeeping data
                  ion Ion singles data
                  log Ion logicals data
                  mq  Ion mass over charge data
                  tof Ion time of flight data
        yy      = 01  Year
        ddd     =     Day of year
        _t      =     A=ASCII, B=binary
 
      The PEPE data are obtained by integrating counts at 16 azimuths,
      16 elevations and 128 energies. The full volume of data produced
      by the instrument exceeds the maximum, 1 kbps rate at which the
      spacecraft collects data. Azimuth/elevation/energy samples are
      collapsed within the instrument to fit within this limit. In the
      archived data files, azimuth, elevation and energy steps always
      refer to the collapsed data products, not the full 16x16x128
      range collected within the instrument.
 
      All data products use the same collapse in energy, from 128 to
      64 steps. Each uncollapsed energy step is centered on an energy
      of 32675*(4096**(-N/119)) eV. The following table gives the
      conversion between collapsed energy step number and the observed
      particle energy per charge.
 
      Table 3. Energy step number and
      ------------------------------------------------------------------
      Energy  Energy   Note
      Step    [eV]
      ------------------------------------------------------------------
      0       31572.1
      1       27453.1
      2       23871.5
      3       20757.1
      4       18049.1
      5       15694.3
      6       13646.8
      7       11866.4
      8       10318.3
      9        8972.1
      10       7801.6
      11       6783.8
      12       5898.7
      13       5129.2
      14       4460.0
      15       3878.1
      16       3372.2
      17       2932.2
      18       2549.7
      19       2217.1
      20       1927.8
      21       1676.3
      22       1457.6
      23       1267.4
      24       1102.1
      25        958.3
      26        833.3
      27        724.6
      28        630.0
      29        547.8
      30        476.4
      31        414.2
      32        360.2
      33        313.2
      34        272.3
      35        236.8
      36        205.9
      37        179.0
      38        155.7
      39        135.4
      40        117.7
      41        102.4
      42         89.0
      43         77.4
      44         67.3
      45         58.5
      46         50.9
      47         44.2
      48         38.5
      49         33.5
      50         29.1
      51         25.3
      52         22.0
      53         19.1
      54         16.6
      55         14.5  0 eV in IPS blocked energy table
      56         12.6  0 eV in IPS blocked energy table
      57         10.9  0 eV in IPS blocked energy table
      58          9.5  0 eV in IPS blocked energy table
      59          8.3  0 eV in IPS blocked energy table
      60          0.0
      61          0.0
      62          0.0
      63          0.0
 
      Electron Spectra:
      These data are the counts of electrons, in four azimuthal, four
      elevation and 64 energy bins. These bins are
 
      Table 4. Electron Azimuths
      --------------------------------------------
      Azimuth number  Minimum angle  Maximum angle
      --------------------------------------------
      0                 0             90
      1                90            180
      2               180            270
      3               270            360
 
      Table 5. Electron Elevations
      ----------------------------------------------
      Elevation number  Minimum angle  Maximum angle
      ----------------------------------------------
      0                 -45            -22.5
      1                 -22.5            0
      2                   0             22.5
      3                  22.5           45
 
      Selected housekeeping data:
      TBS
 
      Ion Singles:
      These data are counts of ions, measured in the time-of-flight
      system&apos;s start detectors. These counts are accumulated
      independently of the TOF measurement, and regardless of whether
      or not the start led to a valid TOF event. This gives them a
      higher sensitivity and lower dead time than the TOF measurements
      but also a high background. These data are returned in eight
      azimuthal and eight elevation bins, and the azimuthal bins have
      a variable pixel size. Tables 6 and 7 give the angular coverage
      of these bins.
 
      Table 6. Ion Singles Azimuths
      --------------------------------------------------------
      Azimuth number  Minimum angle  Maximum angle  Width
      --------------------------------------------------------
      0               340            350            10
      1               350            360            10
      2                 0             10            10
      3                10             20            10
      4                22.5           67.5          45
      5                67.5          157.5          90
      6               157.5          247.5          90
      7               247.5          340            90
 
      Table 7. Ion Singles Elevations
      ----------------------------------------------
      Elevation number  Minimum angle  Maximum angle
      ----------------------------------------------
      0                  45             33.75
      1                  33.75          22.5
      2                  22.5           11.25
      3                  11.25           0
      4                   0            -11.25
      5                 -11.25         -22.5
      6                 -22.5          -33.75
      7                 -33.75         -45
 
      Ion Logicals:
      These data are counts of various single events. The PEPE TOF
      system uses these events to start and stop TOF measurements and
      to determine if a TOF event is valid. Ion logicals are primarily
      used to diagnose the performance of the TOF system, and to provide
      additional data for dead time corrections. These data are not
      azimuthally resolved and are collapsed into two elevations:
 
      Table 7: Ion Logical Elevations
      -----------------------------------------------
      Elevation number  Minimum angle  Maximum angle
      ----------------------------------------------
      0                  45              0
      1                   0            -45
 
      The logicals are:
        Coarse starts: All start counts measured in the coarse azimuth
                       pixels, AZ 4-7 (whether or not the start resulted
                       in a valid TOF event).
        Fine starts:   All start counts measured in the fine azimuth
                       pixels, AZ 0-3 (whether or not the start resulted
                       in a valid TOF event).
        Stops:         All stop counts, whether or not they were
                       preceded by a start event.
        Resets:        All start events which reset, i.e. which were not
                       followed by a stop event within 1536 ns.
 
      Ion Mass-Charge Ratio:
      These data are counts of TOF events, selected on the basis of
      their time-of-flight (i.e. all events with a TOF in a specified
      range.) This largely (but not entirely) separates the data
      into energy spectra of species with a mass to charge ratio within
      a specific range. The TOF bins were selected so that MQ bin 0
      would contain exclusively protons, MQ bin 1 would contain
      primarily He++, and so that the remaining 13 bins would span
      the TOF range with logarithmic widths. These data are collapsed
      over all azimuths and elevations. The TOF bins used are:
 
      Table 8. MQ Bins
      ---------------------------------------------------------
      MQ number  Minimum TOF  Maximum TOF
       0           48            88
       1           89           105
       2          106           125
       3          126           150
       4          151           179
       5          180           214
       6          215           256
       7          257           307
       8          308           367
       9          368           438
      10          439           524
      11          525           627
      12          628           750
      13          751           896
      14          897          1071
 
      Ion Time of Flight:
      These data are time-of-flight mass spectra, summed over all
      energies, elevations and azimuths. TOF bins 48 to 1071 were
      returned in these data. The ions&apos; time-of-flight is nominally
      0.75 ns * TOF bin number. Post-launch experiments with the PEPE
      prototype were more consistent with 0.82 ns * TOF bin number.
      The path length between the start foil and the stop detector is
      81.4 mm.
 
      Ancillary Data
      ==============
      No ancillary data are included in this data set.
 
      Coordinate Systems
      ==================
      DS1 spacecraft coordinates are defined so that the +Z axis is
      is aligned with the IPS direction of thrust and the boresight of
      MICAS (Miniature Integrated Camera And Spectrometer) instrument.
      The spacecraft&apos;s high gain antenna and the PEPE instrument&apos;s
      direction of zero elevation and azimuth are aligned with the
      +X axis. The spacecraft&apos;s solar arrays are extend along the Y
      axis.
 
      The PEPE data are binned by instrument elevation and azimuth. In
      spacecraft coordinates, a unit vector in the direction azimuth (a),
      elevation (e) is {cos(a)*cos(e),sin(e),sin(a)*cos(e)}.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      Review
      ======
 
      These data have been reviewed by the instrument team and are of
      the highest quality that can be generated at this time. Science
      results based on some of these data have been submitted to several
      journals (GRL and Icarus).
 
      External Peer Review - CAUTION
      ==============================
      The PDS external peer review for these data was held in October 2003.
      A number of liens were placed on the data based on the science content
      and, in particular, aspects of the documentation.  After two years many
      of these liens remain either unresolved by the data preparer, or of
      uncertain status. The decision was made to archive these data anyway
      in October of 2005, with the list of liens included as part of the
      data set documentation.
 
      In addition, the text above, describing the data set, and the text
      in the instrument catalog file both contained several references to
      apparently non-existent publications.  These references have been
      removed.  The YOUNGETINPRESS reference which remains has yet to be
      published as of this writing (October 2005) and consequently is also
      suspect, but has been left in place.
 
      In the event that a fully corrected and documented version of these
      data are ever received, it will be archived as Version 2 of this data
      set.
 
 
      Data Coverage and Quality
      =========================
      These data contain several, brief gaps. Most are associated with
      instrument mode (integration time) or energy sweep change. Table
      M gives the start and end times of these gaps.
 
      Table M. Gaps in coverage
      ------------------------------------------------------------------
      Start time          End time
      ------------------------------------------------------------------
      2001-264T00:51:03   2001-264T06:16:41
      2001-264T17:29:39   2001-264T17:51:22
      2001-265T10:08:14   2001-265T10:23:04
      2001-265T11:27:07   2001-265T11:30:04
      2001-265T12:25:26   2001-265T12:28:04
      2001-266T00:20:11   2001-266T00:22:28
 
      In addition, there are two measurements with missing MQ, logical
      and TOF products. These are the measurements with start times
      at 2001-265T07:14:36 and 2001-265T10:32:52.
 
      Limitations
      ===========
      To reduce data volume, counts as measured on spacecraft are
      converted from 16-bit to 8-bit integers. This mapping is linear
      for low values and approximate logarithmic at high count rates.
      The data numbers are converted back into 16-bit integers on the
      ground. This introduces an approximately -0 to +3 percent
      uncertainty in the actual number of counts. Users of these data
      should assume an uncertainty of sqrt(N + 0.015*N**2) rather than
      the usual, statistical uncertainty of sqrt(N).
 
      The PEPE time-of-flight spectra are subject to repeated pattern
      noise. The instrument computes time of flight using a clock with
      12 nanosecond ticks and an electronic vernier which provides 16,
      approximately 0.75 picosecond sub-ticks within each clock cycle.
      Due to irregularities in the
      electronic vernier, the time-of-flight spectra contain repeated
      pattern noise, with a 16 bin period.
 
      The electron measurements contain a high background at energies
      above approximately 3 keV. The cause of this background is not
      completely understood, but is related to solar UV photons reaching
      the electron detector. All electron data above 3 keV should be
      considered suspect.
 
      TOF run at 11 kV not 8 or 15 (calibration, low + ion yield,
      high scattering) electrons with IPS on (s/c potential) TOF
      background with IPS on.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SAFED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

