<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-e-v-h-grns-3-grs-cdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER E/V/H GRNS 3 GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER CALIBDATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:grs.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-grns-3-grs-cdr-v1.0__browserp_mess-e-v-h-grns-3-grs-cdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-grns-3-grs-cdr-v1.0__browser_mess-e-v-h-grns-3-grs-cdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-grns-3-grs-cdr-v1.0__dvo_mess-e-v-h-grns-3-grs-cdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Goldsten, J.O., E.A. Rhodes,, W.V. Boynton, W.C. Feldman, D.J. Lawrence, J.I.
                   Trombka, D.M. Smith, L.G. Evans, J. White, N.W. Madden, P.C. Berg, G.A. Murphy,
                   R.S. Gurnee, K. Strohbehn, B.D. Williams, E.D. Schaefer, C.A. Monaco, C.P.
                   Cork, J.D. Eckels, W.O. Miller, M.T. Burks, L.B. Hagler, S.J. Deteresa, and
                   M.C. Witte, The MESSENGER Gamma-Ray and Neutron Spectrometer, Space Science
                   Reviews, 131, 339-391, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GOLDSTENETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-E/V/H-GRNS-3-GRS-CDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESSENGER E/V/H GRNS 3 GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER CALIBDATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-05-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-08-12T22:01:55Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-04-30T14:24:17Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>PATRICK PEPLOWSKI</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            E. A. Rhodes (APL), MESSENGER E/V/H GRNS 3 GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER
            CALIBDATA V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2010.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The MESSENGER GRS calibrated/reduced observations consist of
            science and instrument data collected by the GRS sensor.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== This data set consists of the MESSENGER GRS
            calibrated observations (CDRs) and the reduced data product
            (RDR). The GRS experiment is a gamma ray spectrometer designed to
            observe spectra of gamma rays emitted from Mercury&apos;s surface
            in the energy range from 0.1 to 10 MeV. There are seven basic GRS
            CDR data products: the Ge raw spectra data (GRS_CAL_RAW), the
            anti-coincidence spectra data (GRS_CAL_AC), the shield spectra
            data (GRS_CAL_SH, GRS_CAL_SH2, GRS_CAL_SH3), the shield count
            rate (GRS_CAL_SCR) and the engineering data (GRS_ENG). There is
            one GRS RDR product (GRS_RDR_SUM), a spectral sum of the
            GRS_CAL_RAW and GRS_CAL_AC spectra.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
   Data Set Overview
   =================
     This data set consists of the MESSENGER GRS calibrated
     observations, also known as CDRs, and the GRS reduced data known
     as RDRs. There are seven standard CDR data products associated
     with the GRS sensor. A single CDR data file contains the
     observations with a time tag corresponding to a given Earth day.
     There are seven CDR data product files: one engineering file, one
     count rate file, and five spectra files. The engineering files
     contain selected relevant data from the EDR status files,
     converted to calibrated physical units. The shield count rate
     files contain summed total event rates in the anti-coincidence
     shield at 10-ms integration cadence. In addition to the spectra,
     the spectra files contain spacecraft navigation and attitude data
     derived from SPICE files, that are relevant to the GRS, as well
     as selected engineering data relevant to the GRS. The raw
     spectrum files contain Ge raw spectra and counter data, the
     anticoincidence spectrum files contain Ge anticoincidence spectra
     and counter data, and the shield spectrum files (3 versions)
     contain shield spectra and counter data. There is one RDR product
     which contains the spectral sum over a one year period. These
     sums are created from the anti-coincidence and raw spectra.
 
 
   Instrument Overview
   ===================
     The GRS detector is a high-resolution coaxial germanium crystal
     50 mm in diameter and 50 mm in length, chosen for its radiation
     damage resistance and annealing capabilities. The detector is
     rigidly clamped in a hermetically sealed Al capsule pressurized
     with clean, dry nitrogen. The capsule is cooled to an operating
     temperature in the 80-95 K range by a mechanical cryocooler. A
     plastic scintillator anti-coincidence shield surrounds the
     germanium detector in its sides and back, for rejection of
     cosmic-ray background. Galactic cosmic rays continuously bombard
     the surface of Mercury, and through interactions with the
     surface, gamma-rays of discrete energies that are characteristic
     of specific elements are created. A fraction of these gamma-rays,
     as well as those from the decay of radiogenic elements escape
     from the surface, where they can be detected by the orbiting GRS.
     Gamma-ray fluxes are measurable at altitudes up to 1000 km and
     for gamma-rays up to about 10 MeV that emanate from depths of up
     to tens of centimeter beneath the surface. Detected fluxes are
     generally low and require numerous orbital passes over a specific
     region to obtain a statistically well-defined energy spectrum.
     The measurements of elements such as Fe, Si, Mg, Ca, Ti, K and Th
     by GRS will provide insight into distinguishing between different
     formation models for Mercury as well as other planetary evolution
     issues.
 
     See the INSTRUMENT.CAT file for more information and
     [GOLDSTENETAL2007] for full details.
 
 
   Calibration Overview
   ====================
     This data set is calibrated; it provides the calibrated GRS
     sensor measurements. Raw engineering units have been converted to
     calibrated physical units. Where the unit value depends on
     temperature, temperature corrections based on flight and ground
     data were performed. The Ge raw and anticoincidence spectra have
     a temperature dependence through the gain change in the
     preamplifier and shaper amplifier, which have been corrected with
     flight data. The Ge spectra have been normalized to 0.604
     keV/channel, based on strong gamma peaks in the
     temperature-corrected spectra, providing the transformation from
     counts per channel to counts per energy bin. Spectra derived from the
     anticoincidence detector are not calibrated in energy but remain as
     channel. Spacecraft navigation, attitude, and time data relevant to
     the GRS have been added to each spectral file based on calibrated
     SPICE data. There was no consideration of deadtime, detector
     efficiencies, or gamma-ray attenuation and no spatial processing.
 
 
   Parameters
   ==========
     The principal parameters when observing with the GRS are as
     follows:
 
     * Accumulation Time: The accumulation time, in seconds, of the Ge
       detector.
 
 
   Data
   ====
     There are seven standard CDR data products associated with the GRS
     sensor: the Ge raw spectra data GRS_CAL_RAW, the Ge
     anti-coincidence spectra data GRS_CAL_AC, the shield spectra data
     GRS_CAL_SH, GRS_CAL_SH2, and GRS_CAL_SH3, the shield count rate
     data GRS_CAL_SCR and the engineering data GRS_ENG. A single CDR
     data file contains the observations with a time tag corresponding
     to a given Earth day. There is one RDR product GRS_RDR_SUM
     associated with the GRS sensor: the sum of one Earth year of Ge
     raw spectra data and Ge anti-coincidence spectra data.
 
     The Ge raw spectra data file contains a set of raw spectra data
     collected from the high-purity Ge detector during a specified
     amount of time. These data are contained in 16,384 (2^14)
     channels, which can be used to create a histogram that shows the
     distribution of events (number of counts) as a function of energy
     (channel number). Because of the low count rates usually
     encountered, accumulation times of minutes to hours are normal.
     Temperature correction of the spectra shifts event energies with
     respect to channel energy bands, requiring rebinning of the
     counts fractionally among neighboring channels, so spectra counts
     are represented as floating point numbers. Spectrum Counters are
     also included, as are spacecraft navigation and attitude
     parameters relevant to the GRS and UTC time, obtained from
     calibrated SPICE data at the midpoint of the time interval.
     Selected engineering data relevant to the GRS, in calibrated
     physical units and temperature corrected as necessary, are also
     included, interpolated to the midpoint of the time interval.
 
     The Ge anti-coincidence spectra data file contains a set of
     spectra data collected from the high-purity Ge detector during a
     specified amount of time, for events not in coincidence with
     events detected in the shield. These data are contained in 16,384
     (2^14) channels, which can be used to create a histogram that
     shows the distribution of events (number of counts) as a function
     of energy channel number). Because of the low count rates usually
     encountered, accumulation times of minutes to hours are normal.
     Temperature correction of the spectra shifts event energies with
     respect to channel energy bands, requiring rebinning of the
     counts fractionally among neighboring channels, so spectra counts
     are represented as floating point numbers. Spectrum Counters are
     also included, as are spacecraft navigation and attitude
     parameters relevant to the GRS and UTC time, obtained from
     calibrated SPICE data at the midpoint of the time interval.
     Selected engineering data relevant to he GRS, in calibrated
     physical units and temperature corrected as necessary, are also
     included, interpolated to the midpoint of the time interval.
 
     The GRS shield spectra data file contains a set of spectra data
     collected from the borated-plastic shield during a specified
     amount of time. These data are contained in 1024 (2^10) channels,
     which can be used to create a histogram that shows the
     distribution of events (number of counts) as a function of energy
     (channel number). Because of the low count rates usually
     encountered, accumulation times of minutes to hours are normal.
     Spectrum Counters are also included, as are spacecraft navigation
     and attitude parameters relevant to the GRS and UTC time,
     obtained from calibrated SPICE data at the midpoint of the time
     interval. Selected engineering data relevant to the GRS, in
     calibrated physical units and temperature corrected as necessary,
     are also included, interpolated to the midpoint of the time
     interval.
 
     The GRS shield count rate data file contains are time series
     measurements of the total count rate measured by the GRS
     anti-coincidence shield, and are due to incident particles
     (primarily electrons, but also gamma-rays, protons, and
     neutrons). Each data product, which is associated with a given
     measurement time, is subdivided into 10-ms-cadence measurements
     of the count rate, which are sequentially assigned to the 16,384
     channels in the spectrum array. For short integration periods,
     this array is not filled and remaining channels are assigned
     values of zero. For longer integration times, the array is filled
     prior to the end of the data collection period and the final
     channel includes the sum of all values collected after the array
     is filled. This typically occurs when the spacecraft is far from
     Mercury, and therefore the measurements of less interest. Zeros
     at the beginning of the array correspond to an approximately
     0.5-sec-long electronics deadtime at the beginning of each run.
     This data product was created following the February 25, 2013
     flight software upload. After a commissioning phase, official
     production of the new data products commenced on March 18, 2013.
 
     The GRS engineering data file contains a set of selected
     engineering data from the GRS EDR status data relevant to the
     GRS, in calibrated engineering units, temperature corrected as
     necessary, at specified times. Included are such parameters as
     high voltages, electronics voltages and currents, preamplifier
     and shaping amplifier temperatures, Ge temperature, and
     cryocooler currents and temperature. Noise spikes in the data
     have been filtered out.
 
     The GRS summed spectra data file contains a set of spectral sums
     and ancillary information connected with the sums. There are
     four sums in each record: a sum of the Ge raw spectra data, Ge
     raw spectra corrected data, Ge anti-coincidence spectra data, and
     Ge anti-coincidence corrected spectra data. There are also
     minimum, maximum, mean and standard deviation for several
     temperature readings as well as altitude and latitude and
     longitude variations.
 
     The user is referred to the GRS CDR-RDR-DAP SIS in the DOCUMENT
     directory for details as to what types of sums are created and
     what the altitude and spatial representation are.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
   Confidence Level Overview
   =========================
     The GRS CDR/RDR data form the calibrated data set released for
     the GRS. Data presented here are as accurate a representation of
     the GRS calibrated data as possible at time of delivery. There
     may be further recalibrated deliveries of this data if needed and
     future data may require calibration changes.
 
 
   Review
   ======
     The GRS CDR/RDR SIS and data were reviewed internally by the GRS
     team prior to release to the PDS. PDS also performed an external
     review of the GRS CDR/RDR. The CDR/RDR data are based on the
     uncalibrated EDR data and the calibrated data, which have been
     previously reviewed, and GRS science spectra have been analyzed
     based on the EDR data. However, GRS science analysis based on
     this CDR/RDR data has not yet taken place; when this occurs, it
     may be found that a new release of these CDR/RDR data, possibly
     recalibrated, is needed.
 
 
   Data Coverage and Quality
   =========================
     Data reported are the calibrated data received from the
     spacecraft during the the following mission phases: Launch,
     Earth Cruise, Earth Flyby, Venus 1 Cruise, Venus 1 Flyby,
     Venus 2 Cruise, Venus 2 Flyby, Mercury 1 Cruise, Mercury 1 Flyby,
     Mercury 2 Cruise, Mercury 2 Flyby, Mercury 3 Cruise,
     Mercury 3 Flyby, Mercury 4 Cruise, Mercury Orbit, Mercury
     Orbit Year 2, Mercury Orbit Year 3, Mercury Orbit Year 4, and
     Mercury Orbit Year 5. These mission phases are defined as:
 
                           Start time         End time
     Phase Name            Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)
     -------------------   -----------------  -----------------
     Launch                03 Aug 2004 (216)  12 Sep 2004 (256)
     Earth Cruise          13 Sep 2004 (257)  18 Jul 2005 (199)
     Earth Flyby           19 Jul 2005 (200)  16 Aug 2005 (228)
     Venus 1 Cruise        17 Aug 2005 (229)  09 Oct 2006 (282)
     Venus 1 Flyby         10 Oct 2006 (283)  07 Nov 2006 (311)
     Venus 2 Cruise        08 Nov 2006 (312)  22 May 2007 (142)
     Venus 2 Flyby         23 May 2007 (143)  20 Jun 2007 (171)
     Mercury 1 Cruise      21 Jun 2007 (172)  30 Dec 2007 (364)
     Mercury 1 Flyby       31 Dec 2007 (365)  28 Jan 2008 (028)
     Mercury 2 Cruise      29 Jan 2008 (029)  21 Sep 2008 (265)
     Mercury 2 Flyby       22 Sep 2008 (266)  20 Oct 2008 (294)
     Mercury 3 Cruise      21 Oct 2008 (295)  15 Sep 2009 (258)
     Mercury 3 Flyby       16 Sep 2009 (259)  14 Oct 2009 (287)
     Mercury 4 Cruise      15 Oct 2009 (288)  03 Mar 2011 (062)
     Mercury Orbit         04 Mar 2011 (063)  17 Mar 2012 (077)
     Mercury Orbit Year 2  18 Mar 2012 (078)  17 Mar 2013 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 3  18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 4  18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 5  18 Mar 2015 (077)  30 Apr 2015 (120)
 
     These specific operational periods in relation to the mission
     phases were:
 
                           Start time         End time
     Phase Name            Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)         Sensor
     --------------------  -----------------  -----------------  ------
     Launch                12 Aug 2004 (225)  13 Aug 2004 (226)
     Earth Cruise          10 Nov 2004 (315)  16 Nov 2004 (321)   Ge
     Earth Flyby           No Data
     Venus 1 Cruise        No Data
     Venus 1 Flyby         No Data
     Venus 2 Cruise        27 Mar 2007 (088)  30 Mar 2007 (089)   shield
     Venus 2 Flyby         04 Jun 2007 (155)  08 Jun 2007 (159)   shield
     Mercury 1 Cruise      26 Sep 2007 (269)  29 Sep 2007 (272)   shield
     Mercury 1 Flyby       05 Jan 2008 (005)  15 Jan 2008 (015)   shield
     Mercury 1 Flyby       13 Jan 2008 (013)  15 Jan 2008 (015)   Ge
     Mercury 2 Cruise      No Data
     Mercury 2 Flyby       03 Oct 2008 (277)  06 Oct 2008 (280)   shield
     Mercury 2 Flyby       04 Oct 2008 (278)  06 Oct 2008 (280)   Ge
     Mercury 3 Cruise      24 Sep 2009 (267)  27 Sep 2009 (270)   shield
     Mercury 3 Flyby       28 Sep 2009 (271)  06 Oct 2009 (279)   Ge
     Mercury 4 Cruise      02 Apr 2010 (092)  12 Apr 2010 (102)   shield
     Mercury 4 Cruise      13 Apr 2010 (103)  15 Apr 2010 (105)   Ge
     Mercury 4 Cruise      17 Sep 2010 (260)  24 Sep 2010 (267)   shield
     Mercury Orbit         23 Mar 2011 (082)  03 Jun 2011 (154)   Ge
     Mercury Orbit         11 Jun 2011 (162)  14 Jun 2011 (165)   Ge
     Mercury Orbit         16 Jun 2011 (167)  05 Jul 2011 (186)   Ge
     Mercury Orbit         20 Jul 2011 (201)  25 Jul 2011 (206)   Ge
     Mercury Orbit         28 Jul 2011 (209)  06 Sep 2011 (249)   Ge
     Mercury Orbit         08 Sep 2011 (251)  17 Sep 2011 (260)   Ge
     Mercury Orbit Year 2  18 Mar 2012 (078)  15 Jun 2012 (167)   shield
     Mercury Orbit Year 3  18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)   shield
     Mercury Orbit Year 4  18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)   shield
     Mercury Orbit Year 5  18 Mar 2015 (077)  30 Apr 2015 (120)   shield
 
     In this list, &apos;shield&apos; means shield only and &apos;Ge&apos; means Ge and
     shield. The GRS operational mode during most of the flyby time
     periods was a &apos;sleep mode&apos; during which an operational heater
     maintained the cryocooler temperature at a constant value (to
     avoid temperature cycling of the cryocooler He seals) and the
     remainder of the instrument was shut down. Status data are
     continuously collected in this mode. Cryocooler exercises were
     conducted approximately every 6 months, but this is of
     engineering interest only.
 
     Data from the cryocooled GRS high-resolution Ge detector were
     collected only during the full functional test in November 2004
     and during the Mercury flybys in January and October 2008 and
     September-October 2009. This limitation preserves the lifetime of
     the limited-life cryocooler.
 
     Data from the borated plastic shield were collected as part of a
     periodic cryocooler exercise; for the Venus-2 flyby (as another
     neutron detector to aid the NS); during the Mercury 1 Cruise in
     September 2007; for the Mercury 1, 2, and 3 Flybys.
 
     A nonscience &apos;aliveness&apos; test was conducted in August 2004.
 
     The Ge detector energy resolution was somewhat degraded during
     Mercury Flyby 1 due to crystal displacement damage by cosmic
     rays, despite a 3-day anneal at 84C prior to the Flyby. To
     improve energy resolution for Flyby 2, the detector was kept at
     room temperature in July through mid-September in &apos;hot zombie&apos;
     mode (no communication with the DPU to reduce memory usage and
     avoid upset events from cosmic rays). Then a 14-day anneal at 84C
     was conducted. After this, energy resolution was improved to
     nearly that found in the first cruise test shortly after launch.
 
     During Mercury Flyby 3, the GRS data were collected only up to
     approximately 6 minutes before closest approach, at approximately
     661 km altitude, due to a S/C safing that occurred. The GRS was
     restarted once the S/C was promoted to operation, but the S/C was
     far from the planet by this time. It is estimated that only
     approximately 18 percent of the signal counts from the planet
     were obtained below 2500 km altitude, compared to previous
     flybys. After the Ge detector recooled to operational
     temperature, engineering tests were run involving Ge temperature
     and high-voltage changes.
 
     The shield was operated during May 2009 for some engineering
     tests. Otherwise the GRS operational mode during the Mercury 3
     Cruise was &apos;warm zombie&apos; mode, which performs a relatively low
     temperature Ge anneal to reduce radiation damage. Also the
     operational heater maintains the cryocooler temperature, to avoid
     cycling of the cryocooler He seals. On September 2 2009, the GRS
     was brought out of warm zombie mode and a 3-day Ge anneal at 84C
     was then performed. After this anneal the Ge energy resolution
     appeared to be close to that obtained for Mercury Flyby 2.
 
     During Mercury 4 Cruise, the GRS remained in warm zombie mode,
     except the shield was on for some spectral tests on shield-only
     data and the Ge detector and shield were on for some spectra
     tests on coincidence spectra between the shield and and the Ge
     detector.
 
     Just before orbit insertion, the GRS was brought out of warm
     zombie mode, and the Ge crystal was annealed for 7 days at 84C.
     After a few days of orbital operations the Ge energy resolution
     was measured to be close to the same value obtained for the M3
     flyby. S/C temperatures were somewhat higher than expected during
     orbital operations, but the GRS cryocooler was able to cool the
     Ge detector easily.
 
     During orbital operation, the GRS remained on continuously,
     except for periods when the high voltage was down, for various
     reasons, including an X-class SPE (Solar Particle Event) that
     safed the detector, OCMs (Orbital Correction Maneuvers), and
     cryocooler temperature setpoint changes. Periods having
     conditions that lead to broad energy resolution, such as
     radiation damage revealed by a Ge temperature increase or large
     very low-energy noise, have also been removed. Not shown in the
     table of operational periods are periods of SPEs that did not
     safe the detector: SPE2 08-02-2011, SPE3 08-04/05-2011,
     SPE4 08-09-2011, and SPE5 09-08/09-2011. These time periods
     should probably be eliminated from analysis, due to count-rate
     saturation and strong activation of gamma-ray peaks.
 
     Beginning on 11 October, 2011, the HPGe detector began
     registering anomalous counts in the low-energy (&lt; 300 keV)
     portion of the spectrum. While these events are lower in energy
     than the gamma-ray photopeaks of interest, the resulting count
     rate during these periods is sufficiently high to degrade the
     energy resolution for the detection of all gamma rays, regardless
     of energy. The magnitude of the anomalous counts and
     corresponding degradation of the energy resolution varies, and
     all data acquired after 11 October, 2011 should be carefully
     evaluated for its energy resolution prior to analysis. Particular
     care should be taken prior to summing individual gamma-ray
     spectra with differing energy resolution to produce summed
     spectra for analysis.
 
     The GRS operated in anomalous count rate mode for the remainder
     of its life. The high voltage (HV) was maintained at its nominal
     value of 3200 V until 18 November, 2011, when it was lowered to
     2700 V. It returned to 3200 V on 21 November, 2011, which was
     followed by a change to 2400 V. These changes were implemented in
     an attempt to maintain the highest possible energy resolution in
     the presence of the increased leakage current.
 
     A short detector annealing activity took place from 15 December,
     2011 to 21 December, 2011. This was followed by the arrival of an
     energetic solar particle event on 26 December, 2011 to
     27 December, 2011.
 
     A detector annealing activity took place from 19 March, 2012 to
     29 March, 2012. Following this activity the detector leakage
     current was observed to have increased significantly with a
     corresponding degradation in the leakage current.
 
     From 30 March, 2012 to 11 April, 2012, the detector high voltage
     value was varied between 1500 to 2400 V to characterize the
     energy resolution of the system as a function of high voltage.
 
     A detector annealing activity took place from 11 April, 2012 to
     28 April, 2012. Following this activity, the detector was
     operated at 2400 V.
 
     In an attempt to preserve the limited lifetime of the GRS
     cryocooler, the detector was kept warm from 5 May 2012 to
     1 June 2012. This time period corresponded to a time of elevated
     spacecraft temperatures. On 8 June, 2012 a week long detector
     annealing activity began.
 
     On 15 June, 2012, the GRS cryocooler failed after approximately
     9,500 hours of operation. This compares favorably to the 8,000
     hour mean lifetime for these coolers. The failure occurred during
     a routine detector cool down following the 8 June 2012 annealing
     activity. Several unsuccessful attempts to revive the cooler have
     been made. Without the ability to maintain the HPGe detector at
     cryogenic temperature, gamma-ray measurements are not possible.
     No Germanium data collected after June 15, 2012 will be supplied
     to PDS for archiving.
 
     On 25 February, 2013, new flight software was uploaded to the
     GRS. The purpose was to optimize the capability of the instrument
     to characterize neutron emission from Mercury&apos;s surface by
     changing the gain of the shield spectrum. Additionally, a new
     data product was added (SCR), which produces 10-ms cadence
     measurements of the total shield count rate. Because the shield
     responds to charged particles, these measurements represent the
     highest time cadence samples of the energetic charged particle
     environment around Mercury. The first several weeks were devoted
     to parameter optimization, with official data collection
     beginning on 18 March, 2013. Following the software upload, CDR
     creation was handled by APL instead of the University of Arizona,
     and the format of the shield products changed (SH3). See the
     CDR-RDR-DAP SIS in the DOCUMENT directory for details.
 
     Beginning on 9 September, 2014, a new data operations mode was
     implemented in which the SHI data is acquired at a higher time
     cadence when MESSENGER is within 500 km altitude of Mercury.
     During these periods, SCR data collection is temporarily
     suspended. his operational cadence lasted until the end of the
     mission.
 
     In order to reduce the load on the spacecraft solid state
     recorder, GRS FPGA data collection was suspended on DOY 2015 092
     through the end of the mission. In addition, the GRS Software
     Counters (SWC) were collected at a reduced cadence from
     DOY 2015 069 until the end of the mission. This necessitated a
     need to interpolate SWC-derived housekeeping values in the EDRs
     from this date. This includes the &apos;DEADTIME_FRAC&apos; and
     &apos;SHIELD_CHG_RSET&apos; values in SH3 and SCR.
 
     Periods of elevated count rates resulting from
     spacecraft-incident SPE events includes data collected on:
 
     3-11 June, 2011;
     2 August, 2011;
     4-5 August, 2011;
     9 August, 2011;
     6 September, 2011;
     7 September, 2011;
     8 September, 2011;
     22-23 September, 2011;
     4-6 October, 2011;
     14 October, 2011;
     17 October, 2011;
     3-5 November, 2011;
     8-10 November, 2011;
     17-18 November, 2011;
     19-21 November, 2011;
     23 January - 3 Feburary, 2012;
     3 March, 2012;
 
     Post-January 2012 flares are difficult to isolate in the
     count-rate anomaly compromised dataset. Care should be used when
     utilizing these data as they may also contain gamma-ray
     detections resulting from prompt and/or long-lived activation
     products. The count rate anomaly issue does not apply to data
     collected following the 25 February, 2013 flight software upload.
 
     For measurements taken following the 25 February, 2013 software
     upload, the following times included data compromised by SPEs:
 
     15-16 March, 2013;
     11-12 April, 2013;
     21-22 April, 2013;
     13-14 May, 2013;
     31 May - 1 June, 2013;
     21-24 June, 2013;
     19 August - 9 September, 2013;
     30 September - 2 October, 2013;
     5-7 October, 2013;
     11-15 October, 2013;
     22-23 October, 2013;
     25-30 October, 2013;
     4-10 November, 2013;
     19-21 November, 2013;
     29 November - 1 December, 2013;
     13-16 December, 2013;
     25-28 December, 2013;
     6-13 January, 2014;
     22-23 January, 2014;
     27-31 January, 2014;
     10-15 February, 2014;
     17-21 February, 2014;
     24 February - 8 March, 2014;
     12-14 March, 2014;
     24-25 April, 2014;
     5-6 May, 2014;
     4-6 June, 2014;
     11 June, 2014;
     12-13 June, 2014;
     17 June, 2014;
     8-9 August, 2014;
     1 September - 1 October, 2014;
     14-19 October, 2014;
     20-22 October, 2014;
     26 October, 2014;
     27 October, 2014;
     29-30 October, 2014;
     1 November;
     3-6 November, 2014;
     13-15 December, 2014;
     13-23 December, 2014;
     26-27 December, 2014;
     21 January, 2015;
     21-23 February, 2015;
     2-4 March, 2015;
     24 March - 3 April, 2015;
     4-5 April, 2015;
     13-16 April, 2015;
     28-29 April, 2015;
 
     These time periods are denoted more precisely within the archive
     via the &apos;BAD_DATA_FLAG&apos;. The degree to which science data can be
     derived from these SPE-comprised periods varies on an
     event-by-event basis.
 
     Periods with no science data, corresponding to instrument safing
     or operations activities include:
 
     4 June, 2011; (Safed)
     15 June, 2011; (HV shutdown during OCM)
     6 July, 2011; (HV off)
     12-20 July, 2011; (GRS Annealing)
     26 July, 2011; (HV shutdown during OCM)
     7 September, 2011; (HV shutdown during OCM)
     24 October, 2011; (HV shutdown during OCM)
     8 November, 2011; (HV off)
     4-6 December, 2011; (Instrument Safing)
     15-20 December, 2011; (Detector Annealing)
     2-12 March, 2012; (HV shutdown during OCM)
     24-25 April, 2013; (HV shutdown during OCM)
     21-24 June, 2013; (Instrument Safing due to SPE)
     19-22 August, 2013; (Instrument Safing due to SPE)
     25-30 October, 2013; (Instrument Safing due to SPE)
     25-28 December, 2013; (Instrument Safing due to SPE)
     17 June, 2014; (HV shutdown during OCM)
     1-3 September, 2014; (Instrument Safing due to SPE)
     10-12 September, 2014; (Instrument Safing due to SPE)
     10-11 September, 2014; (Instrument Safing due to SPE)
     12 September, 2014; (HV shutdown during OCM)
     24 October, 2014; (HV shutdown during OCM)
     13-15 December, 2014; (Instrument safing due to SPE)
     20 December, 2014; (HV shutdown during OCM)
     21-22 December, 2014; (HV shutdown during OCM)
     21 January, 2015; (HV shutdown during OCM)
     24-25 March, 2015; (Instrument saying during SPE)
     27 March, 2015; (HV shutdown during OCM)
 
     These time periods are denoted more precisely within the archive via
     the &apos;BAD_DATA_FLAG&apos;.
 
     The HPGe high voltage (HV) was changed periodically from December
     2011 until 15 June 2012 to improve performance during periods of
     anomalously high count rates thought to be due to increased
     leakage current following the December 2011 annealing. The data
     are tagged via the &apos;BAD_DATA_FLAG&apos;, and its usefulness varies and
     should be evaluated carefully by the end user.
 
     Restrictions on data generation resulting from limited space on
     the spacecraft data record resulted in SCR products being
     suspended during the following periods:
 
     14 December 2013 - 2 January, 2014;
     16 January 2014 - 1 February, 2014;
 
     The latter portions of data collected on 8 and 10 April, 2015 are
     missing from the CDRs.
 
     Finally, the MESSENGER spacecraft solid state recorder filled and
     stopped recording new data during DOY 2014 360, resulting in a
     permanent ~3-hour-long data gap from approximately 14:15 to 17:38.
 
   Limitations
   ===========
     Though calibrated, this data set is based on minimally processed
     data received from the spacecraft telemetry and ingested into the
     MESSENGER Science Operations Center (SOC). No corrupted data have
     been identified for any of the GRS operational periods. A single
     data gap exists and was denoted in this document. Although there
     may be some data not identified as missing or corrupted, such
     data should be minimal and a very small fraction of the available
     data.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

