<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mro-m-crism-4-typespec-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MRO MARS CRISM 4 TYPE SPECTRA LIBRARY V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:crism.mro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-crism-4-typespec-v1.0__browserp_mro-m-crism-4-typespec-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Viviano-Beck, C.E., F.P. Seelos, S.L. Murchie, E.G. Kahn, K.D. Seelos, H.W.
                   Taylor, K. Taylor, B.L. Ehlmann, S.M. Wiseman, J.F. Mustard, and M.F. Morgan,
                   Revised CRISM Spectral Parameters and Summary Products Based on the Currently
                   Detected Mineral Diversity on Mars, J. Geophys. Res., Vol. 119, pp. 1403-1431,
                   doi:10.1002/2014JE004627, 2014.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.VIVIANO-BECKETAL2014</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MRO-M-CRISM-4-TYPESPEC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MRO MARS CRISM 4 TYPE SPECTRA LIBRARY V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2014-05-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2015-12-01</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>CHRISTINA E. VIVIANO-BECK</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Viviano-Beck, C., Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter Compact
            Reconnaissance Imaging Spectrometer for Mars Type Spectra
            Library, MRO-M-CRISM-4-TYPESPEC-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2015.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Minerals Identified through CRISM Analysis (MICA) Library.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset includes spectral data from type spectra of phases
            identified using the CRISM (Compact Reconnaissance Imaging
            Spectrometer for Mars) instrument on MRO. Type locations for the
            diversity of currently identified mineral spectral signatures
            have been compiled into this library of spectra. The type spectra
            assembled into the MICA library represent the results of over
            seven years of measurements from CRISM of the surface of Mars and
            represent the compilation of many researchers&apos; efforts.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      This volume contains the Minerals Identified through CRISM
      Analysis (MICA) Library Archive, a collection of CRISM type
      spectra of the currently identified diversity of phases on
      the surface of Mars. A &apos;type spectrum&apos; is representative of a
      spectral signature of a particular phase previously identified
      on Mars as seen by the CRISM instrument. Data consist of
      atmospherically and photometrically corrected CRISM TER3
      (non-map-projected) non-ratioed I/F spectra of type locations
      for each library member. The data also include I/F spectra for
      spectrally bland units within the same detector column of the
      same CRISM observation, which are used as the denominators for
      the CRISM ratioed I/F spectra (also provided in the dataset).
 
      File labels provide citation information for the original
      observation of the type location and identification of the
      mineral/ice phase.  Also provided is the center location
      (column, row) used to extract the type spectrum and spectrally
      bland denominator spectrum in non-map-projected space. The label
      also includes information on the number of pixels averaged
      together in the region of interest (ROI).  All ROIs are a
      continuous set of pixels in a square surrounding the defined
      (column, row) center pixel location.
 
    Processing
    ==========
      CRISM radiance data has been processed to atmospherically-
      corrected I/F and has undergone other calibrations outlined in
      the MTRDR dataset catalog file
      (DATA_SET_ID = MRO-M-CRISM-5-RDR-MPTARGETED-V1.0).
 
      The original hyperspectral (545 total) channels have been
      downsized to a conservative subset of (480 total) channels that
      exhibit no known calibration or filter/detector boundary
      artifacts, such that the MICA library contains only the best
      representation of spectral characteristics of phases present on
      Mars. The MTRDR dataset catalog file summarizes the specific VNIR
      and IR &apos;bad channels&apos; that have been filtered from the MICA
      dataset.
 
    Data
    ====
      There is only one data type associated with this volume, the
      MICA library or CRISM type spectra.  These data consist of
      separate comma-delimited &apos;.tab&apos; files that include 7 columns
      including: 1) the wavelength array, 2) the CRISM ratioed I/F
      corrected type spectra data, 3) the CRISM ratioed I/F type
      spectra data, 4) the CRISM I/F corrected type spectra data
      (numerator), 5) the CRISM I/F type spectra data (numerator),
      6) the CRISM I/F corrected data of spectrally-bland material
      (denominator), and 7) the CRISM I/F data of spectrally-bland
      material (denominator).
 
      &apos;Corrected spectra&apos; have been adjusted to mitigate a small
      variable offset that remains near 1 micron at the join between
      the VNIR and IR detectors due to a nonlinear decrease in the
      spectral response approaching the longest wavelengths of the
      VNIR detector. The offset was quantitatively determined for
      extracted spectra between overlapping wavelengths in the VNIR
      and IR detectors and used a fourth-order polynomial with an
      onset at ~720 nm to multiplicatively adjust the VNIR reflectance
      until it matched the IR via nonlinear least squares fitting.
      A residual small offset may still remain at the detector join
      after correction.
 
      I/F spectra are ratioed to spectrally unremarkable material that
      falls within the same detector column to mitigate effects of
      residual atmospheric and instrumental artifacts in the spectra.
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      The coordinate system of this dataset is consistent with that
      defined for the CRISM MTRDR data products
      (DATA_SET_ID = MRO-M-CRISM-5-RDR-MPTARGETED-V1.0). The
      cartographic coordinate system used for the CRISM data products
      conforms to the IAU planetocentric system with East longitudes
      being positive. The IAU2000 reference system for Mars
      cartographic coordinates and rotational elements was used for
      computing latitude and longitude coordinates.
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The CRISM archive is available online via Web and FTP servers.
      This is the primary means of distribution. As new phases are
      discovered on Mars, products will be added to the volume data
      directory, and the volume&apos;s index table will be updated
      accordingly.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      There are a number of sources of uncertainty in the
      interpretation of CRISM spectra pertaining to noise, optical
      distortions, spectral resolution, calibration artifacts, and
      optical effects.  Please refer to the CRISM MTRDR dataset catalog
      file for a summary of known issues.
 
    Review
    ======
      This data set was examined by a peer review panel prior to its
      acceptance by the Planetary Data System (PDS).  The peer review
      was conducted in accordance with PDS procedures.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

