<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mro-m-mcs-2-edr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MRO MARS CLIMATE SOUNDER LEVEL 2 EDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mcs.mro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-mcs-2-edr-v1.0__browserp_mro-m-mcs-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   D. McCleese, J. Schofield, F. Taylor, S. Calcutt, M. Foote, D. Kass, C. Leovy,
                   D. Paige, P. Read, and R. Zurek, &apos;Mars Climate Sounder: An Investigation of
                   Thermal and Water Vapor Structure, Dust and Condensate Distribution in the
                   Atmosphere, and Energy Balance of the Polar Regions&apos;, Journal of Geophysical
                   Research, TBD
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MCCLEESEETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MRO-M-MCS-2-EDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MRO MARS CLIMATE SOUNDER LEVEL 2 EDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2006-07-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2006-10-12T19:10:51.999Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DANIEL J. MCCLEESE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            McCleese and Schofield, MRO MARS CLIMATE SOUNDER LEVEL 2 EDR
            V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, MRO-M-MCS-2-EDR-V1.0, 2006.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Unpacked, uncalibrated MRO MCS engineering and science
            measurements
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>Unknown</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      This document describes how the MRO MCS instrument acquired the
      Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter Experiment Data Record (EDR) data, and
      how the data are processed, formatted, labeled, and uniquely
      identified. This document discusses standards used in generating
      the product and software that may be used to access the product.
      The data product structure and organization is described in
      sufficient detail to enable a user to fully utilize the EDR data
      product.
 
      This data set consists of tables and supporting documentation from
      the final analysis of the Experimental Data Records (EDR) from the
      Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter (MRO) Mars Climate Sounder (MCS)
      instrument. The MCS instrument, its scientific goals, its
      measurement objectives, and its observational strategies are
      discussed in MCCLEESE ET Al 2006 and the INSTRUMENT.CAT file
      accompanying this data set.
 
      MCS is an atmospheric sounder that makes one measurement every
      2.048 seconds, containing science, engineering and housekeeping
      data, whenever the instrument is powered on. The instrument
      operates in a single data-taking mode and observational
      flexibility is provided by actuators that allow telescope
      boresights to be directed over a range of 270 degrees in azimuth
      and elevation.
 
      Each instrument packet contains one measurement. The MCS EDR
      contains time-ordered, unpacked, raw data for the entire MCS
      mission, starting with the initial instrument power-on in the MRO
      mapping orbit at 16:00 UT on 24th September 2006. The data are
      organized by UTC in monthly archive volumes, with 6 four-hour ASCII
      tables per day accompanied by detached headers. Each table row
      contains one measurement, and each column contains one unpacked
      science, engineering or housekeeping parameter.
 
      The MCS EDR contains all the good packets received by the MCS
      science team in APID 87. No attempt has been made to reconstruct
      corrupted packets in APID 88. Gaps in the data set are only evident
      from discontinuities in the timing of table rows (see Data Coverage
      and Quality section). Some, sub-commutated raw housekeeping data
      are not available every 2.048 seconds. For convenience these are
      presented in the same table format with -9999 indicating time slots
      where data are not taken.
 
 
      Data Product Acquisition
      ------------------------
        The MCS software collects 192 sixteen-bit science measurements
        from the focal plane interface electronics every 2.048 seconds,
        along with associated instrument engineering and housekeeping
        measurements. The science and housekeeping data are organized
        into data packets that are transmitted to the spacecraft at the
        same 2.048-second spacing. The data packets are downlinked to the
        MRO Ground Data System (GDS) and placed into the Raw Science Data
        Server (RSDS). MCS software queries the data from the RSDS and
        assembles them into EDR data tables, each covering a 4 hour time
        period.
 
        Each MCS EDR data table will be approximately 16MB for each 4
        hour time period; the volume of the EDR data product will be
        approximately 96 MB per day; 3 GB per month.
 
 
      Data Product Generation and Flow
      --------------------------------
        The MCS EDR data products, generated by the MCS Instrument Team
        at JPL, are reconstructed from telemetry data products and
        formatted according to the MRO/MCS EDR SIS. Meta-data derived
        from fields in the EDR, will be used to populate the PDS label.
 
        MCS science and engineering telemetry are transferred to the MRO
        Project RSDS. Once transferred, the MCS software automatically
        processes the telemetry into Level 0 EDR data products. The MCS
        EDR data products are then archived locally at the MCS operation
        center. After an initial 6 month data validation period, the MCS
        team assembles the data products and ancillary files into archive
        volumes and transfers the assembled volumes to the PDS
        Atmospheres Node.  An archive volume consists of one month of
        data.  Volumes are delivered approximately every 3 months.
 
        The MCS EDR archive will be made available via data
        releases scheduled at three month intervals as specified in the
        Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter Project Data Archive Generation,
        Validation and Transfer Plan
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The MCS EDR data have been unpacked from raw packets and formatted
      into ASCII tables. The only derived parameters are Date (Column 2),
      UTC (Column 3) and decimal spacecraft clock (SCLK, Column 4). Time
      requires special treatment because MCS packets are delivered
      asynchronously to the spacecraft and are generated using an
      internal instrument clock.
 
      Decimal SCLK at the center of each measurement integration period
      is derived from linear fits of instrument fine time to spacecraft
      time supplied to MCS at roughly 51 second intervals in time
      commands referenced to a 1 Hz time tick.
 
      Instrument fine time at the start of each packet (Ticks_pkt_start,
      Column 16), and at the receipt of the one second time tick
      corresponding to the spacecraft time command (Ticks_at_SC_time,
      Column 17), is available at a resolution of 64 ticks per 2.048
      second integration period, or 32 msec. Spacecraft time consists of
      integer and decimal parts of the spacecraft clock in seconds
      referenced to 00:00 UTC January 1st 1980. These parts are contained
      in Last_time_command (Column 48) and the last command received
      column (Last_command_rec, Column 45).
 
      Linear fits between instrument fine time and spacecraft time (SCLK)
      at the receipt of each spacecraft time are performed over each four
      hour file. This is done for the following reasons.
 
      1.  To preserve the accurate, 2.048 second spacing of MCS
          measurements.
      2.  To track the slow drift between instrument and spacecraft clocks.
      3.  To correct occasional +- 1 second error associated with S/C time.
      4.  To correct ~50 second time jumps associated with anomalies in the
          MSC software.
 
      Formally, the absolute time derived from this process could be in
      error by up to +- 32 msec, which is acceptable for MCS science. The
      relative timing between MCS samples is much better than 1 msec,
      except at the boundaries of four-hour files where errors of up to 4
      msec are seen, which is also acceptable for MCS science.
 
      SCLK is converted to UTC using the SPICE NAIF SCLK to SCET and Leap
      Seconds kernels.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      The MCS EDR is represented by a single PDS labeled table.  Each
      table is accompanied by a full PDS detached label with the same
      name except for suffix *.LBL.  The format of the table is described
      in detail in MCS_EDR.FMT.  The PDS label completely describes the
      format and contents of the table.
 
      The naming convention for the tables and detached headers follow
      the time-organization of the data itself and use the following
      naming convention:
 
         yyyymmddhh_EDR.TAB; where:
 
              yyyy = year in which the data was acquired
                mm = month of the year in which the data was acquired
                dd = day of the month in which the data was acquired
                hh = hour of the day in which the data was acquired
 
      Note that the hour is UT (to within the nearest second) at the start
      of the coverage of the data contained in the file.  There are six
      possible values for hour.
 
      The first data after powering on in September 2006 are:
 
         - 2006092416_EDR.LBL:   The PDS label that describes the EDR data
         - 2006092416_EDR.TAB:   The actual EDR data formatted into a PDS
                                 TABLE object
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      Ancillary data is limited to Spacecraft clock (sclk) to UTC
      conversion is performed using the following SPICE NAIF Kernels:
 
       1. Sclk to Scet kernel
       2. Leap Seconds kernel
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      The only coordinate system appropriate to MCS EDR data is time.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      The MCS EDR products are formatted as columnar ASCII data; and as
      such, they can be read and manipulated by standard, public-domain
      software. For this reason, no special utilities are provided.
 
      The MCS EDR products are standard PDS-labeled tables that can be
      viewed with NASAView, an application developed by the PDS and
      available for a variety of computer platforms from the PDS web
      site.
 
 
    Archive Format
    ============
      The individual archives were delivered to the PDS Atmospheres
      node as gzipped tar files via ftp.  Once validated they are
      available online with the archive volume structure.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
 
      With respect to the EDR data, the data exists in 2 states -- Absent
      or Present.  For the data that is present, the confidence level is
      high due to simplicity of the processing and structure of the data.
 
      The quality flag (column 1) has limited meaning for the EDR
      records.  A value of 0 indicates present and completely valid
      data; a value of 1 indicates a record header line; a value of 4
      indicates the unpacking software had an issue with the time
      interpolation (note there are only 4 records immediately at
      power on flagged this way).
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was examined by a peer review panel prior to
      its acceptance by the Planetary Data System (PDS). The peer review
      was conducted in accordance with PDS procedures.
 
      Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data set,
      key elements of the archive were distributed for preliminary
      review.  These included electronic versions of example PDS labels,
      CATALOG files, and Software Interface Specifications (SISs).
      These materials were distributed to PDS personnel, the experiment
      investigator, and others, as appropriate.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      All MCS packets supplied to the MCS team by the project are
      included in the archive.  Each MCS packet is complete due to the
      handling methods used by the spacecraft and ground system.  The
      data in each packet is the information generated and sent by the
      instrument (checksums and other techniques are used to detect and
      correct any corruption).
 
      There are a number places where there are gaps and missing packets.
      Most of these gaps are small (the largest is about 2 hours long).
      The gaps are due to a number of causes.  The primary cause are
      those lost due to not being received at a DSN ground station.
      Other losses come from spacecraft activities (primarily ELECTRA
      testing and reformatting the SSR--solid state recorder), interface
      errors between MCS and the spacecraft, and ground data system
      issues.
 
      Missing packets can be identified in several ways.  The first is by
      looking for gaps of more than 2.05 seconds between packets.  MCS
      produces a packet every 2.048 seconds, unless powered off. The
      date and time of the packet is represented in columns 2 and 3,
      respectively. Except for when the counter rolls (at 65535), the
      packet counter, column 5, can also be used to detect missing
      packets.  Finally, there are 64 instrument ticks between each
      packet (column 16).
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The limitations in this data set follow from the quality of the
      execution, which is described above under Data Coverage and
      Quality.
 
      The only known limitation is the occurence of brief periods of
      elevation mis-pointing associated with position errors.  During
      these periods, the actuator (and thus the telescopes) are not in
      the intended orientation and thus not viewing the intended
      scene.  These do not affect the quality of the EDR records, but
      are relevant for analysis and processing of higher data levels,
      as well as the conversion of EDR records to RDR records.
 
      Position errors occur when the MCS FSW and the hardware disagree on
      the position of an actuator.  The position of the actuators is
      checked at two locations: 0 degrees (blackbody position) and 105.7
      degrees (step 2046, between the standard limb and space views).  A
      position error is presumed (and in many cases confirmed) to
      indicate a physical mis-pointing of the instrument.  Position
      errors only occur while slewing, but a mis-pointing caused by a
      position error will persist (with the same magnitude) until the
      actuator is re-intialized and in synch with where FSW assumes it is
      pointing.
 
      Finding where the position errors are reported by MCS FSW is
      straight forward.  The error is reported in the ERROR_ID column as
      error 19 (note that the last error generated is reported in every
      packet as a historical field, but is only generated when the
      ERROR_COUNT increments).  The first byte of the ERROR_DETAIL field
      will indicate the number of position errors that FSW will allow
      before stowing the instrument.
 
      After reporting a position error, the FSW re-intializes both
      actuators, removing any pointing errors.  The time taken is
      variable depending on where the error is handled (it can take a
      minute in some cases), but all packets from that time are flagged
      as moving.  The LAST_AZ_CMD and LAST_EL_CMD do not update until an
      SST commands a move for that actuator after the re-intialization
      (the re-intialization is not considered commanded movement).
 
      The complexity is that the FSW does not report the error when it is
      detected, it is only reported at the end of an SST.  The error was
      detected during one of the check points in that SST (there are
      special cases involving freeze and stow sequences).  Thus, the
      actual pointing error occurred at some point before the last check
      point crossing in the SST.  This is even more complicated in cases
      (e.g., limb staring) were the sequence does not go through any of
      the position check locations.
 
      Position errors can also usually be detected by looking at the
      radiances when pointed at the limb.  This is done by using A3 (core
      of the 15 micron band) and comparing the calibrated radiances of
      the limb views during the period around when the error is reported.
      We use limb view before the probable slewing error, while the error
      is in effect and after the actuator has been re-synchronized.  This
      provides additional information on the timing of the position error
      and sometimes also provides knowledge of the magnitude and
      direction of the error.  Based on experience, we&apos;ve found that for
      small errors (&lt; 1 degree), looking at the limb radiance provides a
      pointing accuracy of one actuator step (0.101 degrees). There are
      cases (especially over the poles) when the atmosphere is changing
      too fast and it is not possible to accurately measure the pointing
      error.
 
      Note that even during a position error, all the fields in the EDR
      are correct since the instrument does not report the actual
      pointing, but the commanded pointing; see colums LAST_AZ_CMD and
      LAST_EL_CMD (columns 27 and 28, respectively).
 
      Note that for the derived RDR data product, we have flagged the
      regions of the pointing errors and corrected them where possible.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

