<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mer1-m-apxs-2-edr-ops-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MER 1 MARS ALPHA PARTICLE X-RAY SPECTROMETER 2 EDR OPS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_exploration_rover::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mer1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:apxs.mer1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer1-m-apxs-2-edr-ops-v1.0__browserc_mer1-m-apxs-2-edr-ops-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer1-m-apxs-2-edr-ops-v1.0__browser_geo_mer1-m-apxs-2-edr-ops-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer1-m-apxs-2-edr-ops-v1.0__dvo_geo_mer1-m-apxs-2-edr-ops-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer1-m-apxs-2-edr-ops-v1.0__pds.geo.mer.analysts_notebook::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mars Exploration Rover Mission, Alpha Particle X-Ray Spectrometer
                   Experiment Data Record Software Interface Specification, 2003
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.APXSEDRSIS2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Rieder, R., et al., The New Athena Alpha Particle X-Ray Spectrometer (APXS) for
                   the Mars Exploration Rovers, Journal of Geophysical Research- Planets, 2003.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.RIEDERETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MER1-M-APXS-2-EDR-OPS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MER 1 MARS ALPHA PARTICLE X-RAY SPECTROMETER 2 EDR OPS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2004-08-24</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-01-26T04:29:52.112Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>Rudi Rieder</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Rieder, Rudolf, and Ralf Gellert, MER 1 Alpha Particle X-Ray
            Spectrometer 2 EDR V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            MER1-M-APXS-2-EDR-OPS-V1.0, 2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains Alpha Particle X-ray Spectrometer (APXS)
            Operations Experiment Data Records (EDRs) acquired by Opportunity
            (MER 1) during the Mars Exploration Rover Mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This archive contains Mars Exploration Rover Operations (Ops)
            APXS Experiment Data Record (EDR) products and ancillary files.
            Each EDR product has a detached PDS label that describes the file
            structure and instrument parameters used for that image. The APXS
            Operations EDR products archived on this volume are theoriginal
            products used during mission operations by the Mars Exploration
            Rover project. Supporting documentation and label files conform
            to the Planetary Data System (PDS) Standards, Version 3.6, Jet
            Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) document number D-7669.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set contains data that is useful for determining the
    major and minor elemental composition of Martian soils, rocks,
    and other geological materials that the rover encountered.  The
    EDR data products are raw uncalibrated data reconstructed from
    telemetry data products and formatted according to the APXS EDR
    Software Interface Specification.  Meta-data acquired from the
    telemetry data headers are used to populate the PDS label.  There
    will not be multiple versions of an APXS EDR.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The Committee On Data Management and Computation (CODMAC) data
    level numbering system is used to describe the processing level
    of the EDR data product.  APXS EDR data products are considered
    CODMAC Level 2 or Edited Data (equivalent to NASA level 0)
    products.  The EDR data files are generated from Level 1 or Raw
    Data, which are the telemetry packets within the project specific
    Standard Formatted Data Unit (SFDU) record.
 
    The APXS EDR data products were generated by the MIPL
    (Multimission Image Processing Laboratory) at JPL under the
    Operations Product Generation Subsystem using the telemetry
    processing software, mertelemproc.  If telemetry packets are
    missing during the initial downlink from the rover memory,
    partial data sets will be created and the missing data will be
    filled with [zeroes].  The data will be reprocessed after all
    data are received and the original version will be overwritten.
 
    The APXS memory is maintained by a battery, and in theory,
    retransmits from the APXS memory could be commanded.  In this
    instance, a new data product will be created, because there will
    likely be subtle and potentially useful changes in the data when
    a retransmit from the APXS memory is commanded.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    Each APXS EDR consists of two files.  The first file is an ASCII
    formatted detached PDS label.  The second file is a binary data
    file.  The APXS EDR data file is a copy of what was in the APXS
    memory buffer.  That is, the EDR consists of unprocessed
    experiment data stored in binary format.  The APXS EDR contains
    energy spectra in units of counts and temperature values.
    Temperatures are derived from the two temperature sensors.  There
    are two types of APXS spectra in each measurement: one x-ray, and
    two alpha spectra.  The energy scale is divided into discrete
    channels with 256 channels for the alpha spectra and 512 channels
    for the x-ray spectra.  The instrument holds data for the twelve
    most recent measurements in memory.  When a new measurement
    begins, the oldest one is discarded.  Each spectrum has a unique
    identifier.  There are also 2 Kbytes at the end of the APXS EDR
    data file that are transferred from the instrument&apos;s internal
    RAM.  This 2 Kbyte section of RAM is used for instrument
    engineering data.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    A reader program, called apxs2asc will be available to convert
    the APXS EDR binary format data into ASCII format.  This reader
    will be archived with the EDR data products.  The ASCII format
    data can be imported into spread sheet and plotting programs.
 
    PDS labeled tables can be viewed with the program NASAView,
    developed by the PDS.  NASAView is available in versions that run
    on SUN/SOLARIS, WINDOWS, and LINUX operating systems.  NASAView
    can be obtained from the PDS web site at
    http://pdsproto.jpl.nasa.gov/Distribution/license.html.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    The data set will be intitially delivered and kept online.  Upon
    Mission completion, the APXS EDRs will be delivered to PDS on DVD
    as part of the complete MER EDR data set.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
NULL
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

