<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ro-cal-cosima-3-v2.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ROSETTA-ORBITER CAL COSIMA 3 V2.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.international_rosetta_mission::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.ro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:cosima.ro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ro-cal-cosima-3-v2.0__browserp_ro-cal-cosima-3-v2.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Archive Review Board, ROSETTA Science Archive, 1st delivery Review Report for
                   orbiter Instruments, Issue 1, Revision 0, March 15, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.RO-EST-RP-3461</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>RO-CAL-COSIMA-3-V2.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ROSETTA-ORBITER CAL COSIMA 3 V2.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2008-11-17</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2002-05-29</start_time>
        <stop_time>2008-07-23</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JOHAN SILEN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            2010-07-30 SBN:T.Barnes Added ABSTRACT_DESC, and ,NONE SUPPLIED
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            COSIMA substrate operations and calibrations
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset contains data from COSIMA instrument in the Rosetta
            spacecraft. The set covers the substrate history from the
            calibration period of the instrument starting 2002-05-29 up to
            the payload checkout #8 2008-11-17. (Version 2.0 is the first
            version archived.)
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
 
    This dataset contains data from COSIMA instrument in the Rosetta
    spacecraft. The set covers the substrate history from the
    calibration period of the instrument starting 2002-05-29 up to the
    payload checkout #8 2008-11-17.
 
    Note that Version 2.0 is the first version archived for this
    dataset.  Version 1 was never archived.
 
    During the calibration period the instrument was operated with
    several software versions and for test purposes the operations
    were not always nominal. The substrate histories are anyway
    considered to be complete.
 
    During the first commissioning period from 2004-03-02 to
    2004-06-06 the substrates from the target holder #D8 covering the
    dust inlet was stored.
 
    During the second commissioning period from 2004-09-06 to
    2004-10-16 the first ever in space secondary ion mass spectra were
    generated. These can be found from the substrate #1C2 data.
 
    During the passive payload checkouts (PC) no science data was
    generated.  The target holder #C2 was to be lifted to test the
    target manipulator unit. This failed in PC1 and PC3 due to
    hardware anomaly. Due to spacecraft telemetry problem, this
    history is not available from PC2 either.
 
    Test images from empty COSISCOPE slot were taken in all payload
    checkouts. All the substrates were also imaged in space to be used
    later as initial reference images.
 
    During the active checkouts the main operational concentration was
    to heal the baddly behaving ion emitter A. During those operations
    some spectra was acquired, but without intention to generate
    really scientifically usable background spectra from the
    substrates.
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
    The primary measured parameter is the time of flight mass spectrum
    of a grain, ion events collected for 131072 time bins, each
    1.953125 ns in length. For data selection purposes, three
    individual time windows can be selected for each generated
    spectrum. In addition or instead, a peak list separating the
    organic and inorganic peaks can be generated. For quantitive
    analysis and gain optimisation, instead of individual time bins,
    a sum of events in three time windows can be collected. These are
    called scans in the COSIMA system.
 
    Grains in the substrate are searched with the COSISCOPE camera.
    COSISCOPE main task is to generate grains list of the prominent
    features on the substrate surface. The images itself can also be
    generated.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
 
    The spectrum time of flight ion data is mass calibrated with the
    same procedure as is used in space for the peak data. The
    calibration should be used only as rude starting point and for
    scienctific analysis each calibration must be checked.
 
    The housekeeping data covering the data aqcuisition period is
    calibrated to physical units and statistically analyzed were
    applicable to support the evaluation of the data quality.
 
  Data
  ====
 
    COSIMA generates the following PDS products
 
    spectrum
    --------
      The spectrum is generated by bombing the comet grains collected
      on the substrate by indium ions. The seconday ions are measured
      by time of flight mass spectrometer. The spectrometer collects
      individual ion arriving times to an array of 131072 bins, each
      1.953125 nanosecond in size. From accumulated ion data, peaks
      are detected and from the assumed mass scale and detected peak
      positions a mass is given to each time bin. This calibration
      is automatic and the user must check the scale for real use.
 
      The spectrum can be divided in time to at most tree different
      subspectrums to reduce the amout of data to be transmitted.
 
      The product files have the naming convention
      CS_YXX_YYYYMMDDTHHMMSS_SP_Z.TAB, where the Y is either 1 for
      top, 2 for middle and 3 for bottom substrate. The XX is target
      holder number in the range C1 to D8, counting in hexadecimal
      number base. The YYYYMMDDTHHMMSS gives the start year, month,
      day, hour, minute and second. The Z is P for positive and N for
      negative ion spectrum.
 
    peaks
    -----
      Generated as the spectrum, but the spectrum mass scale is
      established onboard COSIMA. The list of 300 first organic and
      inorganic peaks is transmitted. For higher masses, the total of
      count hits for a mass range is given.
 
      The product files have the naming convention
      CS_YXX_YYYYMMDDTHHMMSS_PK_Z.TAB, where the Y is either 1 for
      top, 2 for middle and 3 for bottom substrate. The XX is target
      holder number in the range C1 to D8, counting in hexadecimal
      number base. The YYYYMMDDTHHMMSS gives the start year, month,
      day, hour, minute and second. The Z is P for positive and N for
      negative ion spectrum.
 
    scan
    ----
      Used for instrument calibration and gain optimisation. Currently
      no PDS product available, as the spectrum window limits are very
      difficult to find to all the scans made. Produces total sum of
      the event counts over three possible time windows.
 
    spectrum housekeeping
    ---------------------
      There&apos;s three kind of housekeeping information.
 
      First, the minimum, maximum, mean and standard deviation of the
      analog data, temperatures, voltages and currents, is calculated
      for the period of the measurement.
 
      Second, the used time to digital converter timing for the ion
      beam chopper, bunchers and ion optics is given.
 
      Third, the time to digital converter temperature calibration for
      the delay line is given. The calibration is needed to adjust the
      delay line so, that the 16 bin hardware event counter gets even
      bin distribution over the sampling period.
 
      The product files have the naming convention
      CS_YXX_YYYYMMDDTHHMMSS_S_HK.TAB, where the Y is either 1 for
      top, 2 for middle and 3 for bottom substrate. The XX is target
      holder number in the range C1 to D8, counting in hexadecimal
      number base. The YYYYMMDDTHHMMSS gives the start year, month,
      day, hour, minute and second.
 
    grains
    ------
      The grain list is taken by the COSISCOPE camera from the
      substrate surface. The orientation of the substrate is
      calculated from the reference dots on target holder. The
      binding box of the substrate feature is given in substrate
      coordinates, which has origo at lower left corner and is 10000
      times 10000 micrometers. The grain quality, based on the
      brightness is given as relative number from 0-255.
 
      The product files have the naming convention
      CS_YXX_YYYYMMDDTHHMMSS_GR__.TAB, where the Y is either 1 for
      top, 2 for middle and 3 for bottom substrate. The XX is target
      holder number in the range C1 to D8, counting in hexadecimal
      number base. The YYYYMMDDTHHMMSS gives the start year, month,
      day, hour, minute and second.
 
    image
    -----
      The image take by the COSISCOPE camera. The image has 1024*1024
      pixels resolution with 10 bit brightness information. The PDS
      product uses 16 bits for brightness storage.
 
      The product files have the naming convention
      CS_YXX_YYYYMMDDTHHMMSS_IM_Z.IMG, where the Y is either 1 for
      top, 2 for middle and 3 for bottom substrate. The XX is target
      holder number in the range C1 to D8, counting in hexadecimal
      number base.The YYYYMMDDTHHMMSS gives the start year, month,
      day, hour, minute and second. The ZX is P for right (plus) side
      and N for left (minus) side led illumination.
 
      The image files can be viewed only with software, that
      understands PDS data formats, like &apos;NASAView&apos;, available from
      PDS.
 
    COSISCOPE housekeeping
    ----------------------
      For the COSISCOPE housekeeping the operating temprature mimimum,
      maximum, mean and standard deviation is calculated for the
      operation time period. In addition, the COSISCOPE operation
      setup parameters are given. Also the subsrate orientation
      information is given.
 
      The product files have the naming convention
      CS_YXX_YYYYMMDDTHHMMSS_G_HK.TAB, where the Y is either 1 for
      top, 2 for middle and 3 for bottom substrate. The XX is target
      holder number in the range C1 to D8, counting in hexadecimal
      number base.The YYYYMMDDHHMMSS gives the start year, month, day,
      hour, minute and second.
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
 
    Other data required to interpret this data, especially if it is
    not included in the dataset (for example, laboratory calibration
    values)
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
 
    COSIMA substrates are exposed 3 at a time to the +Z side of the
    spacecraft. The dust funnel has 20 * 34 degree field of view.
 
 
                                ^
                                |  direction of
                                |    flight
                                |
 
                                ^ +Xcosima (down-track)
                                |
                                |
     ---              +---------|---------+
      ^               |         |         |
      |               |         |         |
      |               |         |         |
      |               |         |         |
      | 20 deg        |         x-------------&gt; +Ycosima (cross-track)
      |               |     +Zcosima      |
      |               |                   |
      |               |                   |
      V               |                   |
     ---              +-------------------+
 
                      |       34 deg      |      Boresight (+Z axis)
                      |&lt;-----------------&gt;|       is into the page
                      |                   |
 
    No S/C geometry is calculated for the data.
 
  Software
  ========
 
All the data can be used by PDS tools or any ASCII reading software.
 
  Media/Format
  ============
 
    The data is delivered as PDS standard compliant electronic files.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
 
    The data have been automatically processed from raw data. Care
    should be taken in spectrum analysis, the housekeeping values for
    operating voltages should be checked for possible anomalies. Some
    of the operations during the calibration were really outside of
    normal instrument operation.
 
  Review
  ======
 
    The dataset review is available from the RO-EST-RP-3461, ROSETTA
    Science Archive 1st Delivery Review Report for Orbiter instruments
    (15 March 2007). This covers the dataset v1.0, where there was no
    spectrum mass scale.
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
 
    The data covers the COSIMA flight model operations from the flight
    substrate delivery 2002-05-29 to the eight payload checkout
    2008-07-23.
 
    The production of the substrates is not part of the substrate
    history.
 
    Regardless of the several anomalies in the instrument operations
    during the calibration period, the substrate histories are
    complete. Only the scan results are missing, but the ion emission
    and positions on the substrates are known from the housekeeping
    data.
 
  Limitations
  ===========
 
    Housekeeping data outside spectral measurements and COSISCOPE
    operations is not delivered. This would include indium ion emitter
    history and target manipulator operations. Though vital to the
    instrument operations, they are not needed in the scientific
    interpretation of the COSIMA data.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SUPERSEDED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

