<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lro-l-dlre-4-rdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LRO DLRE 4 CALIBRATED RADIANCE V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:dlre.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-dlre-4-rdr-v1.0__browserp_lro-l-dlre-4-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-dlre-4-rdr-v1.0__dvo_geo_lro-l-dlre-4-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-dlre-4-rdr-v1.0__pds.geo.lro.orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Paige, D.A., et al., The Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter Diviner Lunar Radiometer
                   Experiment, Space Sci. Rev., doi: 10.1007/s11214-009-9529-2, 2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PAIGEETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LRO-L-DLRE-4-RDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LRO DLRE 4 CALIBRATED RADIANCE V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-06-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2009-07-05T16:50:26.195Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2016-03-15T23:59:59.897Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID PAIGE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Paige et al., LRO DLRE LEVEL 4 RDR V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, LRO-L-DLRE-4-RDR-V1.0, 2010.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            LRO DLRE RDR, calibrated with pointing location geometry
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set consists of the Diviner Lunar Radiometer Experiment
            Reduced Data Records also known as RDRs. The DLRE is a surface
            pushbroom mapper that measures emitted thermal radiation and
            reflected solar radiation from the surface of the moon. Two
            Diviner solar channels measure 0.3-3 micrometers reflected solar
            radiation. Three Diviner channels near 8 micrometers classify
            regolith mineralogy by mapping the location of the Christiansen
            feature. The remaining four Diviner channels measure surface
            temperature in four spectral bands ranging from 12.5 micrometers
            to beyond 200 micrometers.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
-------------------------------------------------------------------------+
 
Data Product Overview
=====================
 
Every 2.048 seconds Diviner collects a data &apos;frame&apos; containing
the following:
 
* 16 sets of science data, with each set containing 189 sixteen-bit
  science measurements from the focal plane interface electronics
  obtained over integration periods of 0.128 seconds
* A single set of instrument engineering and housekeeping
  measurements (or &apos;engineering data&apos;)
 
The data are downlinked to the LRO Ground Data System (GDS) and are
pushed to the Diviner SOC at the end of each downlink pass. Diviner
software assembles the telemetry files into EDR data tables, each
covering a one-hour time period.  The RDR data tables are produced
directly from the EDR data tables using Diviner software, geometry,
and ephemeris data provided by the LRO project.
Each Diviner RDR data product will consist of two files.  The first
file is an ASCII formatted detached PDS label.  The second file is
the ASCII data table file.  Unlike the EDR data tables, which contain
values for each of the 189 detectors in a single record
(every 0.128 seconds), the RDR data tables have one record per detector.
Therefore, for every EDR record there will be 189 detector-specific
RDR records, each with the same &apos;date&apos; and &apos;utc&apos; time as the original
EDR record.
 
Due to the size of the RDR dataset, each RDR data table will cover
ten minutes of time, one-sixth of the EDR data tables.   In order to
save space on disk and to facilitate faster downloading, the RDR
data tables will be compressed using Info-ZIP (freely available utility).
 
The RDR data product is considered to be foremost of scientific interest,
and thus contains a minimal representation of engineering and
housekeeping data needed to verify instrument status and data quality.
 
 
 
Data Processing Level
=====================
 
The Diviner RDR data products are derived directly from the
Diviner EDR data products and are considered &apos;Diviner Level 1&apos;.
It is similar to CODMAC Level 3 (NASA Level 1A) in that the data
are reversibly calibrated and located in space, yet the content
resembles more traditional CODMAC Level 4 (NASA Level 1B) data.
 
 
Data Product Generation
=======================
 
The Diviner RDR data products and labels will be generated by the
Diviner Instrument Team at JPL. The RDR data products will be derived
from the EDR data products, merged with geometry and ephemeris data
provided by the LRO Project, and formatted according to the RDR SIS.
 
 
Data Flow
=========
 
After an initial data validation period, the Diviner team at JPL will
transfer the data tables and labels to the UCLA SOC, which will assemble
the archive volumes and transfer them to the PDS Geosciences Node.
 
The Diviner RDR archive will be made available via data releases
scheduled at three month intervals as specified in the Lunar
Reconnaissance Orbiter Project Data Management and Archive Plan.
 
For more information please see the document DP_SIS.HTM
(HTML format) or DP_SIS.PDF (Adobe Acrobat format) located
in the DOCUMENT directory of this archive.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
Individual columns in the data records will contain the
UNKNOWN_CONSTANT (-9999) where data is missing or unknown.
 
 
Review
======
 
This archival data set was examined by a peer review panel prior to
its acceptance by the Planetary Data System (PDS). The peer review
was conducted in accordance with PDS procedures.
 
Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data set,
key elements of the archive were distributed for preliminary
review.  These included electronic versions of example PDS labels,
CATALOG files, and Software Interface Specifications (SISs).
These materials were distributed to PDS personnel, the experiment
investigator, and others, as appropriate.
 
 
Data Coverage and Quality
=========================
 
The Diviner instrument has a 98% data return rate of expected data.
Data loss is typically seen during data transmission or spacecraft and
instrument anomalies.  Diviner performed a Warm Reset after failing to
see a valid equator crossing from LRO on August 22, 2009.  The Warm
Reset was needed to clear the bad equator crossing value.  Diviner
lost a few soundings.  The LRO spacecraft triggered a sun-safed event
that powered off all instruments on October 10, 2009. Approximately
eight hours of Diviner data was lost due to the anomaly.  Two more
sun-safed events occurred on both January 12, 2010 and February 9, 2010.
The Diviner instrument was powered off for both events.  On July 23, 2010
Diviner was powered off for almost five hours during a spacecraft maneuver
during which Diviner data were not collected.  On December 23, 2010
Diviner was powered off for about 12 hours during an eclipse.
On February 23, 2011 Diviner was powered off for about 46 hours due
to a spacecraft safing event.  On April 03, 2011 Diviner was powered off
for about 23 hours due to a spacecraft safing event.  On June 06, 2011
Diviner lost about 14 hours of data due to a Ka-comm problem.
On March 22, 2012 Diviner was powered off for about 40 hours due to a
spacecraft safing event.  On September 04, 2012 Diviner was powered off
for about 17 hours due to a spacecraft safing event.  One September 08,
2012 Diviner was powered off for about 13 hours due to a spacecraft safing
event.
 
The following hours were affected by the anomalies and have either partial
data tables or are completely missing:
 
2009082202** - partial - missing data between times
   02:03:55.171 - 02:04:06.422 - Due to invalid equator crossing from LRO.
 
2009101016** - partial - missing data after 16:14:38.980
2009101017** through 2009101023** ---------&gt; 7 hours missing
2009101100** - partial - missing data before 00:41:15.607
 
2010011210** - partial - missing data after 10:00:00:468
2010011211** through 2010011220** ---------&gt; 10 hours missing
2010011221** - partial - missing data before 21:18:56:194
 
2010020914** - partial - missing data after 14:59:48:182
2010020915** through 2010021520** --------&gt; 150 hours missing
2010021521** - partial - missing data before 21:54:34:397
 
2010072414** - partial - missing data after 14:34:04:253
2010072415** through 2010072418** --------&gt; 4 hours missing
2010072419** - partial - missing data before 19:24:37:058
 
2010122105** - partial - missing data after 05:08:03:297
2010122106** through 2010122116** --------&gt; 11 hours missing
2010122117** - partial - missing data before 17:08:15:134
 
2011022314** - partial - missing data after 14:24:57:290
2011022315** through 2011022512** --------&gt; 46 hours missing
2011022513** - partial - missing data before 13:07:28:380
 
2011040317** - partial - missing data after 17:29:04:698
2011040318** through 2011040413** --------&gt; 20 files missing
2011040414** - partial - missing data before 14:44:47:900
 
2011061409** - partial - missing data after 09:37:20:572
2011061410** through 2011061423** --------&gt; 14 files missing
2011061500** - partial - missing data before 00:07:20:869
 
2012032202** - partial - missing data after 02:30:26:215
2012032203** through 2012032317** --------&gt; 39 files missing
2012032318** - partial - missing data before 18:15:47570
 
2012090405** - partial - missing data after 05:15:27:414
2012090406** through 2012090420** --------&gt; 15 files missing
2012090421** - partial - missing data before 21:01:36:575
 
2012090801** - partial - missing data after 01:15:04:908
2012090802** through 2012090812** --------&gt; 11 files missing
2012090813** - partial - missing data before 13:51:51:681
 
2013112704** - partial - missing data after 04:09:51:689
2013112705** through 2013112919** --------&gt; 63 files missing
2013112920** - partial - missing data before 20:51:58:203
 
2014022611** - partial - missing data after 11:20:42:962
2014022612** through 2014022620** --------&gt; 9 files missing
2014022621** - partial - missing data before 21:29:57:716
 
2014041504** - partial - missing data after 04:25:43:225
2014041505** through 2014041516** --------&gt; 12 files missing
2014041517** - partial - missing data before 17:31:47:179
 
 
Limitations
===========
 
Data seen immediately after the instrument is powered on or after
a restart is suspect for a few seconds to a few minutes.  The pointing
information is typically incorrect or missing.
 
Known Issues
============
 
1. Noise Events
 
A quality flag (qmi, bit 5) has been implemented to mark data
collected during noise periods.  Episodic noise events of unknown
origin are observed to affect a small fraction of Diviner&apos;s
housekeeping and radiometric data.  The noise signature in the
radiometric data consists of simultaneous correlated signal spikes
or offsets in all 189 Diviner detectors. Potential noise events are
cataloged by reviewing one-hour plots of Diviner housekeeping data
and flagging those periods in which noise is suspected.
 
Noise events have been flagged from 2009-07-05 to 2010-12-15
Noise events for the period 2010-12-15 to 2012-03-15 will be
applied in a later PDS data release.
 
2. Geometric Errors
 
None.
 
3. Radiometric Linearity
 
In the course of the analysis of the Diviner laboratory calibration
data, concerns have developed regarding the linearity of the
radiometric response of the instrument in the longer wavelength
channels at temperatures higher than 300K. The current calibration
algorithm assumes linear response at all signal levels.
Brightness temperatures will be recalculated based on updated
linearity parameters based on reanalysis of laboratory and in-flight
data in updated versions of the dataset.
 
4. Short Wavelength Spectral Leaks
 
We have evidence that the measured radiances in Channels 8 and 9
are affected by the intensity of reflected solar radiation. Only
daytime data are affected and no evidence for similar spectral
leaks has been identified in any other channels. Since the intensity
of reflected solar radiation from the moon is correlated with
temperature, the effects of the spectral leaks in these channels tend
to be greatest at higher temperatures. The most pronounced effects are
most evident at temperatures greater than 300K. However, pending
further investigation, the radiometric accuracy of daytime data in
Channels 8 and 9 should be considered suspect.
 
5. Eclipse Events
 
A quality flag (qmi, bit 1) has been implemented to mark data
collected during eclipse periods.  The eclipse period begins at entering
penumbra and ends two hours after the exit from penumbra.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

