<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.c130-e-asas-3-rdr-image-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>C130 EARTH ASAS CALIBRATED REDUCED DATA RECORD IMAGE V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.geologic_remote_sensing_field_experiment::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.c130::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:asas.c130::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.c130-e-asas-3-rdr-image-v1.0__browserp_geo_c130-e-asas-3-rdr-image-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.c130-e-asas-3-rdr-image-v1.0__dvo_geo_c130-e-asas-3-rdr-image-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Irons, J.R., and R.R. Irish, Sensor calibration for
                   multiple direction reflectance observations, Recent
                   Advances in Sensors, Radiometry, and Data Processing
                   for Remote Sensing, Proc. SPIE, 924, 109-119, 1988.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.IRONS-IRISH1988</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Irons, J.R., F.G. Huegel, and R.R. Irish, Prairie grass
                   hemispherical reflectances from airborne multi-directional
                   observations, Nineteenth Conference on Agriculture and
                   Forest Meteorology, 152-155, 1989.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.IRONSETAL1989A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Irons, J.R., K.J. Ranson, D.L. Williams, and R.R. Irish,
                   Forest and grassland ecosystem studies using the Advanced
                   Solid-State Array Spectroradiometer, Proc. of IGARRS&apos;89
                   Symp., 1761-1764, 1989.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.IRONSETAL1989B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Irons, J.R., K.J. Ranson, D.L. Williams, R.R. Irish, and
                   F.G. Huegel, An off-nadir pointing imaging
                   spectroradiometer for terrestrial ecosystem studies, IEEE
                   Trans. Geosci. Remote Sensing, 29, 66-74, 1991.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.IRONSETAL1991</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Stewart, S.E., R.R. Buntzen, and J. Carbone, Advanced CID
                   array multispectral pushbroom scanner, Laser
                   Focus/Electro-Optics, 21, 88-100, 1985.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.STEWARTETAL1985</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>C130-E-ASAS-3-RDR-IMAGE-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>C130 EARTH ASAS CALIBRATED REDUCED DATA RECORD IMAGE V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1991-05-28</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1989-07-17T14:33:05.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1989-07-17T21:16:42.000Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JAMES R. IRONS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Irons, J. R., C130 EARTH ASAS CALIBRATED REDUCED DATA RECORD
            IMAGE V1.0, C130-E-ASAS-3-RDR-IMAGE-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 1991
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This archive contains reduced data records (RDRs) acquired by the
            Advanced Solid-State Array Spectroradiometer (ASAS) during the
            earth-based 1989 Geologic Remote Sensing Field Experiment (GRSFE).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Most of the ASAS data acquired for GRSFE were taken during
            flights over Lunar Lake, Nevada, at a nominal altitude of 5000 m
            above ground level. Flights over Lunar Lake were repeated to
            acquire data for a range of solar zenith angles and to obtain
            data for several view azimuth angles (i.e., for several flight
            headings relative to the solar principal plane). On most flights,
            the sensor field of view was initially pointed forward 45 degrees
            as the aircraft approached the site. The sensor then imaged the
            site through a sequence of seven fore-to-aft view directions
            ranging from 45 degrees forward to 45 degrees aft in 15 degree
            increments as the aircraft flew over the site. The primary target
            of interest was the Lunar Lake playa, but the digital images also
            include data for the lava flow and cobble areas within and around
            the playa. Data were acquired in a similar manner on one flight
            over the Ubehebe Crater. One flight over Lunar Lake was also
            flown approximately along the solar principal plane with the ASAS
            view zenith angle fixed at the solar zenith angle. The purpose of
            this flight was to observe the opposition effect.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      Most of the ASAS data acquired for GRSFE were taken during
      flights over Lunar Lake, Nevada, at a nominal altitude of 5000
      m above ground level.  Flights over Lunar Lake were repeated to
      acquire data for a range of solar zenith angles and to obtain
      data for several view azimuth angles (i.e., for several flight
      headings relative to the solar principal plane).  On most
      flights, the sensor field of view was initially pointed forward
      45 degrees as the aircraft approached the site.  The sensor
      then imaged the site through a sequence of seven fore-to-aft
      view directions ranging from 45 degrees forward to 45 degrees
      aft in 15 degree increments as the aircraft flew over the site.
      The primary target of interest was the Lunar Lake playa, but
      the digital images also include data for the lava flow and
      cobble areas within and around the playa.  Data were acquired
      in a similar manner on one flight over the Ubehebe Crater.  One
      flight over Lunar Lake was also flown approximately along the
      solar principal plane with the ASAS view zenith angle fixed at
      the solar zenith angle.  The purpose of this flight was to
      observe the opposition effect.
 
      Several characteristics of the ASAS digital image data should
      be noted by investigators and analysts.  First, the image data
      are geometrically distorted.  One reason for the distortion is
      the roll, pitch, and yaw of the C-130 aircraft during data
      acquisition.  A second reason is the rectangular, instead of
      square, dimensions of the surface area represented by each
      image pixel.  The pixel dimensions depend on the aircraft
      speed, the instrument scan rate, and the pointing angle of the
      instrument.  Two of the ASAS scenes (with GRSFE product IDs
      ASALL04D and ASALL05D) were acquired at 48 scan lines per sec.
      Given the nominal aircraft speed of 100 meters per second, the
      along-track pixel dimension in these two scenes is 2 meters.
      The rest of the ASAS scenes were acquired at a scan rate of 64
      scan lines per second and the along-track pixel dimension for
      these scenes is 1.5 meters.  The across-track dimensions of the
      pixels in all of the ASAS scenes are 4.3 meters, 4.5 meters,
      5.0 meters, and 6.1 meters for pointing angles of 0 (nadir),
      15, 30, and 45 degrees, respectively.  No attempt has been made
      to geometrically rectify the ASAS digital image data provided
      for the GRSFE CD-ROMs.
 
      Another intermittent distortion has been observed during
      initial inspections of ASAS imagery acquired for GRSFE.  The
      scan lines occasionally appear to shift laterally by one or two
      pixels with the direction of the shift alternating every scan
      line.  This distortion is most clearly exhibited at a smooth
      boundary between a bright area and a dark area within a scene.
      Such smooth boundaries will occasionally appear jagged in ASAS
      imagery particularly when the image around the boundary is
      magnified.  The cause of this distortion has not yet been
      determined.
 
      Investigators and analysts should also note that the ASAS data
      are stored as binary integers in units of 0.1 watts/(meter
      squared * micrometer * steradian).  In other words, any integer
      ASAS datum should be divided by 10 to recover a real number
      radiance value in units of watts/(meter squared * micrometer *
      steradian).  The factor of 10 for all ASAS channels was chosen
      for the convenience of analysts.  Analysts should not infer
      that the radiometric resolution of each ASAS detector is 0.1
      watts/(meter squared * micrometer * steradian) per raw digital
      count.  The actual radiometric resolution varies from channel
      to channel and, to a lesser degree, from detector to detector
      for the 512 detectors per channel.
 
      Processing Level Id            : 3
      Software Flag                  : N
      Processing Start Time          : 1989-07-23T00:00:00.000
      Processing Stop Time           : 1990-02-27T00:00:00.000
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;RADIANCE&apos;
      -----------------------------
        Radiance is the amount of energy per time per projected area
        per steradian.
 
        Data Set Parameter Name        : RADIANCE
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : WATT/(METER*METER)/STERADIAN
        Sampling Parameter Name        : PIXEL
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : METER
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 12.02
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : 4.25
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : N/A
        Noise Level                    : UNK
 
 
    Source Instrument Parameters
    ============================
      Instrument Host ID              : C130
      Data Set Parameter Name         : RADIANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
 
    Measurement Information
    =======================
 
      Atmospheric Conditions
      ----------------------
        Not Applicable
 
 
      Source
      ------
        The sunlight reflected from the Earth&apos;s surface is the source
        of the measurement.
 
 
      Calibration Standard
      --------------------
        Not Applicable
 
 
      Wavelength Calibration
      ----------------------
        Not Applicable
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      Processing History
      ------------------
        Source Data Set ID          : N/A
        Software                    : UNK
        Product Data Set ID         : C130-E-ASAS-3-RDR-IMAGE-V1.0
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      The digitized response of each detector element to incident
      radiant flux is characterized as a piecewise linear function of
      spectral radiance on the basis of the laboratory calibration
      data.  The data acquired by each detector in flight are
      converted to radiance units by inverting the appropriate
      response function.  The resulting values are stored as binary
      integers in units of 0.1 W/(m**2 sr).  The uncertainty
      associated with spectral radiance values is approximately 6%.
      Note that the values represent the radiant flux received by the
      sensor at the altitude of the platform aircraft.
 
      The calibration and correction procedures are discussed in
      greater detail by Irons and Irish, 1988 and Irons, et al.,
      1989.  Finally, band 1 was inoperable, but data for this band
      are included in the ASAS data set.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XD-21A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

