<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mgs-m-tes-5-timap-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MGS MARS TES DERIVED THERMAL INERTIA MAPS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_global_surveyor::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mgs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:tes.mgs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-tes-5-timap-v1.0__browserp_mgs-m-tes-5-timap-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-tes-5-timap-v1.0__browser_mgs-m-tes-5-timap-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-tes-5-timap-v1.0__dvo_mgs-m-tes-5-timap-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Putzig, N.E., and M.T. Mellon, Apparent thermal inertia and the surface
                   heterogeneity of Mars, Icarus, 191, 68-94, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PUTZIGANDMELLON2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Putzig, N.E., M.T. Mellon, K.A. Kretke, and R.E. Arvidson, Global thermal
                   inertia and surface properties of Mars from the MGS mapping mission, Icarus,
                   173, 325-341, 2005.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PUTZIGETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MGS-M-TES-5-TIMAP-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MGS MARS TES DERIVED THERMAL INERTIA MAPS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1999-02</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>NATHANIEL E. PUTZIG</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Putzig, N.E., M.T. Mellon, T.L. Heet, and J.G. Ward, MGS Mars TES
            Derived Thermal Intertia Maps V1.0, MGS-M-TES-5-TIMAP-V1.0, NASA
            Planetary Data System, 2009.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Mars Global Surveyor Thermal Emission Spectrometer derived
            thermal inertia maps.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains thermal inertia maps derived from Mars
            Global Surveyor Thermal Emission Spectrometer observations of the
            surface temperatures of Mars taken over three Mars-years from OCK
            (Orbit Counter Keeper) 1583 to 24346.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set consists of Thermal Inertia maps derived using Mars Global
    Surveyor Thermal Emission Spectrometer thermal bolometer temperature
    observations taken over three Mars-years from orbit 1583 to 24346 (note that
    in this context orbit refers to the TES specific Orbit Counter Keeper
    (OCK)), from February 1999 (beginning of mapping mission) to April 2004.Maps
    use only nightside or dayside data with surface temperatures between 160 and
    400 K.  Nightside (southbound) and dayside (northbound) maps are included
    and each has been infilled between 87 degrees south and 87 degrees north
    latitude. The derived range is 5 to 5000 J/(m^2*K*sqrt(s)).  Higher and
    lower values are not computed.
 
    An interpolation mask is provided for each map, which identifies those
    pixels where the map has been infilled by interpolation (less than 8% in
    each case).  If the interpolated pixels are not desired, they can be removed
    by multiplying the thermal inertia map by the associated interpolation mask.
 
    Browse color images including scale bars are available in JPEG format for
    nightside and dayside thermal inertia maps.  Large (approximately 3.3 Mb)
    and small (approximately 0.15 Mb) versions are included.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The processing of this data set was carried out by Nathaniel E. Putzig,
    currently at the Southwest Research Institute, and Michael T. Mellon,
    currently at the University of Colorado in Boulder.  The processing to
    convert TES bolometer temperature observations to thermal inertia has been
    described in detail elsewhere.  See the papers by Putzig and Mellon (2007)
    and Putzig et al. (2005) listed in ref.cat for more information.
 
    Note that the MGS-TES published bolometric thermal inertia was not used to
    derive these maps.  The thermal inertia model that was used to calculate and
    populate the MGS-TES Bolometer tables is different than that used here, and
    querying the thermal inertia data (i.e. from published CDs or from
    http://tes.asu.edu/data_tool/index.php) will not reproduce the maps in this
    dataset.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    This data set comprises several images that include:
 
    (1) Thermal Inertia Maps     (2) Interpolation Masks (3) Browse JPEGs
 
    (1) Thermal Inertia Maps     These images contain thermal inertia values
    derived from MGS TES thermal bolometer temperature observations taken over
    three Mars-years from orbit 1583 to 24346, from February 1999 (beginning of
    mapping mission) to April 2004.  Maps use only nightside or dayside data
    with surface temperatures between 160 and 400 K.  Nightside (southbound) and
    dayside (northbound) maps are included and each has been infilled between 87
    degrees south and 87 degrees north latitude.  The derived range is 5 to 5000
    J/(m^2*K*sqrt(s)).  Higher and lower values are not computed.  Map
    resolution is 20 pixels per degree.  Dayside and nigthside images are
    denoted in filenames by &apos;day&apos; and &apos;night,&apos; respectively.  &apos;2007&apos; denotes the
    year in which these maps were published.
 
    (2) Interpolation Masks     An interpolation mask is provided for each map,
    which identifies those pixels where the map has been infilled by
    interpolation (less than 8% in each case).  If the interpolated pixels are
    not desired, they can be removed by multiplying the thermal inertia map by
    the associated interpolation mask. There is one interpolation mask each for
    both the nightside and dayside thermal inertia maps.  The resolution of the
    interpolation masks is 20 pixels per degree.  Interpolation masks are
    denoted in filenames by &apos;msk.&apos;
 
    (3) Browse JPEGs The browse JPEGs consist of colorized representations of
    the thermal inertia maps.  A large (approximately 3.3 Mb) and small
    (approximately 0.15 Mb) version is available for both nightside and dayside
    thermal inertia maps.  A scale bar to roughly interpret the value of thermal
    inertia based on color is included on each browse JPEG. Units for the browse
    images are tiu (tiu = J/(m^2*K*sqrt(s)) ). In filenames &apos;d&apos; denotes dayside
    maps, &apos;n&apos; denotes nightside maps, &apos;b&apos; stands for bolometer, and &apos;s&apos; stands
    for small.
 
    See the papers by Putzig and Mellon (2007) and Putzig et al. (2005) listed
    in ref.cat for more information on the data products included in this data
    set.
 
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    Mars Planetocentric referenced to the IAU_1991 ellipsoid, east positive;
    Mars is assumed to be a sphere with radius 3396.0 km.  All images in this
    data set cover a latitude range of 90 to -90 degrees north and a longitude
    range of -180 to 180 degrees east.  Images are centered at 0 degrees north
    and 0 degrees east.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    This data set is available electronically via the PDS Geosciences Node web
    site at http://pds-geosciences.wustl.edu.  Formats are be based on the
    standards established by the Planetary Data System (PDS).
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Please refer to [PUTZIGANDMELLON2007] listed in ref.cat.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

