<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.vl1-vl2-m-lcs-2-edr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>VL1/VL2 MARS LCS EXPERIMENT DATA RECORD V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.viking::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vl1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vl2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:cam1.vl1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:cam1.vl2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:cam2.vl1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:cam2.vl2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vl1-vl2-m-lcs-2-edr-v1.0__browserp_geo_vl1-vl2-m-lcs-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vl1-vl2-m-lcs-2-edr-v1.0__browser_image_vl1-vl2-m-lcs-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vl1-vl2-m-lcs-2-edr-v1.0__browser_vl1-vl2-m-lcs-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vl1-vl2-m-lcs-2-edr-v1.0__dvo_geo_vl1-vl2-m-lcs-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vl1-vl2-m-lcs-2-edr-v1.0__dvo_imaging_vl1_vl2-m-lcs-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vl1-vl2-m-lcs-2-edr-v1.0__dvo_usgs_vl1-vl2-m-lcs-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Arvidson, R.E., J.L. Gooding, and H.J. Moore, The martian surface as
                   imaged, sampled, and analyzed by the Viking Landers, Rev. Geophys., 27,
                   39-60, 1989.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ARVIDSONETAL1989</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Colburn, D.S., J.B. Pollack, and R.M. Haberle, Diurnal variations in
                   optical depth at Mars: Observations and interpretations, NASA Tech. Memo.
                   TM 100057, 1988.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.COLBURNETAL1988</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Jones, K.L., M. Henshaw, C. McMenomy, A. Robles, P.C. Scribner, S.D. Wall,
                   and J.W. Wilson, Viking Lander imaging investigation during extended and
                   continuation automatic missions, NASA Reference Publication 1068, 2 vols.,
                   1981.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JONESETAL1981</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Levinthal, E.C., and K.L. Jones, The mosaics of Mars as seen by the Viking
                   Lander cameras, NASA Contractor Report 3326, 1980.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEVINTHAL-JONES1980</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Levinthal, E.C., W. Green, K.L. Jones, and R. Tucker, Processing the Viking
                   Lander camera data, J. Geophys. Res., 82, 4412-4420, 1977.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEVINTHALETAL1977A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Levinthal, E.C., K.L. Jones, P. Fox, and C. Sagan, Lander imaging as a
                   detector of life on Mars, J. Geophys. Res., 82, 4468-4478, 1977.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEVINTHALETAL1977B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Liebes, S., Viking Lander Atlas of Mars, NASA Contractor Report 3568,
                   1982.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LIEBES1982</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mutch, T.A., A.B. Binder, F.O. Huck, E.C. Levinthal, E.C. Morris, C. Sagan,
                   and A.T. Young, Imaging experiment: The Viking Lander, Icarus, 16, 92-110,
                   1972.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MUTCHETAL1972</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tucker, R.B., Viking Lander imaging investigation: Picture catalog of
                   primary mission experiment data record, NASA Reference Publication 1007,
                   1978.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TUCKER1978</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Wall, S.D., and T.C. Ashmore, Conclusion of the Viking Lander imaging
                   investigation, NASA Reference Publication 1137, 1985.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.WALL-ASHMORE1985</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>VL1/VL2-M-LCS-2-EDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>VL1/VL2 MARS LCS EXPERIMENT DATA RECORD V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1997-04-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1976</start_time>
        <stop_time>1982</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>EDWARD A. GUINNESS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Guinness, E. A., VL1/VL2 MARS LCS EXPERIMENT DATA RECORD V1.0,
            VL1/VL2-M-LCS-2-EDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 1997
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Viking Lander Experiment Data Record (EDR) Image Archive is
            the complete collection of raw images acquired by the two Viking
            Landers on the surface of Mars, 1976-1982, along with detailed
            documentation and ancillary data.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The imaging system on the Viking Landers consisted of two
            identical cameras. These cameras operated throughout the mission
            and returned nearly 6600 images. This dataset includes the
            Experiment Data Record (EDR) version of all available images
            acquired on Mars by the Viking Lander imaging systems. This EDR
            dataset is the primary record of lander image data as it was
            received on Earth. EDR images were originally distributed to
            lander imaging team members and to NSSDC as photoproducts and
            digitally on 9-track magnetic tapes. The images in this dataset
            have not been processed in any form other then generating and
            attaching PDS labels and histograms to the original EDR data.
            This dataset also includes documentation about the imaging system
            and radiometric and geometric calibration of the image data EDR
            images for loading into spreadsheet or DBMS programs.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Dataset Overview
    ================
      The imaging system on the Viking Landers consisted of two
      identical cameras.  These cameras operated throughout the
      mission and returned nearly 6600 images.  This dataset includes
      the Experiment Data Record (EDR) version of all available
      images acquired on Mars by the Viking Lander imaging systems.
      This EDR dataset is the primary record of lander image data as
      it was received on Earth.  EDR images were originally
      distributed to lander imaging team members and to NSSDC as
      photoproducts and digitally on 9-track magnetic tapes.  The
      images in this dataset have not been processed in any form
      other then generating and attaching PDS labels and histograms
      to the original EDR data.  This dataset also includes
      documentation about the imaging system and radiometric and
      geometric calibration of the image data; browse versions of the
      EDR images; and metadata about the images in a format suitable
      for loading into spreadsheet or DBMS programs.
 
      Full quantitative use of Viking Lander image data requires an
      understanding the radiometric and geometric properties of the
      Viking Lander cameras.  EDR pixel values can be converted to
      radiance or reflectance at the sensor using the calibration
      data available with this dataset.  Since a Viking Lander image
      was acquired by a single diode with a linear response, the
      radiometric calibration is basically a linear scaling of pixel
      values that is dependent on the diode, gain and offset, and
      time (i.e., Mars-Sun distance).  Additional corrections can be
      made for atmospheric effects.  The radiometric calibration data
      available with this dataset are based on pre-flight testing.
      In-flight calibration measurements (internal calibration
      images) are included in this dataset since they are part of the
      original EDR dataset.  Stereo imaging (viewing the same spot
      with both cameras) can be used to extract the 3-dimensional
      location of objects.  Three-dimensional measurements can be
      used to construct topographic maps of the landing sites[Liebes,
      1982].
 
 
    Science Objectives
    ==================
      This section outlines the scientific objectives of the imaging
      experiment and describes the imaging sequences used to
      investigate these objectives.  The specific intent for
      acquiring each image is given by the NOTE keyword of the PDS
      label.  The major scientific objectives of the Viking Lander
      imaging investigation were to analyze the geology, cartography,
      meteorology, and biology of the landing sites [Mutch et al.,
      1972].  Geologic studies included characterizing the morphology
      of rocks, soils, and other features from texture and color,
      determining the size distribution of rocks, and understanding
      sediment transport.  Cartographic studies involved mapping
      features at the landing sites, measuring surface topography,
      and determining lander location by comparing features seen in
      both lander and orbiter images.  Meteorological investigations
      with Viking Lander images determined atmospheric aerosol
      properties (abundance, size, composition, and distribution) and
      searched for evidence of dust and condensate clouds.
      Biological studies with Viking Lander image data consisted of
      searching for evidence of living things [Levinthal et al.,
      1977b].  Arvidson et al.  [1989] review the major results of
      the lander imaging investigations.
 
      Imaging sequences during the Primary Mission focused on: A)
      characterizing the surface and atmosphere at the landing sites;
      B) monitoring the sites for change; and C) supporting other
      experiments and sampling activities.  Both landing sites were
      imaged with high resolution diodes during both the morning and
      afternoon.  At VL2, a noon-time high resolution set of images
      were also acquired because of the longer Primary Mission.
      These high resolution images have been assembled into a set of
      mosaics [Levinthal and Jones, 1980].  The high resolution
      mosaics were the primary images used to generated systematic
      topographic analyses.  The scene at both sites was also imaged
      in color at noon-time, and selected areas were imaged with the
      three infrared diodes.  Furthermore, a portion of the scene was
      imaged in the high resolution color mode (low resolution color
      diodes with high resolution stepping).  Several types of image
      sequences were acquired for atmospheric studies.  The sun diode
      was used to determine atmospheric optical depth [Colburn et
      al., 1988].  Aerosol distribution was analyzed from twilight
      rescan images were the sky was imaged in a color rescan mode at
      dawn and dusk.  In another atmospheric sequence, known as a sky
      brightness sequence, images of the sky were taken at different
      azimuths from the Sun.  Scan verification and internal
      calibration images were periodically acquired to monitor the
      health of the cameras.  Several sequences were acquired to
      search for variable features using rescan images and by
      repeatedly imaging the same areas.  A series of images were
      collected to study the photometry of the surface.
 
      Image sequences supported several other lander experiments.
      Magnets on the lander and surface sampler backhoe were imaged
      periodically for the magnetic properties investigation.  Images
      of spacecraft parts, trenches, and surface sampling activities
      were taken for the physical properties team.  Images of
      sampling sites before and after sampling, including color and
      stereo images, were taken to support the planning and
      collection of samples.  Images were also taken of the entry
      ports of the sampling experiments to check whether the ports
      opened after landing and to support sample collection.
      Problems with the surface sampling system were also analyzed
      with special images.
 
      During the Extended Mission and beyond, the emphasis of imaging
      shifted to: A) monitoring the surface and atmosphere through
      the Mars seasons; B) supporting other lander investigations;
      and C) performing special experiments.  Camera health was
      monitored throughout the Extended Mission.  Surface monitoring
      included periodically looking at disturbed areas (trenches and
      soil piles) and undisturbed areas (e.g., drifts) for movement
      and change.  Images were also acquired to search for evidence
      of sediment deposition.  During the winter season, the
      spacecraft and surface at VL2 were monitored for frost
      formation.  Images, known as repro images, were acquired to
      match the lighting conditions of Primary Mission images so that
      subtle changes could be detected without complications from
      lighting differences.  Jones et al.  [1981] and Wall and
      Ashmore [1985] have image lists sorted by sun position to
      identify such repro images.  Atmospheric studies during the
      Extended Mission continued with optical depth, twilight rescan,
      and sky brightness sequences.  Some of the special imaging
      sequences of the Extended Mission included images to search for
      fog and ozone, images for photometric studies, and rescan
      images to detect the passage of the shadow of Phobos over
      VL1.
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      The original EDR dataset was produced by the Viking Project and
      Lander Imaging Team.  Levinthal et al.  [1977a] explains the
      processing done to produce the original EDR images.  Initial
      EDR processing included selecting and merging the best
      available data recorded at one or more DSN stations.  After
      merging several playbacks, some imaging data were still not
      extracted from the telemetry stream because of noise in the
      data identification tags.  Thus, special purpose software
      searched the telemetry stream to identify and extract imaging
      data with noisy tags.  In some cases, this secondary processing
      greatly increased the amount of data recovered from the
      telemetry stream.  Even with the secondary recovery, the EDR
      data contained random noise and missing lines.  Random noise
      was usually due to transmission errors.  Missing scan lines
      were filled with zero valued pixels.  Missing data appear as
      black vertical lines in the image since the primary scan
      direction was vertical.  As noted in the previous section, the
      camera voltage signal was digitized on the spacecraft to a
      6-bit integer number (possible values between 0 and 63).
      However, the maximum brightness value output from the camera
      was 62 due to limitations of the system.  As part of the
      standard EDR processing the original 6-bit value was converted
      to an 8-bit integer number by multiplying the 6-bit values by
      4.  These 8-bit values are the data archived in this dataset.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Several steps were taken to insure that the best available
      image data and label information were included in this dataset.
      The primary source of digital image data was the Viking Lander
      Imaging Team set of EDR 9-track magnetic tapes at Washington
      University.  The data from these tapes were transferred to 8-mm
      tape and then to CD-WO before this archive was made.  Since the
      original EDR files did not contain histogram or checksum
      values, automated data validation could not be done.  Instead,
      each digital image was visually inspected and compared to a
      photoproduct version of the image.  This check insured that the
      file contained the correct image data and that there were no
      obvious errors, such as missing or corrupted data.  In a few
      cases errors were detected and a replacement image was obtained
      from the EDR set at JPL.
 
      The original EDR image files were stored in a VICAR format with
      metadata attached in a VICAR label.  These metadata were used
      to populate the PDS label.  Label parameters were checked for
      acceptable values and corrected if necessary.  Catalogs
      [Tucker, 1981; Jones et al., 1981; Wall and Ashmore, 1985] and
      planning notes produced by the Lander Imaging Team were used to
      determine the purpose for acquiring a given image.  This
      information was added to the PDS label as a NOTE field.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>75-075C-06d</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>75-083C-06c</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

