<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lp-l-mag-5-surface-field-map-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LP MOON MAG LEVEL 5 SURFACE MAGNETIC FIELD MAPS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_prospector::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mag.lp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lp-l-mag-5-surface-field-map-v1.0__browserc_lp-l-mag-5-surface-field-map-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lp-l-mag-5-surface-field-map-v1.0__browserp_lp-l-mag-5-surface-field-map-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LP-L-MAG-5-SURFACE-FIELD-MAP-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LP MOON MAG LEVEL 5 SURFACE MAGNETIC FIELD MAPS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2003-10-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1998-01-16</start_time>
        <stop_time>1999-07-29</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>LON L. HOOD</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>not applicable</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            LUNAR PROSPECTOR MAGNETOMETER LEVEL 4 DATA (CODMAC LEVEL 5).
            LARGE-SCALE VECTOR FIELD MAPS AT A COMMON ALTITUDE OF 37 KM. THE
            SPATIAL RESOLUTION OF THE GRID (0.25 X 0.25 DEGREES) IS MUCH LESS
            THAN THE MEAN S/C ALTITUDE.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>not applicable</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    Lunar Prospector magnetometer (MAG) Level 4 Data (CODMAC Level 5).
    Large-Scale Vector Field Maps at a Common Altitude of 37 km.
    The spatial resolution of the grid (0.25 x 0.25 degrees) is much
    less than the mean S/C altitude.
 
 
  Sampling
  ========
    The measured parameters consist of the three vector components
    of the lunar crustal magnetic field in East, North, and Radial (ENR)
    coordinates, and the field magnitude at an altitude of 37 km.  The
    units of the field measurements are nanoTeslas (nT). 1 nT = 0.00001
    Gauss.  ENR coordinates are centered at the instantaneous spacecraft
    location with X directed eastward, Y directed northward, and Z
    directed radial to the Moon.
 
    The constant spacecraft altitude is estimated by subtracting the mean
    lunar radius (1738 km) from the radial distance of the spacecraft
    to the lunar center of figure.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    Step 1:  The Level 3 MAG data (two-dimensional, filtered regional field
    maps at the spacecraft altitude) are continued to a common altitude.
    Only those maps produced at relatively low altitudes (less than 50 km)
    during the extended mapping phase of the LP mission are processed to
    obtain maximum accuracy and horizontal resolution.  Only upward
    continuation is applied in order to prevent amplification of data
    errors by the continuation procedure.  The upward continuation was
    accomplished by applying a simple power law algorithm to each field
    component on the regional maps.  The exponent for the power law was
    determined empirically by comparing measured field components at
    several different altitudes over the same regions.  The field magnitude
    is calculated from the smoothed component files on the same
    two-dimensional grid.  The resulting two-dimensionally filtered
    gridded files at a common altitude are the Level 4 data.  They
    contain latitude, longitude, the field component in nT (or the
    altitude in km), and the number of data points in each bin.
 
    Step 2:  If a significant longitudinal gap between
    usable orbit segments is present, linear interpolation between the
    two nearest orbit segments is applied to create an interpolated
    orbit segment.  This interpolated segment is then read into the
    two-dimensional filtering code to fill in the missing grid values.
    This method is applied only when the gap between usable orbits is
    smaller than the 5-bin size of the two-dimensional filter.  Where
    possible, the resulting regional gridded files at a common altitude
    are joined together to construct larger-scale gridded files.
 
    Step 3:  For visualization purposes, a suitable
    graphics utility is applied to construct regional shaded contour plots
    of the vector components of the crustal field and the field magnitude.
    These are contained in .tif files that are included with the filtered
    gridded files in appropriate subdirectories identifying their location
    on the Moon.  The .tif files are labeled in the format east.tif,
    north.tif, radial.tif, and total.tif.  The contour interval on all
    field plots isfield plots is 2 nT.  (Note:  On the PDS disk volume,
    the graphics files are JPEG files and are under the BROWSE directory.)
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    File naming convention:  B_aaa-bbbc_ddd.TAB, where:
       aaa and bbb indicate the initial and final latitude or
         longitude for the file;
       c is the letter N, S, E or W, indicating a compass direction
         (this also tells you whether the aaa and bbb are latitude
         or longitude; for example, if c is E, then aaa-bbb must
         be east longitude);
       ddd indicates which field component is mapped in the file
         (EAS = East field component; NOR = North field component;
         RAD = Radial field component; TOT = total field).
 
     File name example:  B_120-180E_RAD.TAB describes the radial
         component of B from 120-180 east longitude.
 
     Data File Description:
 
     Column 1: Latitude at this grid point (South is negative; North
               is positive).
     Column 2: East longitude at this grid point.
     Column 3: Magnetic field value in nanoTeslas at constant altitude
               of 37 km.  The extension of the file name indicates what
               is contained in this column (EAS = East field component;
               NOR = North field component; RAD = Radial field component;
               TOT = total field)
     Column 4: Number of data points in this latitude/longitude bin.
               The bin size can be deduced from the difference between
               successive latitude and longitude values (0.25 degrees
               by 0.25 degrees for this altitude).
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Review
  ======
    These data have been examined by the data producer, and as of
    2003-10-01 are being prepared for peer review by the PDS.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    The quality of the measurements is a strong function of the
    spacecraft altitude, which varies from a minimum of about 80 km
    during the first year of the mission to a minimum of about 15 km
    during the final six months of the mission.  The best crustal field
    measurements were therefore obtained during the final
    ``extended mission&apos;&apos; phase when the orbit periapsis was lowest.  The
    surface resolution of the measurements is normally of the same order
    as the spacecraft altitude. At the lowest altitudes (about 15 km), the
    resolution is limited also by the orbit track separation, which is
    approximately 30 km at the lunar equator.  The accuracy to which the
    crustal field is measured at a single point along the spacecraft
    trajectory is limited by residual external field variations and is
    approximately 0.1 nT.  The upward continued field maps at 37 km
    altitude have essentially the same horizontal resolution and accuracy
    as the Level 3 regional maps (about 25 km and 0.1 nT, respectively).
 
 
  Data Coverage
  =============
    The coverage of the measurements over the lunar surface is limited to
    those areas on the near and far side when the Moon and the LP
    spacecraft were favorably located to allow direct measurements of the
    crustal magnetic field.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

