<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dawn-a-grand-5-vesta-gamma-iron-unc-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DAWN GRAND MAP VESTA GAMMA FE UNCORRECTED COUNTS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.dawn_mission_to_vesta_and_ceres::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:grand.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.4_vesta::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dawn-a-grand-5-vesta-gamma-iron-unc-v1.0__browserp_dawn-a-grand-5-vesta-gamma-iron-unc-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lawrence, D.J., P.N. Peplowski, T.H. Prettyman, W.C. Feldman, D. Bazell, D.W.
                   Mittlefehldt, R.C. Reedy, N. Yamashita, Constraints on Vesta&apos;s Elemental
                   Composition: Fast Neutron Measurements by Dawn&apos;s Gamma Ray and Neutron
                   Detector, Meteoritics and Planetary Science (2013), DOI:10.1111/maps.12187,
                   2013.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LAWRENCEETAL2013B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Peplowski, P. N., D. J. Lawrence, T. H. Prettyman, N. Yamashita, D. Bazell, W.
                   C. Feldman, L. Le Corre, T. J. McCoy, V. Reddy, R. C. Reedy, C. T. Russell, and
                   M. J. Toplis, Compositional variability on the surface of 4 Vesta revealed
                   though GRAND measurements of high-energy gamma rays, Meteoritics and Planetary
                   Science, DOI: 10.1111/maps.12176
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PEPLOWSKIETAL2013</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Prettyman, T.H., W.C. Feldman, H.Y. McSween, Jr., R.D. Dingler, D.C. Enemark,
                   D.E. Patrick, S.A. Storms, J.S. Hendricks, J.P. Morgenthaler, K.M. Pitman, R.C.
                   Reedy, Dawn&apos;s Gamma Ray and Neutron Detector, Space Sci. Rev. (2011)
                   163:371-459, doi:10.1007/s11214-011-9862-0
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PRETTYMANETAL2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Prettyman, T.H., D.W. Mittlefehldt, N. Yamashita, D.J. Lawrence, A.W. Beck,
                   W.C. Feldman, T.J. McCoy, H.Y. McSween, M.J. Toplis, T.N. Titus, P. Tricarico,
                   R.C. Reedy, J.S. Hendricks, O. Forni, L. Le Corre, J.-Y. Li, H. Mizzon, V.
                   Reddy, C.A. Raymond, C.T. Russell, Elemental Mapping by Dawn Reveals Exogenic H
                   in Vesta&apos;s Regolith, Science (2012) 338(6104):242-246, DOI
                   10.1126/science.1225354
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PRETTYMANETAL2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Prettyman, T., D. Mittlefehldt, N. Yamashita, A. Beck, W. Feldman, J.
                   Hendricks, D. Lawrence, T. McCoy, H. McSween, P. Peplowski, R. Reedy, M.
                   Toplis, L. Le Corre, H. Mizzon, V. Reddy, T. Titus, C. Raymond, C.T. Russell,
                   Neutron absorption constraints on the composition of 4 Vesta, Meteoritics and
                   Planetary Science (2013), DOI: 10.1111/maps.12244
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PRETTYMANETAL2013</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Yamashita, N., T.H. Prettyman, D.W. Mittlefehldt, M.J. Toplis, T.J. McCoy, A.W.
                   Beck, R.C. Reedy, W.C. Feldman, D.J. Lawrence, P.N. Peplowski, O. Forni, H.
                   Mizzon, C.A. Raymond, C.T. Russell, Distribution of iron on Vesta, Meteoritics
                   &amp; Planetary Science (2013), DOI: 10.1111/maps.12139
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.YAMASHITAETAL2013</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DAWN-A-GRAND-5-VESTA-GAMMA-IRON-UNC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DAWN GRAND MAP VESTA GAMMA FE UNCORRECTED COUNTS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2013-07-26</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2011-12-08</start_time>
        <stop_time>2012-04-27</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>NAOYUKI YAMASHITA</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Yamashita N., T.H. Prettyman, D.W. Mittlefehldt, M.J. Toplis,
            T.J. McCoy, A.W. Beck, R.C. Reedy, W.C. Feldman, D.J. Lawrence,
            P.N. Peplowski, O. Forni, H. Mizzon, C.A. Raymond, C.T. Russell,
            Dawn GRaND Fe uncorrected counting rate,
            DAWN-A-GRAND-5-VESTA-GAMMA-IRON-UNC-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2013.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Global, vestan Fe uncorrected counting rate map determined by 7.6
            MeV gamma rays binned on 30-deg equal area pixels
            [YAMASHITAETAL2013].
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set provides tables of net counting rates of Fe gamma
            rays at 7.6 MeV measured by the BGO detector of Dawn&apos;s Gamma
            Ray and Neutron Detector acquired at the low altitude mapping
            orbit. The counting rates are accompanied by their 1-sigma
            standard errors of the mean and average numbers of 5-deg pixels
            used to derive the 30-deg counting rates and errors. The counting
            rates were normalized for variations of live time, solid angle of
            Vesta, and galactic cosmic ray intensity, but were not corrected
            for variations of neutron number density. The table contains the
            original Fe counting rates and errors reported by
            YAMASHITAETAL2013.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
     These tables provide maps of net counting rates of Fe gamma rays at 7.6
     MeV measured by the BGO detector of Dawn&apos;s Gamma Ray and Neutron Detector
     acquired at the low altitude mapping orbit. The data are binned on 30
     degree equal area pixels. The counting rates are accompanied by their
     1-sigma standard errors of the mean and average numbers of 5-deg pixels
     used to derive the 30-deg counting rates and errors. The counting rates
     were normalized for variations of live time, solid angle of Vesta, and
     galactic cosmic ray intensity, but were not corrected for variations of
     neutron number density. The table contains the original Fe counting
     rates and errors reported by YAMASHITAETAL2013.
 
     The data were acquired during the low altitude mapping orbit
     (approximately 210 km from the surface) phase (LAMO). Only those when
     the spacecraft is nadir pointing (less than 5 degrees between the +Z axis
     of the spacecraft and the center of Vesta) are used to map Fe counting
     rates. At this altitude, the spatial resolution of the gamma ray
     spectrometer was about 300 km (PRETTYMANETAL2011).
 
  Parameters
  ==========
     Each row of the table provides composition information for a
     single pixel. The format for each row is &apos;(i10,6(f7.1),2(1x,e13.3)),i10&apos;.
     East longitude convention is used (-180 to 180 degrees) with Claudia
     (double prime) coordinate systems. The column description follows:
 
     COLUMN    NAME              FORMAT  DESCRIPTION                     UNITS
     0         PIXEL_INDEX       (I10)   N/A
     1         MIN_LAT           (F7.1)  Pixel latitude lower boundary     deg
     2         MAX_LAT           (F7.1)  Pixel latitude upper boundary     deg
     3         DELTA_LON         (F7.1)  Width of Pixel in latitude        deg
     4         MIN_LON           (F7.1)  Pixel longitude lower boundary    deg
     5         MAX_LON           (F7.1)  Pixel longitude upper boundary    deg
     6         DELTA_LON         (F7.1)  Width of Pixel in longitude       deg
     7         FE_COUNTING_RATE (E13.3)  Fe counting rate uncorrected  count/s
                                         for neutron number density
     8         SIG_FE_COUNTING_RATE
                                (E13.3)  1-sigma uncertainty in the    count/s
                                         uncorrected Fe counting rate
     9         FE_SAMPLES         (I10)  Average number of 5-deg pixels
                                         per 30-deg pixel used to
                                         determine the uncorrected Fe
                                         counting rate and uncertainty
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
 
  The data set is a high order data product derived from gamma ray
  counting data acquired by GRaND in LAMO as described by YAMASHITAETAL2013.
  The instrument and observation strategy are described by PRETTYMANETAL2011.
 
  Review
  ======
 
  This data set is in review by NASA Planetary Data System.
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
 
  The data set contains a global map of the counting rate of gamma rays
  emitted from Fe within Vesta&apos;s regolith.  There are no gaps in coverage.
  The depth sampled by gamma rays from which Fe gamma rays are provided is
  a few decimeters (for example, see PRETTYMANETAL2011).
 
  Coordinate System:
 
  The data were analyzed and mapped in the Claudia coordinate system, in which
  the prime meridian passes close to a small crater named Claudia.  In this
  coordinate system, the prominent Marcia crater is located at 190E longitude.
  Maps published by the Dawn Geochemistry Working Group in the literature are
  presented in the Claudia coordinate system [PRETTYANETAL2012,
  LAWRENCEETAL2013B, PEPLOWSKIETAL2013, PRETTYMANETAL2013, YAMASHITAETAL2013].
 
  Consistent with IAU guidelines, maps of GRaND data in this archive are
  presented in the &apos;Claudia Double Prime&apos; (CDP) coordinate system.  CDP
  has the same pole position as Claudia such that latitudes are the same;
  however, the prime meridian of CDP is shifted by 210 degrees from that of
  Claudia, passing 20 degrees to the east of Marcia.  The coordinate systems
  are describes in detail by J.-Y. Li in VESTA_COORDINATES_120918.pdf, which
  accompanies this archive in the DOCUMENTS directory.
 
  All of the maps use rectangular pixels with east longitudes within
  -180 to 180 degrees in the Claudia system.  For archiving, the longitudes
  were converted to CDP as follows:
 
    longitude_CDP = longitude_Claudia - 210 degrees.  If longitude_CDP is
    less than -180 degrees, add 360 degrees.
 
  For example, if longitude_Claudia = -170 (the location of Marcia crater),
  then longitude_CDP = -20.
 
  Similarly, longitudes in the CDP system can be converted to Claudia as
  follows:
 
    longitude_Claudia = longitude_CDP + 210.  If longitude_Claudia is greater
    than 180 degrees, subtract 360 degrees.
 
  Thus, the pixel longitude boundaries, which were tabulated in this archive
  in the CDP system, can easily be converted back to the Claudia system, in
  which the data were analyzed, by the user when desired.  To further
  facilitate comparison between the PDS archived maps and those published in
  the literature, a &apos;side-by-side&apos; display of each map in the Claudia and
  CDP systems is included in the accompanying browse file (see BROWSE
  directory).
 
  For further clarification, we note that map pixels in the Claudia system
  always have MIN_LON &lt; MAX_LON; however, when transformed into the
  CDP system, not all pixels will meet this condition.  For example, in
  some quasi-equal area maps, the polar pixels have MIN_LON = -180 and
  MAX_LON = 180 in the Claudia coordinate system.  These pixels span
  360 degrees in longitude.  When transformed to the CDP coordinate system,
  these pixels have MIN_LON = -30 and MAX_LON = -30, such that MIN_LON =
  MAX_LON.  In addition, for some maps, a portion of the pixels will have
  MIN_LON &gt; MAX_LON when transformed into the CDP system.  To avoid confusion,
  we included the width of each pixel in longitude as DELTA_LON.  For example,
  for the aforementioned polar pixels, DELTA_LON = 360.
 
  Limitations
  ===========
 
  Assumptions and limitations underlying the analysis of Fe gamma rays
  within Vesta&apos;s regolith are described by YAMASHITAETAL2013.  We note that
  the tabulated values give the range of counting rates of Fe gamma rays,
  but in order to quantitatively correlate them with the surface Fe
  abundance, they need to be corrected for variations of number density of
  subsurface neutrons that excite Fe nuclei and induce Fe gamma-ray
  emissions.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

