<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.hp-ssa-gcms-3-fco-descent-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>HUYGENS TITAN GAS CHROMATOGRAPH MASS SPEC 3 DESCENT V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.hp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:gcms.hp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.titan::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.hp-ssa-gcms-3-fco-descent-v1.0__browserp_hp-ssa-gcms-3-fco-descent-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.hp-ssa-gcms-3-fco-descent-v1.0__dvo_hp-ssa-gcms-3-fco-descent-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lebreton, J.P., O. Witasse, C. Sollazzo, T. Blancquaert, P. Couzin, A.M.
                   Schipper, J.B. Jones, D.L. Matson, L.I. Gurvits, D.H. Atkinson, B. Kazeminejad,
                   and M. Perez-Ayucar, An overview of the descent and landing of the Huygens
                   Probe on Titan, Nature, Volume 438, pp 758-764, 2005
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEBRETONETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Niemann, H.B., J.R. Booth, J.E. Cooley, R.E. Hartle, W.T. Kasprzak, N.W.
                   Spencer, S.H. Way, D.M. Hunten, and G.R. Carignan, Pioneer Venus orbiter
                   neutral gas mass spectrometer experiment, IEEE Transactions on Geoscience and
                   Remote Sensing, GE-18-1, pp 60-65, 1980
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NIEMANNETAL1980</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Niemann, H.B., D.N. Harpold, S.K. Atreya, G.R. Carignan, D.M. Hunten, and T.C.
                   Owen, Galileo Probe Mass Spectrometer experiment, Space Science Reviews volume
                   60, pp 111-142, 1992
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NIEMANNETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Niemann, H.B., S.K. Atreya, G.R. Carignan, T.M. Donahue, J.A. Haberman, D.N.
                   Harpold, R.E. Hartle, D.M. Hunten, W.T. Kasprzak, P.R. Mahaffy, T.C. Owen, N.W.
                   Spencer, and S.H. Way, The Galileo Probe Mass Spectrometer: Composition of
                   Jupiter&apos;s Atmosphere, Science 272, pp 846-849, 1996
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NIEMANNETAL1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Niemann H., S. Atreya, S.J. Bauer, K. Biemann, B. Block, G. Carignan, T.
                   Donahue, L. Frost, D. Gautier, D. Harpold, D. Hunten, G. Israel, J. Lunine, K.
                   Mauersberger, T. Owen, F. Raulin, J. Richards, S. Way, The Gas Chromatograph
                   Mass Spectrometer Aboard Huygens, Huygens - Science, Payload and Mission, ESA
                   SP-1177, pp 85-107, 1997
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NIEMANNETAL1997</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Niemann H.B., S.K. Atreya, G.R. Carignan, T.M. Donahue, J.A. Haberman, D.N.
                   Harpold, R.E. Hartle, D.M. Hunten, W.T. Kasprzak, P.R. Mahaffy, T.C. Owen, S.H.
                   Way, The composition of the Jovian atmsophere as determined by the Galileo
                   probe mass spectrometer, Journal of Geophysical Research, volume 103, No. E10,
                   pp 22,831-22,846, 1998
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NIEMANNETAL1998</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Niemann, H.B., S.K. Atreya, S.J. Bauer, K.Biemann, B. Block, G.R. Carignan,
                   T.M. Donahue, R.L. Frost, D. Gautier, J.A. Haberman, D. Harpold, D.M. Hunten,
                   G. Israel, J.I. Lunine, K. Mauersberger, T.C. Owen, F. Raulin, J.E. Richards,
                   S.H. Way, The Gas Chromatograph Mass Spectroameter for the Huygens Probe, Space
                   Science Review 104, pp 553-591, 2002
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NIEMANNETAL2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Niemann H.B., S.K. Atreya, S.J. Bauer, G.R. Carignan, J.E. Demick, R.L. Frost,
                   D. Gautier, J.A. Haberman, D.N. Harpold, D.M. Hunten, G. Israel, J.I. Lunine,
                   W.T. Kasprzak, T.C. Owen, M. Paulkovich, F. Raulin, E. Raaen, and S.H. Way, The
                   Abundances of Constituents of Titan&apos;s Atmosphere from the GCMS Instrument on
                   the Huygens Probe, Nature volume 438, pp 779-784, 2005
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NIEMANNETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>HP-SSA-GCMS-3-FCO/DESCENT-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>HUYGENS TITAN GAS CHROMATOGRAPH MASS SPEC 3 DESCENT V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2006-08-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1997-05-01</start_time>
        <stop_time>2005-01-31</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JOHN HABERMAN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>Unknown</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This Huygens Probe Gas Chromatograph Mass Spectrometer data set
            includes all testing and mission data from the GCMS instrument
            from May 1997 until Titan Entry on 2005-01-14. Post-mission
            corrections and processing added as appropriate.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>Unknown</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
Content: Notes
         Data Set Overview
         Science Objectives
         Mission Phase Definition
         Data and Data Processing
         Quality of Stage 2 Archived Data
         Creating Meaningful GCMS Archive Data File Names
         Structure of the DATA Directory &amp; Comments
         Document Subdirectory
         Extras Subdirectory
         Dataset Review
 
=================================== NOTES ====================================
 
2006-06-20:              ATMOSPHERIC DESCENT (ENTRY) DATA
 
The decision was made to not integrate the Titan Entry atmsophere data
(altitude, pressure and temperature at the time of each mass spec. scan)
into the direct atmosphere mass spectrometer data set files. These data can
be found in the HASI and/or the DTWG data sets that are a part of this
Huygens Probe data set.
 
 
2006-07-26:                    DOWNLOADING NOTICE
 
If you are downloading files from multiple DATA subdirectories, be aware that
the same file names are used in the different folders. If your system
downloads all files to one subdirectory, it is likely that you will overwrite
existing files with the result being that the affected file(s) will not
contain the expected data.
 
==============================================================================
 
 
Data Set Overview
=================
 
Gas Chromatograph Mass Spectrometer (GCMS) Instrument
=====================================================
 
The GCMS uses a quadrupole mass filter with a secondary electron multiplier
detection system and a gas sampling system providing continuous direct
atmospheric composition measurements and batch sampling through three gas
chromatographic columns. The mass spectrometer used five electron impact ion
sources with available electron energies of either 70 or 25 eV. Three ion
sources served as detectors for the gas chromatographic columns and two were
dedicated to direct atmosphere sampling and Aerosol Collector Pyrolyser (ACP)
gas sampling, respectively. The multiple ion source approach allowed rapid
switching between sample systems and prevented cross-contamination. The
instrument was also equipped with a chemical scrubber cell for noble-gas
analysis and a sample-enrichment cell for selective measurement of
high-boiling-point carbon-containing constituents. The mass filter produced
flat-top mass peaks that allowed rapid scanning in 5-ms steps of unit values
of mass to charge (m/z) ratios over a range from 2 to 141. The nominal
detection threshold was at a mixing ratio of 10^-8.
 
Pressure reduction from the ambient pressure, ~3 to ~1,500 hPa (~1.5 bar),
during the probe&apos;s descent to the vacuum level of &lt;10^-4 hPa was achieved with
micrometre-sized glass capillary arrays. A choice of two capillary arrays of
different gas conductance was used for the direct atmosphere ion source to
cover the wide pressure range during the descent. Gases were removed from the
ion sources by conductance limited getter and sputter ion pumps. The maximum
ion source operating pressure was 10^-4 hPa and the mass filter pressure was
always kept below 10^-6 hPa. The ambient atmosphere was sampled from flow
through a tube whose inlet was near the apex of the probe fairing and whose
outlet was at the rear of the probe. The pressure difference created between
the inlet and outlet owing to the motion of the Probe caused the atmospheric
gas to flow through the tube during the descent. To prevent condensation and
to cause rapid evaporation of condensates that might flow through the gas
sampling system, the inlet section, upstream from the sampling area, was
heated up to 80 deg. C, and reached temperatures that depended on gas flow
rates through the inlet line.
 
The measurement sequence was pre-programmed. Direct atmospheric samples were
taken nearly continuously during the entire descent, interrupted only when the
ACP samples and the contents of the rare-gas and the sample-enrichment cells
were analysed.
 
The sample inlet system and the mass spectrometer were sealed under vacuum
until exposed to the ambient atmosphere after jettison of the probe&apos;s heat
shield. The descent sequence was properly executed during the mission.
However, ion source 5, serving as the detector for the N2-CO separation
column, ceased operation owing to an electrical malfunction early in the
descent. This resulted in the loss of all data from this column, and in
particular the measurement of the CO height profile. Coincidentally, external
perturbations affecting the Huygens probe motion were also experienced at the
same time.
 
 
Science Objectives
==================
 
Written PRIOR TO the Huygens Mission Titan Atmosphere Entry Event
-----------------------------------------------------------------
Titan is unique in the solar system in several respects. The dense atmosphere
is still chemically reducing, even though Titan is small enough to allow
hydrogen to escape readily from its gravitational field. The major
constituents of the atmosphere, nitrogen and methane, are continuously broken
apart by a combination of solar UV, impinging electrons from Saturn?s
magnetosphere, and a steady flux of cosmic rays. The resulting molecular
fragments recombine to form a variety of new species, many of which were
detected for the first time by Voyager 1. The existence of still more complex
compounds is manifested by the ubiquitous, surface-hiding aerosol blanket. In
addition to hydrocarbons and nitriles, the atmosphere is known to contain CO,
CO2 and externally delivered H2O. The origin of this atmosphere, the processes
involved in its evolution, the end products and their subsequent fate as they
interact with the surface remain to be elucidated. A particularly interesting
aspect of this investigation is the possible relevance of the chemical
evolution currently occurring on Titan to some of the prebiotic syntheses that
took place on the early Earth. It is the purpose of the GCMS to provide an
accurate analysis of Titan?s atmospheric composition along the descent
trajectory of the Huygens Probe. The instrument is a follow-on to others used
in making measurements of the atmosphere of Venus and Jupiter (see the
references cited near the end of this document&gt;.
 
 
Written AFTER the Huygens Mission Titan Atmosphere Entry Event
--------------------------------------------------------------
Data were collected for two hours and 27 min from an altitude of 146 km to the
surface. The Huygens probe and the instrument survived the surface impact,
allowing data collection of gases evaporated from the surface for an
additional 69 min. UNFORTUNATELY, the loss of the Probe to Orbiter &apos;A&apos; data
channel resulted in a failure to receive 50% of the GCMS data!
 
Saturn&apos;s largest moon, Titan, remains an enigma, explored only by remote
sensing from Earth, and by the Voyager and Cassini spacecraft. The most
puzzling aspects include the origin of the molecular nitrogen and methane
in its atmosphere, and the mechanism(s) by which methane is maintained in the
face of rapid destruction by photolysis. The Huygens probe, launched from the
Cassini spacecraft, has made the first direct observations of the satellite&apos;s
surface and lower atmosphere. Here we report direct atmospheric measurements
from the Gas Chromatograph Mass Spectrometer (GCMS), including altitude
profiles of the constituents, isotopic ratios and trace species (including
organic compounds). The primary constituents were confirmed to be nitrogen and
methane. Noble gases other than argon were not detected. The argon includes
primordial 36Ar, and the radiogenic isotope 40Ar, providing an important
constraint on the outgassing history of Titan. Trace organic species,
including cyanogen and ethane, were found in surface measurements.
 
Determining the composition of the atmosphere of Titan and the nature of the
aerosols making up the surface-hiding haze layers are two of the primary
objectives of the Cassini-Huygens mission. Whereas nitrogen (N2) and methane
(CH4 ) were well established as the major atmospheric constituents after the
Voyager 1 encounter, the vertical distribution of methane, the isotopic ratio
of N in N2 and the abundances and isotope ratios of noble gases, including
radiogenic 40Ar, were not measured by the Voyager remote-sensing observations.
Similarly, photochemically produced trace gases in the upper atmosphere had
been identified by the Voyager Infrared Radiometer and Spectrometer (IRIS),
but the fate of these constituents remained obscure. To what extent did they
form more complex molecules, for example, before condensing and precipitating
on the surface?
 
The Gas Chromatograph Mass Spectrometer (GCMS) on the Huygens probe was
designed to help answer these and other questions concerning the atmosphere of
Titan, to measure isotope abundances, and to attempt to analyse condensed
phases (including isotope ratios) on the surface.
 
The GCMS composition and isotopic measurements provide important constraints
on models of the formation of Titan and its atmosphere in particular, and on
theories of the protosolar nebula and the origin and evolution of planetary
systems and atmospheres in general. It is thought that planetary atmospheres
are generated in two principal ways: by accretion of a portion of the solar
nebula, or by impact of gas-rich planetesimals. A variation on the theme of
solar nebula accretion is a subnebula in the region surrounding a giant planet
such as Saturn. The giant planets seem to be an example of a blend of solar
nebula accretion and degassing from planetesimals, because Jupiter has a
proportional endowment of heavy noble gases and other heavy elements (relative
to hydrogen) that is greater than existed in the solar nebula. The rarity of
noble gases in the atmosphere of Earth has long been viewed as strong support
for a planetesimal influx, and the near absence of noble gases from Titan, as
we will discuss later, provides more support for this hypothesis. Except for
36Ar, heavy primordial noble gases were not detected by the GCMS instrument,
yielding an upper limit for 38Ar, krypton and xenon below mole fractions of
10^-8 . The mole fraction of 36Ar is (2.8 +- 0.3) x 10^-7. This value will
become more precise with further work.
 
The photochemistry of nitrogen and methane leads to the formation of complex
hydrocarbons and nitriles. Methane is also key to themaintenance of the thick
nitrogen atmosphere. The nitrogen atmosphere would gradually condense in the
absence of warming resulting from the hydrocarbon haze and the H2-N2 and
CH4-N2 collision-induced opacity in the infrared. The height dependence of the
methane abundance in the well-mixed atmosphere could not be determined until
the Huygens probe measurements were carried out. Results of the data analysis
show that the mole fraction of methane is 1.41 x 10^-2 in the stratosphere,
increasing below the tropopause, levelling off at 4.9 x 10^-2 near the
surface. The uncertainty in these methane measurements is +-5%. Rapid increase
of the methane signal after landing suggests that liquid methane exists on the
surface, together with several species of higher molecular weight. GCMS
isotopic measurements of carbon, nitrogen, hydrogen and argon further help to
constrain atmospheric evolution and composition models. The isotopic ratio of
12C/13C is 82.3 +- 1, of 14N/15N is 183 +- 5, and of D/H is
(2.3 +- 0.5) x 10^-4. Radiogenic 40Ar was detected at a mole fraction of
(4.32 +- 0.1) x 10^-5.
 
 
Mission Phase Definition
========================
 
Each operation of the GCMS instrument(s) falls into one of five categories.
 
Phase          Description
--------------+---------------------------------------------------------------
pre-delivery   Ground Check-Out and Entry simulation testing and calibration
at GSFC        work done with the unit flown to Titan. 1997 (May - September)
--------------+---------------------------------------------------------------
post-delivery  Ground Check-Out testing performed at KSC before and after
at KSC         the mechanical and electrical integration of the flown GCMS
               with the Huygens Probe 1997 (June - September)
--------------+---------------------------------------------------------------
post-launch    Flight Check-Out testing during the CRUISE Mission phase
CRUISE         beginning in October 1997 and ending in December 2004
--------------+---------------------------------------------------------------
ENTRY          Titan Atmosphere DESCENT (Entry) Mission:  2005-01-14
--------------+---------------------------------------------------------------
post-entry     GCMS SPARE Instrument Ground Check-Out and calibration and
at GSFC        characterization testing done at GSFC. 1997 - ?
--------------+---------------------------------------------------------------
 
 
Pre-delivery instrument operations at GSFC:
-------------------------------------------
One Entry Simulation test was performed with the unit flown to Titan during
May 1997. No gases were introduced into the instrument. The data represent
instrument residual background. Valves and heaters were functional. This
data is archived in the /DATA/19970506_DESCENT_BENCH/ folder.
 
     Instrument Calibration testing done pre-delivery:
     -------------------------------------------------
     Much work was performed on the sensor in the laboratory to evaluate its
     performance. Brief summaries of selected studies are included in the
     /DOCUMENT/PRELAUNCH_CALIBRATION/ folder of this archive. The data from
     these tests is both poorly documented and the data files are archived
     using formats that are poorly documented and difficult to recover. At
     the time of the first data delivery, we will NOT be archiving any of
     this data. We are working to recover the data files and will archive
     these when possible.
 
 
Post-delivery instrument operations at KSC:
-------------------------------------------
The flown GCMS instrument was delivered to the facilities at the Kennedy Space
Center for integration with the Huygens Probe craft. It was operated several
times to verify its operation and performance. These tests were performed
before and after mechanical and electrical integration with the Huygens Probe
and before and after the final &apos;closure&apos; of the spacecraft. These tests were all
performed using a SUN Workstation and, because of storage space issues, the
files were archived in compressed formats on various media. Much of the hardware
necessary to read these archive media is no longer available. We are working to
resolve these issues. The data that has been recovered is included with this
dataset. Additional data will be added to the archives as it is recovered.
 
 
Post-Launch operations - CRUISE mode:
-------------------------------------
Following launch on October 15, 1997 the GCMS instrument was operated 21
times. Sixteen of these were Flight Check-Out tests, performed
approximately every six months. These are called Type 1 (FCO1), Type 1B
(FCO1B) or Type 2 (FCO2) tests. The FCO1B test is a slightly modified FCO1
test. Additional details about the FCO1 and FCO2 tests are documented in the
file /EXTRAS/DOCUMENTS/FS_CRUISE_OPS.PDF. One important change that was made
after the cruise operations document was finalized was that no operations of
the GCMS valves were allowed.
 
The Cruise Checkout Scenario 1 (Flight Check-Out Type 1 &amp; 1B) tests are done
to verify the proper operation of the GCMS instrument. The instrument is
powered on in its pre-T0 configuration to allow the electronics and mass
spectrometer (MS) hardware to warm-up and stabilize. (T0 is defined as the
start time of the Entry mission. This time is &apos;declared&apos; either by a
gravity-switch or by software. During the testing, software defines the
T0 time.) Ion source #5 is primarily used but all of the ion sources are
operated for short intervals and return data for programmed test sequences.
When the GCMS is first powered on for a FCO test, the ion pumps were NOT
turned on. This was done so that a relatively large residual background gas
sample would be present for MS analysis and so that the test could monitor
the operation of the ion pump when it was turned on. These data are used to
evaluate the health of the GCMS Instrument. The Flight  Check-Out tests 2, 4,
6, 8, 10, 12, 13, 15, 16, NO_PREHEATING and PREHEATING are all Type 1 or
Type 1B tests. As the data is first processed by the SUN Workstation a
standard packet of graphs is produced for each test. These packets are
archived in the /EXTRAS/FLIGHT_CHECKOUT/ folder.
 
The Cruise Checkout Scenario 2 (Flight Check-Out Type 2) tests are similar to
the Type 1 tests. During a Type 2 test, selected parameters are varied to
evaluate the &apos;fine-tuned&apos; status of the GCMS instrument since the ageing of
the electronics or vibrations or the thermal condition of the instrument
could cause changes to the tuned condition of the GCMS. Had detrimental
changes been observed, software patches could have developed and uploaded
to correct the condition. No problems were identified! The Flight Check-Out
tests 1, 3, 5, 7, 9, 11 and 14 were Type 2 tests. The standard package of
instrument health graphics created as the SUN workstation processed the
telemetry is archived and available for review in the
/EXTRAS/FLIGHT_CHECKOUT/ folder.
 
Two of the tests were planned pre-entry battery depassivation tests, to be
performed shortly before the probe was released from the orbiter, where
little instrument data was returned.  The purpose of these tests was that
the probe batteries needed to be &apos;exercised&apos; to insure optimal performance
during Titan entry: the data from these tests is located in the folders
/DATA/20040919_BAT_DEPSV1/ and /DATA/20041205_BAT_DEPSV2/.
 
In 2003 a decision to have a spacecraft option available to allow the probe&apos;s
electronics system to warm-up, called a &apos;pre-heating&apos; option, required the
upload of a software patch to the GCMS instrument: 1 data folder resulted from
this activity: /DATA/20031206_PATCHING/. The patched GCMS was then tested to
verify both the non-pre-heating and the pre-heating operations modes. These
data are archived in the /DATA/20031209_NO_PREHEATING/ and the
/DATA/20031213_PREHEATING/ folders. Be aware that the total files size of the
pre-heating folder is large because the GCMS was powered on and producing
data for ~7 hours as opposed to the traditional ~3 hours necessary with the
standard Flight Check-Out tests.
 
***************************************
WHY PRE-HEATING? See [LEBRETONETAL2005]
***************************************
 
 
Titan Atmosphere Entry - DESCENT:
---------------------------------
Data were collected for two hours and 27 min from an altitude of 146 km to the
surface. The Huygens probe and the instrument survived the surface impact,
allowing data collection of gases evaporated from the surface for an
additional 69 min. The failure of the &apos;A&apos; telemetry channel between the Probe
and Orbiter meant that we only received ~50% of the data generated by the
GCMS instrument.
 
The mass spectrometer has 5 sample input ports. During the sequence there are
times when it is desireable to monitor the samples from all 5 sources. The
generation of this volume of data greatly exceeds the total data bandwidth
alloted to the Probe Mission. The design of the MS instrument, with 5 inputs
but 1 quadrupole mass filter and electron multiplier detector dictates that
only 1 of the data sources can be monitored at any time. This does reduce the
bandwidth demands on the data system but the creation of a full MS sweep
approximately every 1 second still creates a large volume of data: enough to
exceed the bandwidth alloted to the GCMS instrument. Many iterations were
evaluated relative to the question of how to select the data for telemetry.
It was concluded that attempting to select which of the 5 MS data sources
yielded the &apos;most meaningful&apos; data from a single mass sweep was too risky.
Thus, when multiple data sources are being monitored, the data packetizer
selects data from Source 1 then from Source 2 then from Source 3 etc. and
repeats the sequence for the &apos;active&apos; data sources. This means that if only
1 data source is activated then the temporal resolution for that source will
be ~1 second.  When 4 or 5 data sources are simultaneously active, the
temporal resolution of the data from each source will be ~4 or ~5 seconds
respectively. These temporal resolutions assume that both telemetry data
channels are functioning correctly.
 
The probe to orbiter telemetry system utilizes two independent communication
channels; designates the &apos;A&apos; and &apos;B&apos; channels (streams). The original mission
plan suggested that the instruments use these channels redundantly: i.e.,
all data packets be sent to both channels. The GCMS team decided that a low
risk solution to the data volume problem would be to send sequential data
packets from each data source alternately to each channel: i.e., sweep 1 goes
to the &apos;A&apos; channel, sweep 2 goes to the &apos;B&apos; channel, sweep 3 goes to the &apos;A&apos;
channel etc.. The only exception is the Housekeeping Type 2 data which is
deemed important enough to be sent redundantly to both data channels. This
effectively doubles the volume of GCMS data returned. Using this technique
even if one data channel failed the GCMS would still return the volume of
data specified in the original mission plan, albeit with lower temporal
resolution. And, in fact, one data channel did not work and so the GCMS
team lost ~50% of the data generated by the instrument.
 
As programmed, the GCMS was powered on in pre-T0 time to warm up and
stabilize its components. Unlike the Flight Check-Out tests, no data was
made available for this pre-T0 operation.  T0 was declared by the probe at
UTC 2005-01-14T09:10:20.760 at which time power was applied to the GCMS
instrument. Refer to the /DOCUMENT/ subdirectory where the document(s)
DESC_FM_08F or WORKING_SEQUENCE reveal the exact timings and details and to
BLOCK_DIAGRAM to identify the component heaters and valves indicated.
 
The GCMS instrument&apos;s operations can be categorized as indicated in the table
that follows. The actual temporal resolution of the data during each phase
is indicated for the DESCENT MISSION where the &apos;A&apos; telemetry channel failed
to function.  (All times indicated in the table, below, assume T0 to be
time 0. s.)
 
Sampling Event(s)      What&apos;s Happening as the GCMS falls through Atmosphere
----------------------+-------------------------------------------------------
Pre-T0                 GCMS is powered on for warm-up and component
                       stabilization. Data system is operating but data
                       is NOT forwarded to the Probe&apos;s data system.
----------------------+-------------------------------------------------------
                          Sampling temporal resolution ~2 s.
Residual Background    Apply power at time 0 s. Turn ion sources on from
                       9 - 17 s. Set key inlet system valves to their entry
                       state. Probe fires the GCMS Inlet &amp; Outlet Pyros at
                       50 &amp; 53 s.
----------------------+-------------------------------------------------------
                          Sampling temporal resolution ~2 s.
Direct Atmosphere      Open valve VZ at 52 s. Open VL1 at 56 s. Only IS1 is
via Leak 1             being monitored so sampling occurs at ~2 s. intervals.
                       VL1 is a &apos;large&apos; leak intended for use in the lower
                       pressure (upper) atmosphere.
                          Open/Close VS7 &amp; collect EC1/Rg sample from
                          1500 - 1545 s.
----------------------+-------------------------------------------------------
                          Sampling temporal resolution ~2 s.
Instrument Background  Close VL1 at 1748 s. &amp; VZ at 1800 s. and monitor
                       instrument pump-down &amp; background samples for 89 s.
                          Begin flowing H2 by opening the puncture valve IV.
----------------------+-------------------------------------------------------
                          Sampling temporal resolution ~2 s.
Rare Gas Cell          Open VL3 &amp; begin sampling the Rare Gas sample volume.
via Leak 3             Continue this analysis for 91 s.
----------------------+-------------------------------------------------------
                          Sampling temporal resolution ~2 s.
Enrichment &amp; RG Cells  At time 1980 s. open valve VE and add the content of
via Leak 3             the Enrichment Cell to the Rare Gas sample. Continue
                       this analysis for 90 s.
----------------------+-------------------------------------------------------
                          Sampling temporal resolution ~2 s.
Instrument Background  Close VL3 at 2070 s. and monitor instrument pump-down
                       &amp; background sample for 90 s.
                          Open puncture valve IVA to connect the ACP to
                          the GCMS inlet system.
----------------------+-------------------------------------------------------
                          Sampling temporal resolution ~2 s.
Direct Atmosphere      At time 2160 s. open VL2 and begin sampling the Direct
via Leak 2             Atmosphere using Leak 2. The flow rate through Leak 2
                       is ~28% that of Leak 1. Leak 2 is used in the higher
                       pressure (lower) atmosphere.
                          Collect GC Sample 1 volume from 2340 - 2370 s.
                          Collect GC Sample 2 volume from 3150 - 3180 s.
                          Collect GC Sample 4 volume from 5130 - 5160 s.
                       -------------------------------------------------------
                          Sampling temporal resolution ~8 s.
                       At time 2368 s. begin sequentially monitoring IS1,
                       IS3, IS4 &amp; IS5. This changes the temporal resolution
                       to ~ 8 s except as noted during ACP sampling.
----------------------+-------------------------------------------------------
                          Sampling temporal resolution ~8 s.
GC Sample Injections   GC Sample  1 (Grab Sample #1) at 2400 s.
 Continue monitoring   GC Sample  2 (Grab Sample #2) at 3210 s.
 Direct Atmosphere
----------------------+-------------------------------------------------------
                               Sampling temporal resolution ~2 s.
ACP MS Sampling        ACP Sample 1 (Ambient T): 3886 - 3970 s.
 via. Leak 4           -------------------------------------------------------
                               Sampling temporal resolution ~10 s.
                                             3970 - 4066 s.
                       -------------------------------------------------------
                               Sampling temporal resolution ~2 s.
                       ACP Sample 2 (250 deg.C): 4066 - 4150 s.
                       -------------------------------------------------------
                               Sampling temporal resolution ~10 s.
                                             4150 - 4375 s.
                       -------------------------------------------------------
                               Sampling temporal resolution ~8 s.
                       ACP Sample 3 (600 deg.C): 4375 - 4445 s.
GC Sample Injection    ACP - GC Sample 3 at 4388.625 s.
 of ACP Sample         -------------------------------------------------------
                               Sampling temporal resolution ~10 s.
                                             4445 - 4800 s.
----------------------+-------------------------------------------------------
                          Sampling temporal resolution ~8 s.
GC Sample Injection    GC Sample  4 (Grab sample #3) at 5190 s.
 Continue monitoring
 Direct Atmosphere
----------------------+-------------------------------------------------------
                               Sampling temporal resolution ~2 s.
ACP MS Sampling        ACP Sample 4 (Ambient T): 5935 - 6010 s.
 via. Leak 4           -------------------------------------------------------
                               Sampling temporal resolution ~10 s.
                                             6010 - 6115 s.
                       -------------------------------------------------------
                               Sampling temporal resolution ~2 s.
                       ACP Sample 5 (250 deg.C): 6115 - 6190 s.
                       -------------------------------------------------------
                               Sampling temporal resolution ~10 s.
                                             6190 - 6415 s.
                       -------------------------------------------------------
                               Sampling temporal resolution ~2 s.
                       ACP Sample 6 (600 deg.C): 6415 - 6485 s.
                       -------------------------------------------------------
                               Sampling temporal resolution ~10 s.
                                             6485 - 6499 s.
                          IS2 (ACP-MS) is powered OFF at 6501 s.
----------------------+-------------------------------------------------------
                          Sampling temporal resolution ~8 s.
GC Sample Injections   GC Sample  5 (Direct) at 6511 s.
 directly from         GC Sample  6 (Direct) at 7320 s.
 ambient atmosphere    GC Sample  7 (Direct) at 8131 s.
 Continue monitoring
 Direct Atmosphere
----------------------+-------------------------------------------------------
                          Sampling temporal resolution ~8 s.
Surface Sampling       Huygens Probe Lands at 8871 s. Direct Atmosphere
                       MS and GC sampling with a temporal resolution of ~8 s.
                         continues as programmed.
GC Sampling            GC Sample  8 (Direct &amp; Surface) at 8941 s.
 on surface &amp;          GC Sample  9 (Direct &amp; Surface) at 9751 s.
 Contiue monitoring    GC Sample 10 (Direct &amp; Surface) at 10561 s.
 Direct &apos;Atmosphere&apos;       Last GCMS MS data at 13047.125 s.
----------------------+-------------------------------------------------------
 
 
Post-Mission Calibration and Characterization at GSFC:
------------------------------------------------------
A GCMS identical to the instrument flown on the Huygens Mission resides in the
laboratory at GSFC. During the cruise phase of the mission, this instrument
was occasionally operated using the simulated probe electronics interface
with ground checkout (GCO) test sequences identical to the flight checkout
(FCO) sequences performed on the flown instrument. This &apos;spare&apos; GCMS will
be used to study and simulate the performance of the instrument used at
Titan in the hopes to better understand the results. Issues that need to be
studied include the &apos;calibration&apos; of the instrument with various gas samples
used to simulate the entry conditions (gas composition, pressures,
temperatures.) We also need to evaluate the performance of the GC and MS
instruments and their subcomponents. The data resulting from this work and
relevant to the understanding of the GCMS results will be added to the archives
by 2008.
 
 
 
Data and Data Processing:
=========================
(Refer to the document /EXTRAS/DOCUMENTS/EIDB_A2.PDF for details.)
 
The biggest problem with the processing of data from the GCMS instrument
has been the lack of person continuity of those persons manipulating the
data. Those persons who created the original hardware, hardware interfaces
and software long ago moved to new projects leaving only minimal and cryptic
instructions. Over time at least six people have been responsible for
data processing and monitoring the instrument&apos;s health. Again, the
documentation and instructions leave more than a little to be desired.
 
The operation of the GCMS Instrument generates the following types of data:
 
                           Instrument
       Data Type           Operation      Frequency
--------------------------+---------+-----------------------------------------
Unit resolution           |   All   |
mass sweep at 70eV        |         |
--------------------------+---------+
Unit resolution short     |  FCO2   |
   mass sweep at 70eV     |         |
--------------------------+---------+
Unit resolution low power |  FCO1   |
       mass sweep at 70eV | FCO1B   |   Approximately every 1 second
                          |  FCO2   |   the GCMS instrument performs
--------------------------+---------+-------+   a mass sweep analysis
Unit resolution           |   All   |       |   on one of the ion
mass sweep at 25eV        |         |       |   source samples.
--------------------------+---------+       |
Unit resolution short     |  FCO2   | Once  |
   mass sweep at 25eV     |         | every |
--------------------------+---------+  64   |
Unit resolution low power |  FCO1   | scans |
       mass sweep at 25eV | FCO1B   |       |   When more than 1 ion
                          |  FCO2   |       |   source is being
--------------------------+---------+       |   monitored, the number
Housekeeping Type 1       |   All   |       |   of ion sources being
--------------------------+---------+-------+-------------+  monitored
High resolution           |   All   |                     |  determines
mass sweep at 70eV        |         |                     |  the
--------------------------+---------+ A block of 8 Hi-Res |  frequency
High resolution short     |  FCO2   |   scans is done     |  at which
   mass sweep at 70eV     |         |   once every 320    |  each
--------------------------+---------+-------+  scans or   |  source
High resolution           |   All   | Once  |  approx.    |  is checked.
mass sweep at 25eV        |         | every |  once       |
--------------------------+---------+ 64    |  every      |
High resolution short     |  FCO2   | scans |    307      |
   mass sweep at 25eV     |         |       |  seconds    |
--------------------------+---------+-------+-------------+-------------------
Telecommand               |   All   |   When a software patch (Telecommand)
Acknowledge               |         |   is sent to the GCMS.
--------------------------+---------+-----------------------------------------
Telecommand               |   All   |   When a software patch (Telecommand)
NOT Acknowledge           |         |   is sent to the GCMS
--------------------------+---------+-----------------------------------------
Housekeeping Startup      |   All   |   Once shortly after Power ON
--------------------------+---------+-----------------------------------------
Housekeeping Type 2       |   All   |   Every 40 scans
--------------------------+---------+-----------------------------------------
Housekeeping Idle         |   All   |   As needed to satisfy the requirements
        Subpacket         |         |   of the GCMS to Probe Data interface
--------------------------+---------+-----------------------------------------
High Speed Housekeeping   |   All   |   ~every 10 seconds
--------------------------+---------+-----------------------------------------
Medium Speed Housekeeping |   All   |   every 10 scans
--------------------------+---------+-----------------------------------------
RAM Dump                  |  Dump   |   As commanded
--------------------------+---------+-----------------------------------------
IORAM Dump                |  Dump   |   As commanded
--------------------------+---------+-----------------------------------------
EEPROM Dump               |  Dump   |   As commanded
--------------------------+---------+-----------------------------------------
 
As noted previously, the probe to orbiter communication uses two independent
telemetry channels; called the &apos;A&apos; and the &apos;B&apos; channels. Each of the probe&apos;s
data system channels is expecting to receive data from the instrument(s) at
approximately a constant rate. This rate does vary depending on the priorities
assigned to the probe&apos;s data system at any specific time. With the GCMS
instrument, insuring that data is always available for the probe to pick-up is
accomplished by having the instrument&apos;s data system utilize two data buffers
and putting the (GCMS) data into either the channel A or B buffer. The probe
then picks-up (pulls) the data from the data buffers as it wishes. The GCMS
instrument&apos;s data system maintains a record for each data type of the data
channel most recently used. Thus it can alternately direct the sequential data
from each source into the correct (A or B) data buffers. The only exceptions
are the Housekeeping Startup and the Housekeeping Type 2 data packets which
are deemed important enough to be pushed into both data buffers to force data
redundancy. The GCMS also maintains a continually refreshed data packet,
called a Housekeeping Idle Data Packet, that is pushed into the instrument&apos;s
data buffer in those instances when no other instrument data is availble.
 
The Huygens Probe&apos;s data system packages the GCMS data with that from the
other instruments plus probe housekeeping data and transmits this to the
Cassini Orbiter. The Orbiter then repeats this and forwards the data to
the Deep Space Network Antennas on Earth. This process is then reversed at
JPL and ESA/ESOC and the data are separated into files: each file contains
data relevant only to a single instrument. The instrument teams then pick-up
their data file(s) from the Huygens Data Distribution Server at ESOC. This
telemetry file is in binary format and requires special software to process.
 
When the mission was developed, the only computers with sufficient power to
handle the processing of this type of large data file were the SUN
workstations. The GCMS data was processed in &apos;real&apos; time as it was acquired by
the hardware interface integrated with the SUN workstation. This also meant
that, in order to process the telemetry data downloaded from ESA, we had to
channel the telemetry data through the hardware interface in order to have the
software accept the data for processing. Several of these workstations and the
custom developed software needed to process the telemetry files were assembled.
This allowed us to process the data. This was all completed in the early 1990s.
These people were then transferred to other projects. This meant that most of us
were able to process the data only by following the directions provided to us
and that it was not possible to handle the data in any new and special way.
 
The first stage of data processing yields a number of data files, listed
below. Each &apos;archive&apos; file contains the data from one of the telemetry
channels, A or B, for one of the data packet types but the data remains in
binary stream format. The mergem.dat file is an ASCII text file containing
selected mass sweep data extracted from the gcmsswpA and gcmsswpB files.
Additional details about these files are in the GCMS_EAICD Document.
     gcmsackA.archive          gcmsackB.archive
     gcmsbinA.archive          gcmsbinB.archive
     gcmsdumpA.archive         gcmsdumpB.archive
     gcmshkhsA.archive         gcmshkhsB.archive
     gcmshkIA.archive          gcmshkIB.archive
     gcmshkIIA.archive         gcmshkIIB.archive
     gcmshkmsA.archive         gcmshkmsB.archive
     gcmshksA.archive          gcmshksB.archive
     gcmsidleA.archive         gcmsidleB.archive
     gcmsnackA.archive         gcmsnackB.archive
     gcmsswpA.archive          gcmsswpB.archive
     gcmssw.archive            mergem.dat
The software that creates these &apos;archive&apos; files also creates a standard
package of graphs for each type of instrument operation: FCO1, FCO2 and
DESCENT. These plots were used to evaluate the instrument&apos;s health following
each in-flight (CRUISE) test. These plot packages are available for review
in the /EXTRAS/FLIGHT_CHECKOUT/ subdirectory as multipage PDF documents.
 
In late 2003 it was determined that desktop computers had become powerful
enough (large enough hard drives, enough memory and fast clocks) and that
unix software had become available such that the telemetry file could be
processed, at least to a limited extent, on these platforms. In 2005 it
was discovered how to read and process the binary stream &apos;raw&apos; telemetry
file using programs running in the Microsoft Windows environment. The
end result of these works is this rather sizeable set of archived data.
 
The binary stream telemetry file and the &apos;archive&apos; files were first processed
to the Stage 1 level. These files consist of 8-bit ASCII TEXT values. All of
the resulting Stage 1 files are included in the PSA/PDS archives. This has
been done to allow users to reprocess the data in the event that they have
issues with what we have done. Additional information about the files in
these archives are contained in the GCMS_EAICD document.
 
The Stage 1 workstation &apos;archive&apos; mass sweep files (gcmsswpA &amp; gcmsswpB) have
been further processed for the purposes of the PDS/PSA archives to create
files containing data for each ion source and operating condition. The
resulting files are:
     GCMS_1FA_STG1  Ion Source 1, Fractional sweeping, 25 eV ion energy
     GCMS_1FS_STG1  Ion Source 1, Fractional sweeping, 70 eV ion energy
     GCMS_1UA_STG1  Ion Source 1, Integer sweeping, 25 eV ion energy
     GCMS_1US_STG1  Ion Source 1, Integer sweeping, 70 eV ion energy
     GCMS_2UA_STG1  Ion Source 2, Integer sweeping, 25 eV ion energy
     GCMS_2US_STG1  Ion Source 2, Integer sweeping, 70 eV ion energy
     GCMS_3UA_STG1  Ion Source 3, Integer sweeping, 25 eV ion energy
     GCMS_3US_STG1  Ion Source 3, Integer sweeping, 70 eV ion energy
     GCMS_4US_STG1  Ion Source 4, Integer sweeping, 70 eV ion energy
     GCMS_5US_STG1  Ion Source 5, Integer sweeping, 70 eV ion energy
You will find an example of the first few lines from several of these files
in the file /EXTRAS/DATASET_RELATED/SAMPLE_TABLE_FILES_STG1.PNG. The first 20
columns of data and the very last column are added during data processing.
Columns 1 - 3 contain the mass sweep time. Columns 10 - 20 contain the most
recent values of selected data from the instrument Type 2 and Idle
housekeeping data. All other data columns are the data directly from the
workstation &apos;*.archive&apos; files. Additional details about the content of
each column are available from the GCMS_EAICD document and from the LABEL
files associated with each data table file.
 
The Stage 1 files are of little direct value to most users because they, in
general, associate &apos;mystery units&apos; with the data. Selected housekeeping files
and all of the mass sweep (scan) data have been processed to yield Stage 2
data files. In Stage 2 housekeeping data files the values have been
converted to meaningful values: such as volts, amps, Bars etc..
 
For Stage 2 processed data, the mass sweep data has been converted to
counts/second and selected useful data and a column labels (row 1) have been
added. Columns 1 - 3 contain time data. For Direct Atmosphere measurements
(ion source 1), we had hoped to fill columns 4 - 6 with ambient atmospheric
data - BUT REFER TO THE NOTE BELOW! For the other data sources columns 4 - 6 are
undefined. Columns 7 - 10 contain selected values extracted from the Type 2 and
Idle Housekeeping data (refer to the GCMS_EAICD document.) Columns 11 &amp; 12
contain the Start and End &apos;mass&apos; values for the mass sweep. Columns 13 - 154
contain the mass sweep data. Columns 155 - 169 contain the &apos;totals&apos; data for the
scan. Refer to the GCMS_EAICD document and to the LABEL files associated with
each data file for additional details.  You can review samples of selected Stage
2 data files in the file /EXTRAS/DATASET_RELATED/SAMPLE_TABLE_FILES_STG2.PNG.
 
------------------------------
NOTE - AMBIENT ATMOSPHERE DATA
------------------------------
When the Stage 2 processed data files were finalized, the actual entry data
(DESCENT trajectory) was not available for general distribution. The data
columns have been filled with the value ZERO (0.)
-----------------------------
 
As stated, above, columns 13 - 154 contain the mass sweep data from the scan
started at the time indicated in column 1. The start and end masses for the
sweep are identified in columns 11 and 12. The mass step increment is either
1 (integer or unit stepping) or 0.125 (fractional stepping).
 
To allow for adequate resolution over the entire m/z (mass) range of 0.5 -
141.25, dual RF voltages are used with the GCMS&apos;s quadrupole mass filter.
The high frequency RF covers the m/z range 0.5 - 19.875. The low frequency
oscillator is used to cover the m/z range 20.0 - 141.25. At the start of each
scan and every time the oscillator frequency is changed the instrument
re-initializes the quadrupole frequency parameters. After each initilization
the first data point obtained is of questionable quality because the
circuitry and system require time to settle and stabilize and so in all
instances the sampling step is repeated. This dictates that the first value
of every sweep should be considered to be invalid and so the sweep actually
begins with sample #2. This also means that the first sample following an
oscillator frequency change should be considered as invalid. Most of the scans
are performed using unit stepping with start and end (m/z) values of 2 and
141 and so samples 1 and 20 (data in columns 13 and 32) are considered
invalid. The situation is more complicated during fractional scanning.
Again, the data from Sample 1 (column 13) is always considered to be invalid.
During fractional scaning the GCMS must change RF during the scan including
m/z 20. The GCMS performs full high-resolution mass scans (m/z 0.5 - 141.25)
by performing 8 sub-scans.  The m/z ranges of the individual sub-scans are:
       0.50 -  18.000
     18.125 -  35.500
     35.625 -  53.125
     53.250 -  70.750
     70.875 -  88.375
     88.500 - 106.000
    106.125 - 123.625
    123.750 - 141.125
Notice that mass 20 occurs during the second high-resolution sub-scan, at
sample 17 (column 29) thus this value is to be ignored in favor of the valid
sample for mass 20 recorded in the next column. A graphic sampling of the
structures and content of these Stage 2 processed files can be reviewed in
the file /EXTRAS/DATASET_RELATED/SAMPLE_TABLE_FILES_STG2.PNG. The use of
orange background indicates those readings considered to be invalid.  For the
case of the fractional scans, a pink background highlights the start and end
mass values for that scan where mass 20 occurs.
 
In the case of the files containing unitary mass stepping data (integer value
sweeps). the label (row 1) is used to simplify the identification of the
m/z (mass) value of the column&apos;s data.  The labels will look something like
&apos;X1&apos;, &apos;M2&apos;, &apos;M3&apos;, ..., &apos;X20&apos;, &apos;M20&apos;, ..., &apos;M#&apos; where the number following
the &apos;M&apos; indicates the m/z of the data in the column. Those columns with the
&apos;X&apos; in the label correspond to the initiation of the scan or the first
occurrence of m/z = 20 and should be considered to be invalid.
 
For the ion source 1 files with fractional mass stepping (high resolution)
data the typical column label will be &apos;FR2&apos;, &apos;FR3&apos;, ..., &apos;FR142&apos; where these
labels denote the fractional sample (number): i.e., 2, 3, ..., 142. Users
of these data files must determine the appropriate m/z assignment for the
row of data of interest using the start mass value (column 11) and remembering
to ignore the first sample and the first sample when m/z = 20 occurs.
 
Users of the Stage 2 processed data files need keep in mind that these data
have been processed to convert the data to meaningful values. Referring to the
GCMS_EAICD the reader will note that raw data values of 0 - 127 convert
directly to counts per sample. Larger raw data values convert to counts per
sample using the formula counts/sample = (raw - 128)^2: i.e., the instrument&apos;s
data system square rooted the original data. To convert to counts per second
the user must know that the sampling period is 4.592 milliseconds. With these
Stage 2 results, we have attempted to also remove the most obvious known
idiosyncrasies (defects) of the GCMS data. Refer to one example, below.
Additional data corrections are still necessary and will be done when we
archive the Stage 3 data products. For example, counting system (electronics)
dead time and missed data resulting from &apos;pulse pile-up&apos; conditions are well
known problems. These conditions necessitate only small corrections with low
count rates but can require significant corrections when the count rate is
large. These CORRECTIONS have NOT yet been INCLUDED in the Stage 2 processed
data files associated with this document.
 
****** EXAMPLE OF SECONDARY DATA PROCESSING REQUIRING MANUAL CORRECTION ******
Too much input signal causes the detector (counting system) to overflow. The
system was not designed to detect and flag this condition. In most instances
this is obvious as we process the data *BUT* we must manually correct the data
based on our determination that it has occurred. One example of data showing
this situation is available in the /EXTRAS/DATASET_RELATED/ subdirectory in
either of the files GCMS_OVERFLOW_EXAMPLE_STG1.PNG or
GCMS_OVERFLOW_EXAMPLE_STG2.PNG. The behavior flagging this as a secondary
counter overflow problem is the drop in the data value (at time ~-1470)
followed immediately by the large jump.
******************************************************************************
 
All of the instrument housekeeping (health) data files are archived as
Stage 1 processed data. These values are of minimal use unless the user is
familiar with the instrument&apos;s basic operation. The following tables
identify selected TYPE 2 and IDLE HOUSEKEEPING parameters and reveal the
values needed to convert the raw data (Stage 1) to more meaningful Stage 2
processed values.
 
All conversions require that the raw data (Stage 1) be converted to &apos;volts.&apos;
The conversion formula is:  Volts = (counts * 0.0201) - 0.037. In the table
the uA indicates micro-amps and A indicates amperes. The other values are
obvious.
 
TYPE 2 Housekeeping:
--------------------
 
Label          In English                         Conversion
------------------------------------------------------------------------------
ANODE1A        Anode 1 current                    uA=4.223*V
ANODE2A        Anode 2 current                    uA=4.209*V
FILI1A         Filament 1 current                 A=0.3141*V
FILI2A         Filament 2 current                 A=0.3131*V
EMIS2A         Emission 2 current                 uA=5.003*V
EMIS1A         Emission 1 current                 uA=5.003*V
H2CLPR         Column Pressure of H2              Bars=0.918*V
FBSTRNG        FB String (V)                      Volts=84.55*V
ANODE3A        Anode 3 current                    uA=4.007*v
ANODE4A        Anode 4 current                    uA=4.012*v
FILI3A         Filament 3 current                 A=0.3228*V
FILI4A         Filament 4 current                 A=0.3219*V
EMIS4A         Emission 4 current                 uA=4.777*V
EMIS3A         Emission 3 current                 uA=4.768*V
H2RESP         H2 Cylinder Pressure               Bars=5.336*V
ANODE5A        Anode 5 current                    uA=4.2168*V
ANODE6A        Anode 6 current                    uA=29.9908*V
FILI5A         Filament 5 current                 A=0.3183*V
BACURNT        BA Gauge Current                   A=0.2658*V+0.155
BAEMIS         BA Gauge Emission                  uA=31.7463*V-.18
EMIS5A         Emission 5 current                 uA=5.021*V
SHELLP         Instrument Shell Pressure          Bars=0.32131+0.19920*V
POS13_MON      +13 V Mon                          Volts=2.907*V
5R_MON         +5 Reference Voltage Monitor       Volts=1.0989*V
ACP_PRB1       ACP transfer line Pressure #1      Bars=0.918*V-0.354
ACP_PRB2       ACP transfer line Pressure #2      Bars=0.918*V-0.354
5R_FC_MON      +5R Mon                            Volts=2.0*V
EM1HV          Multiplier 1 High Voltage          uA=9.837*V
EM2HV          Multiplier 2 High Voltage          uA=9.837*V
 
IDLE Housekeeping:
------------------
 
Label          In English   Conversion
---------------------------------------------------------
Anode 1        Anode1A      uA = 4.223*V
Anode 2        Anode2A      uA = 4.209*V
Fil1I          Fil1A        A=0.3141*V
Fil2I          Fil2A        A=0.3141*V
Fil_Emis2      Emis2A       uA = 5.003*V
Fil_Emis1      Emis1A       uA = 5.003*V
BiasM2         FBSTRNG      84.550*V
Anode3         Anode3A      uA = 4.007*V
Anode4         Anode4A      uA = 4.012*V
FilI3          FilI3A       A = 0.3228*V
FilI4          FilI4A       A=0.3219*V
Fil_Emis4      Emis4A       uA = 4.777*V
Fil_Emis3      Emis3A       uA = 4.768*V
Pres2          H2ResP       Bars = 5.336 * V
Anode5         Anode5A      uA = 4.217*V
Anode6         Anode6A      uA = 29.9908*V
FilI5          FilI5A       A = 0.3183*V
FilI6          BACURNT      A = 0.2658*V + 0.155
FilEmis6       BAEMIS       uA = 31.7463*V - .18
FilEmis5       Emis5A       uA = 5.021 * V
SHELL_PRES     SHELLP       Bars = 0.32131+0.19920*V
POS_30VL                    6.63 * V
POS13_MON                   2.907*V
5R_MON                      1.098*V
IMON1                       A=0.00779*Counts-0.07288
IMON2                       A=0.007118*Counts-0.1851
Multana1       Multana1A    uA = 2.0*V
Multana2       Multana2A    0.3*V
5R_FC_MON                   2.0*V
EM1_MON        EM1_HV       uA = 9.837*V
EM2_MON        EM2_HV       uA = 9.837 * V
 
 
When the HOUSEKEEPING data is Temperature, the Celsius scale is used with
the following conversions:
 
Standard Temperatures:
    T(C) = 1/[M1 + M2*ln(abs(Rtherm))+M3*(ln(abs(Rtherm)))^3] - 273.15
 
Enrichment Cell Temperatures:
    T(C) = 1/[M4 + M5*ln(abs(Rtherm1))+M6*(ln(abs(Rtherm1))^3] - 273.15
 
where:
 
  M1 = 0.0024983939203     M2 = 0.00024717631804        M3 = 3.75056e-7
  M4 = 0.0008253           M5 = 0.0002045               M6 = 1.144e-7
 
Rtherm     = Vmon * 18.7 / (5REF - V)
 
Constants below are for temps T_EC1 and T_EC2
Rtherm1    = Vmon * 3010.0 / (5.0 - V)
 
             where &apos;5REF&apos; is the scaled value for &apos;5REF&apos; in Volts.
 
 
Stage 3 Data Processing:
------------------------
Following our post-mission calibration and characterization with the spare
GCMS instrument we will integrate this information into the data set and
forward the fully corrected STAGE 3 data files to the PDS/PSA for archiving.
 
 
 
Quality of the Stage 2 Archived Data:
=====================================
The archived data in all folders has been processed to the Stage 2 level. The
counts telemetry has been examined and the low counts data (raw telemetry
less than 128) and the square rooted counts data (raw telemetry 139 - 255)
have been converted to counts per sample and then counts per second. The
process of checking for counter overflow requires an examination of the
results from the Stage 2 processing and is a laborious process. ONLY THE
DESCENT DATA HAS BEEN EXAMINED AND CORRECTED FOR COUNTER OVERFLOW! An
examination of the in-flight (FCO) testing data will show that the overflow
problem is occasionally present and has not yet been corrected. None of the
counts data have been corrected for the known multiplier and counter problems
of simultaneous pulse arrival and electronic recovery time issues. These
issues have minimal effects on low count rate data but can become an issue
with higher count rates. Following the careful examination of all of the
data and the completion of mission simulation efforts in the laboratory, we
will release Stage 3 processed data where all of the known data set issues
have been resolved.
 
The archived instrument TYPE 2 and IDLE HOUSEKEEPING DATA have been processed
and converted from raw units to more meaningful values expressed in volts,
(micro)-amps, (milli)-Bars and such. For the DESCENT ONLY data, the HIGH-
and MEDIUM-SPEED HOUSEKEEPING have also been converted to the meaningful
values.
 
 
 
Creating Meaningful GCMS Archive Data File Names:
=================================================
There really is a method to the madness with the data file names. Refer to the
GCMS_EAICD document for additional details and a listing of all possible data
(named) products.
 
----------------------------+-------------------------------------------------
File Name                    Translation
----------------------------+-------------------------------------------------
----------------------------+-------------------------------------------------
                   Form of ALL file names
----------------------------+-------------------------------------------------
GCMS_[stuff]_STG#.EXT        REQUIRED FORM of file name and extension
                              Limited to &apos;27.3&apos; format.
                             # = Stage (level) of data processing
                               1 8-bit (unprocessed) values
                               2 counts/second values
                               3 All Stage 2 data corrected for instrumental
                                 and experimental issues
----------------------------+-------------------------------------------------
----------------------------+-------------------------------------------------
                     Mass Scan Data
           Stage 1 and Stage 2 Processed Data
----------------------------+-------------------------------------------------
GCMS_#                       Data Source (Ion Source Number)
                               1 Direct Atmosphere Sampling
                                 Rare Gas &amp; Enrichment Cell Sampling
                               2 ACP MS Samples
                               3 GC Column 1
                               4 GC Column 2
                               5 GC Column 3 (NO DESCENT DATA)
GCMS_1$                      Scan type (mass increment stepping)
                               F Fractional (0.125 per step)
                               U Unitary (1. per step)
GCMS_1U$                     Ionization Energy
                                A 25 eV
                                S 70 eV
GCMS_1US_$_                  Special Operating Options
                                X Short Scan, CO2 only
                                Z Low Power Scan, CO1 &amp; CO2 only
----------------------------+-------------------------------------------------
                     Mass Scan Data
              Stage 2 Processed Data only
----------------------------+-------------------------------------------------
GCMS_1US_B#                  GCMS Instrument Background Sample #
                                1     9 -   56 s.
                                2  1800 - 1889 s.
                                3  2070 - 2160 s.
GCMS_1US_L#                  Data through Leak #
                                1  9 - 1748 s.
                                2  2160 s. - end
                                3  1889 - 2070 s.
                                4  3896 - 3970 s.
                                4  4076 - 4145 s.
                                4  4376 - 4450 s.
                                4  5936 - 6010 s.
                                4  6116 - 6190 s.
                                4  6416 - 6487 s.
GCMS_1US_L1_GRABEC           Direct Atmosphere MS data during the time
                               the Rg + EC sample was collected
                                 1500 - 1545 s.
GCMS_1US_L2_GRABGC#          Direct Atmosphere MS data during the time
                               GC &apos;GRAB&apos; Sample # was collected
                                1  2340 - 2370 s.
                                2  3150 - 3180 s.
                                4  5130 - 5160 s.
GCMS_1US_L3_RG               MS Data via Leak 3 (Rare Gas Cell Sampling)
                                 at times 1889 - 1980 s.
GCMS_1US_L3_RGEC             MS Data via Leak 3 (Rare Gas +
                               Enrichment Cell Sampling)
                                 at times 1980 - 2070 s.
GCMS_2US_S#                  MS Data via Leak 4 for ACP Sample #
                                1  3886 - 3970 s.
                                2  4066 - 4150 s.
                                3  4375 - 4445 s.
                                4  5935 - 6010 s.
                                5  6115 - 6190 s.
                                6  6415 - 6485 s.
GCMS_3US_GC1_S#              MS Data from IS3, GC Column 1, Sample #
                                1  Grab Sample #1 at 2400 s.
                                2  Grab Sample #2 at 3210 s.
                                3  ACP Sample at 4388.625 s.
                                4  Grab Sample #4 at 5190 s.
                                5  Direct Atmosphere Injection at 6511 s.
                                6  Direct Atmosphere Injection at 7320 s.
                                7  Direct Atmosphere Injection at 8131 s.
                                8  Surface Sample at  8941 s.
                                9  Surface Sample at  9751 s.
                               10  Surface Sample at 10561 s.
GCMS_4US_GC2_S#              MS Data from IS4, GC Column 2, Sample #
                               Same as GCMS_3US_GC1_S#
GCMS_5US_GC3_S#              MS Data from IS5, GC Column 3, Sample #
                               Same as GCMS_3US_GC1_S#
----------------------------+-------------------------------------------------
           Combined and time ordered Housekeeping Data
                 converted to Real World values
----------------------------+-------------------------------------------------
GCMS_HK_HS_STG2              High Speed Housekeeping
GCMS_HK_IDLE_STG2            Housekeeping Idle Data Packets
GCMS_HK_MS_STG2              Medium Speed Housekeeping
GCMS_HK_TYPE2_STG2           Type 2 Housekeeping Data
----------------------------+-------------------------------------------------
          Files from the SUN workstation necessary to
              create/verify all subsequent files.
----------------------------+-------------------------------------------------
GCMS_TELEMETRY_STG1          Telemetry data stream as Stage 1 processed file
GCMS_HK_$_ACK_STG1           Command Acknowledge response from the GCMS
                               indicating that the telecommand sent to
                               the instrument was considered to be valid.)
                                A  gcmsackA.archive
                                B  gcmsackB.archive
GCMS_HK_$_HS_STG1            High Speed Housekeeping Data
                                A  gcmshkhsA.archive
                                B  gcmshkhsB.archive
GCMS_HK_$_IDLE_STG1          Idle Housekeeping Data Packet
                                A  gcmsidleA.archive
                                B  gcmsidleB.archive
GCMS_HK_$_MS_STG1            Medium Speed Housekeeping Data
                                A  gcmshkmsA.archive
                                B  gcmshkmsB.archive
GCMS_HK_$_NACK_STG1          Command NOT-Acknowledge response from he GCMS
                               indicating that the telecommand sent to the
                               instrument was NOT verified as valid.
                                A  gcmsnackA.archive
                                B  gcmsnackB.archive
GCMS_HK_$_SOFTWARE_STG1      Startup/Software Packet from workstation
                                A  gcmshksA.archive
                                B  gcmshksB.archive
GCMS_HK_$_TYPE1_STG1         Type 1 Housekeeping Data
                                A  gcmshkIA.archive
                                B  gcmshkIB.archive
GCMS_HK_$_TYPE2_STG1         Type 2 Housekeeping Data
                                A  gcmshkIIA.archive
                                B  gcmshkIIB.archive
GCMS_ALL_$_STG1              Copy of workstation gscmbin$.archive file
                                A  gcmsbinA.archive
                                B  gcmsbinB.archive
GCMS_SWEEPS_$_STG1           Copy of workstation gcmsswp$.archive file
                                A  gcmsswpA.archive
                                B  gcmsswpB.archive
----------------------------+-------------------------------------------------
       Data Products Created from other processed files.
----------------------------+-------------------------------------------------
GCMS_SWEEPS_ALL_TOTALS_STG2  Total Signal values extracted from the Stage 2
                               processed mass scan data files.
GCMS_MOLE_FRACTION_STG2      Mole Fraction data for the most important species
                               extracted from the processed Stage 2 data
                               and submitted to the DTWG team.
----------------------------+-------------------------------------------------
----------------------------+-------------------------------------------------
 
 
Structure of the DATA Directory &amp; Comments:
===========================================
 
/DATA/ Subdirectories:
-----------------------
19970506_DESCENT_BENCH    Final Descent Sequence Check-out at GSFC
19970802_MATED_CO1        Check-Out type 1 at KSC after probe mating
19970805_MATED_CO2        Check-out type 2 at KSC after probe mating
19970910_PRECLOSE_CO1     Check-out type 1 at KSC before probe reclosure
19970913_POSTCLOSE_CO1    Check-out type 1 at KSC after probe reclosure
19970919_CONTINGENCY      Contingency check-out test at KSC
19971023_F01              In-Flight Check-Out #1
19980327_F02              In-Flight Check-Out #2
19981221_F03              In-Flight Check-Out #3
19990915_F04              In-Flight Check-Out #4
20000202_F05              In-Flight Check-Out #5
20000728_F06              In-Flight Check-Out #6
20010322_F07              In-Flight Check-Out #7
20010919_F08              In-Flight Check-Out #8
20020415_F09              In-Flight Check-Out #9
20020916_F10              In-Flight Check-Out #10
20030503_F11              In-Flight Check-Out #11
20030918_F12              In-Flight Check-Out #12
20031206_PATCHING         GCMS Software Patching Verification Data
20031209_NO_PREHEATING    In-Flight testing No-Preheating entry scenario
20031213_PREHEATING       In-Flight testinf of preheating scenario
20040320_F13              In-Flight Check-Out #13
20040714_F14              In-Flight Check-Out #14
20040914_F15              In-Flight Check-Out #15
20040919_BAT_DEPSV1       Battery Depassivation #1 returned data
20041123_F16              In-Flight Check-Out #16
20041205_BAT_DEPSV2       Battery Depassivation #2 returned data
20050114_DESCENT          Titan Entry (DESCENT) Mission Data
DTWG_MOLE_FRACTION        Product generated from DESCENT &amp; submitted to DTWG
 
 
DOCUMENT Subdirectory:
======================
 
BLOCK_DIAGRAM.PDF         Simplistic block diagram of GCMS Inlet System.
BLOCK_DIAGRAM.PNG
DESC_FM_08F.ASC           Sampling Sequence used by engineers
DESC_FM_08F.PDF
HUYGENS_GCMS.ASC          Content of GCMS Instrument Article published in
                           &apos;Space Science Reviews&apos; (2002)
HUYGENS_GCMS_EAICD_ASC    GCMS_EAICD Document
HUYGENS_GCMS_EAICD.PDF
HUYGENS_GCMS_NATURE.ASC   GCMS results published in &apos;Nature&apos; (December 2005)
HUYGENS_GCMS_NATURE.PDF
HUYGENS_GCMS_SP1177.ASC   ESA SP-1177 GCMS article (August 1997)
HUYGENS_GCMS_SP1177.PDF
WORKING_SEQUENCE.ASC      Sampling Sequence as originally developed
WORKING_SEQUENCE.PDF
WORKING_TIMELINE.PDF      Graphic of Sampling Sequence with MODEL Atmospheres
                           Altitudes &amp; Pressures shown
WORKING_TIMELINE.PNG
 
/DOCUMENT/HUYGENS_GCMS/ Files:
------------------------------
FIGURE_1.PNG    Modeled MS &amp; GC Results
FIGURE_2.PNG    Block Diagram, Key Instrument Components
FIGURE_2A.PNG   Color version of FIGURE_2
FIGURE_3.PNG    Graphic of GCMS Instrument
FIGURE_3A.PNG   Color version of FIGURE_3
FIGURE_4.PNG    Mission Timeline with annotations
FIGURE_4A.PNG   Better resolution version of FIGURE_4
FIGURE_5.PNG    Figure of Ion Source, Lens, Quadrupole &amp; Multiplier
                 configuration. Includes vacuum (pumping) model.
FIGURE_5A.PNG   Color version of FIGURE_5
FIGURE_6.PNG    Photo of Ion Source
FIGURE_6A.PNG   Better Photo of Ion Source
FIGURE_7.PNG    Photo of Instrument MS
FIGURE_7A.PNG   Photo of Instrument MS with color background
FIGURE_8.PNG    Photo of detector
FIGURE_9.PNG    Photo of Getter Pump &amp; its components
FIGURE_10.PNG   Photo of Ion Pump
FIGURE_10A.PNG  Photo of Ion Pump components
FIGURE_11.PNG   Block Diagram of Electronics
FIGURE_11A.PNG  Same ad FIGURE_11
FIGURE_12.PNG   Photo of electronics component
FIGURE_12A.PNG  Color version of FIGURE_12
FIGURE_13.PNG   CADD cut-away drawing of instrument in its shell
FIGURE_13A.PNG  Color version of cut-away CADD drawing
FIGURE_14.PNG   Photo of electronics assembled around MS Instrument
FIGURE_14A.PNG  Color Photo, same as FIGURE_14
FIGURE_15.PNG   Photo of shell of assembled GCMS instrument
FIGURE_15A.PNG  Same as FIGURE_15
FIGURE_16.PNG   RF Amplitude vs. time showing mass scans &amp; totals regions
FIGURE_17.PNG   Modeled GC results for the 3 parallel columns
FIGURE_17A.PNG  Color version of FIGURE_17
FIGURE_18.PNG   Annotated Sample of &apos;typical&apos; Mass Spectrum Data
FIGURE_19.PNG   Block diagram of GCMS calibration system
 
/DOCUMENT/HUYGENS_GCMS_NATURE/ Files:
-------------------------------------
FIGURE_1.PNG   Integrated Titan results: Atmosphere, Rare Gas Cell &amp; Surface
FIGURE_2.PNG   Methane Mole Fraction Results from Titan
FIGURE_3.PNG   Methane and Nitrogen data around time of surface landing
TABLE_1.PNG    GCMS determination of isotope ratios from Titan data
 
/DOCUMENT/PRELAUNCH_CALIBRATION/ Files:
---------------------------------------
CALPRES.ASC    Component characterizations &amp; gas mixes used
CALPRES.DOC
CALPRES.PDF
CALPRES2.ASC   Sub-system test descriptions &amp; component characterizations
CALPRES2.DOC
CALPRES2.PDF
CALPRES3.ASC   Sub-system &amp; component testing descriptions
CALPRES3.DOC
CALPRES3.PDF
CALPRNT2.ASC   Sample MS &amp; GC descriptions
CALPRNT2.DOC
CALPRNT2.PDF
CALPRNTS.ASC   Sample MS &amp; GC with PHD information
CALPRNTS.DOC
CALPRNTS.PDF
 
 
EXTRAS Subdirectory:
====================
 
/EXTRAS/ANIMATED_GIF/ Files:
----------------------------
ANIMATED_GIF_SCREEN.pdf   Brief Overview of annotated Screen Display
                           used for animated GIF files of the GCMS Sequence.
GCMS_A2.gif               Animated GIF of GCMS Sampling Sequence.
                           Displays a MODEL Altitude Profile Insert.
GCMS_P2.gif               Animated GIF of GCMS Sampling Sequence.
                           Displays a MODEL Pressure Profile Insert.
/EXTRAS/DATASET_RELATED/ Files:
-------------------------------
DATA_PROCESSING.PDF             Details of processing the data from Stage 0
                                 to Stage 3 (4) with examples.
GCMS_OVERFLOW_EXAMPLE_STG1.PNG  Sample of Stage 1 processed data exhibiting
                                 counter overflow condition.
GCMS_OVERFLOW_EXAMPLE_STG2.PNG  Sample of Stage 2 processed data exhibiting
                                 counter overflow condition.
SAMPLE_TABLE_FILES_STG1.png     Sample of selected data TABLE files proc&apos;d
                                 to Stage 1 level showing labels and
                                 typical data content.
SAMPLE_TABLE_FILES_STG2.png     Sample of selected data TABLE files proc&apos;d
                                 to Stage 2 level showing labels and
                                 typical data content. Examples of invalid
                                 data resulting from oscillator frequency
                                 changes are highlighted.
 
/EXTRAS/DOCUMENTS/ Files:
-------------------------
EIDB_A1.pdf               EID - appendix - telecommanding instrument
EIDB_A2.pdf               EID - appendix - telemetry handling
FS_CRUISE_OPS.pdf         FS instrument&apos;s in-flight cruise operations
GCMS_FS_USER_MANUAL.pdf   GCMS FS User&apos;s Manual
 
/EXTRAS/FLIGHT_CHECK_OUT/ Files:
--------------------------------
F01_CO2.pdf                  Type 2 in-flight check-out #1
F02_CO1.pdf                  Type 1 in-flight check-out #2
F03_CO2.pdf                  Type 2 in-flight check-out #3
F04_CO1.pdf                  Type 1 in-flight check-out #4
F05_CO2.pdf                  Type 2 in-flight check-out #5
F06_CO1.pdf                  Type 1 in-flight check-out #6
F07_CO2.pdf                  Type 2 in-flight check-out #7
F08_CO1.pdf                  Type 1 in-flight check-out #8
F09_CO2.pdf                  Type 2 in-flight check-out #9
F10_CO1.pdf                  Type 1 in-flight check-out #10
F11_CO2.pdf                  Type 2 in-flight check-out #11
F12_CO1.pdf                  Type 1B in-flight check-out #12
NO_PREHEATING.pdf            Type 1B in-flight no-preheating check-out
PREHEATING.pdf               Type 1B in-flight preheating check-out
F13_CO1B.pdf                 Type 1B in-flight check-out #12
F14_CO2.pdf                  Type 2 in-flight check-out #14
F15_CO1B.pdf                 Type 1B in-flight check-out #12
BATTERY_DEPASSIVATION_1.pdf  In-flight battery depassivation #1
F16_CO1B.pdf                 Type 1B in-flight check-out #12
BATTERY_DEPASSIVATION_2.pdf  In-flight battery depassivation #2
DESCENT_AS_CO1.pdf           DESCENT mission plotted as type FCO1 check-out
ENTRY_PLOT_DESCENT.pdf       DESCENT mission data
 
 
Dataset Review
==============
 
The tentative GCMS dataset was made available to the PDS and PSA teams in late
March 2006. The files were reviewed by Roland Thissen and Heidi L.K. Manning
and their comments were made available to the GCMS team in early June.
The work of the reviewers
is greatly appreciated. The suggestions of the reviewers and the formatting
errors discovered by the PDS and PSA teams have been incorporated in this
(June) revision to the dataset.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
N/A
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

