<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.gio-c-jpa-4-ddr-halley-merge-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GIOTTO JOHNSTONE PARTICLE ANALYZER MERGED DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.giotto::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.gio::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:jpa.gio::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.halley::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.gio-c-jpa-4-ddr-halley-merge-v1.0__browserp_gio-c-jpa-4-ddr-halley-merge-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   The Giotto Mission, R. Reinhard and B. Battrick, ESA SP-1077, ESA Pub Div,
                   Noordwijk, Netherlands, 1986.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ESA-SP1077</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   &apos;Encounters with Comet Halley, The first results&apos;, Nature, Volume 321, No.
                   6067, 15 May 1986.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NATURE321</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GIO-C-JPA-4-DDR-HALLEY-MERGE-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GIOTTO JOHNSTONE PARTICLE ANALYZER MERGED DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1986-03-12T06:09:30.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1986-03-15T02:31:28.108Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>INTERNATIONAL HALLEY WATCH</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Coates, A., K.H. Glassmeier, H. Reme, M. Neugebauer, E. Grayzeck,
            and A.C. Raugh, GIOTTO JOHNSTONE PARTICLE ANALYZER MERGED DATA
            V1.0, GIO-C-JPA-4-DDR-HALLEY-MERGE-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 1992
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            GIOTTO Johnson Particle Analyzer (JPA) merged observations of
            1P/Halley
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset contains results from the Implanted Ion Sensor (IIS)
            4DH mode and the Fast Ion Sensor SW and HAR modes of the Three-
            Dimensional Particle Analyzer (JPA) experiment on the GIOTTO
            spacecraft for the mission to comet Halley. The results of the
            Fast Ion Sensor (FIS - inbound) and IIS (outbound) have been
            merged with results from other Giotto instruments. In the first
            submitted table, magnetometer measurements are included.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
Data Set Overview
=================
 
    This dataset contains results from the Implanted Ion
    Sensor (IIS) 4DH mode and the Fast Ion Sensor SW and
    HAR modes of the Three- Dimensional Particle Analyzer
    (JPA) experiment on the GIOTTO spacecraft for the
    mission to comet Halley.  The results of the Fast Ion
    Sensor (FIS - inbound) and IIS (outbound) have been
    merged with results from other Giotto instruments.
     In the first submitted table, magnetometer
    measurements are included.  Values are given for
    protons.
 
 
     JPA FIS data are from two sources:
 
    - up to March 13, 19:24:55 SCET, data are from the
    solar wind mode at 8 seconds time resolution.  The
    moments are derived from data in a 45 x 45 degree
    field of view, centered on the nominal solar wind
    direction.  There is continuous coverage in energy
    and angle.  The peak remains within this reduced
    field of view.
 
     - March 13, 19:24:55 to 22:38:17 SCET, data are from
    the HAR mode at 24 second time resolution.  This mode
    has an angular field of view accepting ions from all
    directions except a 20 deg cone in the ram direction.
     Energy-angle coverage is not contiguous in this mode
    so an assumption is made to boost the counts in each
    bin to make the distribution appear contiguous.  The
    peak of the solar wind flux alternates between the
    last two 26 deg bins during this period.  Moments are
    calculated for the regions of space sampled by the
    detector, i.e.  up to the 20 deg ram cone, with no
    assumption to increase the range beyond this.
 
     The following assumptions hold: FIS is an
    electrostatic analyzer and so cannot distinguish mass
    - except in the solar wind mode where the protons and
    alpha particles are cold enough that they separate in
    energy/charge; in HAR mode the moment is over the
    full FIS energy range so includes anything (all
    protons).
 
     The temperature profile from solar winds to HAR mode
    is not continuous due to the different bin sizes
    involved, so the sudden temperature jump at 19:24:55
    should not be take to be correct.
 
     JPA IIS data is from the 4DH mode.  In this mode,
    the Time of Flight measurement is combined with the
    energy level information provided by the IIS to
    separate mass groups, e.g., 0-1.7 amu/q (presumably
    protons).  The moments are derived from data
    collected during one spacecraft spin, i.e., 128 s, at
    each of 32 energy levels to obtain a complete
    distribution.  Pickup protons are included in the
    numbers but this is only a small effect.
 
     The &apos;JPAMERGE&apos; file includes both FIS and IIS data.
     The JPA data up to 22:38:17 are from FIS given every
    8 s.  (At this time the sampling changes to every 64
    s; only magnetometer values are listed in this
    interval.) The JPA data starts again at approx 0104
    on March 14 (MJD 13221 or day 73), and is from the
    IIS 4DH mode.  This data has a time resolution of 128
    seconds - in the merge file it is combined with 64s
    magnetometer data, which is why there are two MAG
    points for every JPA data repeated twice here.  (The
    last 16 lines are again only magnetometer values.)
 
    In the second table, the results from the FIS have
    been merged with data from the magnetometer, the
    RPA-Copernic plasma experiment, and the Ion Mass
    Spectrometer (IMS) HERS instrument to form this file.
     The original file was called GIOMERGE and its
    explanation follows below:
 
    The file contains data for the period between March
    12, 06:09:30 to March 13, 23:36:34 SCET for the MAG,
    RPA and IMS/HERS experiments and the JPA experiment,
    which ended earlier (at approximately 22:38 SCET).
 
 
     MAG 8s averaged data
 
    RPA 8s averaged data
 
    JPA 8s data up to March 13, 19:24:55, 24s after this
    time
 
    IMS/HERS 16s proton samples after March 13, 18:30:00
    64s averaged alpha data
 
    MAG and RPA data are available for all of the above
    given intervals.
 
     JPA FIS data are from two sources:
 
    - up to March 13, 19:24:55 SCET, data are from the
    solar wind mode at 8 seconds time resolution.  The
    moments are derived from data in a 45 x 45 degree
    field of view, centered on the nominal solar wind
    direction.  There is continuous coverage in energy
    and angle.  The peak remains within this reduced
    field of view.
 
     - March 13, 19:24:55 to 22:38:17 SCET, data are from
    the HAR mode at 24 second time resolution.  This mode
    has an angular field of view accepting ions from all
    directions except a 20 deg cone in the ram direction.
     Energy-angle coverage is not contiguous in this mode
    so an assumption is made to boost the counts in each
    bin to make the distribution appear contiguous.  The
    peak of the solar wind flux alternates between the
    last two 26 deg bins during this period.  Moments are
    calculated for the regions of space sampled by the
    detector, i.e.  up to the 20 deg ram cone, with no
    assumption to increase the range beyond this.
 
     The temperature profile from solar winds to HAR mode
    is not continuous due to the different bin sizes
    involved, so the sudden temperature jump at 19:24:55
    should not be taken to be correct.
 
     IMS proton and alpha data have been processed
    differently:
 
    - Proton data were obtained during ~1 s intervals
    every 16 s.  Since the measurement intervals happened
    to fall approximately midway between the 8 s times at
    which the other data in this file are given, each
    proton parameter is given twice -- ~4 s before the
    measurement and ~4 s after the measurement was made.
     Up until ~1830 on March 13, the solar wind was close
    to or slightly beyond the proton field of view of the
    HERS so V[z] could not be determined.  We recommend
    using JPA proton data for this time interval, and so
    have not included IMS proton data in the merged file
    for this early period.
 
     - Alpha data were also obtained during ~1 s
    intervals every 16 s, but the parameters have been
    calculated for averages over 4 such measurements;
    each value is therefore repeated 8 times in this data
    file.
 
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
Confidence Level Overview
=========================
    N/A
 
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XD-B3A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

