<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mgs-m-mola-3-prdr-l1a-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MOLA PRECISION RADIOMETRY DATA RECORD</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_global_surveyor::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mgs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mola.mgs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-mola-3-prdr-l1a-v1.0__browserp_geo_mgs-m-mola-3-prdr-l1a-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-mola-3-prdr-l1a-v1.0__dvo_geo_mgs-m-mola-3-prdr-l1a-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Abshire, J. B., X. Sun, and R. S. Afzal, Mars Orbiter Laser Altimeter:
                   Receiver Model and Performance Analysis, Applied Optics-LP, 39, 2449, 2000.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ABSHIREETAL2000</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Davies, M.E., V.K. Abalakin, M. Bursa, J.H. Lieske, B. Morando, D. Morrison,
                   P.K. Seidelman, A.T. Sinclair, B. Yallop, and Y.S. Tjuflin, Report of the
                   IAU/IAG/COSPAR Working Group on Cartographic Coordinates and Rotational
                   Elements of the Planets and Satellites, Celestial Mechanics and Dynamical
                   Astronomy, Vol. 63, pp. 127-148, 1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DAVIESETAL1994B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Seidelmann, P.K., V.K. Abalakin, M. Bursa, M.E. Davies, C. de Bergh, J.H.
                   Lieske, J. Oberst, J.L. Simon, E.M. Standish, P. Stooke, and P.C. Thomas,
                   Report of the IAU/IAG working group on cartographic coordinates and rotational
                   elements of the planets and satellites: 2000, Celestial Mechanics and Dynamical
                   Astronomy, 82, 83-111, 2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SEIDELMANNETAL2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Sun, X., F.M. Davidson, L. Boutsikais, and J.B. Abshire, Receiver
                   characteristics of laser altimeters with avalanche photodiode, IEEE Trans.
                   Aerosp. Electron. Syst., 28, 268-274, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SUNETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Sun, X., J.B. Abshire, G.A. Neumannn, and M.T. Zuber, Radiometry
                   measurements Of Mars at 1064 nm using the Mars Orbiter Laser Altimeter,
                   EOS Transactions, American Geophysical Union, Fall Meeting Supplement, 82
                   (47), p. F723, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SUNETAL2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MGS-M-MOLA-3-PRDR-L1A-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MOLA PRECISION RADIOMETRY DATA RECORD</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2002-07-10</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2001-10-10T00:40Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID E. SMITH</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Smith, D., G. Neumann, E. A. Guinness, and S. Slavney, Mars
            Global Surveyor Laser Altimeter Precision Radiometry Data Record,
            NASA Planetary Data System, MGS-M-MOLA-3-PRDR-L1A-V1.0, 2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            MGS Laser Altimeter Passive Radiometry Measurements
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Mars Orbiter Laser Altimeter not only provides surface
            topography from the laser pulse time-of-flight, but also two
            radiometric measurements, the active measurement of transmitted
            and reflected laser pulse energy, and the passive measurement of
            reflected solar illumination. The passive radiometry measurement
            is accomplished in a novel fashion by monitoring the noise
            density at the output of the photodetector and solving for the
            amount of background light. The passive radiometry measurements
            provide images of Mars at 1064-nm wavelength over a 2 nm
            bandwidth with sub-km spatial resolution and with 2% or better
            precision under full illumination.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The Mars Global Surveyor spacecraft includes a laser altimeter
    instrument. The primary objective of the Mars Orbiter Laser
    Altimeter (MOLA) is to determine globally the topography of Mars at
    a level suitable for addressing problems in geology and geophysics.
    Secondary objectives include characterizing the 1.064 micrometer
    wavelength surface reflectivity of Mars to contribute to analyses of
    global surface mineralogy and seasonal albedo changes.
 
    The ability of MOLA to determine the surface albedo actively is
    limited by the precision and dynamic range of the energy measurement
    of returned pulse echoes, and by the changing characteristics of the
    atmosphere. There is a passive measurement capability as well, that
    depends on the background light received by the detector from solar
    illumination reflected off the surface. This capability has been
    enhanced in resolution by replacing the altimetry in the MOLA
    telemetry packet with high-rate background counts. The detector
    images an area on the surface approximately 300 m by 300 m. The
    detector was calibrated prior to launch while in thermal vacuum
    testing with a series of noise vs. threshold tests, as well as for
    noise response vs.temperature. Packet data include detector
    threshold voltages and average noise counts once per second, as well
    as temperature readings from an interface plate on which the
    detector is mounted. The noise counts on channels 1 and 2 are now
    recorded 8 times per second, during which time MOLA travels
    approximately 375 m, for an along-track resolution of approximately
    1/2 km. The measurements have been made continuously throughout the
    mission at 3-km resolution along-track, with a lower average
    background count rate and therefore lower overall precision.
 
    A Precision Radiometry Data Record (PRDR) contains MOLA science mode
    telemetry data that has been converted to engineering and physical
    units. Each PRDR contains a 1.25 second span of data, called a
    half-frame, that is retrieved from the MOLA science mode telemetry
    packet. Therefore, 14 PRDRs are generated from each MOLA packet
    during a 17.5 second interval. Additional packet information, e.g.,
    time, thresholds, temperature etc, are stored in the PRDR.  These
    values are used to process the telemetry data into the PRDR.  The
    raw telemetry data continue to be stored in the AEDR data set.
 
    Contained in a PRDR are range value, target position, and the
    planetary radius at the half-frame mid-point, interpolated from
    precision orbit data, spacecraft attitude data, and a MOLA shape
    model of Mars at 1/16 degree per pixel resolution. Also included are
    solar illumination data and season. These data are for convenience
    in interpretation and do not constitute independent planetometric
    data.  There are 10 radiometric values or &apos;shots&apos; in each
    half-frame.  The location of individual shots may be obtained by
    interpolation for a pair of half-frames via the generic formula:
    shot_location = x * mid_pt_location1 + (1.-x) * mid_pt_location2,
    where x = (shot-5.5)/10. for half-frame 1, and x =
    (shot-15.5)/10. for half-frame 2.
 
    The range and precision orbit data are given with respect to the
    Mars Global Surveyor center of mass. The planetary radius values are
    computed with respect to the center of mass of Mars. Ground
    locations are given in the IAU 2000 coordinate system
    [SEIDELMANNETAL2002].
 
    A complete listing of all parameters contained in a PRDR can be
    found in the accompanying detached label.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The Precision Radiometry Data Record (PRDR) was not defined prior to
    the end of the altimetry mission. The files are in ASCII text format
    with detached PDS labels. The PRDRS consist of 38 columns of
    instrument science and engineering data, sub-spacecraft location,
    and ancillary illumination data.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The MOLA instrument measures the spectral radiant flux from the
    Martian surface at 1064 nm wavelength, in a 2-nm-wide waveband.
    Such measurements have been normalized to a constant mean solar
    distance for convenience. They may be interpreted as a spectral
    albedo using the solar constant of roughly 290 milliwatts per meter
    squared per nanometer at 1064 nm wavelength, given appropriate
    corrections for the illumination angle of the sun and for surface
    scattering.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The PRDRs are processed using the threshold calibrations in the
    receiver model of [ABSHIREETAL2000]. The thresholds and noise counts
    are inverted for radiant power at the detector using an analytic
    model [SUNETAL1992, SUNETAL2001] corrected for measurement
    biases. The model assumes a Gaussian noise characteristic convolved
    with the response of a 5-pole Bessel lowpass filter, using detector
    response and noise characteristics. A further correction for changes
    in the detector sensitivity with respect to temperature is applied,
    allowing for phase shifts between the temperature of the detector
    and the measurement point.  Caution must be exercised when
    interpreting these measurements pending inter-instrument
    comparisons.
 
    Time tags are given in ET seconds of MOLA fire time.  Timing of the
    shots is synchronized to the spacecraft 8-Hz real-time interrupt
    (RTI) signal, as well as the spacecraft one-second time marks.  The
    latest spacecraft SCLK timing corrections have been applied.  In the
    software version RTIB, the RTI signal counter was stored for each
    shot in the storage once allocated for laser transmit energy.
    Following instrument reset on 19 January 2002, after current
    anomalies suggested that the laser might occasionally be firing, the
    laser energy record was restored and the RTI counter was stored once
    per frame in an unused location. This packet format change was
    implemented in the processing software version RTIB2.
 
    The ground location and planetary radius is calculated in inertial
    (J2000) coordinates by projecting the MOLA boresight vector to the
    surface of Mars, using project-supplied spacecraft attitude kernels
    and the boresight calibration of the instrument with respect to the
    spacecraft. An iterative solution is obtained for the planetary
    range using a 1/16 degree per pixel MOLA shape model.  The ground
    point position vector is transformed into planetocentric body-fixed
    coordinates, using the IAU 2000 planetary rotation model
    [SEIDELMANNETAL2002].
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    N/A
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    The areocentric coordinate system is used to describe data products
    on this volume. The areocentric coordinate system, more
    generally described as planetocentric, is body-centered, using the
    center-of-mass as the origin.  Areocentric latitude is defined by
    the angle between the equatorial plane and a vector extending from
    the origin of the coordinate system to the relevant point on the
    surface.  Latitude is measured from -90 degrees at the south pole to
    +90 degrees at the north pole.  Longitude extends from 0 to 360
    degrees, with values increasing eastward (i.e., it is a right-handed
    coordinate system) from the prime meridian [DAVIESETAL1994B].  This
    coordinate system is preferred for use in geophysical studies in
    which, for example, estimates of elevation or gravitational
    potential are generated mathematically.
 
 
  Software
  =======
    N/A
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    The MGS MOLA PRDR dataset will be available on DVD media and
    electronically via the PDS Geosciences Node web site at
    http://wwwpds.wustl.edu and the MOLA Science Team web site at
    http://ltpwww.gsfc.nasa.gov/tharsis/mola.html.  Formats will be
    based on standards established by the Planetary Data System (PDS).
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The resolution of the data is about 300 m across-track and 500 m
    along-track. The uncertainty in absolute ground spot location is
    limited by the attitude knowledge of the spacecraft, and is
    estimated to be about 400 m at a nominal range of 400 km.
    The radiometry calibrations are accurate to approximately one
    milliwatt per meter squared per steradian per nanometer, subject
    to further calibration.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    The volume containing the MOLA PRDR radiometry dataset was reviewed
    by MOLA science team members and the PDS.
 
 
  Data Coverage/Quality
  =====================
    On June 30, 2001, the Mars Orbiter Laser Altimeter (MOLA) ceased
    altimetry operations. Operation in radiometry mode commenced on
    October 10, 2001, and have continued with some interruptions due
    to spacecraft anomalies and investigation of a current anomaly
    on the MOLA instrument on January 19, 2002. A total of 134 days
    of data were collected up to MGS entry into contingency mode
    on February 27, 2002. Operations resumed and are ongoing as of
    July 2002.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    The use of MOLA as a radiometer was not part of the initial
    instrument requirements. Such calibrations were part of routine
    checkout.  The long-term stability of radiometric measurements has
    not been quantified.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

