<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.co-ssa-radar-5-stdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CASSINI ORBITER SSA RADAR 5 STDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:radar.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.titan::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.co-ssa-radar-5-stdr-v1.0__browserp_co-ssa-radar-5-stdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.co-ssa-radar-5-stdr-v1.0__browser_co-ssa-radar-5-stdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Elachi, C., M.D. Allison, L. Borgarelli, P. Encrenaz, E. Im, M.A. Janssen,
                   W.T.K. Johnson, R.L. Kirk, R.D. Lorenz, J.I. Lunine, D.O. Muhleman, S.J. Ostro,
                   G. Picardi, F. Posa, C.G. Rapley, L.E. Roth, R. Seu, L.A. Soderblom, S.
                   Vetrella, S.D. Wall, C.A. Wood and H.A. Zebker, RADAR: The Cassini Titan RADAR
                   Mapper, Space Science Reviews, Vol. 115, No. 1-4, pp. 71-110, 2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ELACHIETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Elachi, C., S. Wall, M. Allison, Y. Anderson, R. Boehmer, P. Callahan, P.
                   Encrenaz, E. Flamini, G. Franceschetti, Y. Gim, G. Hamilton, S. Hensley, M.
                   Janssen, W. Johnson, K. Kelleher, R. Kirk, R. Lopes, R. Lorenz, J. Lunine, D.
                   Muhleman, S. Ostro, F. Paganelli, G. Picardi, F. Posa, L. Roth, R. Seu, S.
                   Shaffer, L. Soderblom, B. Stiles, E. Stofan, S. Vetrella, R. West, C. Wood, L.
                   Wye, and H. Zebker, Cassini Radar Views the Surface of Titan, Science, Vol.
                   308, No. 5724, pp. 970-974, 2005.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ELACHIETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lorenz, R.D., B.W. Stiles, O. Aharonson, A. Lucas, A.G. Hayes, R.L. Kirk, H.A.
                   Zebker, E.P. Turtle, C.D. Neish, E.R. Stofan, and J.W. Barnes, the Cassini
                   RADAR Team, A global topographic map of Titan, Icarus, Volume 225, Issue 1,
                   Pages 367-377, July 2013.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LORENZETAL2013</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Iess, L., N.J. Rappaport, R.A. Jacobson, P. Racioppa, D.J. Stevenson, P.
                   Tortora, J.W. Armstrong, and S.W. Asmar., Gravity field, shape, and moment of
                   inertia of Titan, Science 327, no. 5971: 1367-1369, 2010.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LUCIANOETAL2010</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Stiles, B.W., S. Hensley, Y. Gim, D.M. Bates, R.L. Kirkb, A. Hayes, J.
                   Radebaugh, R.D. Lorenz, K.L. Mitchell, P.S. Callahan, H. Zebker, W.T.K.
                   Johnson, S.D. Wall, J.I. Lunine, C.A. Wood, M. Janssen, F. Pelletier, R.D.
                   West, C. Veeramachaneni, and the Cassini RADAR Team, Determining Titan surface
                   topography from Cassini SAR Data, Icarus, Vol. 202, No.2, pp. 584-598. 2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.STILESETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CO-SSA-RADAR-5-STDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CASSINI ORBITER SSA RADAR 5 STDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-06-17</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2015-260T16:19:10.828Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>Bryan W. Stiles</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>Unknown</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Cassini SARTopo product contains surface heights estimates
            (and related measurements) of Titan in profiles between two SAR
            beams within a single SAR image.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>Unknown</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
* Data Set Overview
 
The SARTopo file contains surface height estimates in profiles between
two SAR beams. Each row in the file contains height estimates and ancillary
data that correspond to a set of pixels in the BIDR image.
 
For more information about the format and content of the SARTopo files,
see the Cassini Radar Burst Ordered Data Product (BIDR) Software
Interface Specification, JPL D-27899.  A copy of the document is located on
this volume as file BIDRSIS.PDF in the DOCUMENT directory.
 
 
* Parameters
 
A complete listing of the parameters can be found in the SIS.
 
 
* Processing
 
The encoded raw active mode data in the Burst Ordered Data Product
(LBDR) files is decoded and processed into SAR images by the Cassini
RADAR Instrument Team.  Each of the five beams is treated separately
by typical SAR processing (azimuth and range compression).  The image
strip is then produced by selecting the best beam for each pixel.  The
selection is performed by choosing the beam with the most looks.  In
the event of a tie the highest SNR beam is chosen.
 
The pixel values in the primary BIDR images will be normalized
backscatter cross-section values corrected for incidence angle effects.
The incidence angle correction algorithm is TBD and will be determined
jointly by the Cassini RADAR Instrument and Science Teams after enough
data is acquired to estimate the variation of sigma0 due to incidence
angle over the surface of Titan.  Until the final correction algorithm is
determined, the primary BIDR image will be computed with a preliminary
incidence angle correction.  The exact form of this correction can be
found in the PDS label for the primary BIDR image file.
 
These BIDR files are used to generate SARTopo files (CSV format) that
contain height estimates of Titan in profiles between two SAR beams
within a single SAR image. Each row in the file contains height estimates
and ancillary data that correspond to a set of pixels in the BIDR image.
A seperate SARTopo file is produced for each SAR beam overlap profile.
The SARTopo implementation yields 1-5 profiles in each SAR pass that are
10 km by 1000s of km long.
 
 
 
* Data
 
See Parameters.
 
 
* Ancillary Data
 
There are no ancillary data needed to use the SARTopo files.
 
 
* Coordinate System
 
The oblique cylindrical coordinate system is fully described in the
data set map projection catalog DSMAP.CAT, which is located in the
CATALOG directory on this volume.
 
 
* Software
 
No software is provided within this volume.
 
 
* Media/Format
 
The data are provided on media as determined by PDS.  The BIDR data files
are ZIPPED as described in the PDS standard.  Detached labels are provided
for the ZIPPED files; the ZIPPED files also include their attached labels.
Detailed formats are defined within the attached labels of the files and
in the Cassini Radar Basic Image Data Record Software Interface
Specification.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
* Confidence Level Overview
 The SARTopo data product has been produced using BIDR data sets that have
been calibrated. Empirical range and doppler corrections have been applied to
BIDR product being used in order to minimize image artifacts due to errors in
pointing and emphemeris knowledge.
 
 
* Review
 
SARTopo data will be validated internally by the Cassini Radar Team prior to
each release of data to the PDS.  The overall data set organization will
also be peer reviewed once by the PDS prior to the release of the first
volume.
 
* Data Coverage and Quality
 
Currently 20 SAR observations comprising roughly 20% of the surface of
Titan are planned for the nominal Cassini mission.  BIDR data will be
obtained for each such observation.  SAR observations of Titan occur
at irregular intervals throughout the mission.  Each observation is
nominally 40 minutes long.  Shorter-duration cases occur whenever RADAR
shares a Titan observation with another Cassini instrument. SARtopo data
will be available for observations that have BIDR data.
 
The SARtopo file contains estimated surface heights (and related
measurements) of Titan in profiles between two SAR beams within a single
SAR image.
 
SARTopo files will only be produced for Titan flybys that have SAR imaging.
 
* Limitations
 
Ephemeris error is expected to improve throughout the mission.  Since
there is no plan to recompute the ephemeris of previous observations as
new measurements are obtained, however, earlier observations may have
poorer location accuracy.
 
The dominant calibration error term is error in our knowledge of the
gain of the attenuators in the receiver.  Engineering tests are currently
planned to improve our knowledge of the attenuator gains.
 
SAR images are prone to artifacts such as:
 
1) poor calibrations at the edge of the beams
2) extreme noisiness in regions with a small number of overlapping
   measurements (looks)
3) scalloping and antenna calibration misalignment due to errors in
   ephemeris and pointing knowledge
4) distorted imagery near the ends of the swath due to non-optimal
   pointing while turning to make altimeter measurements.
 
Artifacts of type 2 and 4 are unavoidable.  Types 1 and 3 can be minimized
by empirically correcting range and doppler biases in the data.  We have
sought to minimize the occurrence of these artifacts in the BIDR images,
but there are still noticeable seams between beams and poor calibration
near the edges of the swath.  The artifact minimization algorithm does not
attempt to use the estimated range and doppler biases to correct ephemeris
or pointing.  For this reason location errors of a few kilometers are
possible.
 
The TA Titan Observation on October 25, 2004, was the first SAR
observation.  It has some special features.  The first (earliest) third
of the swath has noticeable scalloping in the along track dimension and
is noisier than the rest of the image.  This portion of the swath has
non-optimal viewing geometry and a small number of looks due to pointing
constraints for other Cassini instruments.  A substantial portion of the
last (latest) third of the swath is in low resolution SAR mode.  This
mode coarsens the cross track resolution of the image by a factor of 2.
It was used on TA in order to accommodate conservative SNR expectations.
In the same region of the image, an experiment was performed in which the
data compression technique typically used by SAR was turned off.  Due to
data volume and data rate constraints this resulted in fewer looks and
noisier data.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

