<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-e-v-h-mascs-4-uvvs-ddr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER E/V/H MASCS 4 UVVS DERIVED DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mascs.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-4-uvvs-ddr-v1.0__browserp_mess-e-v-h-mascs-4-uvvs-ddr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-4-uvvs-ddr-v1.0__browser_geo_mercury_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-4-uvvs-ddr-v1.0__browser_mess-e-v-h-mascs-4-uvvs-ddr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-4-uvvs-ddr-v1.0__dvo_geo_mess-e-v-h-mascs-4-uvvs-ddr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Bishop, J., Geocoronal structure - The effects of solar radiation pressure and
                   the plasmasphere interaction, J. Geophys. Res., 90, 5235-5245, 1985.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BISHOP1985</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Chamberlain, J.W., Planetary coronae and atmospheric evaporation, Planetary and
                   Space Science, 11, 901, 1963.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CHAMBERLAIN1963</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Feynman, R.P., Feynman Lectures on Physics - Volume 1, Chapter 40, edited by
                   Feynman, R.P., Leighton, R.B., and Sands, M., Reading, Ma., Addison-Wesley,
                   1963.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FEYNMAN1963</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   McClintock, W.E., and M.R. Lankton, The Mercury Atmospheric and Surface
                   Composition Spectrometer for the MESSENGER mission, Space Science Reviews, 131,
                   481-521, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MCCLINTOCK-LANK2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Wang, Y.C., and W.H. Ip, Source dependency of exospheric sodium on Mercury,
                   Icarus, 216, 387-402, 2011.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.WANG-IP2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-E/V/H-MASCS-4-UVVS-DDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESSENGER E/V/H MASCS 4 UVVS DERIVED DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-05-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2011-088T01:33:53Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-120T15:01:43Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>NOAM IZENBERG</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Izenberg, N., MESSENGER E/V/H MASCS 4 UVVS DERIVED DATA V1.0,
            MESS-E/V/H-MASCS-4-UVVS-DDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2013.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The MESSENGER MASCS UVVS derived data records consist of science
            and instrument data collected by the UVVS detector during orbital
            operations of Mercury.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== This data set consists of the MESSENGER MASCS
            UVVS derived data records, also known as DDRs. There are three
            types of UVVS DDRs: surface, atmosphere, and atmospheric model.
            There are two surface DDR data products associated with each UVVS
            observation set: a science header table and a science data table.
            There are nine atmosphere DDR data products, consisting of three
            different observation types for each of sodium (Na), calcium
            (Ca), and magnesium (Mg). There are 3 atmospheric model data
            products, one each for observations of Na, Ca, and Mg.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
   Data Set Overview
   =================
     This data set consists of the MESSENGER MASCS UVVS derived data
     records (DDRs). The UVVS experiment is equipped with three
     photomultiplier tubes, which are sensitive to three different
     wavelength ranges. Resulting spectra cover the wavelength ranges
     of the far ultraviolet (FUV)(115-190 nm), middle ultraviolet
     (MUV) (160-320 nm), and visible (VIS) (250-600 nm), with a
     resolution of 0.5 nm for the FUV channel and 1.0 nm for the MUV
     and VIS channels. There is a data overlap with VIRS in the VIS
     wavelength range. DDR products are generated from CDRs of orbital
     data.
 
     There are three types of UVVS DDRs: surface, atmosphere, and
     atmospheric model.
 
     For the UVVS surface DDR data products, one DDR will contain all
     the derived reflectance data from one MUV surface observation.
     Not all CDRs will be converted to DDRs; only targeted surface
     observations of the MUV PMT from Mercury orbit will be processed
     to a DDR.  Thus, there will only be a few thousand total UVVS
     DDRs. CDRs are converted to DDRs by first filtering out
     non-planet-targeted observations, then converting to reflectance
     by dividing the solar irradiance spectrum out of the MASCS
     radiance data. A photometric correction is then applied to the
     reflectance data for corrected data. Bins of approximately 1 nm
     bandwidth (~5 UVVS steps) are created by coadding the signal in
     each step of the bin. In a 660 step scan of the standard UVVS
     surface observation, this results in a single UVVS spectrum of
     about 132 bins.
 
     One observation set is associated with two surface DDR data
     products: a science header table, showing the instrument command
     parameters for a given observation, and a science data table,
     showing counts, derived science data, and pointing information
     for each bin of 5 steps of an observation. The surface DDRs are
     in binary table format, and each is described by a detached PDS
     label. The label points to an associated format file that defines
     the fields of the binary table contained within the data file.
 
     The UVVS atmosphere DDRs consist of time-ordered sequences of
     radiance values that are measured along lines of sight
     perpendicular to Mercury radius vectors.  The viewing direction
     for each measurement is determined by specifying the latitude,
     longitude, and altitude of the spacecraft and the latitude,
     longitude, and altitude of the minimum ray. There are three
     categories of observations in the DDRs: 1) dayside limb scans,
     which are acquired as sets of dedicated limb altitude profiles at
     specific local times, 2) dayside and nightside limb drift
     profiles, which are acquired in a more random fashion as time and
     observational circumstances allow, and 3) nightside tail sweeps,
     which are sets of back-and-forth sweeps of the UVVS line of sight
     across the nightside exosphere. Each of these products is
     generated for the three major exosphere species that are observed
     by the UVVS: sodium (Na), magnesium (Mg), and calcium (Ca). The
     Mg data in the DDRs are observations of the emission line at
     285.3 nm, the Ca data are observations of the emission line at
     422.8 nm, and the Na data are observations of the doublet
     emission lines at 589.2 nm (D2) and 589.8 nm (D1). All
     wavelengths are specified in vacuum.  The total radiance
     calculated for Na pertains to the sum of the D1 and D2 lines,
     which overlap to some extent at the spectral resolution of the
     UVVS.
 
     A single atmosphere DDR contains all of the observations for a
     given species and observational category that were acquired
     during a single Mercury year. &apos;Mercury year&apos; is defined as the
     time to cover the full 360 degrees of Mercury&apos;s orbit around the
     Sun, with the starting point being at 0 degrees true anomaly.
     Because the orbital phase of the MESSENGER mission did not start
     at 0 degrees true anomaly, the first &apos;Mercury year&apos; will be
     partial, running from 73 to 360 degrees.
 
     The UVVS Atmospheric Model DDRs consist of a series of model fits
     to data averaged over specific Mercury true anomalies and local
     times.  These model fits, and the parameters provided in the
     DDRs, are described below in &apos;Derived Product Overview.&apos;  The
     description is given for Na, but Ca and Mg are similarly fitted.
 
   Instrument Overview
   ===================
     The MASCS instrument consists of a small Cassegrain telescope
     that simultaneously feeds the UVVS and VIRS experiments. The
     MASCS UVVS experiment is a scanning grating monochromator
     equipped with three photomultiplier tubes, providing spectral
     information in the far ultraviolet (115-190 nm), middle
     ultraviolet (160-320 nm), and visible (250-600 nm) wavelength
     ranges. The UVVS detector will determine the composition of
     Mercury&apos;s exosphere by measuring the spatial and vertical
     distribution of known species as well as search for new ones. See
     the INST.CAT file for more information and [MCCLINTOCK&amp;LANK2007]
     for full details.
 
   Derived Product Overview
   ========================
     This data set consists of data derived from MASCS UVVS Calibrated
     Data Records (CDR). The Science CDRs are the processed data
     records used to derive emission or reflectance data used for
     scientific analysis. The UVVS Science CDRs contain emission data
     of the UVVS photomultiplier tubes (PMT) at the commanded step of
     the UVVS grating, which corresponds to a specific wavelength of
     light. Wavelength range and sensitivity of each PMT at each
     grating step vary, as documented in the MASCS Calibration Report,
     MASCS_CAL_RPT.PDF, provided in the DOCUMENT directory. Before the
     science data can be used for scientific analysis, the count rates
     in the EDRs must be converted to physical units and the data must
     be transformed into meaningful physical reference systems. This
     conversion yields calibrated data which are stored in Calibrated
     Data Records (CDRs).
 
     Surface DDRs:
     The CDR to surface DDR processing steps include:
 
     1. Filter out non-surface observations.
     2. Divide by solar spectrum for reflectance, bin steps to 1 nm
     bandwidths.
     3. Apply photometric correction.
 
     Atmosphere DDR:
     The CDR data for Na, Ca, and Mg is filtered by observational
     category and combined according to Mercury year to create the
     atmosphere DDR file.
 
     The processing steps from the CDR to the atmosphere DDR level
     include:
 
     For each of:
     a) Dayside limb altitude profiles
     b) Dayside and nightside limb drift profiles
     c) Night side tail sweep profiles
 
     carry out the following:
       1. Filter CDRs for a specified species and observational
       category.
       2. Order as a time series, which keeps individual altitude
       profiles together.
 
     Atmospheric Model DDR:
     The model employed is adapted from the model developed by
     Chamberlain [1963].  The temperature and density of the dayside
     sodium exosphere were found by fitting the estimated column
     densities from individual limb scans. The fit applies only to the
     lower 700-1000 km of the exosphere, which is relatively cold and
     dense compared to the exosphere at higher altitudes. The DDRs give
     the averages of these fits as a function of true anomaly in 5
     degree increments.
 
     The column density N (cm^-2) is derived from radiance I (kR) using
 
     N=I/(g 10^6)                                     (1)
 
     The g-value is the rate (s^-1) at which an atom scatters sodium D1
     and D2 solar photons. It depends on distance from, and radial
     velocity relative to, the sun. The sodium atoms have a
     distribution of speeds, but because this distribution is
     relatively narrow for the low-altitude, low-temperature portion of
     the exosphere described in this data product, we use Mercury&apos;s
     radial velocity and distance from the sun to calculate g.
 
     The exospheric column density is related to the density via
 
     N=KHn                                            (2)
 
     where n is the density of the exosphere at the line-of-sight
     tangent point, H is the scale height of the exosphere, and K is
     the ratio between the line-of-sight column density and the
     vertical column density (~Hn) and given, approximately, by
     [pi*r/(2H)]^(1/2). These formulas come from Chamberlain [1963].
 
     The density is approximated by
 
     n=n0e^-(U/kT)                                    (3)
 
     where U is the gravitational potential energy due to gravity and
     photon acceleration, T the temperature, and n0 the surface density
     (see Feynman [1963] for a general discussion of this formula). The
     temperature and surface density are the free parameters of our
     fits to the limb scans and are provided in the DDR.
 
     Photon acceleration (also called photon pressure or radiation
     pressure) is an antisunward acceleration due to the resonant
     scattering of sunlight. It is directly proportional to the
     g-value. At Mercury, for sodium, it can be nearly half as large as
     surface gravity (e.g., Wang and Ip [2011]). For that reason we
     included it along with the gravitational potential term in
     Eq. (1), so that the potential energy is written as
 
     U=GMm/r + mbrcos(theta)                          (4)
 
     as described in Bishop [1985], where b is the photon acceleration,
     theta is the angle between the local radial vector and the
     Mercury-sun axis, G is the gravitational constant, M is the mass
     of Mercury, m is the mass of a sodium atom, and r is the distance
     from Mercury&apos;s center. For each limbscan, because they all have
     line-of-sight tangent points near the equator, theta is derived,
     approximately, by the angular distance from noon as measured by
     the local time provided in the DDR.
 
     The scale height, used in the formulas above and provided in the
     data product, is defined by
 
     H = n/(dn/dr) = kT/( GMm/r^2 + mbcos(theta) ).   (5)
 
     Note that in the absence of photon pressure and ignoring the
     radial variation in gravity, this definition reduces to the
     classic kT/ma, where a is gravitational acceleration. Alternately,
     we can write H as
 
     kT/m(a + bcos(theta) )                           (6)
 
     where the parenthetical term in the denominator can be seen as a
     sum of two terms, the gravitational term and the radial component
     of the photon pressure. This scale height (measured in km) is also
     provided in the DDR.
 
   Coordinate Systems
   ==================
     MASCS UVVS data are represented in the following coordinate
     systems:
 
     * Planetocentric body fixed: The MBF coordinate system is defined
     by the planetocentric position, Cartesian X, Y, Z coordinates
     related to the planetocentric distance, latitude measured
     positive northward from the equator, and longitude measured
     positive eastward from the prime meridian.
 
     * Cartographic: Surface observations use IAU planetocentric
     system with East longitudes being positive for planetary
     surfaces. The MESSENGER-derived reference system
     (pck00010_msgr_v21.tpc) for cartographic coordinates and
     rotational elements was used for computing latitude and longitude
     coordinates of planets.
 
   Data
   ====
     Surface DDRs:
     There are two surface DDR data products associated with each UVVS
     observation set: a science header table, showing the instrument
     command parameters for a given observation, and a science data
     table, showing counts, derived science data, and pointing
     information for each bin of 5 steps of an observation. The
     surface DDRs are in binary table format, and each is described by
     a detached PDS label. The label points to an associated format
     file that defines the fields of the binary table contained within
     the data file.
 
     There are four types of spectra stored in each surface DDR
     science data file: IOF_BIN_DATA (table column 14),
     PHOTOM_IOF_BIN_DATA (table column 15), IOF_ BIN_NOISE_DATA (table
     column 16), and PHOTOM_IOF_ BIN_NOISE_DATA (table column 17).
 
     Atmosphere DDR:
     There are nine UVVS atmosphere DDR data products per Mercury year
     (as defined above), one for each species (Na, Ca, Mg) and for
     each observation category (dayside limb altitude profile, dayside
     and nightside limb drift profile, and night side tail sweep
     profile). Data from the MASCS housekeeping EDR product generated
     by the MASCS instrument, which is the same for both the UVVS and
     VIRS components of the MASCS experiment, are incorporated into
     the CDRs, and data from both EDR and CDR are passed through to
     the DDR.
 
     Atmosphere DDRs for each species and observation category consist
     of individual files spanning one Mercury year from true anomaly 0
     to 360 degrees. Fractional years (including the beginning of the
     orbital phase and the end of mission) will not contain data for
     all true anomaly values. There are two types of data stored in
     each science file: RADIANCE versus WAVELENGTH (spectra) and
     TOTAL_RADIANCE in each observed emission line [total radiance
     integrated over the emission line(s) as measured at each tangent
     altitude].
 
     Atmospheric Model DDR:
     The UVVS Atmospheric Model DDRs consist of average fits to
     observations at a series of Mercury true anomaly and local
     times.  The model parameters near-surface density, temperature,
     and scale height are provided.  The data are provided in an ASCII
     table format.  There are 3 atmospheric model DDRs for the sodium,
     magnesium, and calcium models, respectively.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
   Confidence Level Overview
   =========================
     The MASCS UVVS Derived Data Records (DDRs) consist of derived
     data converted to physical units and represented in physical
     coordinate systems. Data presented here are an accurate
     representation of the UVVS data as received from the spacecraft,
     and reflect the processing steps from the MASCS UVVS Calibrated
     Data Record (CDR) to the Derived Data Record (DDR) level as
     detailed in the document UVVS_CDR2DDR located in the DOCUMENT
     directory. The UTC and MET time tags have been corrected for
     timing latencies in the instrument so that the UTC and MET
     correspond to the physical time of the observation.
 
     It should be noted that the atmospheric models are intended only
     as a first-order approximation of the average atmospheric state
     on the dayside using a well-known and accepted model (the
     Chamberlain model).  However, such models lack some of the
     relevant physics that are pertinent to the Mercury exosphere.
     As such, they are excellent starting points for more detailed
     models but should not be interpreted as a true representation of
     the actual exosphere.  More detailed models are too complicated
     to provide in any meaningful way.
 
   Review
   ======
     The UVVS DDR was reviewed internally by the MASCS team prior to
     release to the PDS. PDS also performed an external review of the
     MASCS UVVS DDRs.
 
   Data Coverage and Quality
   =========================
     Data reported are the derived data received from the
     spacecraft during the orbital mission phases: Mercury Orbit,
     Mercury Orbit Year 2, Mercury Orbit Year 3, Mercury Orbit Year 4,
     and Mercury Orbit Year 5. These mission phases are defined as:
 
                                Start time   End time
     Phase Name                 Date (DOY)   Date (DOY)   Mercury Years
     -------------------------  -----------  -----------  -------------
     ORB: Mercury Orbit         04 Mar 2011  17 Mar 2012  1 (partial),
                                (063)        (077)        2,3,4,
                                                          5 (partial)
     OB2: Mercury Orbit Year 2  18 Mar 2012  17 Mar 2013  5 (partial),
                                (078)        (076)        6,7,8,
                                                          9(partial)
     OB3: Mercury Orbit Year 3  18 Mar 2013  17 Mar 2014  9 (partial),
                                (077)        (076)        10,11,12,
                                                          13 (partial)
     OB4: Mercury Orbit Year 4  18 Mar 2014  17 Mar 2015  13 (partial),
                                (077)        (076)        14,15,16,
                                                          17 (partial)
     OB5: Mercury Orbit Year 5  18 Mar 2015  30 Apr 2015  17 (partial),
                                (077)        (112)        18 (partial)
 
     To validate the initial DDR dataset, the MASCS team did the
     following:
 
        * Examined one Mercury year of data for each DDR product type.
 
            - Checked all data columns for format and sanity numbers.
            - Compared calibration numbers for earlier independent
              analysis before DDR development.
            - Compared pointing information (vectors, latitudes,
              longitudes, distances, angles) to previous independent
              solutions.
 
        * Spot-checked additional data sets from other Mercury years.
 
     The orbital DDR dataset is evaluated on an ongoing basis,
     checking for completeness and data integrity.
 
     MASCS UVVS data were collected during all phases except
     Venus 1 Flyby. DDR data are derived from orbit only. Data quality
     information for DDR observations are available in the DQI of
     matching CDRs.
 
 
     Removal of Low-Altitude Magnesium Data
 
     A systematic instrument effect on the UVVS data has been found in
     some of the dayside observations. This effect, likely due to a
     scattering problem of unknown origin, mimics a constant background
     that shows a dependence on local time. While the UVVS team tracks
     down the cause and develops a correction, all dayside magnesium
     DDR data (LS and LD) have been excluded from the archive to
     prevent analysis of bad data. This effect has minimal to no
     impact on the nightside magnesium tail sweeps (NS) nor on any of
     the calcium or sodium observations, so these data have not been
     excluded from the DDRs.
 
   Limitations
   ===========
     This data set is derived data.  The data are received from the
     spacecraft telemetry and ingested into the MESSENGER Science
     Operations Center (SOC), then run through the MASCS pipeline. No
     data uncharacterized gaps have been identified for any of the
     MASCS operational periods.
 
     The data have been calibrated to the best possible level;
     however, there are temperature-dependent effects in the
     background removal and wavelength calibration that are still
     being evaluated on an ongoing basis.  The user is warned that
     these effects may sometimes result in false positives in the
     calibrated radiance (i.e., false detections).  Care should be
     exercised in using the data, particularly when results are
     anomalous in appearance.
 
     It is noted that the UVVS DDRs represent the best calibrated set
     of exosphere observations for Na, Ca, and Mg. Because of issues
     that remain in the CDRs (as stated in the confidence notes),
     users are STRONGLY ENCOURAGED to use the DDRs for scientific
     analysis.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

