<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ear-l-mro24m_photgjon-2-edr-lcross-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MAGDALENA RIDGE OBSERVATORY 2.4M PHOTGJON LCROSS OBSERVATION</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_crater_observation_and_sensing_satellite::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.mro24m::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:photgjon.mro24m::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-l-mro24m_photgjon-2-edr-lcross-v1.0__geo_lcross_analysts_notebook::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-l-mro24m_photgjon-2-edr-lcross-v1.0__geo_lcross_mro24m_photgjon_ftp_resource::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-l-mro24m_photgjon-2-edr-lcross-v1.0__pds.geo.lcross.webservices::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kieffer, H.H., and T.C. Stone, The Spectral Irradiance of the Moon, The
                   Astronomical Journal, 129, 2887-2901, 2005.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KIEFFER-STONE2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Young, E.F., L.A. Young, C.B. Olkin, K. Shoemaker, R.G. French, J. Regester,
                   and M.W. Buie, Development and performance of the PHOT (Portable HIgh-Speed
                   Occultation Telescope) systems, submitted to Publications of the Astronomical
                   Society of the Pacific, 2010.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.YOUNGETAL2010</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>EAR-L-MRO24M_PHOTGJON-2-EDR-LCROSS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MAGDALENA RIDGE OBSERVATORY 2.4M PHOTGJON LCROSS OBSERVATION</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2010-02-05</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2009-10-09T05:34:15Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2009-10-09T11:40:02.123Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>MARC W. BUIE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Buie, M.W., Magdalena Ridge Observatory 2.4m PHOTGJON
            Observations of LCROSS, NASA Planetary Data System,
            EAR-L-MRO24M_PHOTGJON-2-EDR-LCROSS-V1.0, 2010.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This archive contains raw observations of the 2009-10-09 impact
            of the LCROSS spacecraft on the moon by the PHOTGJON instrument
            on the Magdalena Ridge Observatory 2.4m telescope.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This archive contains raw observations of the 2009-10-09 impact
            of the LCROSS spacecraft on the moon by the PHOTGJON instrument
            on the Magdalena Ridge Observatory 2.4m telescope. This dataset
            consists of frame-transfer CCD observations of the LCROSS impact
            site as well as unresolved images of the primary impactor in the
            final hours before impact.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The LRO/LCROSS spacecraft was launched on June 18, 2009, and crashed into
    the Cabeus crater near the Moon&apos;s south pole on October 9, 2009. The spent
    upper stage, called the Centaur, impacted the moon at 11:31:19.51 UTC
    at -84.68 deg latitude, -48.69 deg longitude, Mean Earth frame, and the
    LCROSS shepherding spacecraft impacted the surface at 11:35:34 UTC.
 
    This dataset consists of frame-transfer CCD observations of the LCROSS
    impact site as well as unresolved images of the primary impactor in the
    final hours before impact.  The instrument is described in Young et al.
    (2010) [YOUNGETAL2010].  For this event two micro-Max cameras were
    deployed on the dichroic holder assembly so that two simultaneous imaging
    streams could be collected.  All timing for the system is controlled by
    custom GPS-based units that provide timing accuracy good to ~3
    milliseconds.
 
    Our observations were taken at the 2.4-m telescope on Magdalena Ridge.
    This facility is owned and operated by New Mexico Tech under the
    direction of Eileen Ryan.  This is a new alt-az mount telescope system
    designed for fast and accurate tracking.  It provides a Naysmith port
    with integral field de-rotator and filter wheel.  The instrument was
    mounted on this port and rotated so that North was up in the raw imaging
    data.  Telescope and weather status information were collected by
    separate programs and were interpolated to populate the final data
    headers for each image.
 
    The dichroic splits the range of a CCD detector into two roughly equal
    components.  The blue light is reflected and the red light is
    transmitted.  Internal reflections in the dichroic create low-level
    ghost images that are readily apparent on very bright objects. These
    reflections, while present in the primary data, do not affect the system
    sensitivity to the LCROSS impacts.  During the pre-event imaging this
    was the only filtering element in the beam.  The data from the Gjon
    camera was the blue channel and the data from the Doc camera was the red
    channel.  The lunar observations were completely saturated with just the
    dichroic.  Event night was the only night we were able to take data on
    the Moon without clouds and that was the night we discovered the
    saturation problem.  The only tool available to cut the flux down was
    the standard filter wheel on the telescope.  It was hoped that the
    Bessel U filter had sufficient red-leak to serve as a UV and Red
    attenuator. At the telescope we certainly did see the flux in both
    channels drop into a useful range.  The flat fielding pattern also
    looked different giving some confidence to the interpretation that we
    were seeing different wavelengths.  Further research into the
    characteristics of the dichroic and the filters revealed that the
    dichroic was not perfectly reflecting short-ward of 400 nm.  As a
    result, the throughput for each channel was almost exactly the same with
    the same effective wavelength.
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The images have been processed to remove bias, dark-current, and
    pixel-to-pixel quantum efficiency variations.  The native unit of the
    data is ADU or detected electrons/photons.  The conversion to absolute
    flux is made by using calibrated images of the Moon from the ROLO
    project provided by T. C. Stone at USGS (ROLO data described in Kieffer
    and Stone, 2005) [KIEFFER&amp;STONE2005].
 
  Data
  ====
    As soon as the impactor rose above the local horizon we began imaging
    observations for the purposes of extracting a light curve. These
    observations reveal a very strong light curve, in excess of 4-5
    magnitudes, caused by the tumbling motion of the cylindrical booster
    stage.  The object is known to be in non-principal axis rotation and the
    data are consistent with this in that details of the light curve
    features do not closely repeat on successive rotations.  The images are
    flat-fielded as well as could be done but the later images suffer from
    severe scattered light as the projectile got ever closer to the Moon.
    Simple photometry from the images shows a strong light curve but the
    data were not calibrated due to other constraints on our time on event
    night. However, the light curve has such a large amplitude that
    calibration corrections are small.  Absolute calibration is also not as
    important for an object of a known size and albedo (color).
 
    Data were taken on standard regions of the Moon as well as the impact
    site at a variety of airmasses through the night.  All data were taken
    as high-speed frame-transfer image cubes.  The read-out rate limit is
    determined by the speed of the A/D converter as well as the chip
    clocking speed.  The rates in the data correspond to the fastest rate
    possible for the given sub-array size.  As the night progressed we
    worked with ever smaller sub-arrays in order to get the fastest possible
    imaging sequence.
 
    The impact observations did not reveal any observable effect from the
    impact.  Quick-and-dirty image differencing immediately after the event
    did not reveal any signature.  Later, more detailed, efforts to subtract
    a template lunar image to find a trace of the impact flash was also
    unsuccessful.  Given the brightness observed by the LCROSS spacecraft we
    would have been able to see the flash if we did not also have fully
    illuminated portions of the lunar surface in the same field of view. The
    16-bit A/D converter on the CCD system simply has insufficient dynamic
    range to get the flash and the illuminated surface at the same time.
    The ratio between the two was so large that we were unable to work
    around a saturated lunar surface being in the field-of-view. Once the
    filter was introduced the signal was cut to a manageable range but the
    flash would have been much too faint to see.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    All data are stored in FITS format.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
 
 
  Review
  ======
    This data set has been subjected to peer review according to Planetary
    Data System standards.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

