<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lp-l-rss-5-los-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LP L RSS LINE OF SIGHT ACCELERATION PROFILES V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_prospector::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.lp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lp-l-rss-5-los-v1.0__browserc_lp-l-rss-5-los-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lp-l-rss-5-los-v1.0__browserp_geo_lp-l-rss-5-los-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lp-l-rss-5-los-v1.0__dvo_geo_lp-l-rss-5-los-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Carranza, E., A. Konopliv, M. Ryne, Lunar Prospector Orbit Determination
                   Uncertainties Using the High Resolution Lunar Gravity Models, AAS Paper
                   99-325, AAS/AIAA Astrodynamics Specialists Conference, Girdwood, Alaska,
                   August 16-19, 1999.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CARRANZAETAL1999</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Konopliv, A.S. and D.N. Yuan, Lunar Prospector 100th Degree Gravity Model
                   Development, 30th Lunar and Planetary Science Conference, 1067-1068, 1999.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KONOPLIV-YUAN1999</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Konopliv, A. S., A. B. Binder, L. L. Hood, A. B. Kucinskas, W. L. Sjogren, and
                   J. G. Williams, Improved gravity field of the moon from Lunar Prospector,
                   Science, 281, 1476-1480, 1998.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KONOPLIVETAL1998</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Moyer, T.D., Mathematical Formulation of the Double-Precision Orbit
                   Determination Program (DPODP), TR 32-1527, Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena,
                   CA, 1971.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MOYER1971</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Moyer, T.D., Changes to the ODP and the ODE for processing X-Band Uplink
                   Data, EM-314-430, Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, 1987.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MOYER1987</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Newhall, X X, and J. G. Williams, Estimation of the Lunar Physical
                   Librations, Celestial Mechanics and Dynamical Astronomy, 66, 21-30, 1997.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NEWHALL-WILLIAMS1997</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LP-L-RSS-5-LOS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LP L RSS LINE OF SIGHT ACCELERATION PROFILES V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2000-05-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1998-01-13</start_time>
        <stop_time>1999-07-30</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>ALEX S. KONOPLIV</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Konopliv, A. S., LP L RSS LINE OF SIGHT ACCELERATION PROFILES
            V1.0, LP-L-RSS-5-LOS-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2000
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This archive contains Lunar Prospector Line of Sight Acceleration
            Profile Data Record (LOSAPDR) products from both the nominal and
            extended part of the mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Line of Sight Acceleration Profile Data Records (LOSAPDR) consist
            of data from Doppler tracking of the orbiting spacecraft. The
            relative motion of the spacecraft and the earth-based radio
            receiver is measured very precisely, and known motions are
            removed a priori (i.e. earth rotation, planetary motions,
            spacecraft orbital motion, solar pressure, drag), leaving small
            velocity changes caused by variations in the mass distribution of
            the planet. The residual Doppler frequency shifts are linearly
            proportional to the component of velocity in the Earth direction.
            Numerical differentiation of these velocity residuals with
            respect to time produces line-of-sight (LOS) gravity. These
            measures are accelerations at spacecraft altitude which can be
            modeled for geophysical interpretation. For information on Lunar
            Prospector (LP) gravity investigations see [KONOPLIVETAL1998
            CARRANZAETAL1999].
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      Line of Sight Acceleration Profile Data Records (LOSAPDR)
      consist of data from Doppler tracking of the orbiting
      spacecraft.  The relative motion of the spacecraft and the
      earth-based radio receiver is measured very precisely, and
      known motions are removed a priori (i.e.  earth rotation,
      planetary motions, spacecraft orbital motion, solar pressure,
      drag), leaving small velocity changes caused by variations in
      the mass distribution of the planet.  The residual Doppler
      frequency shifts are linearly proportional to the component of
      velocity in the Earth direction.  Numerical differentiation of
      these velocity residuals with respect to time produces
      line-of-sight (LOS) gravity.  These measures are accelerations
      at spacecraft altitude which can be modeled for geophysical
      interpretation.  For information on Lunar Prospector (LP)
      gravity investigations see [KONOPLIVETAL1998; KONOPLIV&amp;YUAN1999;
      CARRANZAETAL1999].
 
      The LOS data have been produced using a 100th degree and order
      spherical harmonic model LP100J [KONOPLIV&amp;YUAN1999] of the Lunar
      gravity field.  The gravity model and other relevant gravity data
      and documentation are available via the World Wide Web at:
      http://pds-geophys.wustl.edu/pds/lunar_prospector/harmonics_maps/
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      Users of these data should be aware of particular events and
      tracking station operations to properly reduce the complex
      motions inherent in the Doppler signals.
 
      Lunar Prospector is a simple spin-stabilized 1.3 meter high by
      1.4 meter diameter cylindrical spacecraft with a 191-kg mass
      after lunar orbit insertion. LP had minimal orientation changes
      (roughly every two weeks) and very small nongravitational
      accelerations. The spin of LP results in a bias in the Doppler
      due to the spacecraft antenna pattern spinning with respect to
      the Earth station. For the case where the omni antenna is used
      for both the up-link and down-link, a bias of (1+240/221)xS Hz
      is the result where S is the spin rate of the spacecraft in
      revs/sec (0.2 for LP). The bias is thus 0.417 Hz or 27.3 mm/s
      (1 mm/s = 0.0153 Hz at S-band). For the medium gain antenna
      which is only used for the down-link or spacecraft-to-Earth,
      the polarization changes for the down-link and the bias
      is (1-240/221)xS Hz. For LP the bias is thus 0.0172 Hz or
      -1.12 mm/s. For the LOS data, the bias is removed for the
      corresponding antenna configuration.
 
      In addition to the bias and a completely different effect, a
      sinusoidal signature appears in the high-rate (1 second)
      Doppler data due to an offset of the antenna phase center
      from the spacecraft spin axis. Since the spacecraft spin
      axis is nearly normal to the line-of-sight direction from
      the Earth station, most of the phase center motion about
      the spin axis is seen in the high-rate Doppler.
      Using the omni antenna for the up-link and down-link, the
      result is a signature with a 5-second period and 8.15 mm/s
      amplitude due to the spin. This indicates a 6.4 mm offset of
      the omni antenna phase center from the spin axis. The
      amplitude reduces to 4.5 mm/s when using the medium gain
      antenna for down-link. Since the Doppler data are essentially
      a differenced range measurement, these amplitudes can be
      mostly removed by using a sample time that is a multiple of
      5 seconds. The LOS data is sampled at 5 seconds and so after
      5 seconds, the antenna phase center returns to nearly the same
      location and results in a small remaining signature less than
      0.1 mm/s [CARRANZAETAL1999]. This small signature is the
      result of the spacecraft spin period not being exactly
      5 seconds.
 
      The transmitter ramp rates and initiation times are
      listed in the ODFDR (Orbit Data File Data Record) and ATDFDR
      (Archival Tracking Data File Data Record) data files.
      The equations to incorporate the ramp data as well as the
      complete theoretical Doppler observable are given
      in [MOYER1971; MOYER1987].  The ATDFDR and ODFDR data can
      be obtained from the Geophysics Subnode of the Planetary Data
      System (http://pds-geophys.wustl.edu/pds/lunar_prospector).
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The raw S-Band uplink/downlink Doppler observations have been
      fit with a model which accounts for theoretical motions and
      other signal effects.  The difference between the observed or
      measured Doppler and the theoretical model are Doppler
      residuals.  These are small systematic variations and are
      attributed to unmodeled gravity field perturbations.
 
      The Doppler residuals are then spline fitted and analytically
      differentiated to produce line-of-sight (LOS) accelerations.
      The spacecraft position in orbit at each acceleration point is
      noted at a specific altitude, latitude and longitude.
 
      All the Doppler residuals are two-way (round trip), where the
      Doppler shift is the shift between the outgoing and returned
      frequency.  The Doppler residuals can be converted into
      velocity residuals of the spacecraft relative to Earth using:
 
           (Doppler residual * c) / (2 * frequency),
 
      where c is the velocity of light, 2.997925E11 mm/sec, and the
      frequency is 2273 MHz for the down-link, which reduces to 1 Hz
      Doppler being equivalent to 65.95 mm/sec (range-rate).
 
      The LOS data during the nominal mission at 100-km average altitude
      (Jan. 13, 1998 to Dec. 19, 1998) and extended mission data at
      40-km (Dec. 19, 1998 to Jan. 29, 1999) and 30-km average altitudes
      (Jan. 29, 1999 to July 30, 1999) have been produced using a 100th
      degree and order spherical harmonic model LP100J
      [KONOPLIV&amp;YUAN1999]of the Lunar gravity field, which causes the
      Doppler residuals to be much smaller and thus the LOS
      accelerations to be also small (i.e. on the order of a few
      milligals as compared to 50-80 milligals with the GM only model,
      which has only a central term and without any spherical harmonic
      coefficients).
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      N/A
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      The lunar gravity field was developed using the lunar orientation
      specified by JPL planetary ephemeris DE403. On the ephemeris, the
      orientation of the Moon with respect to the Earth Mean Equator of
      J2000 (EME2000) is given by three Euler angles
      [NEWHALL&amp;WILLIAMS1997]: (1) the rotation by angle j about the
      Z-axis from the vernal equinox or X-axis of EME2000 to the
      intersection of the ascending node of the lunar equator, (2) the
      tilt up about the X-axis by q to match the lunar equator, and
      (3) the rotation by y along the lunar equator to the lunar prime
      meridian. These three angles describe the lunar librations to a
      very high accuracy (2-3 cm accuracy for the Lunar Laser Ranging,
      Dickey et. al., 1994) and were determined from numerically
      integrating the lunar orientation together with the planetary
      positions. These three angles give a lunar body-fixed coordinate
      system with axes aligned with the lunar principal axes.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      N/A
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The nominal and extended mission LOSAPDR dataset will be available
      electronically via the World-Wide Web at:
            http://pds-geophys.wustl.edu/pds/lunar_prospector/los/
      The archive will also be delivered to the National Space Sciences
      Data Center (NSSDC) using compact disk write once (CD-WO) media.
      Formats will be based on standards established by the Planetary
      Data System (PDS).
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      The Doppler residuals were differentiated to produce LOS
      acceleration profiles.  These LOS profiles however have
      distortions in them due to viewing geometry, variations in
      spacecraft altitude and the least squares reduction process.
      With the high degree and order spherical harmonics, similar
      profiles can be generated that are free from most of the above
      effects, but may suffer from loss of high frequency components
      that remain in the raw data.  The LOS data should be used for
      refinements when small features are important to the analyst,
      but otherwise the gravity field as defined by the harmonics is
      the most valid.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      The LOSAPDR archive was reviewed by PDS and planetary
      scientists familiar with the dataset, prior to release to the
      planetary community.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      There were 3854 LOSAPDRs for the one-year nominal mission
      (orbits 1-4165) produced at JPL and then validated and archived
      at the Planetary Data System&apos;s Geophysics Subnode at Washington
      University, St. Louis, MO.  There was about 220 degrees of
      longitude coverage with periapsis altitude between 75 to 100 km
      for a 100-km semi-major axis altitude. The lunar farside was not
      covered because the spacecraft was occulted by the Moon and
      complete coverage for the nearside occured every 14 days. The
      typical remaining data RMS for the nominal mission with respect
      to the 100th degree gravity field is 0.3 mm/s.
 
      During the 7-month extended mission, the coverage was again
      redundant with coverage for the nearside every 14 days and no
      farside coverage. The average altitude of the orbit for the first
      six weeks (Dec. 19, 1998 to Jan. 29, 1999) was 40-km and then was
      lowered to 30-km for the rest of the extended mission (Jan. 29,
      1999 to July 30, 1999). There were 2774 LOSAPDRs for the extended
      mission. Orbit numbering was restarted for the extended mission;
      the LOS files cover orbits 1-2878 of the extended mission. Since
      the altitude of LP was much lower for the extended mission, the
      remaining RMS of the residuals with respect to LP100J was larger
      at about typically 2 mm/s.
 
      During the extended mission, additional data noise is clearly
      visible when the spacecraft is near the polar regions. Open-loop
      recording shows an increase in background noise for these areas
      and lower signal-to-noise ratios. This was also manifested by the
      spacecraft at times not executing up-link commands. Careful
      processing of these areas is needed to extract the full gravity
      signal. This increase in noise is also in the nominal mission
      data but at a much smaller level.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      N/A
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

