<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.msl-m-sam-4-rdr-l1b-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MSL MARS SAMPLE ANALYSIS AT MARS 4 RDR LEVEL 1B V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_science_laboratory::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.msl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:sam.msl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.msl-m-sam-4-rdr-l1b-v1.0__browserp_msl-m-sam-4-rdr-l1b-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.msl-m-sam-4-rdr-l1b-v1.0__dvo_geo_msl-m-_sam-4-rdr-l1b-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.msl-m-sam-4-rdr-l1b-v1.0__pds.geo.msl.analysts_notebook::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mahaffy, P.R., et al., Space Science Reviews 170, 401-478, 2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MAHAFFYETAL2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MSL-M-SAM-4-RDR-L1B-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MSL MARS SAMPLE ANALYSIS AT MARS 4 RDR LEVEL 1B V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2013-02-27</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2012-09-03T07:16:55Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>PAUL MAHAFFY</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Mahaffy, P., MSL SAM Level 1B Data, MSL-M-SAM-4-RDR-L1B-V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 2013.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The MSL SAM Level 1B data set is generated by applying
            corrections to Level 1A data, e.g. detector dead time, TCD
            temperature, noise removal, corrections for saturation and
            instrument response function.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            TBD (one or two paragraph summary)
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The Sample Analysis at Mars (SAM) suite in the MSL Analytical
    Laboratory is designed to address the present and past
    habilitability of Mars by exploring molecular and elemental
    chemistry relevant to life. SAM addresses carbon chemistry through
    a search for organic compounds, the chemical state of light elements
    other than carbon, and isotopic tracers of planetary change.
 
    SAM is a suite of three instruments: a Quadrupole Mass Spectrometer
    (QMS), a Gas Chromatograph (GC), and a Tunable Laser Spectrometer
    (TLS). The QMS and the GC can operate tpgether in a GCMS mode for
    separation (GC) and definitive identification (QMS) or organic
    compounds. The mass range of the QMS is 2-535 Da. The TLS obtains
    precise isotope ratios for C and O in carbon dioxide and H and O in
    water. It also measures trace levels of methane and its carbon
    isotope ratio.
 
    The three SAM instruments are supported by a sample manipulation
    system (SMS) and a Chemical Separation and Processing Laboratory
    (CSPL) that includes high conductance and micro valves, gas
    manifolds with heaters and temperature monitors, chemical and
    mechanical pumps, carrier gas reservoirs and regulators, pressure
    monitors, pyrolysis ovens, and chemical scrubbers and getters. The
    Mars atmosphere is sampled by CSPL valve and pump manipulations
    that introduce an appropriate amount of gas through an inlet tube
    to the SAM instruments.
 
    The solid phase materials are sampled by transporting finely-
    sieved materials to one of 74 SMS sample cups that can then be
    inserted into a SAM oven and thermally processed for release of
    volatiles.
 
    The SAM L1B data set represents preliminary processing of science
    data.
 
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The SAM L1B data set consists of time series records in science
    units that have been processed with corrections, e.g., detector
    deadtime, TCD temperature, noise removal, and saturation and
    instrument response function. The following types of data may
    be included, depending on the experiments sequence:
 
    QMS
    GC
    TLS
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    Raw data is delivered to the SAM team as Experiment Data Record
    (EDR) products generated by the Multi-mission Image Processing
    Laboratory (MIPL) at JPL under the Operations Products
    Generation Subsystem (POGS), using the telemetry processing
    software MSLEdrGen. Products are created by MIPL during
    operations from: a) MPCS data products, b) SPICE kernels, and
    c) a meta-data database. They are created on the MSL Operations
    Data Store (ODS) and then deposited intoMIPL&apos;s File Exchange
    Interface (FEI) for electronic distribution to remote sites/
    users via a secure subscription protocol. The EDR product is
    considered NASA packet-level data. SAM EDR data products are
    stored at the PDS for safekeeping but are not formally archived
    in PDS. The SAM team converts raw data to a more manageable
    format, which is stored at PDS as NASA level 0 data. Higher
    level RDR products represent the results of further data
    manipulation and interpretation. Details of the processing
    for L1B are discussed below.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The SAM L1B data set is a collection of files containing time-
    stamped, time-ordered data numbers or text strings. It
    represents science data for the SAM instrument components that
    have been processed with initial corrections. Depending on the
    experiment sequence, the following data types might be
    included:
 
    QMS DATA
    --------
      QMS L1B data consists of time series records taken during the
      course of the experiment. Data includes m/z and signal versus
      time. EGA data also includes pyrolysis oven temperature,
      and GCMS data also includes GC column temperature. QMS
      signal has been corrected for detector deadtime.
 
    GC DATA
    -------
      GC L1B data consists of time series records taken during
      the course of the experiment. Data include TCD signal versus
      retention time, pressure, column temperature, and column used.
      The data have been corrected for TCD temperature and noise
      removal.
 
    TLS DATA
    --------
      TLS L1B data consists of time series records taken during the
      course of the experiment. It includes direct and harmonic
      absorption spectra of the sample with filtering.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    No ancillary data are provided.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    Several coordinate systems are used by the MSL project. A
    detailed description can be found in the SAM RDR SIS document
    found in the Documents directory.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    No SAM specific software is provided with this data set. All
    products are ASCII text, viewable in any text editor. TABLE
    and SPREADSHEET products are also suitable for use in
    spreadsheet and database management programs.
 
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    SAM L1B data represent results of preliminary processing of
    SAM science data. Accuracy of the data presented here is dependent
    on appropriate use of pre-flight calibration data for preliminary
    corrections.
 
  Review
  ======
    The SAM RDR was reviewed internally by the SAM team prior
    to release to the PDS. PDS also performed an external peer
    review of the SAM RDR.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    Data reported are the processed data received from the rover
    during nominal SAM operations. This product contains all data
    received from the rover for a single SAM experiment sequence. If
    gaps exist in the telemetry from the rover, data are lost.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    The L1B data set is limited by any errors in the L1A data set.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

