<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.fexp-e-gpsm-5-rdr-topographic-prof-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>FIELD EXP E GPSM DERIVED RDR TOPOGRAPHIC PROFILES V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.geologic_remote_sensing_field_experiment::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.fexp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:gpsm.fexp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.fexp-e-gpsm-5-rdr-topographic-prof-v1.0__browserp_geo_fexp-e-gpsm-5-rdr-topographic-prof-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.fexp-e-gpsm-5-rdr-topographic-prof-v1.0__dvo_geo_fexp-e-gpsm-5-rdr-topographic-prof-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>FEXP-E-GPSM-5-RDR-TOPOGRAPHIC-PROF-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>FIELD EXP E GPSM DERIVED RDR TOPOGRAPHIC PROFILES V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1991-05-28</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1989-10-19T15:47:04.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1989-10-19T17:17:08.000Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JAMES GARVIN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Garvin, J., FIELD EXP E GPSM DERIVED RDR TOPOGRAPHIC PROFILES
            V1.0, FEXP-E-GPSM-5-RDR-TOPOGRAPHIC-PROF-V1.0, NASA Planetary
            Data System, 1991
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The GPS Satellite Profiles Archive contains derived reduced data
            record (RDR) topographic profiles acquired by a GPS Microterrain
            instrument during the earth-based 1989 Geologic Remote Sensing
            Field Experiment (GRSFE).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            A field differential Geopositional Satellite (GPS) survey team
            which included Jim Garvin, Jack Bufton, Bill Krabill, and Earl B.
            Frederick deployed a pair of Motorola Eagle II GPS receivers to
            the southern flanks of the feature known as Mars Hill (an
            alluvial boulder field superimposed on a major lobe of alluvial
            and colluvial material in Eastern Death Valley) on Oct. 19, 1989.
            The objective was to measure the 5-20 cm scale microrelief of the
            boulder field at pixel scales (30-50 m long transects), with
            vertical control to the few cm level. These microterrain profiles
            were to be used to help calibrate radar scattering models, and to
            compare with helicopter stereo data (FEXP-E-HSTP-4
            RDR-TOPOGRAPHIC-PROF-V1.0) for the same location.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      A field differential Geopositional Satellite (GPS) survey team
      which included Jim Garvin, Jack Bufton, Bill Krabill, and Earl
      B.  Frederick deployed a pair of Motorola Eagle II GPS
      receivers to the southern flanks of the feature known as Mars
      Hill (an alluvial boulder field superimposed on a major lobe of
      alluvial and colluvial material in Eastern Death Valley) on
      Oct.  19, 1989.  The objective was to measure the 5-20 cm scale
      microrelief of the boulder field at pixel scales (30-50 m long
      transects), with vertical control to the few cm level.  These
      microterrain profiles were to be used to help calibrate radar
      scattering models, and to compare with helicopter stereo data
      (FEXP-E-HSTP-4 RDR-TOPOGRAPHIC-PROF-V1.0) for the same
      location.
 
      The GLOTAS technique, as implemented at the time of GRSFE,
      involves recording GPS carrier phase data for at least 4
      satellites simultaneously with two 8-channel receivers.  In
      this approach, one (master) receiver/antenna is fixed at a
      reference point (which can be surveyed in using GPS itself),
      and after a suitable calibration period, the second GPS
      receiver/antenna system is moved from its position beside the
      fixed master in whatever pattern is desired to develop a
      topographic profile or grid.  The mobile GPS receiver/antenna
      permits positional data in all three axes (x,y,z) to be
      recorded at a rate of once per second, which can then be
      cross-referenced to the fixed master, and later tied to an
      absolute geodetic positional reference system.  The primary
      interest was in relative horizontal position and in relative
      relief at each position.  Hence, an inverter was attached to a
      jeep battery to power a COMPAQ 386 computer to record all the
      GPS tracking data from both receiver/antenna systems.
 
      Data were collected by cabling the mobile GPS system to the
      computer by means of a 150 ft.  cable, which limited profiling
      length to just under 50 m.
 
      The system was deployed to the southern flanks of Mars Hill,
      and a profile position was randomly chosen with a bearing or
      040 degrees from true magnetic N (measured from the base of
      Mars Hill using a Brunton).  A 100 m long tape measure was used
      to demark the measurement positions, which were spaced every 5
      cm except for flat inter-boulder regions, at which time
      measurements were made every 10 or 20 cm (our fractal
      assumption).  The initial profile extended for 37 m on a
      heading of 040 degrees, and the resampled average measurement
      spacing was about 10 cm.  Measurements were made at 10 sec
      intervals (10 samples) at each data point, and moved the mobile
      GPS unit as rapidly as possible between ground sampling points.
      The antenna was mounted on a fibreglass pole and attached on a
      circular plate at the top of the 6 ft.  long pole to minimize
      interference due to intervening people etc.  The first profile
      took approximately 50 minutes to collect, and the error
      analysis suggests that 2-3 cm RMS vertical precision was
      achieved over the length of a 37 m long GLOTAS profile (we were
      tracking 6-7 satellites during this operation).
 
      After the success of the initial profile, a second profile
      position was chosen at random, to extend from the base of the
      hill to about 30 m distant.  The true bearing of this profile
      was 320 deg. (rel.  to magnetic N), and it was chosen so as to
      begin at the same starting location as Profile 1.  Identical
      conventions were used on this profile, and the average
      resampled data point spacing was 11 cm.  The vertical RMS was
      again 2-3 cm (max), and if a few of the suspect data points are
      removed, the vertical RMS precision is as good as 1 cm.  This
      profile required only 35 minutes to collect.
 
      Processing Level Id            : 5
      Software Flag                  : N
      Processing Start Time          : 1989-10-20T00:00:00.000
      Processing Stop Time           : 1990-06-01T00:00:00.000
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;PLANETARY RADIUS&apos;
      -------------------------------------
        Radial distance from center of planet or satellite to given
        location on the surface.
 
        Data Set Parameter Name        : PLANETARY RADIUS
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : METER
        Sampling Parameter Name        : ALONG TRACK DISTANCE
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : METER
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 0.14
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : 0.05
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : N/A
        Noise Level                    : 0.03
 
 
    Source Instrument Parameters
    ============================
      Instrument Host ID              : FEXP
      Data Set Parameter Name         : PLANETARY RADIUS
      Instrument Parameter Name       : PLANETARY RADIUS
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
 
    Measurement Information
    =======================
      Not Applicable
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      Processing History
      ------------------
        Source Data Set ID  : N/A
        Software            : UNK
        Product Data Set ID : FEXP-E-GPSM-5-RDR-TOPOGRAPHIC-PROF-V1.0
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      A detailed statistical analysis was carried out for these data
      (2 GLOTAS profiles), and height frequency distributions have
      been derived for detrended versions of the data.  In addition,
      slope frequency distributions were computed at horizontal
      baselines of 10 cm, 100 cm, 200 cm (to match the average ATLAS
      footprint scale).
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XD-21A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

