<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.sdu-c-cal-navcam-2-next-tempel1-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>STARDUST 9P/TEMPEL 1 NAVCAM 2 NEXT V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.next::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.sdu::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:navcam.sdu::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.9p-tempel_1_1867_g1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.sdu-c-cal-navcam-2-next-tempel1-v1.0__browserp_sdu-c-cal-navcam-2-next-tempel1-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hillier, J.K., J.M. Bauer, and B.J. Buratti, Photometric modeling of Asteroid
                   5535 Annefrank from Stardust observations, Icarus, v. 211, pp. 546-552, 2011,
                   doi:10.1016/j.icarus.2010.10.009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HILLIERETAL2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., D. Brown, B. Carcich, T. Farnham, W. Owen, and P. Thomas,
                   Stardust-NExT NAVCAM Calibration and Performance, Icarus, 222(2), 436-452,
                   2013, doi:10.1016/j.icarus.2012.01.025.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2011B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Li, J.-Y., M.F. A&apos;Hearn, T.L. Farnham, L.A. McFadden, Photometric analysis of
                   the nucleus of Comet 81P/Wild 2 from Stardust images, Icarus, Volume 204, Issue
                   1, Pages 209-226, ISSN 0019-1035, November 2009,
                   doi:10.1016/j.icarus.2009.06.002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LIETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Newburn, R.L., Jr., S. Bhaskaran, T.C. Duxbury, G. Fraschetti, T. Radey, and M.
                   Schwochert, Stardust Imaging Camera, J. Geophys. Res., v. 108, no. E10, p.
                   8116, 2003, doi:10.1029/2003JE002081.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NEWBURNETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Newburn, R.L., Jr., T.C. Duxbury, M. Hanner, B.V. Semenov, E.E. Hirst, R.S.
                   Bhat, S.Bhaskaran, T.M. Wang, Phase curve and albedo of asteroid 5535
                   Annefrank, J. Geophys. Res., v. 108, no. E11, p. 5117, 2003,
                   doi:10.1029/2003JE002106.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NEWBURNETAL2003B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Semenov, B.V., L.S. Elson, and C.H. Acton, STARDUST SPICE KERNELS V1.0,
                   SDU-C-SPICE-6-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SEMENOVETAL2004B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Stardust encounters comet 81P/Wild 2 Tsou, P. D.E. Brownlee, J.D. Anderson, S.
                   Bhaskaran, A.R. Cheuvront, B.C. Clark, T. Duxbury, T. Economou, S.F. Green,
                   M.S. Hanner, F. Horz, J. Kissel, J.A.M. McDonnell, R.L. Newburn, R.E. Ryan,
                   S.A. Sandford, Z. Sekanina, A.J. Tuzzolino, J.M. Vellinga, M.E. Zolensky,
                   Stardust encounters comet 81P/Wild 2, J. Geophys. Res., v. 109, E12S01, 2004,
                   doi:10.1029/2004JE002317.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TSOUETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>SDU-C/CAL-NAVCAM-2-NEXT-TEMPEL1-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>STARDUST 9P/TEMPEL 1 NAVCAM 2 NEXT V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2011-09-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2007-01-25</start_time>
        <stop_time>2011-02-25</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STARDUST DATA MANAGEMENT AND ARCHIVE TEAM</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Veverka, J.F., et al., STARDUST EDR NAVCAM IMAGES OF 9P/TEMPEL 1,
            SDU-C/CAL-NAVCAM-2-NEXT-TEMPEL1-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2011.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            EDR images taken by STARDUST Navigation Camera (NAVCAM) before,
            during and after the comet 9P/Tempel 1 (1867 G1) encounter.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains EDR pre- and post-encounter and encounter
            images taken by the Stardust Navigation Camera during the
            encounter with comet 9P/Tempel 1 (1867 G1), plus calibration
            images taken throughout the Stardust-NExT mission.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    This description was written by B. Carcich with support from the
    Stardust-NExT operations and science teams.
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
 
      This data set contains Level 2 (EDR) pre- and post-encounter and
      encounter images taken by the Stardust Navigation Camera during
      the encounter with comet 9P/Tempel 1 (1867 G1), plus calibration
      images taken throughout the Stardust-NExT mission.
 
      Every image provided in this data set was taken as a part of a
      particular imaging sequence, each of which is described in the
      Data Collection Periods section below.
 
 
    Data Collection Periods
    =======================
 
      For the complete list of images and their parameters, refer to
      the data set&apos;s index table, INDEX/INDEX.TAB. For additional
      notes on individual images also consult with the document ``Log
      of Stardust-NExT NAVCAM Flight Images&apos;, DOCUMENT/NEXTIMAGELOG.LBL,
      provided with this data set.
 
      N.B. The NAVCAM data collection periods listed here have gaps between
           the stop time of one period and the start of the next; this is
           intentional and consistent with the NAVCAM data set in that no
           NAVCAM image data were taken between these periods.
 
      N.B. The NAVCAM data collection periods listed here overlap, but are
           defined differently than, the mission phases defined in the
           mission catalog (NEXT.CAT).
 
      N.B. Each data collection period listed here corresponds to one or
           more two-letter codes in the NAVCAM image file names and
           PRODUCT_IDs, corresponding to NAVCAM subphases (see
           DATA/DATAINFO.TXT).  The two-letter codes are listed here with
           their corresponding NAVCAM subphase periods and the mission
           catalog phases which they overlap:
 
             Two-
             Letter                       Overlapping Mission
             Code     NAVCAM Subphase     Catalog Phase(s)
             ====     ===============     ================
             CO       Checkout            CRUISE
             C5       Cruise 5            CRUISE
             C6       Cruise 6            CRUISE
             TE       Tempel 1 Encounter  APPROACH, ENCOUNTER, DEPARTURE
 
           For the NAVCAM, operational mission subphases were defined as CO
           (CHECKOUT), C5 and C6 (CRUISE 5 and 6), and TE (TEMPEL
           ENCOUNTER), and those two-letter acronyms were used in the
           NAVCAM PRODUCT_IDs and FILE_NAMEs.  C6 was not intentional but
           was added when the NAVCAM image ID was reset during C5,
           temporarily causing duplicate FILE_NAMEs in the ground data
           system for NAVCAM images taken at different times.  An earlier
           mission phase, C4 (CRUISE 4) was defined but no NAVCAM data were
           taken during that phase.
 
 
      The following sections list the NAVCAM data collection periods:
 
 
      2007-01-25 to 2010-08-23 -- Checkout, Cruise 5, Cruise 6
      --------------------------------------------------------
 
        This section covers the entire CRUISE phase described in the
        Mission Catalog.
 
        The performance of the NAVCAM was monitored throughout the
        Stardust-NExT extended mission using a standard calibration
        sequence along with a few special calibrations.  Calibrations
        involved imaging of a variety of stars, several of which are
        photometric standards, acquiring dark frames, and taking images
        illuminated by the NAVCAM internal calibration lamp.
 
        All of these images were taken with NAVCAM in CRUISE mode which
        included the option to only store and downlink selected windows
        of pixels from the full CCD array, and many of these images used
        this windowing option.
 
        The problem with recurring camera contamination (Hillier, et al.,
        2011; Newburn, et al., 2003a &amp; b; Tsou, et al., 2004; Li, et al.,
        2009 [HILLIERETAL2011] [NEWBURNETAL2003] [NEWBURNETAL2003B]
        [TSOUETAL2004] [LIETAL2009]) was successfully controlled by
        periodic heating of the instrument using its internal electrical
        heaters and by placing direct Sunlight on the camera radiator.
 
        The cruise calibrations allowed characterization of camera imaging
        performance in the areas of geometric fidelity, spatial resolution,
        and radiometry (including zero-exposure signals, shutter times,
        linearity, field flatness, noise, and radiometric response rate)
        more accurately than had been possible during the primary mission.
        Preliminary radiometric calibration results have been incorporated
        into the image processing pipeline. Special observations allowed
        determination of the NAVCAM periscope throughput as a function of
        scan mirror angle, scattered light levels from the spacecraft
        structure as functions of mirror angle and the Sun illumination
        direction on the spacecraft, and charge bleeding and residual image
        in the CCD detector.
 
 
      2010-12-17 to 2011-02-25 -- 9P/Tempel 1 (1867 G1) Encounter
      -----------------------------------------------------------
 
        This section covers the entire APPROACH, ENCOUNTER and DEPARTURE
        phases described in the Mission Catalog.
 
        NAVCAM imaging of Tempel 1 was initiated 60 days before Encounter
        (E-60d) and was repeated twice per week.  Exposures of 10s and 20s
        (the maximum commandable by the spacecraft) were used; however, the
        comet was not bright enough to be detected in the initial images
        even after summing all 8 images taken at each sampling time.  Many
        frames had several pixels of smear using these long exposure times.
        At this time, the spacecraft was oriented with its dust shields
        pointed away from the comet (to avoid having to image it through
        the periscope) and with the high-gain communication antenna pointed
        at Earth to allow data downlinking.  As the spacecraft range to the
        comet decreased, the mirror angle required to view the comet
        progressively increased.  When it exceeded 168deg, increasing
        levels of scattered light began to raise the background signal and
        decrease the signal-to-noise ratio (SNR).  Starting at E-27d, the
        mirror was moved back to 160deg, and the spacecraft was maneuvered
        off Earth point to view the comet.  This reduced the scattered
        light and allowed the first detection of the comet in stacks of 8
        summed images.  Daily 8-frame image sets of 351x351-pixel subframes
        were typically acquired after this time.  These images were usable
        for optical navigation, but the SNR was still too low for useful
        science.  At E-7d, the spacecraft was flipped around to put the
        dust shields forward, and the scan mirror was set at 20deg for
        comet imaging.  The comet SNR in 8-frame stacks became
        scientifically useful at about this time, and sets were taken every
        2 hours from this point until E-2d when approach imaging was halted
        to prepare the spacecraft for the encounter.  Evidence of the
        nucleus brightening the central pixel was first seen at about E-3d.
 
        The close encounter image set was restricted by spacecraft memory
        and software to 72 full-frame compressed images, as had also been
        the case at Wild 2.  These images were sequenced to occur within
        E+/-4m (minutes).  Images were taken on 8s centers outside
        E+/-144s (seconds) and on 6s centers inside that period.  Scan
        mirror pointing was controlled by the onboard autonomous navigation
        software, which worked flawlessly to keep the nucleus in the camera
        FOV.  The pixel scale in the encounter image set ranged from 158
        m/pixel down to 11 m/pixel at closest approach.  Four of the 72
        images (the first, last, and those at E+/-72s) were intentionally
        overexposed to allow better detection of any near-nucleus jets.
        Other than those frames, nearly all images were well exposed.
        Slight saturation of the bright limb occurred on two frames (E-33s
        and E-15s) due to the actual arrival time being 15s earlier than
        nominal.  The first 24 images viewed the comet through the
        periscope; 6 of those frames showed evidence of double images, as
        expected for mirror angles between 8 and 15deg, where light reaches
        the camera both through the periscope and from just outside it.  No
        evidence of any optical contamination was observed.
 
        Departure imaging resumed at E+1d.  With the dust shields forward,
        the scan mirror angle began at about 174deg.  Significant scattered
        light was apparent, but the SNR was adequate for continued useful
        science.  Single 351x351-pixel subframes were acquired every 5
        minutes to support high-time-resolution monitoring of coma
        activity.  Increased central pixel brightening due to the nucleus
        was no longer seen after about E+5d.  At E+7d, the sampling rate
        was decreased to every 11 minutes due to decreasing Deep Space
        Network ground receiving station coverage, and the subframe size
        was reduced to 201x201 pixels one day later.  The scattered light
        level gradually decreased with time, as did the comet signal.
        Useful science imaging was no longer achieved after E+10d, and
        comet imaging was then terminated.  All approach and departure
        images were acquired uncompressed.  No evidence of optical
        contamination was observed except for the residual contamination
        seen after the last heating procedure during cruise.
 
        Calibration sequences similar to the standard cruise calibration
        were executed at E-18d and at E+10d.  The NAVCAM
        performance remained essentially unchanged throughout the
        Stardust-NExT mission.  A publication with more complete NAVCAM
        calibration results is available (Klaasen, et al., 2011
        [KLAASENETAL2011B]).
 
        All approach and departure imaging used CRUISE mode with the
        windowing option.  The close encounter images used ENCOUNTER mode
        which does not have a windowing option, so all close encounter
        images are full-frame images.
 
 
    Instrument and data calibrations
    ================================
 
      This section is duplicated in both calibrated and raw data sets, even
      though it is not represented in the raw data, as calibration is an
      integral part of understanding and using the data.
 
 
      Calibration sources
      -------------------
 
        The calibration data for NAVCAM were derived from pre-launch and
        in-flight testing.
 
        The NAVCAM was specified as an engineering instrument for the prime
        mission to Wild 2.  Its main purpose was for navigation,
        calibration was done on a best-efforts basis, and late hardware
        deliveries severely hampered those efforts.
 
        For Stardust-NExT, imaging was a key part of the science goals, and
        review of existing data plus extensive in-flight calibration was
        done to characterize NAVCAM performance [KLAASENETAL2011B].
 
        This data set includes documents (see /DOCUMENT/DOCINFO.TXT),
        references to published papers, and calibration files (see
        /CALIB/CALINFO.TXT) detailing the calibration of the NAVCAM
        instrument.
 
 
      Data calibration process
      ------------------------
 
        The data calibration pipeline comprised several steps: masking
        pixels outside any windows; quality checks (saturation);
        decompression of compressed data; bias estimation and subtraction;
        dark-current estimation and subtraction; signal-to-noise ratio
        calculation; flat-fielding to remove stable pixel-to-pixel
        variations; calculation of DN rate; conversion to radiance.
 
        The data calibration process does not remove coherent noise
        (CNoise) or Fixed-Pattern Noise (FPN) from the images.  See
        below for a brief description of these effects.
 
 
        N.B. Coherent Noise (CNoise)
        ----------------------------
 
        Coherent Noise is usually only visible in underexposed,
        uncompressed images when viewed using extreme contrast enhancement,
        and appears as stripes of noisy dark and light pixels.  The CNoise
        variation is about +/-5DN in the raw images [KLAASENETAL2011B].
 
 
        N.B. Fixed-Pattern Noise (FPN)
        ------------------------------
 
        Fixed-Pattern Noise (FPN) is usually only noticeable in images
        where the NAVCAM has been on for more than ten hours.  The rise in
        FPN is accompanied by an associated rise in CCD temperature.  It
        occurs independent of the contamination level of the camera.  But
        a peculiar aspect of the FPN is that even after long power-on times
        with elevated CCD temperatures, the FPN does not show up in dark
        frames, only in those that have had the shutter open to admit some
        level of external photons (even if only a low-level scattered light
        background).
 
        Investigation of the FPN during NExT showed that the FPN level also
        depends on the amount of background scattered light in an image.
        The Wild 2 approach images had scattered light levels of &lt;100 DN
        and raw FPN amplitudes of 6-20 DN rms.  But during the NExT
        approach to Tempel 1, much higher levels of scattered light were
        encountered, and the FPN amplitude increased to 25-45 DN rms even
        when the camera had been powered on for only a short time and the
        CCD temperature remained low.
 
        The FPN can be largely eliminated by successive frame differencing
        when identical frame pairs are acquired.  No evidence of FPN is
        found in the Tempel 1 close encounter images, which were acquired
        using data compression, at short power-on time, and with minimal
        scattered light.  No attempts to correct for FPN are included in
        the NAVCAM processing pipeline [KLAASENETAL2011B].
 
 
    Data Product Type and Format Overview
    =====================================
 
      NAVCAM data files provided in this archive are divided by target,
      9P/TEMPEL 1 (1867 G1) and other (CALIBRATION or N/A).
 
      The images in this data set are in FITS format with detached PDS
      labels.
 
      The Primary Data Unit (PDU) of each image file in this data set is a
      two-dimensional array of brightnesses as measured by the array of
      pixels in the NAVCAM CCD, and as viewed through the NAVCAM optics.
 
      The brightnesses in the PDU are the raw (unconverted) Data Number
      (DN) values obtained from the NAVCAM Analog-to-Digital Converter
      (ADC) as it read the voltages in the CCD pixels.
 
      A single Extension Data Unit (EDU) contains BaseLine Stabilization
      pixels which may be used to calculate the bias subtraction in the
      data calibration.
 
      Additional image-synoptic data such as CCD temperature, geometry
      and windowing parameters are stored in the image labels.
 
      In cases where only windows of the detector were stored and
      downlinked, the program filled the pixels in the image corresponding
      to the areas for which data had not been downlinked with raw zeroes.
      In such images WINDOW OBJECTs define the areas containing non-null
      data.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      The primary parameters in this data set are brightness images,
      two-dimensional arrays of brightnesses corresponding to the pixels in
      the NAVCAM CCD, and as viewed through the NAVCAM optics.
 
      The brightnesses are the raw (unconverted) Data Number (DN) values
      from the NAVCAM Analog-to-Digital Converter (ADC).
 
      Ancillary data include bias data and image-synoptic data such as CCD
      temperature and observational geometry.
 
 
    Data Processing
    ===============
 
      The images in this data set were initially assembled at the Jet
      Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) from raw telemetry packets sent down by
      the spacecraft; attached preliminary PDS labels were populated with
      housekeeping values and computed geometry parameters from SPICE
      kernels.
 
      The JPL image files were then multiplexed to several Science Data
      Center (SDC) systems with identical processing pipelines operated by
      Cornell University, where they were converted to FITS format and
      where detached PDS labels for the FITS files were generated.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
 
      The geometry items included in the image PDS labels were computed
      using the SPICE kernels archived in the Stardust SPICE data set,
      SDU-C-SPICE-6-V1.0 [SEMENOVETAL2004B]; refer to that data set for
      details.
 
      Lockheed Martin Astronautics (LMS) provided image command logs,
      which were needed to calibrate the data; see /CALIB/CALINFO.TXT for
      details.
 
 
    Reference Frames
    ================
 
      The geometry items provided in the files are relative to the J2000
      reference frame.  Refer to the description of the geometry table
      columns in /INDEX/INDEX.TAB to see which parameters are defined in
      which frame.
 
      The J2000 reference frame is defined as follows:
 
        -  +Z axis is along Earth Mean Equator North at the J2000 epoch
           (2000 JAN 01 12:00 ET);
 
        -  +X axis is along the vernal Equinox at the J2000 epoch;
 
        -  +Y completes the right hand frame.
 
      The Stardust spacecraft reference frame is defined as follows:
 
        -  +X axis is along the longer side of the spacecraft bus and
           points from the aerogel capsule side towards the dust shield
           side;
 
        -  +Z is perpendicular to the deployed solar arrays surface and
           points along the HGA pointing direction;
 
        -  +Y completes the right hand frame.
 
      This diagram, which is not to scale, illustrates the spacecraft
      reference frame:
 
 
                                          ^+Z      Solar Array
                                     .-.  |        Shield
    Solar Array                      | |  |        .-.
    ===============o===============o======|========| |
                 .-------------------| |  |        `-&apos;
                 |       Periscope/| | |  |                --------&gt;
         (former |           _   | | | |  |      +X          Nominal
         aerogel |   NAVCAM / \  | | | |  x-------&gt;           Comet-
         capsule)|      and|   | |/  | | +Y                 relative
                 |   Mirror \_/      | | (into            Spacecraft
                 &apos;-------------------| | page)              velocity
                                     | |                      during
                             |       `-&apos;                   Encounter
       Direction to comet at |        Whipple
            closest approach |        Shield
         along spacecraft -Z |
                             |
                             V
 
 
      As seen on the diagram, NAVCAM is located on the -Y side of the
      spacecraft bus.  The NAVCAM boresight before the mirror points along
      the spacecraft -Y axis.  The mirror redirects the boresight in the
      spacecraft XZ plane, pointing near spacecraft +X on approach, along
      spacecraft -Z at closest approach, and near spacecraft -Z on
      departure.
 
 
      Epoch of Geometric Parameters
      -----------------------------
 
        All geometric parameters provided in each image PDS label were
        computed at the epoch specified in the start time for that label.
 
 
    Software
    ========
 
      The images in this data set conform to the FITS standard, and have
      standard PDS image labels.  They can be viewed by a number of
      PDS-provided and/or open-source and/or commercial programs.  For this
      reason no data-set-specific software is provided with this data set.
 
 
    Contact Information
    ===================
 
      For any questions regarding the data format of the archive,
      contact Stardust-NExT NAVCAM Science Lead:
 
        Dr. Joseph F. Veverka [JVEVERKA]
 
      or Science Data Center Manager
 
        Brian Carcich [BCARCICH]
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
 
      All telemetry data produced by the NAVCAM contained checksums that
      were validated upon ground receipt.
 
      During the processing of the data in preparation for delivery
      with this volume, the structure of the image data was verified.
      This verification included detection of both the sync word and
      the length of each packet, which ensured that all packets were
      complete and not damaged.  The fundamental validity of the data has
      been inferred by the NAVCAM Science Lead and Science team members
      by display and subsequent review of the images.
 
 
    Breaks in image sequences and missing data
    ==========================================
 
      All NAVCAM image data for the Stardust-NExT mission, which were
      successfully downlinked without corrupted or lost packets during the
      data collection periods listed above, are included in this data set.
 
      Images may appear to be missing because of breaks in the sequence of
      image numbers.  This section gives possible reasons for breaks in the
      sequences, lists all breaks in the image number sequences, and states
      whether any data are actually missing for each break.
 
      Due to the operational constraints on telemetry playback, some of
      the pre-encounter images taken by the camera could not have been
      reconstructed due to an incomplete set of packets and, therefore,
      are not present in this data set.  Specifically an image could not
      have been reconstructed if its first packet was missing or if
      it was a windowed image and any packet was missing.
 
      Some images were only intended for on-board auto-tracking (NAV) and
      never intended for playback.  However, their existence still
      incremented the image number, so images taken from before and after
      NAV image(s) will show a break in their sequence.
 
      Some breaks in the image number sequence occurred because the image
      number was intentionally reset.
 
      A final break in the image number sequence occurred at the end of
      science imaging, as the spacecraft receded from the comet, when it
      was determined that the comet was too dim to be detected in any
      remaining images, which were at that time stored on the spacecraft
      and scheduled to be downlinked, nor would it be detected in future
      images.  At that point the operations and science teams agreed to
      terminate science imaging operations, erase the remaining images from
      spacecraft memory without downlinking them, and prepare for the final
      NAVCAM calibration and end of mission activities.
 
      The breaks in the sequence of image numbers are as follows:
 
        Preceding  Following
        Image      Image      Reason for Absence
        ---------  ---------  ------------------
        N0005CO    N0000C5    Reset sequence to zero; no missing data
        N0133C5    N0000C6    Reset sequence to zero; no missing data
        N0036C6    N10000TE   Reset sequence to zero; no missing data
        N10004TE   N10006TE   Missing packets; missing N10005TE
        N10318TE   N10320TE   Missing packets; missing N10319TE
        N10344TE   N10346TE   Missing packets; missing N10345TE
        N10357TE   N10359TE   Missing packets; missing N10358TE
        N10366TE   N10368TE   Missing packets; missing N10367TE
        N10404TE   N10409TE   Missing packets; missing 4 from N10405TE
        N10414TE   N10416TE   Missing packets; missing N10415TE
        N10419TE   N10421TE   Missing packets; missing N10420TE
        N10638TE   N10641TE   Missing packets; missing 2 from N10639TE
        N10710TE   N30004TE   NAV, Reset sequence to 30000; no missing data
        N30100TE   N30102TE   Missing packets; missing N30101TE
        N30954TE   N30956TE   Missing packets; missing N30955TE
        N30956TE   N30958TE   Missing packets; missing N30957TE
        N30965TE   N30969TE   Missing packets; missing 3 from N30966TE
        N31135TE   N31137TE   Missing packets; missing N31136TE
        N31213TE   N31215TE   Missing packets; missing N31214TE
        N31574TE   N31648TE   Science imaging terminated; no missing data
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

