<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.sdu-c-navcam-3-rdr-wild2-v2.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>STARDUST NAVCAM CALIBRATED IMAGES OF 81P/WILD 2 - VERS 2.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.stardust::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.sdu::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:navcam.sdu::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.81p-wild_2_1978_a2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.sdu-c-navcam-3-rdr-wild2-v2.0__browserp_sdu-c-navcam-3-rdr-wild2-v2.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>SDU-C-NAVCAM-3-RDR-WILD2-V2.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>STARDUST NAVCAM CALIBRATED IMAGES OF 81P/WILD 2 - VERS 2.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2006-01-11</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2003-12-29T04:59:59.797Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2004-01-13T02:30:47.500Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>Ray Newburn</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            R.L. NEWBURN, T.L. FARNHAM, STARDUST NAVCAM CALIBRATED IMAGES OF
            81P/WILD 2, SDU-C-NAVCAM-3-RDR-WILD2-V2.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2008.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Calibrated images of comet 81P/Wild 2 from the Stardust NAVCAM
            instrument
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains calibrated images and calibration data
            from the Stardust Navigation Camera (NAVCAM) observations of
            comet 81P/Wild 2. 206 calibrated images were obtained over the
            5-day period 2003-12-29 to 2004-01-02.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
 
      This data set contains the calibrated images of comet 81P/Wild 2
      taken by the Navigation Camera (NAVCAM) during the Stardust
      spacecraft&apos;s approach to and encounter with the comet, and the post
      encounter observations that were used to aid in the calibration
      process.  The raw data versions of these (and other) images are
      included in the NAVCAM raw data archive
      (SDU-C-NAVCAM-2-EDR-WILD2-V2.0).  This version has also been
      corrected for the exposure time errors that were found after the
      initial submission of the data (see the file SHUTTER_CORRECTION.ASC
      in the documents directory for more information).
 
      These images have been divided into two groups.  The &apos;NAVIGATION&apos;
      directory contains the images of the comet obtained as part of
      navigation sequences.  These are not full-frame images, but
      contain sub-frame windows of the navigation stars and the comet.
      The &apos;ENCOUNTER&apos; directory contains the images obtained during the
      encounter with the comet and are full-frame views.
 
      Every image provided in this data set was taken as a part of a
      particular imaging sequence, each of which is described in this
      section by the NAVCAM Science Lead, Dr. Raymond L. Newburn, Jr.
      For the complete list of images and their parameters, refer to
      the data set&apos;s index table, INDEX/INDEX.TAB. For additional
      notes on individual images also consult with the document ``Log
      of Stardust NAVCAM Flight Images&apos;, DOCUMENT/PIIMGLOG.PDF,
      provided with this data set.
 
      Image Sequence Information
      ---------------------------
      Each sequence is listed here, with information about any
      problems that were encountered during the exposure, readout or
      downlinking of the data.  Additional information about other
      sequences is available in the catalog files for the raw NAVCAM
      data set (SDU-C-NAVCAM-2-EDR-WILD2-V2.0).
 
      2003 DEC 29 05:00:00 -- Images 979-996
      --------------------------------------
        In the series of images 979 through 996, only 983 and 984 are
        missing packets. All images were acquired at a scan mirror
        angle of 21.87 degrees. Images 979 through 982 and 985 through
        987 were given 20 second exposures, while 988 through 996
        received 10 second exposures. All complete images had three 301
        x 301 pixel windows.
 
      2003 DEC 30 05:27:15 -- Images 997-1014
      ---------------------------------------
        Images 997 through 999 were missing the first packet, thereby
        ruining each entire image. In this hectic period, no attempt
        was made to reconstruct them. Image 1000 consisted of one
        normal 301 x 301 pixel window and two 1 x 1 pixel windows. The
        image of Wild2 was in one of the latter. Images 1001 through
        1014 were normal, each having three 301 x 301 windows. The
        first five good frames received 20 second exposures, and the
        last nine were all 10 second exposures. These, of course, were
        again taken for optical navigation purposes.
 
      2003 DEC 30 22:35:15 -- Images 1015-1032
      ----------------------------------------
        The second set of December 30 images probably included 1015
        through 1021, which are missing. I say this because there are
        only two images with 20 second exposures instead of the usual
        nine. The two 20 second images are 1022 and 1023. These are
        followed by 1024 through 1032, which are 10 second exposures.
        All were taken at a scan mirror angle of 21.00 degrees and with
        three 301 x 301 pixel windows.
 
      2003 DEC 31 07:00:00 -- Images 1033-1050
      ----------------------------------------
        Images 1033 through 1050 constituted the first set of December
        31 exposures. All were taken at a scan mirror angle of 20.77
        degrees and with three 301 x 301 pixel windows. The first nine
        were 20 second exposures and the second nine were 10 second
        exposures.
 
      2003 DEC 31 20:18:00 -- Images 1051-1058
      ----------------------------------------
        The second set of December 31 images consisted of eight images
        numbered 1051 through 1058. The first four were 15 second
        exposures, the second four 10 seconds. All utilized a scan
        mirror of 24.49 degrees. Each consisted of three windows of 291
        x 291 pixels.
 
      2004 JAN 01 00:18:00 -- Images 1059-1066
      ----------------------------------------
        The first set of January 1 images, 1059 through 1066, were
        taken at a scan mirror angle of 24.49 degrees. All were
        windowed images using three 291 x 291 pixels with a scan mirror
        angle of 24.49 degrees. The first four were 15 second
        exposures, the second four, 10 second exposures.
 
      2004 JAN 01 05:18:00 -- Images 1067-1074
      ----------------------------------------
        The second set of January 1 images, 1067 through 1074, were
        also taken at a scan mirror angle of 24.49 degrees. All were
        windowed images using three 291 x 291 pixels with a scan mirror
        angle of 24.49 degrees. The first four were 15 second
        exposures, the second four, 10 second exposures.
 
      2004 JAN 01 08:18:00 -- Images 1075-1082
      ----------------------------------------
        The third set of January 1 images, 1075 through 1082, once
        again were taken at a scan mirror angle of 24.49 degrees. All
        were windowed images using three 291 x 291 pixels with a scan
        mirror angle of 24.49 degrees. The first four were 15 second
        exposures, the second four, 10 second exposures.
 
      2004 JAN 01 12:18:00 -- Images 1083-1090
      ----------------------------------------
        The fourth set of January 1 images, 1083 through 1090, once
        again were taken at a scan mirror angle of 24.49 degrees. All
        were windowed images using three 291 x 291 pixels with a scan
        mirror angle of 24.49 degrees. The first four were 15 second
        exposures, the second four, 10 second exposures.
 
      2004 JAN 01 16:18:00 -- Images 1091-1098
      ----------------------------------------
        The fifth set of January 1 images, 1091 through 1098, once
        again were taken at a scan mirror angle of 24.49 degrees. All
        were windowed images using three 291 x 291 pixels with a scan
        mirror angle of 24.49 degrees. The first four were 15 second
        exposures, the second four, 10 second exposures.
 
      2004 JAN 01 21:18:44 -- Images 1099-1106
      ----------------------------------------
        The sixth set of January 1 images, 1099 through 1106, were
        taken at a scan mirror angle of 24.49 degrees. All were
        windowed images using three 291 x 291 pixel windows. Image 1099
        was missing. Image 1100 had two windows, but only the image
        containing the comet was complete. Images through 1102 were 15
        second exposures, the last four were 10 second exposures.
 
      2004 JAN 02 05:18:44 -- Images 1107-1122
      ----------------------------------------
        Images 1107 through 1115, one complete set, are missing. The
        final set of optical navigation images, numbered 1116 through
        1122, were acquired using three 291 x 291 pixel windows and a
        scan mirror angle of 24.49 degrees. The first three utilized 15
        second exposures and the final four 10 second exposures.
 
      2004 JAN 02 18:54:28 -- Images 2000-2115 -- Wild 2 Encounter Set
      ----------------------------------------------------------------
        Images 2005 through 2115 are the 81P/Wild 2 encounter set.
        There are 72 complete images in this set, the missing numbers
        having been used only to establish the auto-tracking on the
        nucleus. There was sufficient memory only for the 72 images. It
        is the nature of the shutter that alternate exposures are 1.65
        milliseconds shorter than the set exposure time. The even
        numbered images are the shorter ones taken during the
        encounter. We were quite limited in the number of changes that
        could be made in the exposure time, so most were taken at
        settings of either 100 milliseconds (actually 98.35
        milliseconds) or 10 milliseconds. Many of the longer exposures
        were saturated, but these serve very well to bring out the many
        jets of gas and dust ejected by the comet. Scan mirror angles
        ranged from 1.37 degrees for image 2005 through 176.05 degrees
        for image 2115. The images with the mirror at more than 170
        degrees all exhibit a great deal of scattered light, probably
        from the sample return capsule. There are lesser amounts of
        scattered light on images back to about 160 degrees. There is a
        problem with images taken near 0 degrees as well, from light
        scattered from the launch vehicle adapter ring which actually
        occludes a bit of the periscope.
 
      2004 JAN 13 02:24:28 -- Images 2116-2130
      ----------------------------------------
        Images 2116 through 2130 were taken to attempt to calibrate all
        of the images, to check the post-encounter state of the
        periscope, and to check the calibration lamp, which appeared to
        have failed pre-encounter. Images 2116 and 2129 were bias
        frames. Images 2117 through 2125 constituted the very limited
        calibration set. Images 2126 through 2128 were for the
        periscope check, and 2130 was the calibration lamp check. The
        calibration images all were taken at scan mirror angles near 24
        degrees, four with 1 second exposures, four with 5 second
        exposures and one with a 15 second exposure. All were
        uncompressed full frame images. The periscope checks were done
        at an angle of -0.10 degrees and were full of scattered light.
        This was expected to some extent, but the very mottled
        appearance of the images indicated that one or both mirrors of
        the periscope were thoroughly sandblasted by the passage
        through the Wild 2 coma. The check of the calibration lamp
        unfortunately was done with a 1 second exposure rather than 20
        milliseconds. It was obviously working just fine, since every
        pixel in the frame was saturated.
 
 
    Processing and Calibration
    ===========================
 
      The images in this data set were created by the DMAPKTDECOM
      program developed by Applied Coherent Technology Corp, Herndon,
      Virginia and operated by the Stardust Data Management and Archive
      Team at JPL, Pasadena, California. This program assembled images
      from raw telemetry packets sent down by the spacecraft and
      populated the images labels with housekeeping values, decommutated
      the binary image headers, and computed geometry parameters using
      SPICE kernels. This program did not apply correction of any kind
      to the image data.
 
      In the cases when only certain sections of the detector were
      downlinked, the program filled the pixels in the image
      corresponding to the areas for which data had not been downlinked
      with hex null values (i.e., zeroes). In such images window
      objects define the areas containing non-null data.
 
 
      Radiometric Calibration
      -----------------------
      The images have been radiometrically calibrated to give
      radiance in units of W m**-2 sR**-1.  Processing can be
      summarized as consisting of six steps:
        1) Undo square-root compression of raw data numbers.
        2) Subtract offset estimated from averaging baseline.
           stabilization pixel values in prefix/suffix of the Image lines
           from all pixels in the image.
        3) Divide by estimate of relative sensitivity of each pixel
           compared to image center pixels.
        4) Scale from data number to radiance based on exposure
           time, distance from  Sun, and absolute calibration
           coefficient derived from analysis of post-encounter star
           images. The conversion coefficient used to convert to
	   radiance is 1.525 x 10^{-6} W/m^2/sr/(DN/s).
        5) Geometrically transpose image data (not including line prefix
           and suffix regions), resulting in a right-reading
           (unmirrored) view of the sky from the spacecraft such as
           would have been obtained by a conventional camera without
           periscope.
        6) Update values of geometric parameters to correspond to
           the transposed image geometry.
 
      An extensive discussion about the calibration procedures can
      be found in the NAVCAM_CALIBRATION.PDF and the
      SBN_CALIBRATION_COMMENTS.ASC documents in the DOCUMENT
      directory.
 
 
    Data
    ====
 
      The images in this data set have been converted by the SBN from
      the standard PDS format to FITS format with detached PDS labels.
      Relevant information in the PDS label has been placed into the
      FITS header, though due to differing conventions, the keywords
      may have changed.  The description field in the FITS header
      should make it clear what the keyword represents.
 
      Camera Description
      ------------------
 
      The STARDUST camera has an angular resolution of
      59 microrad/pixel (12 arcsec/pixel) and a focal length of 202 mm
      at an f-ratio of about f/3.5.  Early in the flight the filter
      wheel failed, possibly due to a failed power supply. Fortunately
      it failed on the filter with the largest throughput, but the
      broad bandpass of that filter caused images taken through it to
      have significant chromatic aberration, which resulted in an
      image resolution of about 2.5 pixels at FWHM (full width at half
      maximum) when observing a point source such as a star. (The high
      resolution filter, intended to be used for near encounter
      imaging, would have resulted in resolution exceeding a half
      pixel.) Without any image processing, the 2.5 pixel resolution
      resulted in a best linear resolution at closest approach of
      about 20 m/pixel.
 
      After launch, it was discovered that the camera optics had been
      contaminated by an unknown substance that significantly reduced
      the quality of the images, and affected the photometric
      properties of the image.  Tests showed that heating the camera
      before critical observations reduced this contamination and
      improved the quality of the images, though some effects still
      remained.  Because the contamination varies with time, a plan
      was developed to obtain calibration images immediately before
      and after the encounter with comet Wild 2, to improve the
      possibility of being able to calibrate the images
      photometrically.  Unfortunately, problems with the camera and
      calibration lamp meant that the only useful calibration
      sequences were obtained 11 days after the encounter.  Further
      details regarding the calibrations are discussed in the
      NAVCAM_CALIBRATION document in the DOCUMENT directory.
 
      The camera has a 1024x1024 array as the active portion of the
      CCD, though the first and last columns are uncalibratable, and
      thus were removed during processing.  The resulting images have
      been trimmed to an array size of 1022x1024.
 
 
      Windowed Images
      ---------------
      The IMAGE size parameter in the image label reflects the size
      of the detector, however in the navigation images, data from
      only certain sections of the detector were downlinked. In
      these cases the pixels in the image corresponding to the areas
      for which data had not been downlinked are filled with hex
      null values (i.e., zeroes). WINDOW objects define the areas
      containing non-null data.
 
      Compression Modes
      -----------------
      The NAVCAM images can be either 8-bit or 12-bit data. The 12-bit
      data is commonly referred to as &apos;uncompressed data&apos;, while the
      8-bit is referred to as &apos;compressed data&apos;. This compression is
      accomplished by a 12-bit to 8-bit square-root look-up-table
      compression method, which is implemented in the hardware of the
      camera electronics. This compression is lossy and the estimate of
      the 12-bit image can be recovered using the look-up table
      mentioned in Appendix 3 of the Calibration Document.
 
      In uncompressed mode with 12-bit data, the pixels are expressed
      in two bytes, as 16 bits per pixel. The upper nibble of the most
      significant byte is always zero for these images. In compressed
      mode with 8-bit data, the pixels are expressed in a single byte.
 
      Exposure Durations
      ------------------
 
      The double-bladed shutter utilized by the camera has a delay in its
      slide mechanism that introduces an offset in the actual exposure
      time, compared to the commanded exposure time.  During the
      recalibration of the NAVCAM as part of the Stardust NExT mission, it
      was determined that the original information about the exposure time
      offsets and the forward/reverse shutter parity were incorrect.  In
      this version (2.0) the images have been corrected to account for the
      updated information.  See the file SHUTTER_CORRECTION.ASC in the
      documents directory for more information.
 
 
      Target Name in the Image Labels
      -------------------------------
      The target name in the image labels was set only for the images
      where the target is either seen in the image or computed to be
      with the camera field of view. For all other images the target
      name was set to ``N/A&apos;.
 
      Consequently the label geometry items pertaining to the target
      -- spacecraft-target position, velocity and distance, pixel
      scales, and phase angle -- are only supplied for the images where
      target name is not ``N/A&apos; and were computed for that specified
      target.
 
 
      Noise in the Images
      -------------------
 
      If the images are stretched to the limit, regular wide
      vertical stripes appear in every image (orignally at the
      level of 1 to 2 dn above background). These appear to be the
      product of coherent noise somewhere in the data stream or from
      a power supply.  Their source is unknown.
 
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
 
      The geometry items included in the image labels were computed
      using the following SPICE kernels archived in the Stardust SPICE
      data set, SDU-C-SPICE-6-V1.0:
 
        Kernel Type   File Name
        ------------  ---------------------
         LSK           naif0008.tls
         PCK           pck00007.tpc
         PCK           sdu_wild2_v01.tpc
         SCLK          sdu_sclkscet_00141.tsc
         FK            sdu_v20.tf
         IK            sdu_navcam_v22.ti
         SPK           sdu_l_2003_w2.bsp
         SPK           sdu_l_2004.bsp
         SPK           sdu_w2_opnav.bsp
         CK (s/c)      sdu_sc_rec_2003_w2_v2.bc
         CK (s/c)      sdu_sc_rec_2004_v2.bc
         CK (s/c)      sdu_sc_rec_w2_opnav.bc
         CK (camera)   sdu_nc_rec_v2.bc
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
 
      Geometric Parameter Reference Frame
      -----------------------------------
      Earth Mean Equator and Vernal Equinox of J2000 is the inertial
      reference system used to specify observational geometry items
      provided in the image labels. Geometric parameters are based on
      best available SPICE data at time of image creation.
 
      Epoch of Geometric Parameters
      -----------------------------
      All geometric parameters provided in the image labels were
      computed at the epoch specified in the START_TIME label field.
 
      Image Orientation
      ------------------
      In the original version of the Stardust datasets, there were
      inconsistencies in the image orientation and the definition of
      the TWIST_ANGLE.  In this version of the images, the orientation
      has been corrected so that, when displayed in the manner defined
      by the LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION and the SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION,
      the images will have the correct orientation as seen on the sky.
      Similarly, the TWIST_ANGLE (and corresponding
      NORTH_CELESTIAL_CLOCK_ANGLE) have been corrected so that they
      follow the PDS definition.  The values in the keywords
      RETICLE_POINT_RA and RETICLE_POINT_DECLINATION have also been
      adjusted to reflect the updated orientation of the images.
      Additional keywords have been added to the FITS header to better
      define the geometry, including the Celestial and Ecliptic North
      clock angles and the projected sunward vector clock angle.
      In this version, all geometric parameters have been recomputed
      using the most recent SPICE kernels (listed above)
 
 
    Contact Information
    ===================
 
      For any questions regarding the data in this archive,
      contact the SBN:
 
        Tony L. Farnham
        Phone: +1 (301) 405-3856
        Electronic mail address: farnham@astro.umd.edu
 
        Department of Astronomy
        University of Maryland
        College Park, MD 20742
        USA
 
      or Stardust Data Management and Archive Team (SDMA):
 
        Charles H. Acton, Jr.
        Phone: +1 (818) 354-3869
        Electronic mail address: Charles.Acton@jpl.nasa.gov
 
        Boris V. Semenov
        Phone: +1 (818) 354-8136
        Electronic mail address: Boris.Semenov@jpl.nasa.gov
 
        MAIL STOP 301-125L
        Jet Propulsion Laboratory
        California Institute of Technology
        4800 Oak Grove Drive
        Pasadena, CA, 91109-8099
        USA
 
 
      Author
      ------
      The descriptions in this file were written by Tony Farnham, and
      include relevant information that was originally archived with
      the PDS archive of NAVCAM raw images.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
      Calibration Quality
      ===================
 
      The absolute calibration of the Wild 2 images is relatively crude
      due to the problems associated with the contaminated optics in the
      navigation camera.  The data presented here represent the best
      attempt at producing an absolute calibration, using the standard
      star measurements obtained eleven days after the comet encounter.
      Further details regarding the calibration can be found in the
      calibration discussions in the DOCUMENTS directory.
 
      As part of the Stardust NExT mission, observations are being
      obtained so that a full recalibration of the NAVCAM
      instrument can be done.  If it is found that the results are
      applicable to this dataset, and that they significantly improve
      on the current version, then a recalibration may be presented in
      a future version of the data.
 
      Data Coverage
      =============
 
      The images contained in this archive comprise all of the Stardust
      images of comet Wild 2 (including the navigation frames and
      encounter data) as well as the calibration images that were
      obtained after the encounter.  Some of the images in the
      navigation sequences did not contain the comet and these images
      have not been included in this dataset.
 
      Review
      ======
 
      The data were peer reviewed in October 2009.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

