<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.phx-m-ase-2-edl-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>PHOENIX MARS ATMOSPHERIC STRUCTURE EXPERIMENT DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.phoenix::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.phx::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:ase.phx::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.phx-m-ase-2-edl-v1.0__browserp_phx-m-ase-2-edl-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.phx-m-ase-2-edl-v1.0__dvo_atm_phx-m-ase-2-edl-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Smith, P.H., L. Tamppari, R.E. Arvidson, D. Bass, D. Blaney, W. Boynton, A.
                   Carswell, D. Catling, B. Clark, T. Duck, E. DeJong, D. Fisher, W. Goetz, P.
                   Gunnlaugsson, M. Hecht, V. Hipkin, J. Hoffman, S. Hviid, H. Keller, S.
                   Kounaves, C.F. Lange, M. Lemmon, M. Madsen, M. Malin, W. Markiewicz, J.
                   Marshall, C. McKay, M. Mellon, D. Michelangeli, D. Ming, R. Morris, N. Renno,
                   W.T. Pike, U. Staufer, C. Stoker, P. Taylor, J. Whiteway, S. Young, and A.
                   Zent, Introduction to special section on the Phoenix Mission: Landing site
                   characterization experiments, mission overviews, and expected science, Journal
                   of Geophysical Research, 113, E00A18, 2008, doi:10.1029/2008JE003083.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SMITHETAL2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>PHX-M-ASE-2-EDL-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>PHOENIX MARS ATMOSPHERIC STRUCTURE EXPERIMENT DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2008-12-24</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2008-05-25T23:30:47.918Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2008-05-25T23:38:36.899Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID C. CATLING</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            D. C. Catling, R.F. Beebe, J.R. Murphy and L.F. Huber, NASA
            Planetary Data System, 2008.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Phoenix Lander Atmospheric Stucture Experiment Data Records,
            Version 1.0
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>Unknown</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
   The DATA directory is divided up into two subdirectories: EDR_DATA
   and RDR_DATA. In each subdirectory, there will be experiment data
   records (EDRs) or reduced data records (RDRs) for the Inertial
   Measurement Unit (IMU) on Phoenix. The location of the IMU within the
   Phoenix spacecraft with respect to various frames of reference is
   described in the EDR Software Interface Specification (SIS) with the
   aid of diagrams.
 
   Data files in the EDR_DATA subdirectory consist of time ordered
   records of linear velocity changes or &apos;delta-v&apos; values every 5
   milliseconds in three Cartesian axes and angle change or the
   &apos;delta-angle&apos; values every 5 milliseconds in three Cartesian
   axes. Data comes from the IMU measurements during the entry and
   descent of the Phoenix spacecraft. NASA Level 1A data have been
   converted to physical units and transformed in space from the local
   reference frame of the IMU to the mechanical Cartesian frame of the
   spacecraft described in the EDR SIS.
 
   Data files in the RDR_DATA subdirectory will contain time-ordered
   altitude, latitude, east longitude, velocity, atmospheric pressure
   (and uncertainty), atmospheric temperature (and uncertainty), and
   atmospheric density (and uncertainty).
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
   The NASA Level 1A data files in the EDR_DATA subdirectory contain the
   following measurements:
    Relative spacecraft event time from start of data acquisition:
      Units = seconds
    Angle change (delta-angle) about the X-axis of the mechanical frame
     of the spacecraft: Units = radians
    Angle change (delta-angle) about the Y-axis of the mechanical frame
     of the spacecraft: Units = radians
    Angle change (delta-angle) about the Z-axis of the mechanical frame
     of the spacecraft: Units = radians
    Velocity change (delta velocity) in the X-axis of the mechanical frame
     of the spacecraft: Units = m/s
    Velocity change (delta velocity) in the Y-axis of the mechanical frame
     of the spacecraft: Units = m/s
    Velocity change (delta velocity) in the Z-axis of the mechanical frame
     of the spacecraft: Units = m/s
 
   The Level 2 data files in the RDR_DATA subdirectory contain the
   following data:
    Spacecraft Clock count: Units = seconds
    Relative time from a defined entry state: Units = seconds
    The altitude of the spacecraft above the landing site: Units = seconds
    Planetocentric latitude of the spacecraft at the time of sample
     acquisition: Units = degrees
    Planetocentric east longitude of the spacecraft at the time of sample
     acquisition: Units = degrees
    Speed of the Phoenix entry probe at the given location: Units = m/s
    Derived atmospheric density along the flight path: Units = kg/m**3
    Derived atmospheric pressure along the flight path: Units = Pascal
    Derived atmospheric temperature along the flight path: Units = Kelvin
    The estimated uncertainty of the atmospheric density: Units = kg/m**3
    The estimated uncertainty of the atmospheric pressure: Units = Pascal
    The estimated uncertainty of the atmospheric temperature: Units = Kelvin
 
   Ancillary quantities are necessary to understand the derivation of
   RDR data and are also found within this archive volume. The CALIB
   directory in the DOCUMENT directory will contain a tabulation of
   three-dimensional force and moment coefficients of the Phoenix
   spacecraft as a function of atmospheric conditions and spacecraft
   attitude with respect to the atmosphere-relative velocity
   vector. INST.CAT contains the entry state of the Phoenix probe,
   consisting of a position vector and entry attitude at a defined
   time. INST.CAT also contains the following additional ancillary
   quantities: the Phoenix entry vehicle mass and its uncertainty: Units
   = kg The entry vehicle cross-sectional area: Units = m**2
 
  Data
  ====
   The Phoenix Lander spacecraft had two Inertial Measurement Units
   (IMUs) that were mounted on the underside of the lander, one as
   backup only that was never turned on. The IMUs were manufactured by
   Honeywell (Clearwater, FL) with part number YG9666BC. The IMUs were
   on the spacecraft as engineering sensors, primarily to assist in
   Entry, Descent and Landing (EDL).  Thus the data were processed and
   collected for engineering use and their scientific use was not a
   driver for the selection of the IMU performance characteristics.
   Consequently, the IMU that collected data was not located close to
   the entry capsule center of mass or spin axis. Data were output from
   one IMU and collected at the full instrument rate of 200 Hz. The DN
   values from the IMU were transmitted back to Earth from the
   spacecraft and converted to physical values after ground
   depacketization using factory calibration data. Frames of reference
   and transformation of the data to the mechanical frame of reference
   are described in the EDR SIS with the aid of diagrams.
 
  Processing
  ==========
   The &apos;raw&apos; DN values were stored on the spacecraft at the instrument
   acquisition rate of 200 Hz. The EDR data presented are those derived
   from the raw DN transmitted from the spacecraft and processed using
   the ancillary information and method described in the EDR SIS.  The
   EDR data products are the time-ordered delta-velocity change (the
   time integral of acceleration) per count in three Cartesian axes and
   delta-angle change (the time integral of angular rate) per count in
   three Cartesian axes. The density, pressure and temperature of the
   atmosphere along the flight path was deduced from this data by
   methods generally outlined in the RDR SIS.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
     TBD
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
   Within the 1 to 93798 data samples recorded every 5 milliseconds in
   the EDR data set, spurious data was recorded for samples 12031 to
   12040 (inclusive) because of a downlink transmission problem. These
   data points are zero-filled. Because of the 50 millisecond duration
   of this anomaly, the effect on higher level analysis is likely to be
   negligible with suitable interpolation in using the data. Another
   noticeable quality aspect of the EDR data is the comparatively high
   noise level, which is a function of the way the instrument was
   selected and configured by spacecraft engineers, as described in
   INST.CAT.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

