<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mro-m-mcs-4-rdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MRO MARS CLIMATE SOUNDER LEVEL 4 RDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mcs.mro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-mcs-4-rdr-v1.0__browserp_mro-m-mcs-4-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MRO-M-MCS-4-RDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MRO MARS CLIMATE SOUNDER LEVEL 4 RDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2005-02-27</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2005-09-12T19:10:51.999Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2005-09-12T19:59:58.366Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DANIEL J. MCCLEESE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            McCleese and Schofield, MRO MARS CLIMATE SOUNDER LEVEL 4 RDR
            V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, MRO-M-MCS-4-RDR-V1.0, 2006.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The MCS atmospheric profiler detects vertical variations of
            temperature, dust, and water vapor concentrations in the Martian
            atmosphere.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>Unknown</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The Mars Climate Sounder is a follow-on experiment to PMIRR, the
    Pressure Modulator Infrared Radiometer lost with the Mars Observer
    spacecraft, and to PMIRR2, lost with the Mars Climate Orbiter.  MCS
    observes radiation in nine spectral bands: eight thermal infrared
    channels are used to determine temperature, pressure, water vapor
    and condensates as a function of altitude; the remaining channel
    operates in the visible and near infrared (0.3-3.0 microns) and is
    used primarily to understand the effects of solar radiation on the
    Martian energy budget.  The determination of the atmospheric
    parameters will lead to an understanding of Martian weather and,
    eventually, of Martian
    climate.
 
    Mars Climate Sounder looks at the horizon of Mars from orbit to
    observe the atmosphere in vertical slices, with measurements every 5
    kilometers (3 miles) down in each slice through the atmosphere.
    These &apos;profiles&apos; are combined into daily, three-dimensional global
    weather maps for both daytime and nighttime. These weather maps will
    show temperature, pressure, humidity, and dust in various layers of
    the atmosphere: the same type of information meteorologists use to
    understand and predict both weather and climate here on Earth.
 
    MCS data are organized into a table of combined engineering and
    science   records. MCS delivers telemetry to the spacecraft every 2
    seconds. Data are accrued over a 4 hour period and packaged into an
    ascii table.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    MCS observes radiation in nine spectral bands: eight thermal
    infrared channels are used to determine temperature, pressure, water
    vapor and condensates as a function of altitude;  the remaining
    channel operates in the visible and near infrared (0.3-3.0 microns)
    and is used primarily to understand the effects of solar radiation
    on the Martian energy budget.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    Each record in the table represent a combination of basic
    engineering and science data taken at 2 second intervals. Columns 1
    - 69 contain engineering data, columns 70 - 258 contain science
    data.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The MCS RDR data products will be generated by the MCS Instrument
    Team at JPL using software on the MCS Analysis and Data Archiving
    (ADAC) computers. This software generateds the RDR data products
    from the corresponding EDRs in the format specified b this SIS.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    ?? Latitude and longitude are in the IAU Mars Centered Mars
    Equatorial System. Altitude is above the IAU reference ellipsoid,
    with a=3393.4 km and f=0.0052083 and including corrections for (4,4)
    gravitational potential.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
 
  ...High-level description of confidence level (reliability, accuracy,
        completeness, etc.)
 
 
  Review
  ======
 
  ...Describe review processes which the data have undergone, including
     the PDS Peer review.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
 
    Data are taken continuously throughout nominal operations...
    ..mention known data gaps and any null values or invalid data flags
    which might be included.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

