<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.pvo-v-onms-4-thermalion-12sec-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>PVO VENUS ONMS BROWSE THERMAL ION 12 SECOND V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.pioneer_venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.pvo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:onms.pvo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.pvo-v-onms-4-thermalion-12sec-v1.0__browserp_pvo-v-onms-4-thermalion-12sec-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Brace, L.H., W.T. Kasprzak, H.A. Taylor, Jr., R.F. Theis, C.T. Russell, A.
                   Barnes, J.D. Mihalov, and D.M. Hunten, &apos;The Ionotail of Venus: Its
                   Configuration and Evidence for Ion Escape, J. Geophys. Res., 92, 15, 1987.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BRACEETAL1987</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>PVO-V-ONMS-4-THERMALION-12SEC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>PVO VENUS ONMS BROWSE THERMAL ION 12 SECOND V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1993-03-31</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1980-03-15T10:26:29.656Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1992-09-25T23:09:39.859Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. WAYNE KASPRZAK</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>TBD</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Species observed include He+, N+, O+, CO+ and/or N2+, NO+, O2+
            and CO2+. H+ is not measurable with the current instrument
            configuration. One component of the ion drift in the ecliptic
            plane can also be determined.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>not applicable</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
Thermal ions can be measured with the filament off and the ion repeller
set at 0 V. Species observed include He+, N+, O+, CO+ and/or N2+, NO+,
O2+ and CO2+. H+ is not measurable with the current instrument
configuration. One component of the ion drift in the ecliptic plane can
also be determined. Thermal ion measurements have been taken
sporadically at the end of neutral density passes and on alternate
orbits when superthermal ions are not being measured.
 
The ONMS instrument was not operated on all orbits and some orbits are
devoted to engineering studies. Typically neutral density passes
occupied -40 min. to +30 min. relative to the time of periapsis.  Ion
and superthermal ion mode passes typically are 15 to 20 minutes in
duration on either side of periapsis. Neutral density passes during
entry also took about this same amount of time.
 
The data values of the data set are sampled approximately once per 12
seconds based on GMT times that have been supplied by the Pioneer Venus
Project.  Each representative data point is constructed using an
exponentially weighted average of the data over a 24 second interval
centered at sample point time.
 
       The data have the following characteristics:
 
     LOGICAL RECORD SIZE:               80 bytes
     FORMAT:                            ASCII
     FILES:                             1
 
      The field names used in RECORD 1:
 
      VARIABLE       COMMENT
        DATE      YYDDD
                  YY=2 digit year (e.g. 78 for 1978)
                  DDD=3 digit day of year (e.g. 053)
        UT        Universal Time represented as the
                  number of milliseconds since
                  1966-01-01T00:00:00Z stored as a double
                  precision floating point number.
        ORBIT     Orbit number
        PSEC      Time after periapsis (sec)
        DENS        Density in particles/cm**3
        WPXY        Minimum ion drift m/sec
        PHSE        Phase shift (degrees)
        MASS        Mass number -
                     4 for He+
                    12 for C+
                    14 for N+
                    16 for O+
                    28 for N2+ and/or CO+
                    30 for NO+
                    32 for O2+
                    44 for CO2+
        VALT        Altitude above the mean surface of
                    Venus in km
        VLAT        Venus latitude in degrees
        VLST        Venus local solar time in hr
        VSZA        Venus solar zenith angle in degrees
 
 
The relationship between thermal ion density and instrument output was
established by direct comparison of the O+ signal with the O+ density
determined from the Orbiter Ion Mass Spectrometer (OIMS) instrument
using O+ data from orbit number 530 at 300 seconds from periapsis.
Other species are assumed to have the same sensitivity as that of O+. In
this mode superthermal ions cannot be distinguished from thermal ions.
 
The data reduction process has been described in Kasprzak et al. (1992)
but was similar to the technique used for the Superthermal O+ ion data.
In order to fit the superthermal O+ data, a minimum of 30 points were
required in 36 seconds. In addition, the maximum to minimum count ratio
was required to be factor of 3 or greater in order to insure that there
was a definitive spin modulation.  The center 12 seconds of data is
divided by the fitting function to derive the equivalent flux for that
point. The center of the new fitting interval is adjusted so that it is
centered on the expected signal maximum predicted from the previous
interval fit. As a result of this method of fitting, discontinuities may
exist near minimum angle of attack where one 12 second interval adjoins
the next interval.
 
The method used to reduce the data assumes cylindrical symmetry of the
ion source.  In actual fact, the source is asymmetrical in its angular
response (Guenther, 1989). This can introduce as much as a factor of 2
scatter in the data. The ion species regularly monitored include: He+,
N+, O+, N2+ and/or CO+, NO+ and CO2+. As part of the reduction process
the minimum ion drift in the ecliptic plane of the apparent ion flow in
spacecraft reference frame has been deduced. The density is computed by
assuming the ions are thermal energy with a speed equivalent to that of
the spacecraft. An approximate correction for spacecraft potential has
been applied. The data are normalized to the OIMS instrument for O+ and
all species are assumed to have the same sensitivity.
 
Several parameters result from the fit: 1) the best estimate of the
density for an approximate 12 second interval (LORES data set); and 2)
the phase shift of signal maximum; and 3) the minimum ion drift speed in
the ecliptic plane. The phase angle is negative if the predicted signal
maximum from the spacecraft velocity is ahead of the true signal maximum
when viewed along the -Z spacecraft axis with clockwise rotation.  The
drift component is derived from the condition that the total relative
velocity in the moving reference frame has no component perpendicular to
the (ONMS axis, Z axis) plane.
 
All data were processed at NASA/Goddard Space Flight Center using custom
programmed software. The software is available. The data represent a
reduction to physical units (density, flux) and were processed from an
intermediate engineering unit file (current, count/sec etc.). Unit and
1/8 unit amu sweeps are not contained in the processed data sets but are
available from the engineering unit data set. The engineering unit data
is converted to ambient values using spacecraft velocity and attitude,
the theoretical expected system response, and the corresponding
calibration factors. Superthermal ion data for species other than O+ is
available in engineering unit form.
 
Kasprzak, W.T. and H.B. Niemann, Evidence for Enhanced Dynamic
  Flow in Ionospheric Holes from the Pioneer Venus Neutral Mass
  Planetary Space Sciences, 40, 33-45,1992.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
In order to fit the data a minimum of 30 points were required in 36
seconds. In addition, the maximum to minimum count ratio was required to
be factor of 3 or greater in order to insure that there was a definitive
spin modulation.  The center 12 seconds of data is divided by the
fitting function to derive the equivalent flux for that point. The
center of the new fitting interval is adjusted so that it is centered on
the expected signal maximum predicted from the previous interval fit. As
a result of this method of fitting, discontinuities may exist near
minimum angle of attack where one 12 second interval adjoins the next
interval.
 
See Kasprzak et al. (1992).
 
Kasprzak, W.T. and H.B. Niemann, Evidence for Enhanced Dynamic
  Flow in Ionospheric Holes from the Pioneer Venus Neutral Mass
  Planetary Space Sciences, 40, 33-45,1992.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>78-051A-11H</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XD-B3A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

