<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mpfr-m-rvreng-2-3-edr-rdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MARS PATHFINDER ROVER MARS ENG 2/3 EDR/RDR VERSION 1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_pathfinder::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mpfr::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rcrr.mpfr::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mpfr-m-rvreng-2-3-edr-rdr-v1.0__browserp_mpfr-m-rvreng-2_3-edr_rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mpfr-m-rvreng-2-3-edr-rdr-v1.0__dvo_imaging_mpfr-m-rvreng-2_3-edr_rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TBD</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MPFR-M-RVRENG-2/3-EDR/RDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MARS PATHFINDER ROVER MARS ENG 2/3 EDR/RDR VERSION 1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1998-01-04</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1997-07-05T02:18:30.266Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1997-09-25T04:52:07.936Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>HENRY W. STONE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Stone, H. W., MARS PATHFINDER ROVER MARS ENG 2/3 EDR/RDR VERSION
            1.0, MPFR-M-RVRENG-2/3-EDR/RDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            1998
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The rover engineering files on this CD contain raw and reduced
            (engineering unit) values for each and every rover channel as
            defined within the Missions Ground Data System Channel Parameter
            Table (CPT).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The rover engineering files on this CD contain raw and reduced
            (engineering unit) values for each and every rover channel as
            defined within the Missions Ground Data System Channel Parameter
            Table (CPT) configuration file.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The rover engineering files on this CD contain raw and reduced
    (engineering unit) values for each and every rover channel as
    defined within the Missions Ground Data System Channel Parameter
    Table (CPT) configuration file.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    Channels
 
    Each of the rover data files contain 380 columns of channelized
    data (i.e., 380 individual channels) and 5 additional columns
    containing the Sol number and the four time values SCLK, SCET,
    ERT, and LST as described below.  Each channel has a unique
    channel identifier of the form E-nnnn or R-nnnn (i.e., the letter
    &apos;E&apos; or &apos;R&apos; followed by a hyphen and a four digit number).  The
    channel identifiers are contained in the header rows of each
    &apos;.CSV&apos; file, and in the PDS labels of the &apos;.TAB&apos; files.
 
    The identifiers can be used as a cross reference into the Rover
    Telemetry Dictionary and into the Channel Parameter Table (CPT)
    and Channel Conversion Language (CCL) configuration files.  Note
    that there are many more channels contained within these data
    files than there are channels defined within the Rover Telemetry
    Dictionary.  The reason for this is that during mission
    operations it was advantageous for the ground data system to
    generate synthesized channels in order to drive a variety of
    real-time display tools.
 
    Channels which do not appear in the &apos;ch_id&apos; column of the Rover
    Telemetry Dictionary are synthesized channels and have been
    derived on the ground via one of several methods.  These include
    generation during initial decommutation of the rover telemetry
    messages by the ground data system decommutation program
    &apos;ccsds_tlm&apos; or by the derived channel algorithms written and
    contained within the missions CCL configuration file.
 
    There are a number of channels (i.e., columns) within the rover
    data files on this CD which do not contain any data.  This is not
    an error or omission in the data files but rather an artifact of
    the fact that a number of channels were initially defined earlier
    in the development of the ground data system but never used.
 
    As a consequence of the existence of synthesized channels and the
    particular needs of the real-time display tools used during
    mission operations, you will notice what appears to be a
    multiplicity in the number of measurements of the same logical
    value (i.e, the X accelerometer measurements) at the same instant
    in time.  For example, every instant of time that a value appears
    in the data tables for channel R-2550 (&apos;Rover X Position, Start&apos;
    ...  see Rover Telemetry Dictionary, Section 5.0) you will see
    the same value appearing in the column for channel R-0500, but
    not vice versa.  Channel R-2550 is defined to be a &apos;unique
    channel&apos; as opposed to a &apos;common channel&apos;.
 
    &apos;Unique channels&apos; contain measurements made of a particular
    logical value during the execution of a specific set of rover
    commands (one or more).  The &apos;common channels&apos;, in general,
    contain all measurements of a logical value regardless of which
    command was actually responsible for taking the measurement.
    Hence, unique channels are much more sparsely populated with
    actual data than are the common channels.
 
    Channel Ordering
 
    The 380 columns of channelized rover data contained with the
    rover data files are ordered by channel identifiers starting with
    the E-nnnn channels first (in ascending numeric order) followed
    by the R-nnnn channels (in ascending numeric order).  As a
    consequence of this and the way in which the rover channels were
    initially defined, channels which are normally associated with
    one another (e.g., common and unique X accelerometer measurements
    do not appear in adjacent columns within the file.  The user can
    easily rearrrange the columns in any fashion so desired.  Note
    the channel identifiers are NOT sequential (e.g., 3,4,5).  There
    are gaps in the identifier numbering.  These are not missing
    channels they are simply channel identifiers which were never
    used.
 
    Row Ordering
 
    The data files SOLxx_DN.TAB and SOLxx_EU.TAB vary in length from
    Sol to Sol.  Within each file the rows are time ordered based
    upon the time at which the measurement was taken by the rover (or
    at least the time the rover thought it was ...  see the section
    &apos;Limitations - Timestamping Anomalies&apos; later in this document).
    The data contained within the files within directory
    &apos;RVR_ENG/SOLxx/&apos; corresponds to measurements actually taken (i.e,
    acquired by) by the rover on the &apos;xx-th&apos; sol of the mission as
    opposed to when the information was received on earth.  The later
    information is contained within the &apos;ERT&apos; column or each file.
 
    Image Data
 
    The files SOLxx_DN.TAB and SOLxx_EU.TAB contain channels of
    information relating to the characteristics and conditions under
    which the rover took images using its three cameras (e.g.,
    exposure time, temperature).  The actual image data (i.e, the
    pixel values), however, was not channelized and hence is not
    contained within these engineering data files.  Rover images
    (i.e., images taken by the rover&apos;s cameras are available
    elsewhere on this CD).
 
    APXS Spectra Data
 
    The files SOLxx_DN.TAB and SOLxx_EU.TAB contain several channels
    of data associated with measurements from the Alpha Proton X-Ray
    Spectrometer Instrument which was onboard the Sojourner Vehicle.
    These channels contain a mix of ancilliary data as well as the
    actual spectra data.  The separation of the ancilliary data from
    the actual spectra data is accommodated within these data
    products.  Instead special software tools elsewhere in the ground
    data system were used to process the telemetered data and
    actually convert it into spectra and ancilliary data sets.  The
    processed/decommutated spectra data are archived elsewhere on
    this CD.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    There are 75 subdirectories within the rover engineering data
    directory, one for each Martian Day (Sol) of the surface mission
    and one for each of the two cruise health checks (i.e.,
    &apos;cruise1&apos;, and &apos;cruise2&apos;).  (Directories containing no data were
    deleted.) The name of each directory contains the Sol number
    (e.g., SOL45 corresponding to the forty fifth day on Mars).  Each
    directory contains two (2) compressed data files and two PDS
    labels.
 
    The data files have been compressed using the ZIP compression
    utility.  The decompression utility UNZIP is widely available.
    Information about where it can be obtained, and source code (if
    necessary), is provided in the SOFTWARE/ directory on this CD.
 
    The files SOLxx_DN.ZIP contain the DN (data number) values for
    each and every rover channel as defined within the Missions
    Ground Data System Channel Parameter Table (CPT) configuration
    file.  The files named SOLxx_EU.ZIP contain the EU (engineering
    unit) values for each and every rover channel as defined within
    the the Missions Ground Data System CPT file, if and only if the
    channel was defined to have an engineering unit conversion.  For
    those channels which no such conversion was defined, the
    SOLxx_EU.ZIP file contains the DN value.
 
    Each compressed file contains a copy of the PDS label, and two
    versions of the data file.  One of these versions, with the file
    extension &apos;.TAB&apos;, is formatted according to PDS standards for
    tables and is fully described by the PDS label.  The other
    version of the data file, with extension &apos;.CSV&apos;, is a simple
    comma-separated value table.  Both versions of the tables are
    large and relatively sparsely filled.
 
    The PDS formatted tables are formatted so that they can be read
    directly into many data management systems.  All fields are
    separated by commas, and character fields are enclosed in double
    quotation marks.  Character fields are left justified, and
    numeric fields are right justified.  Each record ends with the
    ASCII carriage return &lt;CR&gt; and line feed &lt;LF&gt; characters.  The
    &apos;.LBL&apos; files are PDS label files that describe the content and
    structure of the fields in their corresponding tables, including
    field name, format, and description.  The values for start byte
    and number of bytes listed in the label file do not include
    commas between fields or quotation marks surrounding character
    fields.
 
    The &apos;.CSV&apos; files are saved in Comma Separated Value (CSV) file
    format.  Newlines within the file indicate the start of a new row
    within the table and commas (,) mark the separation between
    columns within the table.  The files are in ASCII format and are
    designed to be read into most spreadsheet type applications
    programs (e.g., Microsoft Excel) or processed using relatively
    simple text parsing scripts/programs.  Given that the &apos;.CSV&apos;
    files are significantly smaller in size than the PDS-formatted
    files, they may be easier to load into some database or
    spreadsheet programs.  The &apos;.CSV&apos; files all have four header
    lines which describe the contents of the fields.
 
    Each column within these files corresponds to a specific channel
    of data.  The channel number, format specification (C programming
    style print format used originally to generate the channel by the
    ground data system), DN or EU designation, and units of
    measurement for each column is contained within the first four
    rows of each file (in the &apos;.CSV&apos; files) or in the PDS label (for
    the &apos;.TAB&apos; files).  In the case of the SOLxx_EU files, if there
    was no conversion algorithm in the ground data system to convert
    the DN value to EU values, the corresponding header value for
    that column will have a value of &apos;DN&apos;.  There are a few columns
    which do not have DN/EU designators and/or channel numbers.
    These included the first three columns which contain the Sol
    number, local standard time (i.e., Martian time at the landing
    site), and the SpaceCraft Event Time (SCET); and the last two
    columns which contain the Spacecraft Clock (SCLK) and the Earth
    Receive Time (ERT), respectively.
 
    Each row within the table (with the exception of the first four
    &apos;header rows&apos; in the &apos;.CSV&apos; files) corresponds to a particular
    instant in time at which one or more measurements were taken by
    the rover and telemetered back to earth.  The time at which the
    measurement(s) were taken is indicated by the SOL/LST, SCET, and
    SCLK time values contained within each and every row.  There are
    approximately 380 channels of data contained with each of the
    rover data files.  Only a few channels are measured at any
    instant in time and hence these tables are VERY sparsely
    populated.
 
    All of the rover data files have exactly the same number of
    columns.  In addition, the i-th column of every file corresponds
    to the same rover data channel although in the SOLxx_EU files the
    actual values for the channel may be in EUs as opposed to DNs.
 
    The pairs of files SOLxx_DN and SOLxx_EU contained within each
    sol directory have exactly the same number of rows and columns.
    Within a particular sol directory, the i-th row in file SOLxx_DN
    and SOLxx_EU will always correspond to the same instant in time.
    The number of rows within the SOLxx_DN and SOLxx_EU files,
    however will vary from sol directory to sol directory depending
    upon how much information was collected by the rover.
 
    The fixed and consistent format of the data files SOLxx_DN, and
    similarly for the SOLxx_EU files, are such that files from
    different sols can be simply concatenated in order to create
    multi-sol data files to support multi-sol analyses (albeit you
    will most likely want to first delete the first four &apos;header&apos;
    rows from all but the first of concatenated files).
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    The Rover Telemetry Dictionary, mentioned above, can be found in
    the DOCUMENT/ROVERDOC/TLMDICT/ directory on this CD.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    Complete documentation about the UNZIP decompression software
    necessary to decompress these files is available in the SOFTWARE/
    directory on this CD.
 
    These tables can be read using many database or spreadsheet
    software packages.  However, the length of the records or the
    large number of columns may pose difficulties for some software.
 
    If you need assistance finding software that can be used to
    decompress or display these tables, please contact the PDS
    operator at the following address:
 
    Address:     Planetary Data System, PDS Operator
                 Jet Propulsion Laboratory
                 4800 Oak Grove Drive
                 Pasadena, CA 91109
 
    Phone:       (818) 354-4321
    Email:       pds_operator@jpl.nasa.gov
    WWW URL:     http://pds.nasa.gov/
 
 
  Media / Format
  ==============
    The Rover Engineering data is stored on compact disc-read only
    memory (CD-ROM) media.  The CD is formatted according to ISO-9660
    and PDS standards.  The data files do not include extended
    attribute records (XARs), and are therefore not readable on some
    older VMS operating systems.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
 
    Review
    ------
      Prior to release, the data will be reviewed by the Rover Team
      and the Planetary Data System.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    Derived Channel Data Anomalies
 
    Due to limitations within the capabilities of the Channel
    Conversion Language (CCL) portion of the Mars PathFinder (MPF)
    Ground Data System (GDS), a number of rover derived channels
    contain &apos;bogus&apos; values which are not explicitly indicated as such
    in the rover data files contained on the CD.  These values should
    be replaced by &apos;INVALID&apos; markers by the user prior to analysis.
    The algorithm(s) for determining which values are bogus are
    described below along with a list of potentially affected
    channels.
 
    Pitch, Roll, Tilt:
 
    Derived Channels:
 
          R-0518
          R-0519
          R-0536
          R-0537
          R-0538
          R-0539
          R-0540
          R-0541
          R-0542
          R-0543
          R-0544
          R-0545
          R-0616
          R-0617
          R-2636
          R-2637
          R-2638
          R-2736
          R-2737
          R-2738
          R-3608
          R-3609
          R-3618
          R-3619
          R-3628
          R-3629
          R-3708
          R-3709
          R-3808
          R-3809
          R-3908
          R-3909
          R-3918
          R-3919
          R-3928
          R-3929
 
    Corrective Action:
 
    If any value for DN and/or EU of any of the above listed channels
    is greater than &apos;45.0&apos; the value is INVALID.
 
    Explaination
 
    The above channels, which correspond to angular values (i.e, in
    degrees) of the rover&apos;s pitch, roll, and tilt, are derived by a
    Channel Conversion Language (CCL) routine which takes the actual
    measurements of the rover&apos;s three linear accelerometers and
    converts them to an angular measurements using simple sine and
    cosine functions.
 
    If the value of the accelerometer reading was greater than 1 Mars
    G (= 3/8 of an earth G) the CCL algorithm would generate one of
    several bogus values (e.g., 360.0, 361.0, 362.0).  This was done
    because the ground data system was unable to mix data types
    within a channel.  Hence, you couldn&apos;t literally put in the value
    &apos;INVALID&apos; for the above derived channels since these channels
    were defined to be floating point numbers.
 
    Now you ask, why would the accelerometers ever read more than 1
    Mars G.  The answer is we don&apos;t exactly know but such raw
    measurements were intermittently obtained during the later part
    of the mission.
 
    Other Channel Data Anomalies
 
    General
 
    Due to limitations within the capabilities of the Channel
    Parameter Table (CPT) portion of the Mars PathFinder (MPF) Ground
    Data System (GDS), a number of rover non-derived channel,
    engineering unit representations of the actual DN value contain
    &apos;misleading&apos; information if not properly interpreted.  These
    values should be replaced by markers indicating that these
    particular entries/values have special significance.
 
    Temperature Measurements
 
    The first example of potentially misleading values is in the case
    of the temperature sensors.  The rover&apos;s temperature sensors and
    temperature sensor electronics interface were such that if a
    temperature sensor became disconnected from the rover&apos;s
    electronics (e.g., a broken wire or bad solder joint) the analog
    input signal sent to the rover&apos;s Analog to Digital converter
    would be &apos;pulled high&apos; causing the A/D converter to saturate in
    turn producing a telemetered temperature reading of &apos;7FF&apos; (HEX).
 
    The ground data system was not capable of detecting this prior to
    converting it to a engineering unit temperature value and
    stuffing that value into the channels EU value field.  While the
    conversion function for each temperature sensor is different
    (i.e., they were individually calibrated) a DN value of 7FF will
    produce an EU value of approximately 77 degC.
 
    The point is that if you see any EU temperature values in the
    SOLxx_EU files in the range of 77degC you should correlate this
    with the DN value in the corresponding SOLxx_DN file to confirm
    that the EU value should actually be replaced by a marker such as
    &apos;OUT_OF_RANGE&apos;.  Such measurements were obtained during the later
    portion of the mission on one of the front wheel temperature
    sensors.  During the beginning of the mission this sensor was
    producing consistently reasonable measurements.  later in the
    mission it began saturating whenever it starting getting cold
    (e.g., early in the morning and at night).  Eventually, it
    produced only the saturated value.  We have hypothesized that the
    wire to the sensor and/or one of the related solder joints failed
    during the mission due to thermal cycling.
 
    Laser Spot Measurements
 
    Channels R-1400 through R-1419 correspond to measurements of the
    height of terrain in front of the rover at 20 distinct point
    (i.e., a 4 x 5 grid of points).  The EU values for these channels
    measure the height of the terrain at these points in millimeters
    measured relative to where the lasers would have detected the
    surface to be terrain to be had the rover been sitting on a flat
    surface.  Negative values mean there is a depression (e.g., drop
    off) and positive values represent the presence of an obstacle
    (e.g., a rock).
 
    What is important to remember when analyzing this data is that if
    the rover was unable to detect the location of the laser spot on
    the surface it would send a telemetry value of 7FFF/-128
    HEX/DECIMAL).  Analogous to the temperature sensor issue
    described above, the Ground Data System is/was incapable of
    marking these values so that they would be interpreted to mean
    &apos;SPOT NOT DETECTED&apos;.  Hence, scientists/engineers analyzing the
    laser data on this CD should do this so as not to misinterpret
    the results.  In the files containing the EU values for these
    channels the DN value of 7FFF/-128 (HEX/DECIMAL) gets convertered
    into a value of -179.2 mm.  EU values of -179.2 mm should
    likewise be replaced with a &apos;SPOT NOT DETECTED&apos; marker in the
    SOLxx_EU files.  The bottom line is that such values should NOT
    be interpreted to mean that the rover drove up to hole/cliff that
    was 179.2 mm deep!
 
    There are several reasons why the rover&apos;s hazard detection system
    (i.e., camera/laser system) would fail to detect/see the spot
    generated by one of it&apos;s lasers.  One such reason is that it is
    possible for the rover to physically attain a kinematic
    configuration in which either the front right or front left
    wheels are positioned high enough (via the rocker-bogie
    suspension system) that the wheel actually blocks the projection
    of the lasers output beam and hence the camera(s) are unable to
    detect the beam on the surface of the ground.
 
    The remaining reasons for the existence of the &apos;SPOT NOT
    DETECTED&apos; values are all associated with the physical geometry of
    the terrain and the relative positioning of the cameras and
    lasers to one another.  Fundamentally, the camera/laser detection
    system is based upon measuring distances via triangulation
    between the emitted laser beam and the line of sight from the
    camera to the spot on the terrain illuminated by the laser.
    Obviously there must be a clear line of sight between the camera
    and the actual physical spot on the terrain which is illuminated
    by the laser in order for the camera to see the spot.  There are,
    however, situations in which the laser beam can enter a very
    sharp depression in the terrain, such as in the case of hitting a
    point within a small hole in a vesicular rock, and the line of
    sight from this spot to the camera is obstructed by the
    sharp/steep walls of the hole.  In such a case, the rover would
    not be able to detect the spot at all and it was therefore
    programmed to generate a value of 7FFF in the telemetry data for
    the measurement.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    Timestampimg Anomalies
 
    The Sojourner rover did NOT have an independently powered mission
    clock circuit.  As a consequence, when the rover&apos;s batteries were
    finally exhausted on Sol 58 the rover no longer had an accurate
    means for knowing what time it was when it automatically woke up
    via solar power and the lander was unavailable (i.e., it&apos;s rover
    modem was not yet powered on) to provide an clock/time update.
    This situation unfortunately creates a number of complications in
    terms of analyzing rover data collected after Sol 58,
    particularly, data taken during the early morning hours prior to
    the rover getting an clock update from the lander.
 
    The thing to remember when analyzing the rover data for Sols 58
    and beyond is that the rover executes one command at a time
    (i.e., serially) and executes them in &apos;command sequence number&apos;
    order (e.g., command 61001 is executed prior to command 61002,
    etc).  Thus, any regressions in the command sequence numbers
    contained in these files as time increases is a clear indication
    that a block of data taken by the rover that morning was
    incorrectly timestamped.  Note that the relative timestamping
    within the block is correct its just that the entire block is
    offset in time from when it was actually taken.
 
    A simple example of the situation that occurs should help to
    explain the situation.  Consider the situation in which the rover
    automatically wakes up via solar power at 7:00 am (LST).  Also
    assume that the lander&apos;s rover modem was not yet powered on at
    this time and hence when the rover, during wakeup, tries to get a
    clock update from the lander it cannot.  Under these conditions,
    the rover sets its mission clock according to its best estimate
    of what time it is which happens to correspond to the last time
    it was instructed to wake up.  Lets say that time was 10:00 am.
    The rover then begins/continues to execute its active command
    sequence and time stamps the data starting with 10:00 am on.
    Lets also say, for expository purposes, that the rover executes
    five commands with command sequence numbers 61005, 61006, 61007,
    61008, 61009 and the data from command 61009 is taken at 7:30 am
    (LST).  Because the rover&apos;s clock is off the data from command
    61009 is timestamped as having been collected at 10:30 am (LST).
 
    Now assume that at 7:31 am (LST), the lander powers up it&apos;s rover
    modem and that after executing command 61009 the rover performs
    one of its automatic and/or commanded attempts to contact the
    lander to get a clock update.  The rover does so receiving and an
    update which indicates that the current time is 7:31 am and sets
    it&apos;s mission clock accordingly.  Then command 61010 is executed.
    The telemetry data collected by this command is then timestamped
    as having been taken at 7:31 am.
 
    In the rover data files which are time ordered by SCET, you will
    find the block of commands 61005-61009 appearing after the data
    entries (i.e, rows) containing the data collected by command
    61010.  Again, this situation is relatively easy to detect in the
    data files by simply looking at the ordering of the command
    sequence numbers for each entry (i.e., row).
 
    Ideally, the thing to do is to take the timestamps on the data
    entries for commands 61005-61009 and subtract 3 hours (10:00am -
    7:00am) from each.  Unfortunately, their is no precise way to
    back calculate what time the rover actually woke up.  The wakeup
    time is a function of many unknown variables including actual
    (not measured) vehicle orientation, tilt, optical density of the
    atmosphere on that particular morning, and electrical performance
    of the solar array to name a few.  While one can, with some work,
    come up with a reasonable estimate we have not done so to the
    rover data contained within the rover data files on this CD.
 
    Finally, depending upon the timing involved (e.g., the length of
    time it takes the rover to execute the commands 61005-61009 in
    the example above, the actual time that the rover wakes up, and
    the actual time at which rover is first able to get a clock
    update from the lander) it is possible for the block of commands
    61005-61009 in our example to be interlaced with commands 61010
    and above.  This makes rearranging the data files to be in actual
    time order more complicated and is a process not easily
    automated.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>IN_QUEUE</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

