<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lp-l-er-3-rdr-3deleflux-80sec-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LP ELECTRON REFLECTOMETER 3D ENERGY SPECTRA 80SEC V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_prospector::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:er.lp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lp-l-er-3-rdr-3deleflux-80sec-v1.0__browserc_lp-l-er-3-rdr-3deleflux-80sec-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lp-l-er-3-rdr-3deleflux-80sec-v1.0__browserp_lp-l-er-3-rdr-3deleflux-80sec-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Acuna, M.H., J.E.P. Connerney, P. Wasilewski, R.P. Lin, K.A. Anderson, C.W.
                   Carlson, J. McFadden, D.W. Curtis, H. Reme, A. Cros, J.L. Medale, J.A. Sauvaud,
                   C. d&apos;Uston, S.J. Bauer, P. Cloutier, M. Mayhew, and N.F. Ness, Mars Observer
                   Magnetic Fields Investigation, J. Geophys. Res., 97, 7799-7814, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ACUNAETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Binder, A.B., W.C. Feldman, G.S. Hubbard, A.S. Konopliv, R.P. Lin, M.H. Acuna,
                   and L.L. Hood, Lunar Prospector searches for polar ice, a metallic core, gas
                   release events, and the moon&apos;s origin, Eos, Trans. AGU, 79, 97, 1998.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BINDERETAL1998</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Carlson, C., D. Curtis, G. Paschmann, and W. Michael, An instrument for rapidly
                   measuring plasma distribution functions with high resolution, Adv. Space Res.,
                   2, 67, 1983.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CARLSONETAL1983</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LP-L-ER-3-RDR-3DELEFLUX-80SEC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LP ELECTRON REFLECTOMETER 3D ENERGY SPECTRA 80SEC V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1999-01-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1998-01-16</start_time>
        <stop_time>1999-07-29</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. DAVID MITCHELL</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>not applicable</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Time ordered 3-D spectrum data from the Lunar Prospector Electron
            Reflectometer, in units of particles/cm**2/sec/steradian/eV, for
            dates 1998-01-16 to 1999-07-29.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>not applicable</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The Electron Reflectometer 3-D (ER3D) data is a time ordered series
    of electron measurements from the Lunar Prospector (LP) Mission.
    Each record consists of a time tag with an 88 x 15 array of scalar
    data points representing measurements of the electron flux in 88
    solid angles covering 4-pi steradians and 15 energy channels
    logarithmically spaced from 10 eV to 20 keV, with an energy
    resolution (dE/E) of 25%.  Each data point is a measure of the
    electron flux (cm-2 sec-1 ster-1 eV-1) within one of the 88
    approximately equal-sized solid angles.  Angles are given in &apos;&apos;despun
    spacecraft&apos;&apos; (SCD) coordinates, in which the Z-axis coincides with
    the spacecraft spin vector, and the direction of the sun is in the
    half plane defined by X &gt; 0, Y = 0.  These data records are
    accumulated during 1/2 spin of the spacecraft (~2.5 seconds) and
    sampled every 16 spins (~80 seconds).  For convenience, the average
    magnetic field vector during the ~2.5-second accumulation time is
    provided to facilitate calculation of electron pitch angle
    distributions from the 3-D data.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The ER 3-D data are provided as differential electron flux in units
    of particles per square cm per second per steradian per electron
    volt.  The center angles of the 88 solid angle bins are provided in
    degrees of longitude and latitude in the SCD coordinate system (see
    below for the definition of SCD coordinates).  Note that the center
    angles vary with energy, since the spacecraft rotates by 11.25
    degrees during the time that the ER sweeps through its energy range.
    Each of the 88 solid angle bins are approximately the same size. The
    exact sizes are given in the following table:
 
      Latitude Range      Number of         Solid Angle
        (degrees)       Longitude Bins    Bin Size (ster)
     -----------------------------------------------------
       67.5 to  90.0          4              0.119570
       45.0 to  67.5          8              0.170253
       22.5 to  45.0         16              0.127401
        0.0 to  22.5         16              0.150279
        0.0 to -22.5         16              0.150279
      -22.5 to -45.0         16              0.127401
      -45.0 to -67.5          8              0.170253
      -67.5 to -90.0          4              0.119570
     -----------------------------------------------------
 
    In the above table, latitudes are given in SCD coordinates, and the
    longitude bins are of equal size within each latitude range.
 
    ER 3-D distributions are recorded for 15 different energies ranging
    from 10 eV to 20 keV.  The energy sweep was changed several times
    during the mission for both instrumental and scientific reasons.
    There are two basic sweeps, the first from 40 eV to 20 keV, and the
    second from 7 eV to 20 keV.  The first is used to avoid instrumental
    saturation in the solar wind, where fluxes are relatively high.  The
    second is used to enhance the science return in the geomagnetic tail
    lobes, where fluxes are relatively low.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    Processing is carried out at the Space Sciences Laboratory (SSL) of
    the University of California, Berkeley (UCB), to convert the raw data
    to measurements of the electron flux (cm-2 s-1 ster-1 eV-1) in 88
    solid angles as a function of time.  Because of the instrument&apos;s high
    dynamic range (six decades), the onboard digital processing unit
    (DPU) compresses the raw counts in a logarithmic scale.  The first
    step is to decompress the raw counts and construct a
    three-dimensional data array, where the first dimension is time (1
    element every 16 spins), the second dimension is direction (88
    elements spanning 4-pi steradians), and the third dimension is energy
    (15 elements).
 
    Raw count rate (R) is obtained by dividing the raw counts by the
    integration time, which is a function of energy and solid angle.  In
    general terms, the integration time is longer at higher energies (to
    improve counting statistics) and near the poles of the SCD coordinate
    system, because the ER&apos;s disk-shaped field of view (FOV) always
    includes the poles but requires the spacecraft spin to sweep the FOV
    along the equator.  The data are next corrected for deadtime.  During
    the time it takes the instrument to process a single electron (known
    as the &apos;&apos;deadtime&apos;&apos;, which is about 0.3 microsec for the ER), it
    ignores any other electrons.  The raw count rate is multiplied by the
    factor 1/(1 - RT), where T is the deadtime, to obtain the corrected
    count rate.  Data values are masked when the deadtime correction
    factor exceeds 1.25.  Note that a background count rate due to cosmic
    rays and noise in the electronics (about 10 counts/sec) has not been
    subtracted.  In most cases, measurements in the highest energy
    channel (20 keV) are dominated by background, which allows this
    channel to be used as a baseline for estimating the background level
    in lower energy channels.  Finally, one divides by the geometric
    factor (0.02 cm2 ster) and the center energy (eV) to obtain the
    differential particle flux (cm-2 s-1 ster-1 eV-1).
 
    The electron directions (i.e., the directions in the centers of each
    of the 88 solid angles) are rotated into despun spacecraft (SCD)
    coordinates using sunpulse data.  Special care must be taken when the
    spacecraft is in the Moon&apos;s shadow, where the spacecraft spins up
    slightly as the booms cool and contract.  This gradual spin-up is
    reconstructed on the ground and is not available in real time as the
    ER is collecting data and sorting it into the 3-D data array.  Thus,
    the 3-D look directions must be corrected during post processing
    based on the reconstructed sunpulse data.  Note that an electron&apos;s
    direction is parallel to its velocity.  In other words, we record
    where the electrons are going to, not where they are coming from.
    Finally, the average magnetic field direction (in SCD coordinates)
    during the accumulation time of the 3-D electron distribution is
    calculated and saved with each 3-D data record.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    Data are archived on DVDs in compliance with the ISO 9660 and UDF
    standards. Most DVDs contain 5 months of data. The data are provided
    as ASCII tables of 1 day duration. Each record contains data
    sampled over 16 spacecraft spins (but accumulated over each 1/2
    spacecraft spin) so that a full 3-D spectrum can be produced as the
    detector spins and steps.  To satisfy telemetry constraints, full
    3-D spectra are obtained once every 16 spacecraft spins.
 
    A row (record) in a data file consists of the following fields:
 
       PDS_time:      Time in PDS standard time format.
       time:          Time in seconds since Jan. 1, 1970.
       energy:        Energy bin value.
       spec_no:       Spectrum number (see below under
                      &apos;&apos;Table structure&apos;&apos;).
       MagFieldDespunSCCoords:  Array[3] giving magnetic field values.
       ele_flux:      Array[88] giving electron flux in 88 angle bins.
       dist_phi:      Array[88] giving phi values.
 
    Record format:
 
       PDS_time (A19), time (1X, F15.0), energy (1X, F9.3),
       spec_no (1X, I4, 1X), MagFieldDespunSCCoords 3(F13.6, 1X),
       ele_flux 88(1X, E9.3), phi 88(1X, F6.2).
 
       Each record is terminated by the carriage return and line feed
       (CR/LF) characters.
 
    Table structure:
 
       Each spectrum of 15 electron energies is represented by a set of
       15 consecutive records in the table.  Each such spectrum has a
       distinct spectrum number, which occurs in each record in the
       15-record set.
 
    In addition, there is a file THETA.TAB that gives the
    inclination angle (theta) for each detector step as the
    instrument cycles. These angles are fixed. There is one theta
    value associated with each of the 88 electron flux values.
    THETA.TAB is an ASCII table with one row and 88 columns.
 
    The data were placed in their present format after processing.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    There are several ancillary data sets provided with this
    archive. These include:
 
       Spacecraft Attitude data    LP-L-ENG-6-ATTITUDE-V1.0
       Spacecraft Ephemeris data   LP-L-6-EPHEMERIS-V1.0
       Spacecraft Position data    LP-L-6-TRAJECTORY-V1.0
       Spacecraft Command logs     LP-L-ENG-6-COMMAND-V1.0
 
    These data sets provide additional information about the state
    of the spacecraft and the instrument during data acquisition
    that may aid in the scientific analysis of this data set.
 
 
  Coordinate System(s)
  ====================
    The 3-D data are provided in &apos;&apos;despun spacecraft&apos;&apos; (SCD)
    coordinates, in which the Z-axis coincides with the spacecraft spin
    vector, and the direction of the sun is in the half plane defined
    by X &gt; 0, Y = 0.  Throughout most of the mission the spacecraft
    spin vector was within a few degrees of either the north or south
    ecliptic pole.  Thus, SCD coordinates are closely related to GSE
    coordinates.  Conversion to GSE coordinates is not performed because
    the electrons are constrained to move along the magnetic field lines
    in helices with radii of only a few kilometers.  Thus, only electron
    directions with respect to the magnetic field are meaningful.  The
    magnetic field direction is provided in SCD coordinates for each ER
    3-D distribution, so that electron pitch angle distributions can be
    readily calculated.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    There are no software provided with this data archive.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Review
  ======
    ER data quality has been reviewed at U.C. Berkeley by D.
    Mitchell, J. Halekas, M. Oieroset, T. Phan, S. Frey, and D.
    Curtis.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    The ER 3-D data are intended to be used in conjunction with
    magnetic field and spacecraft ephemeris data, from which
    electron pitch angle distributions can be calculated and
    magnetic field line tracing to the lunar surface can be
    performed.  Magnetic field data are preprocessed (rotated to SCD
    coordinates and averaged over the 3-D integration time) and
    provided with each 3-D data record to facilitate calculation of
    pitch angle distributions.  The magnetic field data are archived
    in separate tables in two different coordinate systems, which,
    together with spacecraft ephemeris data, allows field line
    tracing to the lunar surface.
 
 
  Data Quality
  ============
    The ER 3-D data are generally of very high quality.  Three
    instrumental effects should be noted. (1) Sunlight directly
    enters the ER aperture twice per spacecraft spin.  These photons
    scatter within the instrument and produce secondary electrons,
    which cause a false signal that can overwhelm the desired signal
    from ambient electrons.  In the SCD coordinate system, sunlight
    contamination appears as a flux spike in the direction of the
    sun (0 degrees longitude, ~0 degrees latitude).  The flux spike
    has a longitude width of about 14 degrees, and is more elongated
    in latitude.  (2) Electron fluxes are relatively high at low
    energies, and at times the instrument becomes saturated.
    A deadtime correction of the form 1/(1 - RT) is applied, where R
    is the measured count rate and T is the time needed to analyze a
    single electron.  This correction is only reliable up to values
    of about 1.25, above which data are flagged.  (3) Low energy
    electrons can be perturbed by the spacecraft floating potential
    relative to the plasma in which the spacecraft is immersed.  In
    sunlight, the spacecraft floats a few volts positive, and in the
    Moon&apos;s shadow, it floats tens of volts negative.  Electrons must
    cross this potential before they enter the ER electrostatic
    optics, thus all electron energies are shifted by this potential
    relative to their energies far from the spacecraft.  In addition,
    the trajectories of low energy electrons can be bent by the
    potential, so the imaging characteristics of the ER are degraded
    for electron energies that are comparable to or lower than the
    spacecraft potential.  No corrections are made for spacecraft
    potential effects.
 
 
  Data Coverage
  =============
    ER 3-D data are obtained during 1/2 spin (~2.5 seconds) and
    sampled every 16 spins (~80 seconds).  During this time, the
    spacecraft moves about 128 km in its orbit.
 
    A table of gaps in the raw merged telemetry data (OUTAGES.TAB) is
    included in the Level 0 Lunar Prospector archive (though not in the
    present Level 1 archive) as a rough indication of the data coverage.
    Other gaps may exist due to data contamination or processing
    limitations.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

