<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-e-v-h-sw-epps-2-fips-rawdata-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>EPPS UNCALIBRATED (EDR) DATA E/V/H V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:epps.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-sw-epps-2-fips-rawdata-v1.0__browserp_mess-e-v-h-sw-epps-2-fips-rawdata-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Andrews, G.B., T.H. Zurbuchen, B.H. Mauk, H. Malcom, L.A. Fisk, G. Gloeckler,
                   G.C. Ho, J.S. Kelley, P.L. Koehn, T.W. LeFevere, S.S. Livi, R.A. Lundgren, and
                   J.M. Raines, The Energetic Particle and Plasma Spectrometer instrument on the
                   MESSENGER spacecraft, Space Science Reviews, 131, 523-556, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ANDREWSETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-E/V/H/SW-EPPS-2-FIPS-RAWDATA-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>EPPS UNCALIBRATED (EDR) DATA E/V/H V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2008-07-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-09-13T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2008-01-28T23:59:59Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>GEORGE HO</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            G. C. Ho (APL), EPPS UNCALIBRATED (EDR) DATA E/V/H V1.0, NASA
            Planetary Data System, 2008
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The MESSENGER EPPS uncalibrated observations consist of energetic
            particle and plasma data collected by the EPPS instrument during
            fly-by and orbital operations of Mercury. Also included are
            cruise observations for calibration purposes.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== This data set consists of the MESSENGER
            Energetic Particle and Plasma Spectrometer (EPPS) uncalibrated
            observations, also known as EDRs. The system encompasses 2
            instrument subsystems - the Energetic Particle Spectrometer (EPS)
            and the Fast Imaging Plasma Spectrometer (FIPS). EPS covers the
            energy range of 25 to &gt; 500 keV for electrons, and 10
            keV/nucleon to ~3 MeV total energy for ions. FIPS covers the
            energy/ charge range of &lt; 50 eV/q to 20 keV/q. There are nine
            EDR data products, four of science and ancillary data for the EPS
            and the FIPS, and one of engineering and status for the total
            EPPS instrument.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The data set consists of uncalibrated observations, also known as
      EDRs.
 
      For all the EDR products there is a detached PDS label file that
      describes the contents of one data file. Each label file will have
      the same base name as the data file it is describing, with the
      extension .LBL to denote a label file. The label file defines the
      start time and end of the observation, product creation time, and
      the structure of the binary (or ASCII) tables.
 
      The EPS portion of the data archive will consist of four EDR data
      products, which correspond to the different types of science data
      packets generated by the instrument at high priority, medium
      priority, and low priority.  The EPS instrument creates all of its
      different science data packets during one observation, but the
      packets are telemetered to the ground at different times based on
      priority.  The different formats of these data packets do not lend
      themselves to standardization into one EDR file format. For
      example, the high priority science data packet contains the EPS
      high priority spectra, housekeeping information, and Pulse Hiehgt
      Analysis (PHA) data. Therefore, different EDR formats have been
      developed, each of which captures one specific data grouping
      spectra, housekeeping information, or PHA data.  A given EDR data
      file will contain all the observations obtained on same earth day.
 
      The FIPS portion of the data archive will consist of four EDR data
      products, which correspond to the three priorities of data
      produced by the FIPS instrument: high, medium, and low.  As with
      the EPS the different priority modes result in the data being
      collected and downloaded in different packet formats.  At high and
      medium priority, these packets contain multiple pieces of
      information, such as a spectral observation and housekeeping data.
      Therefore, different EDR formats have been developed, each of
      which captures one specific data grouping spectra, housekeeping
      information, or PHA data.
 
      There will be an EDR data product containing the engineering and
      status information for the EPPS instrument the EPPS Status EDR.
      This data product will consist of an external PDS label file and
      its pointer to an ASCII table file.  The data product is in ASCII
      to facilitate the browsing of instrument status parameters with
      commonly available text readers during mission operations.
 
      In addition to the science data, associated instrument parameters
      are included.
 
 
    Instrument Overview
    ===================
      The EPS sensor consists of a 60-mm diameter, tuna-can-like
      cylinder, in which a start foil and stop foil, wrapped around
      opposite curved sides of the cylinder, constitute the TOF chamber.
       The detectors are arranged so that each detector senses the
      events within a given range of incidence angles.  Each of the 6
      detector modules is composed of 4 pixels: large and small ion and
      large and small electron.  The FIPS consists of an electrostatic
      analyzer (ESA), located at the entrance to the sensor, a
      post-acceleration chamber between the output of the ESA and the
      carbon foil, and a time-of-flight telescope.  The ESA at the
      entrance to the FIPS acts as a wide-angle lens for ions.  It only
      allows ions with a specific energy/charge band to enter through
      its output plane.
 
      See the EPPSINST.CAT file for more information and
      [ANDREWSETAL2007] for full details.
 
 
    Calibration Overview
    ====================
      This data set is NOT calibrated; it only provides the uncalibrated
      sensor measurements.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      The principal parameters during normal science operations when
      observing with the EPPS are as follows:
 
      * EPS Medium-Priority Integration Interval (N2): This parameter
      sets the integration interval for medium-priority data (commonly
      30 s).
 
      * EPS High-Priority Integration Interval (N1): This parameter sets
      the integration interval for high-priority data (commonly 300 s).
      N1 is an integer-multiple of N2.
 
      * EPS Detector Selection: EPS possesses 24 detectors: 12 for ions
      and 12 for electrons.  Half are large-pixel, and half are
      small-pixel.  Only 12 detectors can be used simultaneously, so the
      operational detectors can be set by command.
 
      * FIPS Mode Selection: This command allows selection of the mode
      of operation: normal, burst, and pick-up ion.
 
      The EPPS also includes modes for testing the instrument and
      maintaince activities.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      The nine EDR data products are described as follows (the STANDARD_
      DATA_PRODUCT_ID value is given in parentheses):
 
      The High Priority EPS Spectra EDR (EPS_HI_SPECTRA) contains
      spectral data, hardware and software rate counters in binary table
      format.  Data and counter values are taken from the High Priority
      Science Packet.
 
      The High Priority Housekeeping EDR (EPS_HI_HOUSEKEEPING) is an
      ASCII table file that contains 33 fields of housekeeping data.
 
      The Medium Priority EPS Spectra EDR (EPS_MED_SPECTRA) contains
      spectral data, hardware and software rate counters in binary table
      format.  Data and counter values are taken from the Medium
      Priority Science Packet.
 
      The EPS Pulse Height EDR (EPS_PULSE_HEIGHT) contains Pulse Height
      Analysis data in binary table format.  The PHA data product is
      generated from the high, medium, or low priority science packet.
      The priority level will be identified within the PDS label.
 
      The High Priority FIPS Spectra EDR (FIPS_HI_SPECTRA) contains
      spectral and velocity distribution, hardware and software rate
      counters in binary table format.  Data and counter values are
      taken from the High Priority Science Packet.
 
      The High Priority FIPS Housekeeping EDR (FIPS_HI_HOUSEKEEPING) is
      an ASCII table file that contains 33 fields of housekeeping data
      taken from the High Priority Science Packet.
 
      The Medium Priority FIPS Spectra EDR (FIPS_MED_SPECTRA) contains
      proton velocity distribution, hardware and software rate counters
      in binary table format.  Data and counter values are taken from
      the Medium Priority Science Packet.
 
      The FIPS Pulse Height EDR (FIPS_PULSE_HEIGHT) contains FIPS Pulse
      Height Analysis data in binary table format.  This data product is
      generated from either high, medium, or low priority FIPS packets.
      The priority level will be identified within the PDS label.
 
      The EPPS Status EDR contains engineering and status information
      for the EPPS instrument.  The data product is in ASCII to
      facilitate the browsing of instrument status parameters with
      commonly available text readers during mission operations.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
   Confidence Level Overview
   =========================
     The EPPS EDR data are the least processed data set released for the
     EPPS.  Data presented here are an accurate representation of the EPPS
     data as received from the spacecraft, with minimal timing and no
     spatial processing.
 
 
   Review
   ======
     The EPPS EDR was reviewed internally by the EPPS team prior to
     release to the PDS. PDS also performed an external review of the
     EPPS EDR.
 
 
   Data Coverage and Quality
   =========================
     Data reported are the minimally processed data received from the
     spacecraft during the seven mission phases: Launch, Earth_Cruise,
     Earth_Flyby, Venus_1_Cruise, Venus_1_Flyby, Venus_2_Cruise,
     Venus_2_Flyby, Mercury_1_Crusise, Mercury_1_Flyby.  These mission
     phases are defined as:
 
                        Start time         End time
     Phase Name         Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)
     ----------------- ----------------  ----------------
     Launch             3 Aug 2004 (216)  12 Sep 2004 (256)
     Earth_Cruise      13 Sep 2004 (257)  18 Jul 2005 (199)
     Earth_Flyby       19 Jul 2005 (200)  16 Aug 2005 (228)
     Venus_1_Cruise    17 Aug 2005 (229)   9 Oct 2006 (282)
     Venus_1_Flyby     10 Oct 2006 (283)   7 Nov 2006 (311)
     Venus_2_Cruise     8 Nov 2006 (312)  22 May 2007 (142)
     Venus_2_Flyby     23 May 2007 (143)  20 Jun 2007 (171)
     Mercury_1_Cruise  21 Jun 2007 (172)  30 Dec 2007 (364)
     Mercury_1_Flyby   31 Dec 2007 (365)  28 Jan 2008 ( 28)
 
     No EPPS data were collected during Venus_1_Flyby phases.  The EPPS
     was on for brief periods during the other six mission phases.
     During these planned operational periods, the EPS sensor on the EPPS
     did not have high voltage enable, hence no Time-of-flight data and
     only spectra data were collected.  The EPS was turned on for the
     Venus_2_Flyby and to be remained on throughout the remainder of the
     mission phases.  EPPS data were collected during the Mercury_1_Flyby.
 
     EPS High Ion Sector 1 and 5 have malfunction detectors and do not
     produce any data product.
 
     The lowest energy channel (32 to 55 keV) on the High Ion Sector 3
     and 5 have periodic high count that are due to flight software
     interaction with the instrument and should not be used.  User of
     EPS data should consult with the instrument team at JHU/APL to
     verify the quality of specific data in certain time interval prior
     to publication.
 
     During nominal cruise operations, the radial-flowing solar wind
     is in a blocked segment of the FIPS sensor field-of-view (FOV).  Four
     times during the mission, the spacecraft was rotated such that
     the FIPS FOV can detect the nominal, radial-flowing
     solar wind.  These periods lasted from 1 hr to roughly 12 hrs and
     are identified as:
                        Start time         End time
     Phase Name         Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)
     ----------------- ----------------   ----------------
     Earth_Cruise      05 Apr 2005 (105)  05 Apr 2005 (105)
     Earth_Flyby       07 Aug 2005 (219)  07 Aug 2005 (219)
     Venus_1_Cruise    27 Feb 2006 (058)  27 Feb 2006 (058)
     Venus_2_Cruise    01 Mar 2006 (060)  01 Mar 2006 (060)
 
     When FIPS is run in Magnetospheric Mapping mode (8s/scan), as it
     was during Mercury Flyby 1, the channels above channel 55 are not
     used in order speed up scanning.  The rates in these channels are
     not updated properly by the flight software and should not be
     used.
 
     In general, interpretation of FIPS measurements requires detailed
     understanding of the FIPS FOV at the time of each individual
     measurement.  This FOV information is not incorporated into this
     data set in any way.  Users of this data are thus urged to
     consult with the FIPS instrument team at University of Michigan
     for serious scientific studies.
 
 
   Limitations
   ===========
     This data set is minimally processed data.  The data are received
     from the spacecraft telemetry and ingested into the MESSENGER
     Science Operations Center (SOC).
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SUPERSEDED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

