<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.co-e-j-s-sw-mimi-2-inca-uncalib-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CASSINI E/J/S/SW MIMI INCA SENSOR UNCALIBRATED DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mimi.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.saturn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:plasma_stream.solar_wind::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.co-e-j-s-sw-mimi-2-inca-uncalib-v1.0__browserp_co-e-j-s-sw-mimi-2-inca-uncalib-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Krimigis, S.M., D.G. Mitchell, D.C. Hamilton, S. Livi, J. Dandouras, S.
                   Jaskulek, T.P. Armstrong, J.D. Boldt, A.F. Cheng, G. Gloeckler, J.R. Hayes,
                   K.C. Hsieh, W.-H. Ip, E.P. Keath, E. Kirsch, N. Krupp, L.J. Lanzerotti, R.
                   Lundgren, B.H. Mauk, R.W. McEntire, E.C. Roelof, C.E. Schlemm, B.E. Tossman, B.
                   Wilken, and D.J. Williams, Magnetosphere Imaging Instrument (MIMI) on the
                   Cassini Mission to Saturn/Titan, Space Sci Rev. 114, 233-329, 2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KRIMIGISETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kusterer, M.B., L.M. Burke, Level 1A File Layouts, Cassini/MIMI Data Analysis
                   Center Level 1A File Layouts, The Johns Hopkins University Applied Physics
                   Laboratory Document, Revision 18, December 2003.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KUSTERER-BURKE2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Manweiler, J.W., W.A. Rasmuss, and S. Joy, MIMI Standard Data Products and
                   Archive Volume Software Interface Specification, v2.1, JPL Document D-31634,
                   Cassini document IO-AR-006, 2005.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MANWEILERETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CO-E/J/S/SW-MIMI-2-INCA-UNCALIB-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CASSINI E/J/S/SW MIMI INCA SENSOR UNCALIBRATED DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-04-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1999-01-03T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-06-30T23:59:59Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>Jerry W. Manweiler</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Manweiler, J.W., W. Rasmuss, and S. Joy,
            CO-E/J/S/SW-MIMI-2-INCA-UNCALIB-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2005.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains all of the data collected by the INCA
            sensor of the MIMI instrument aboard the Cassini spacecraft for
            the entire Cassini mission. INCA stands for Imaging Neutral
            Camera. See MANWEILERETAL2005
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Cassini Magnetospheric Imaging Instrument(MIMI) Imaging
            Neutral Camera (INCA) uncalibrated data set includes all data
            collected from the MIMI Data Processing Unit during the mission.
            The original data has been decommutated and decoded by software
            at the Applied Physics Laboratory (APL) and has been then further
            ordered and filtered by software at Fundamental Technologies,
            LLC. The data is provided in an uncalibrated form in conjunction
            with a PDS MIMI calibration volume COMIMI_0000 which provides
            specific algorithms for the derivation of calibrated data. This
            data set includes uncalibrated values of counts in the form of
            rates and of rate images for the INCA sensor for all times during
            the mission including the Earth flyby, the Jupiter flyby,
            interplanetary cruise, and the entire Saturn tour. Data are
            presented in a set of tables which are of variable length and use
            a comma to separate various fields. This data set is intended to
            be the most comprehensive and complete data set included in the
            Cassini MIMI INCA archive. A browse data set is included with Key
            Parameter data that is calibrated using the algorithms provided
            in the Calibration volume. In addition, a series of images are
            provided with the KP browse data that displays the KP data which
            can lead the user to the particular times of interest. This data
            set should be among the first used by a user of any of the MIMI
            INCA archive as it will lead one to information required to
            search for more detailed or highly specialized features in the
            original data.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
      The Cassini Magnetospheric Imaging Instrument(MIMI) Imaging Neutral
      Camera (INCA) uncalibrated data set includes all data collected from
      the MIMI Data Processing Unit during the entire Cassini mission
      [MANWEILERETAL2005].  The original data has been decommutated and
      decoded by software at the Applied Physics Laboratory (APL) and has
      been then further ordered and filtered by software at Fundamental
      Technologies, LLC. The data is provided in an uncalibrated form in
      conjunction with a PDS MIMI calibration volume COMIMI_0000 which
      provides specific algorithms for the derivation of calibrated data.
      This data set includes uncalibrated values of counts in the form of
      rates and of rate images for the INCA sensor for all times during
      the mission including the Earth flyby, the Jupiter flyby,
      interplanetary cruise, and the entire Saturn tour.  Data are
      presented in a set of tables which are of variable length and use a
      comma to separate various fields.  This data set is intended to be
      the most comprehensive and complete data set included in the Cassini
      MIMI INCA archive.  A browse data set is included with Key Parameter
      data that is calibrated using the algorithms provided in the
      Calibration volume. In addition, a series of images are provided
      with the KP browse data that displays the KP data which can lead the
      user to the particular times of interest.  This data set should be
      among the first used by a user of any of the MIMI INCA archive as it
      will lead one to information required to search for more detailed or
      highly specialized features in the original data.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    This data set comprises counts per readout of charged and neutral
    particle imaging measurements for the single telescope of the INCA
    sensor accumulators and images.  In addition this data set includes
    INCA PULSE HEIGHT ANALYSIS measurement data for a statistically select
    sample of the particle measurements. The standard product ID&apos;s are:
 
    INCA Accumulation Rate Data - individual microchannel plate detector
                                  count rate measurements
    INCA Image Data - count rates binned into a maximum of a 64x64
                      geometrical grid as an image, for various particle
                      velocities.
    INCA Pulse Height Analysis Data - Statistically sampled set of
                                      discrete particle measurements.
 
    The data is organized in time by the spin of the spacecraft.  When the
    spacecraft is in staring mode then the MIMI DPU automatically creates
    a virtual spin that divides the time collection periods into 16
    sectors, 16 subsectors, and 16 microsectors and maintains a simple
    organizational structure for characterizing the collection of the time
    into time segments.  When the spacecraft is spinning at a minimally
    defined spin rate (adopted by the MIMI DPU) then the MIMI data is
    automatically segregated into 16 sectors, 16 subsectors, and 16
    microsectors.  When the spacecraft is spinning and the LEMMS
    instrument is rotating the LEMMS rotation period is synchronized to
    the spacecraft spin period so that there are 16 sectors in a spin, 16
    subsectors in a sector and 16 microsectors in a subsector.  The CHEMS
    and INCA instrument collection times are then also keyed to these
    values.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    Data in this data set were processed by the use of a number of
    software programs which assemble segmented mini-packets in the raw
    telemetry packets into complete sets, de-compress the data that were
    compressed by one of a number of compression algorithms by the MIMI
    flight software onboard and organize the channel data into
    appropriate time segments. Images are preprocessing into appropriate
    arrays on board the spacecraft. This preprocessing software
    also includes algorithms to handle the various spacecraft rotation
    modes.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The MIMI INCA uncalibrated data set includes three ASCII CSV tables
    (each associated with a Standard Product ID) of INCA Rate data as a
    function of time collected from the MIMI INCA sensor and collated
    into data sets. Each table contains variable length records for which
    the fields are comma delimited.
 
    INCA Accumulation Rate Data
    ---------------------------
 
      Fields include:
        a purpose identifier where science data records are identified
        with purpose = sci
        starting and ending ephemeris times
        Spin, sector, subsector (and for INCA Fine Rate (FRT) data
        microsector)
        SCLOCK and spin period that are used to derive the starting
        ephemeris time
           Notes regarding the SCLOCK value:
           1.  Only the SCLOCK major segment value is provided - MIMI
               currently does not have access to the fine SCLOCK value
               hence SCLOCK resolution is limited to +- 1/2 SCLOCK count
           2.  The SCLOCK is only available from telemetry at the
               beginning of each spin. All other published SCLOCKS are
               derived from the spin starting SCLOCK, the spin numbers
               (for the current and next available spins), and the spin
               period.
           3.  SCLOCK values are assumed to drive the value of the
               ephemeris times and not vice-versa. All effort is made to
               validate the published ephemeris times but since updates to
               the Cassini SCLOCK kernel in SPICE can occur the values of
               ephemeris time are only as accurate as the currently
               published Cassini SCLOCK SPICE kernel.
        Spacecraft staring mode where staring = 0 when spinning and 1
        otherwise
 
      INCA Accumulation rate data organized as:
          Start fast, pulse, and Start-coincidence counts
          Stop fast, pulse, and Stop-coincidence counts
          Full, Coincidence, and time counts
          Events received and processed counts
 
    (MIMI INCA has 3 microchannel plates, the Start, the Stop, and the
    Coincidence plates.  Start fast is the Start timing signal count;
    Start pulse is the Start pulse-height count; Start-coincidence is the
    count of the coincidences within the alotted time window of signals
    from the Start fast and the Coincidence microchannel plates; Full is
    the count of events with a Start fast, Stop fast, and Coincidence
    signal; time is the count of events with both a Start fast and a Stop
    fast; Events received is the number of valid events sent to the DPU,
    and processed counts are the number the DPU sends inot image bins.
    These latter two may be different because of additional valid event
    criteria imposed by the DPU, and/or inability of the DPU to process
    all of the events it receives.)
 
    INCA Images
    -----------
 
      Fields include:
        a purpose identifier where science data records are identified
        with purpose = sci
        starting and ending ephemeris times
        Spin, sector, subsector
        SCLOCK and spin period that are used to derive the starting
        ephemeris time
           Notes regarding the SCLOCK value:
           1.  Only the SCLOCK major segment value is provided - MIMI
               currently does not have access to the fine SCLOCK value
               hence SCLOCK resolution is limited to +- 1/2 SCLOCK count
           2.  The SCLOCK is only available from telemetry at the
               beginning of each spin. All other published SCLOCKS are
               derived from the spin starting SCLOCK, the spin numbers
               (for the current and next available spins), and the spin
               period.
           3.  SCLOCK values are assumed to drive the value of the
               ephemeris times and not vice-versa. All effort is made to
               validate the published ephemeris times but since updates to
               the Cassini SCLOCK kernel in SPICE can occur the values of
               ephemeris time are only as accurate as the currently
               published Cassini SCLOCK SPICE kernel.
        Spacecraft staring mode where staring = 0 when spinning and 1
        otherwise
 
        INCA Images are organized as:
          Type ID: a 4 byte word characterized as:
                   Byte 0 - Type: 0 = High Spatial, 1 = High Time,
                            2 = High m-TOF
                   Byte 1 - Charge: 0 = Neutral, 1 = Ion
                   Byte 2 - Species: 0 = H, 1 = He, 2 = CNO, 3 = Heavy,
                            4 = Other, 5 = All
                   Byte 3 - TOF: 0 = Low, 1-6 = Medium, 7 = High
          Row ID: the row of the image which can vary from 8 to 64 based
          upon the image type
          Num Rows: the number of rows for this image
          Num Cols: the number of columns for this image which can vary
          from 8 to 64 based upon the image type
          Compression bits, Compression method, log compressed identifier
          Theta and Phi offsets from spacecraft coordinates
          Breakout of the type id into Type, Charge, Species, and TOF
          Column (0-63) counts representing the number of counts each
          pixel of this row x column received
 
    INCA Pulse Height Analysis Data
    -------------------------------
 
      Fields include:
        a purpose identifier where science data records are identified
        with purpose = sci
        starting and ending ephemeris times
        Spin, sector, subsector
        SCLOCK and spin period that are used to derive the starting
        ephemeris time
           Notes regarding the SCLOCK value:
           1.  Only the SCLOCK major segment value is provided - MIMI
               currently does not have access to the fine SCLOCK value
               hence SCLOCK resolution is limited to +- 1/2 SCLOCK count
           2.  The SCLOCK is only available from telemetry at the
               beginning of each spin. All other published SCLOCKS are
               derived from the spin starting SCLOCK, the spin numbers
               (for the current and next available spins), and the spin
               period.
           3.  SCLOCK values are assumed to drive the value of the
               ephemeris times and not vice-versa. All effort is made to
               validate the published ephemeris times but since updates to
               the Cassini SCLOCK kernel in SPICE can occur the values of
               ephemeris time are only as accurate as the currently
               published Cassini SCLOCK SPICE kernel.
        Spacecraft staring mode where staring = 0 when spinning and 1
        otherwise
        Index in sector number - auto generated number to guarantee
        uniqueness within a sector
 
        INCA Pulse Height Analysis data organized as:
          Coincidence indicator, start and stop indicator
          Pulse height data from the front and rear plates
          Time of flight of this particle and the azimuth and elevation
          for this event
          mass range of this particle
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    Included with the INCA data set volumes are ancillary data files
    representing the MIMI Key Parameter (KP) data.  The MIMI KP data is a
    calibrated subset of the important channels for each of the MIMI
    detectors.  The subset of channels have been identified to most
    reasonably show characteristic energetic particle events during the
    mission.  The KP data is calculated at an arbitrarily defined 60
    second cadence which is different than the approximate collection
    times for the instruments as identified below for standard operations:
    (It must be realized that the collection times vary based upon the
    telemetry rate but nothing more than a factor of 2, 4, or 8.)
 
        Instrument      Product Type     Approx Collection Time (s)
        ------------------------------------------------------------
        INCA            Accumulation     7.5
        INCA            IMAGES           180 (2 sectors)
        INCA            PHA              22
        CHEMS           Accumulation     4
        CHEMS           Science          5 (each subsector)
        CHEMS           PHA              80 (each sector)
        LEMMS           Accumulation     5 (each subsector)
        LEMMS           Fine Rate        0.6 (each microsector)
        LEMMS           PHA              5 (each subsector)
 
     Data points for each record of the KP data are first Quartile
     Filtered then averaged (except in the case where the median is zero)
     for each sector.  The sectored data is then interpolated into the 60
     second data cadence of the KP data file.  The KP data is then
     converted into a flux in units of 1/(cm^2*sr*sec*keV) or for the case
     of CHEMS 1/(cm^2*sr*sec*keV/e)
 
     Browse plots for each of the KP data files are produced.  There are 7
     different browse plots available.
 
     Inst    Wild Card File Name                  Plotted KP data
     --------------------------------------------------------------------
     LEMMS   LEMMS_KP_ELEC_(yyyydoy)_(ver#).JPG   KP LEMMS Electron flux
     LEMMS   LEMMS_KP_ION_(yyyydoy)_(ver#).JPG    KP LEMMS Ion flux
     CHEMS   CHEMS_KP_HEP_(yyyydoy)_(ver#).JPG    KP CHEMS Helium Plus
                                                  flux per charge
     CHEMS   CHEMS_KP_HEPP_(yyyydoy)_(ver#).JPG   KP CHEMS Helium Plus
                                                  Plus flux per charge
     CHEMS   CHEMS_KP_HP_(yyyydoy)_(ver#).JPG     KP CHEMS Hydrogen Plus
                                                  flux per charge
     CHEMS   CHEMS_KP_OP_(yyyydoy)_(ver#).JPG     KP CHEMS Oxygen Plus
                                                  per charge
     INCA    INCA_KP_(yyyydoy)_(ver#).JPG         Hydrogen TOF flux
 
     Usage Note
     ----------
       The KP browse data and associated browse plots are to be used as an
       initial characterization of the particle environment and are NOT to
       be used for publications.  The data is not at publication quality
       and is provided as is.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    The data in this data set are measurements of count rates based upon
    the orientation of the INCA instrument (INCA Center look direction).
    Particle flux effects are then determined by transforming from a
    spacecraft centered coordinate system, properly rotated to account for
    the appropriate INCA telescope direction, into whatever external
    coordinate (reference system) is most appropriate.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    There is no sample software provided as of the writing of this catalog
    file although the calibration volume does provide algorithms for
    conversion of count rates into flux.  In general the INCA Images are
    the main product and can be converted into a measurement of flux per
    species with these algorithms and the INCA PHA and Accumulation Rates
    data are used for determining the health and wellness of the INCA
    detectors.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    These data are supplied to the Planetary Data System via electronic
    means and are then broken into segments based upon the media currently
    prescribed by PDS.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    This data set contains all calibrated data for the INCA Detector as
    part of the Cassini MIMI instrument for the interval described above.
    Every effort has been made to ensure that all data returned to APL
    from the spacecraft is included and that the calibrated browse data
    products are accurate.
 
    As of this writing there are no known issues associated with the INCA
    detector that would limit the usability or reliability of the data.
 
  Review
  ======
    The MIMI INCA data will be reviewed internally by the Cassini MIMI
    team prior to release to the PDS. The data set will also be peer
    reviewed by the PDS.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    All data in the stated interval are included, to the best of our
    knowledge and attempts to determine completeness.  In general, the
    instrument was operated only briefly during early tour for the
    following intervals:
 
    1.  Antenna deployment   1997-10-25T00:00 - 1997-10-26T05:30
    2.  Venus 1 flyby        1998-04-26T12:54 - 1998-05-08T19:21
    3.  Instrument Checkout  1998-12-30T09:10 - 1999-01-19T05:40
    4.  Venus 2 flyby        1999-06-24T09:08 - 1999-06-24T21:20
    5.  Earth flyby          1999-08-13T17:39 - 1999-09-14T22:20
 
    Only data for interval 5 is provided to PDS due to technical issues in
    processing.
 
    Beginning in February of 2000 the instrument was operated more-or-less
    continuously with small daily runs of approximately 8 hours.
    Intermittent data collection occurred during 2002 and 2003 with
    multiple day gaps in the data
 
    Large Data Gaps:
    1.  Cruise               2000-066 - 2000-155
    2.  Cruise               2000-210 - 2000-246
    3.  Cruise               2000-311 - 2000-320
    4.  Cruise               2000-322 - 2000-333
    5.  Post Jupiter Cruise  2003-018 - 2003-104
    6.  Post SOI             2004-187 - 2004-193 - Spacecraft Safing
                                                   shut off
    7.  Saturn               2012-286 - 2012-288
    8.  Saturn               2012-293 - 2012-303 - propellant gauging test
 
    On those days for which the instrument did not collect data either due
    to the instrument being off or due to communication issues, the data
    set will not contain any files.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    As noted above there are no know issues associated with the data from
    the INCA detector as of the writing of this catalog.
 
    The KP browse data and associated browse plots are to be used as an
    initial characterization of the particle environment and are NOT to be
    used for publications.  The data is not at publication quality and is
    provided as is.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>IN_PEER_REVIEW</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

