<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.clem1-l-rss-5-bsr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CLEM1 INTERMEDIATE AND REDUCED BISTATIC RADAR DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_space_program_science_experiment::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.clem1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.clem1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-rss-5-bsr-v1.0__browserc_clem1-l-rss-5-bsr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-rss-5-bsr-v1.0__browserp_geo_clem1-l-rss-5-bsr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-rss-5-bsr-v1.0__dvo_geo_clem1-l-rss-5-bsr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Campbell, D.B., J.F. Chandler, S.J. Ostro, G.H. Pettengill, and I.I. Shapiro,
                   Galilean Satellites: 1976 Radar Results, Icarus, 34, 254-267, 1978.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CAMPBELLETAL1978</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Harmon, J.K., M.A. Slade, R.A. Velez, A. Crespo, M.J. Dryer, and J.M.
                   Johnson, Radar Mapping of Mercury&apos;s Polar Anomalies, Nature, 369, 213-215,
                   1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HARMONETAL1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Muhleman, D.O., B.J. Butler, A.W. Grossman, and M.A. Slade, Radar Images of
                   Mars, Science, 253, 1508-1513, 1991.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MUHLEMANETAL1991</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Nozette, S., P. Rustan, L.P. Pleasance, D.M. Horan, P. Regeon, E.M.
                   Shoemaker, P.D. Spudis, C.H. Acton, D.N. Baker, J.E. Blamont, B.J.
                   Buratti, M.P. Corson, M.E. Davies, T.C. Duxbury, E.M. Eliason, B.M.
                   Jakosky, J.F. Kordas, I.T. Lewis, C.L. Lichtenberg, P.G. Lucey, E.
                   Malaret, M.A. Massie, J.H. Resnick, C.J. Rollins, H.S. Park, A.S. McEwen,
                   R.E. Priest, C.M. Pieters, R.A. Reisse, M.S. Robinson, D.E. Smith, T.C.
                   Sorenson, R.W. Vorder Breugge, and M.T. Zuber, The Clementine Mission to
                   the Moon: Scientific Overview, Science, 266, 1835-1839, 1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NOZETTEETAL1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Nozette, S., C.L. Lichtenberg, P. Spudis, R. Bonner, W. Ort, E. Malaret,
                   M. Robinson, and E.M. Shoemaker, The Clementine Bistatic Radar Experiment,
                   Science, 274, 1495-1498, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NOZETTEETAL1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Shoemaker, E., M.S. Robinson, and E.M. Eliason, The South Pole Region of
                   the Moon as Seen by Clementine, Science, 266, 1851-1854, 1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SHOEMAKERETAL1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Simpson, R.A., and G.L. Tyler, Reanalysis of Clementine bistatic radar data
                   from the lunar South Pole, J. Geophys. Res., 104, 3845-3862, 1999.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SIMPSON-TYLER1999</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Simpson, R.A., Spacecraft Studies of Planetary Surfaces Using Bistatic Radar,
                   IEEE Transactions on Geoscience and Remote Sensing, 31, 465-482, March 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SIMPSON1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Stacy, N.J.S., High-Resolution Synthetic Aperture Radar Observations of the
                   Moon, Ph.D. dissertation, Cornell University, May 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.STACY1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CLEM1-L-RSS-5-BSR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CLEM1 INTERMEDIATE AND REDUCED BISTATIC RADAR DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2000-04-30</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1994-04-09T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1994-04-23T23:59:59Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>RICHARD A. SIMPSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Simpson, R. A., Clementine Intermediate and Reduced Bistatic
            Radar Data from the Moon, CLEM1-L-RSS-5-BSR-V1.0 (CL_2101 through
            CL_2108), NASA Planetary Data System, 2000.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Partially and fully processed data from selected Clementine
            bistatic radar observations in 1994. Included are echo spectra
            and derived surface scattering functions.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Partially and fully processed data from Clementine (DSPSE)
            bistatic radar observations of the Moon.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Clementine Bistatic Radar Intermediate and Reduced Data
      Archive (BSR-IRDA) is a collection of partially and fully
      reduced products from bistatic radar scattering experiments
      conducted using the Clementine spacecraft while it orbited
      the Moon.
 
      The spacecraft radio system was used as a signal source,
      and the spacecraft high-gain antenna beamed those signals
      toward surface targets on the Moon.  The transmit polarization
      along the boresight of the spacecraft antenna was right-
      circular; the nominal wavelength was 13 cm (S-band).  Echo
      signals were received coherently in both right- and left-
      circular polarizations (RCP and LCP, respectively) using
      70-m antennas at stations of the NASA Deep Space Network
      (DSN) on Earth.
 
      The scattering experiments were conducted in two
      configurations.  For &apos;spotlight&apos; experiments a single
      target was identified on the Moon; the spacecraft attitude
      was controlled during the experiment so that the HGA always
      pointed toward that target location.
 
      Spotlight experiments, conducted on polar targets were
      designed to detect and measure enhanced backscatter from
      possible ice deposits in areas permanently shaded from
      solar illumination.  Such enhancements have been seen in
      Earth-based radar studies of the Galilean satellites
      [CAMPBELLETAL1978], Mars [MUHLEMANETAL1991], and Mercury
      [HARMONETAL1994].  Although Earth-based radar studies of
      the Moon [STACY1993] have had considerably better
      sensitivity and surface resolution than this experiment,
      the Clementine geometry uniquely allowed measurements as a
      function of the bistatic angle -- the separation angle
      between transmitter and receiver when viewed from the target
      [SIMPSON1993].  The angular variation of any enhancement may
      be related to the distance the radar signal travels through
      the ice and, hence, to the thickness and/or clarity of the
      ice at 13 cm wavelength.
 
      For &apos;quasi-specular&apos; observations, the HGA was aimed toward
      the point on the lunar surface where mirror-like (specular)
      reflections were expected.  Signals transmitted by the
      spacecraft would carom from the lunar surface and be received
      at the DSN stations.  Because the (specular) image of
      Earth moved as Clementine orbited the Moon, the HGA
      illuminated a swath across the surface as the spacecraft
      advanced in its orbit.  A single quasi-specular track was
      obtained -- in the southern hemisphere during the last set
      of bistatic radar observations.
 
      The first analysis of spotlight data was published by
      [NOZETTEETAL1996].  The authors identified an enhancement
      in right-circularly polarized echo power near the time
      when the bistatic angle was zero in permanently shaded
      regions near the South Pole.  A second analysis
      [SIMPSON&amp;TYLER1999] focused on the data with the reported
      enhancement but was unable to reproduce the earlier results.
 
      This data set includes intermediate products from the second
      analysis.  These are large files of double precision complex
      time samples in both RCP and LCP.  The data cover the time
      period 1999-04-09T18:36:45 to 18:52:45 - the time at which the
      bistatic angle was 0 nearest the South Pole was 18:46:36.5.
      The intermediate files are processing output after correction
      for ripples in the receiver filters (equalization), after
      correction for gain changes in both channels, after digitally
      centering the carrier in the passband, and after changing the
      frequency reference so that the South Pole frequency bin
      would be in the center.  These 8 files are in the DATA
      directory, which is spread over all volumes in the data set.
 
      Also in the data set are more highly processed data, including
      a subset of power spectra from the final processing stage
      described above.  Measured echo powers in these spectra were
      sorted to construct empirical scattering functions at 72
      locations near the South Pole.  The spectra, the sorted power
      values, and a table containing two versions of the scattering
      function are in the SORT directory on the final volume.
 
      In order to carry out the sorting, it was necessary to know
      the mapping of Doppler frequencies onto the Moon&apos;s southern
      hemisphere.  Grids of frequency and other parameters were
      computed at 100 second time steps.  These are stored in PDS
      IMAGE format in the IMG directory, which appears on all
      volumes.
 
      Users of the Clementine data interested in fully understanding
      the signal processing might prefer to begin with the raw data,
      which have been archived separately on 13 CD-R volumes as PDS
      data set CLEM1-L-RSS-1-BSR-V1.0.  Users interested in other
      orbits necessarily must start with the raw data, since only
      part of a single orbit is included in this archive.
 
      Users of the partially processed data could pick up the
      processing at any stage and follow it through to completion.
      The calibration files which were used during the Stanford
      processing to equalize the filter response, adjust the gain,
      and modify the frequency of the data are stored in the CALIB
      directory.  Two versions of the list of target points for
      constructing the scattering function(s) are included in the
      GEOMETRY directory.
 
      Users interested only in the two scattering functions
      derived in the Stanford analysis will find them in the
      file RATIOFN.TAB in the SORT directory.  Note, however, that
      these are functions giving the RATIO of RCP to LCP power
      rather than the individual powers themselves, that they were
      derived in only two of several possible ways, and that the
      uncertainties (based on noise in the original measurements of
      echo power) are large.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      Files in the DATA directory contain double precision complex
      time samples of receiver output in RCP and LCP between
      1994-04-09T18:36:45 and 18:52:45, after corrections and
      adjustments for various effects.
 
      Files RCP.IMG and LCP.IMG in the SORT directory are calibrated
      arrays (in PDS IMAGE format) giving echo power in RCP and LCP,
      respectively.
 
      Files SRTPWRR.TAB and SRTPWRL.TAB contain power measurements
      from the arrays above, sorted according to proximity to one of
      72 surface target points and bistatic angle at that point.
      File SRTNPWR.TAB gives the number of measured values that
      have been associated with each target point at each bistatic
      angle.
 
      File RATIOFN.TAB gives the RCP to LCP ratio as a function of
      bistatic angle for the 13 target points poleward of 88 S
      latitude.  The ratio is computed in two different ways.
 
      Ephemerides were used to compute the observing geometry for a
      700x700 grid.  Each grid point was related to a surface point
      orthographically projected onto a plane tangent to the lunar
      surface at the South Pole.  Various observing parameters were
      computed at 100 second time steps and stored in PDS IMAGE
      format.  These include:
 
          BET  bistatic angle (degrees)
          DAR  area (square meters)
          DBR  offset from boresight at the (DSN) receiving
                  antenna (degrees)
          DPR  incremental received power (watts) from the
                  surface element
          FQZ  Doppler frequency relative to the South Pole (Hz)
          GAM  tilt of the surface element (degrees)
          GRX  receiving antenna gain at the surface element (dB)
          GTX  spacecraft transmitting antenna gain at the surface
                  element (dB)
          RRX  distance from the receiving antenna (meters)
          RTX  distance from the spacecraft transmitting
                  antenna (meters)
          SBR  offset from boresight at the spacecraft
                  antenna (degrees)
          SG0  assumed specific radar cross section for
                  calculating DPR
          THI  incidence angle at the surface element (degrees)
          THS  scattering angle at the surface element (degrees)
          VAL  validity mask (1 = grid point within lunar disk;
                  0 = outside)
          DFQ  time derivative of FQZ (Hz/sec)
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      Processing is described in more detail in the file PROCSSNG.TXT
      in the DOCUMENT directory.  The DOCUMENT directory also
      contains other files which may be useful in understanding the
      processing carried out at Stanford.
 
      The raw 8-bit samples from the analog-to-digital converters
      were stored on tape during data acquisition.  Those samples
      were separated into two computer files, corresponding to RCP
      and LCP (also referred to as Channel 1 and Channel 3,
      respectively, in some contexts).  This program (called PREPMO)
      also padded the samples to 16 bits.
 
      The two files of 16-bit samples were then used as input
      (separately) to program PREPFND which carried out digital
      filtering.  The output of this stage was a stream of double
      precision complex time samples at half the original rate for
      each polarization (channel).  The filtering operation in
      PREPFND was &apos;equalization&apos;, in which signal amplitude in
      the center 80 percent of the passband was normalized by the
      filter response with only noise as input.
 
      The output from PREPFND was fed to program GAIN which adjusted
      the sample amplitude in each channel for changes in attenuator
      settings during data acquisition, gain drift in the receiving
      system, and gross differences in levels between the two
      channels.
 
      The output from GAIN was passed to program POWERFIT, which
      located the peak signal in the passband and estimated both its
      amplitude and frequency.  The frequency estimates were used to
      create a file of coefficients for a piecewise continuous
      linear approximation to the carrier frequency.
 
      Using the file of coefficients, the program STEER adjusted
      the phase of the complex output samples from GAIN so that the
      carrier appeared to be at the center of the passband
      (12500 Hz).
 
      Using ephemerides for the spacecraft and planetary bodies,
      the expected Doppler offset between the carrier signal and a
      hypothetical echo from the lunar South Pole was computed.
      This offset was converted to a second set coefficients for a
      piecewise linear approximation to the difference frequency.
 
      The second set of coefficients was used in a second
      application of the STEER program to move the estimated
      frequency of the South Pole to the center of the passband
      (12500 Hz).  From this point, the South Pole frequency
      became the reference.
 
      Program FNDLOOK was used to compute 16384-point power spectra
      from the second-order STEER results.  There was no averaging,
      so spectra were spaced by 0.65536 seconds and frequency
      resolution was approximately 1.5259 Hz.  A subset of the
      frequency range (bins 7356-8379) was saved for further analysis.
      This array of 1464 1024-point spectra had the South Pole echo
      in bin 838.  A smoothed version of the bin 838 response (and
      21 of its neighbors) appeared in [SIMPSON&amp;TYLER1999] as
      Figure 10, from which the authors concluded there appeared to
      be nothing unusual about the response of the South Pole.
 
      The ephemerides were used to locate points in the
      vicinity of the South Pole where bistatic angle went to 0
      during the course of this observation.  72 such points,
      spaced by 1 second, were identified, forming a track which
      passed very close to the Pole (Figure 2 in [SIMPSON&amp;TYLER1999]).
 
      The values stored in the 700x700 grids could be used to map
      Doppler contours onto the lunar surface and to compute expected
      echo spectra (for an assumed scattering function).  As tools
      for interpreting the measured values, they could be used to
      determine which of the 72 target points (if any) contributed
      to a frequency bin at a certain offset from the South Pole
      frequency.  And they could be used to determine the bistatic
      angle at such a target point when the measurement was made.
 
      Such an inversion was accomplished, through a number of steps,
      leading to the sorted echo power measurements in files
      SRTPWRR.TAB and SRTPWRL.TAB in the SORT directory.  The
      arrays of sorted measurements for 72 targets and 101 bistatic
      angles (with up to 42 values in each bin) were then reduced
      to scattering functions for each of the 72 targets and for
      aggregations of those targets.  RATIOFN.TAB in the SORT
      directory contains two such possibilities.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      The data set contains two each of the following files (one for
      each polarization).  Each file is accompanied by a detached PDS
      label which completely describes both the format and content
      of the file.  Each data file has 384002048 bytes and is located
      in the DATA directory.
 
        A. PREPFND output file after filter equalization.  File
             names: PF1.TAB (RCP) and PF3.TAB (LCP)
        B. GAIN output file after gain corrections.  File names:
             GN1.TAB (RCP) and GN3.TAB (LCP)
        C. First-order STEER output file after centering carrier
             at 12500 Hz.  File names: S11.TAB (RCP) and S13.TAB (LCP)
        D. Second-order STEER output file after centering South
             Pole echo.  File names: S21.TAB (RCP) and S23.TAB (LCP)
 
      The data set contains two each of the following files (one for
      each polarization).  Each file is accompanied by a detached PDS
      label which completely describes both the format and content
      of the file.  These files are in the SORT directory.
 
        E. FNDLOOK output file converted to PDS IMAGE format. Each
             is a 1464x1024 array of echo power density with the
             South Pole at bin 838.  File names: RCP.IMG and LCP.IMG
 
        F. Output array from the echo sorting process.  Each file is
             a table but represents data in a three-dimensional
             array (up to 42 valid power measurements in a 72 target
             by 101 angle array).  File names: SRTPWRR.TAB (RCP)
             and SRTPWRL.TAB (LCP).
 
      Accompanying the sorted data are two other arrays.  Each is
      accompanied by a detached PDS label which completely describes
      the format and content of the data file.  These files are in
      the SORT directory.
 
        G. An array giving the number of valid measurements in
             the two data arrays SRTPWRR.TAB and SRTPWRL.TAB.
             File name: SRTNPWR.TAB
 
        H. A table containing two empirical scattering functions.
             File name: RATIOFN.TAB.
 
      The data set contains 59 sets of 15-16 grids.  The sets are
      spaced by 100 seconds in time, starting at 65696 seconds past
      0 h on 1994-04-09 and covering the time during which DSS 14
      tracked the Clementine spacecraft.  Each file occupies 980000
      bytes and is accompanied by a PDS detached label.  Grids are
      ordered chronologically on CD-R volumes (but with no more
      than 256 grids per volume) and are stored in the IMG directory.
      Because the DFQ grid is formed by differencing the EQZ grids at
      the immediately adjacent time steps, there is no DFQ grid for
      the first or last time step.  At each of the other steps there
      are 16 grids.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
 
      Files in the CALIB directory include the following.  Each is
      accompanied by a PDS detached label which describes the format
      and content of the data file.
 
        A. Filter equalization files with names of the form
           FLssbpnn.SPC  where
                     ss  is the DSN antenna number (14 or 43)
                     f   is the frequency band (S)
                     p   is the polarization (R or L)
                     nn  is the sequence number (01 or 02)
           Only data from DSS 14 (ss=14) are included in this archive;
           only filters with sequence number nn=01 were used in the
           Stanford processing.
 
        B. Files containing coefficients for gain correction with
           names of the form G099C14c.TAB where
                     c   denotes the channel number (1=RCP, 3=LCP)
 
        C. A file containing coefficients for centering the carrier
           frequency with name  STEERCF1.TAB
 
        D. A file with coefficients describing the difference in
           frequency between the carrier and South Pole bin with
           name  DF2SCM.TAB
 
        E. A table of noise level measurements for calibrating system
           gain and determining system noise temperature with
           name  TABLE2.TAB  (see Table 2 in [SIMPSON&amp;TYLER1999])
 
      Files in the GEOMETRY directory include the following.  Each is
      accompanied by a PDS detached label which describes the format
      and content of the data file.
 
        F. A table summarizing geometry and observing conditions with
           name  BSRGEOM.TAB
 
        G. Two tables listing coordinates for 72 target points around
           which sorting was carried out and scattering functions
           derived.  BETAZER0.TAB lists the coordinates in radians;
           BETAZER1.TAB lists the coordinates in degrees.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      The radio measurements can be understood without reference to
      a particular coordinate system.  For mapping measurements to
      the lunar surface, a selenocentric system with positive east
      longitude was used.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      This data set contains no software.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The archival data set is written on CD-WO media using a
      Yamaha CRW4260tx CD writer and GEAR software running on a
      Sun Ultra-5 workstation.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      The calibrations, gain corrections, and frequency adjustments
      were done with considerable care.  They have been described
      by [SIMPSON&amp;TYLER1999] and in several documents in the
      DOCUMENT directory.  The files in the DATA and CALIB directories
      and the RCP.IMG and LCP.IMG files in the SORT directory fall
      into this category.
 
      The geometrical calculations were also done carefully and are
      documented in [SIMPSON&amp;TYLER1999] and in the DOCUMENT directory
      of this volume.  Files in the GEOMETRY and IMG directories fall
      into this category.
 
      The sorted files (SRTPWRR.TAB, SRTPWRL.TAB, and SRTNPWR.TAB)
      and the scattering function (RATIOFN.TAB) have been done once.
      The procedures are documented in the DOCUMENT directory and in
      in an abstract for Lunar and Planetary Science XXXI (see
      LPSC_ABS.LBL in the DOCUMENT directory).  But resource
      limitations have prevented the careful scrutiny and double
      checking that were possible in the earlier analysis.  Users
      should view these files more skeptically.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was distributed to a peer review
      panel prior to its acceptance by the Planetary Data System
      (PDS).  The review panel was appointed by the Manager
      of the PDS Geosciences (GEO) Discipline Node (DN); the
      review was conducted in accordance with PDS GEO
      procedures.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      The times covered by this data set are listed in the table
      below.  The depth of coverage is given in the &apos;Analysis&apos;
      column at the right, with entries explained below the table.
 
                                              Revolution
        Start Time (ERT)    Stop Time (ERT)     Number   DSS Analysis
      ------------------- ------------------- ---------- --- --------
      1994-04-09T17:48:45 1994-04-09T18:04:44     233     14     2
      1994-04-09T18:04:45 1994-04-09T18:20:44     233     14     2
      1994-04-09T18:20:45 1994-04-09T18:36:44     233     14     2
      1994-04-09T18:36:45 1994-04-09T18:52:44     233     14     1
      1994-04-09T18:52:45 1994-04-09T19:08:44     233     14     2
      1994-04-09T19:08:45 1994-04-09T19:24:44     233     14     2
      1994-04-09T19:24:45 1994-04-09T19:40:44     233     14     2
      1994-04-09T19:40:45 1994-04-09T19:56:44     233     14     2
      1994-04-09T19:56:45 1994-04-09T20:05:09     233     14     2
      1994-04-09T23:00:55 1994-04-09T23:16:54     234     43     3
      1994-04-09T23:16:55 1994-04-09T23:32:54     234     43     3
      1994-04-09T23:32:55 1994-04-09T23:48:54     234     43     3
      1994-04-09T23:48:55 1994-04-10T00:04:54     234     43     3
      1994-04-10T00:04:55 1994-04-10T00:20:54     234     43     3
      1994-04-10T00:20:55 1994-04-10T00:36:54     234     43     3
      1994-04-10T00:36:55 1994-04-10T00:52:54     234     43     3
      1994-04-10T00:52:55 1994-04-10T01:08:54     234     43     3
      1994-04-10T01:08:55 1994-04-10T01:24:54     235     43     3
      1994-04-10T01:24:55 1994-04-10T01:33:55     235     43     3
      1994-04-10T04:02:22 1994-04-10T04:18:21     235     43     3
      1994-04-10T04:18:22 1994-04-10T04:34:21     235     43     3
      1994-04-10T04:34:22 1994-04-10T04:50:21     235     43     3
      1994-04-10T04:50:22 1994-04-10T05:06:21     235     43     3
      1994-04-10T05:06:22 1994-04-10T05:22:21     235     43     3
      1994-04-10T05:22:22 1994-04-10T05:38:21     235     43     3
      1994-04-10T05:38:22 1994-04-10T05:54:21     235     43     3
      1994-04-10T05:54:22 1994-04-10T06:10:21     235     43     3
      1994-04-10T06:10:22 1994-04-10T06:26:21     236     43     3
      1994-04-10T06:26:22 1994-04-10T06:42:21     236     43     3
      1994-04-10T06:42:22 1994-04-10T06:46:54     236     43     3
 
      Analysis levels represented in the archive:
        1  Exhaustive calibration and correction of data; data
           values sorted into empirical scattering functions
        2  Filter functions, gain corrections, and grids provided;
           no data in the archive, no frequency coefficients
           available.
        3  Notes on gain variations observed are in the archive;
           no calibration/correction files and no data included.
 
      Only very limited work with DSS 63 data from 1994-04-10 was
      carried out at Stanford.  And virtually nothing was attempted
      with data from days 1994-04-23 and 1994-04-24.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      See section Overview and Data Coverage and Quality above.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

