<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.jno-sw-3-fgm-cal-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>JUNO FGM CALIBRATED DATA SW V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.juno::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.jno::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:fgm.jno::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:plasma_stream.solar_wind::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Connerney, J.E.P., M. Benn, J.B. Bjarno, T. Denver, J. Espley, J.L. Jorgensen,
                   P.S. Jorgensen, P. Lawton, A. Malinnikova, J.M. Merayo, S. Murphy, J. Odom, R.
                   Oliversen, R. Schnurr, D. Sheppard, and E.J. Smith, The Juno Magnetic Field
                   Investigation, Space Science Reviews, TBD, TBD-TBD, doiTBD, 2016.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CONNERNEYETAL2016</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>JNO-SW-3-FGM-CAL-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>JUNO FGM CALIBRATED DATA SW V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-11-04</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2011-235T15:06:11Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2018-051T23:59:59Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JOHN CONNERNEY</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            J.E.P. Connerney (GSFC), Juno MAG CALIBRATED DATA SW/J V1.0, NASA
            Planetary Data System, 2016
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Juno Fluxgate Magnetomer (FGM) calibrated observations
            consist of time and position tagged magnetic field samples in
            physical units and coordinate systems collected by the FGM
            instrument during cruise and orbital operations at Jupiter.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== This data set consists of the Juno FGM
            calibrated observations. The FGM sensor block uses two miniature
            ring-core fluxgate sensors to measure the magnetic field in three
            components of the vector field There are multiple FGM data
            products to accomodate different coordinate systems.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
   Data Set Overview
   =================
     The data set consists of calibrated observations.  The MAG measures
     the vector magnetic field.
 
     There are three principal coordinate systems used to represent the data
     in this archive.  The SE  coordinate system is a Spacecraft- Solar
     equatorial system and it will be used for cruise data only.  The
     sun-state (ss) and planetocentric (pc) will be used for Earth Fly By
     (EFB) and Jupiter orbital data. Cartesian representations are used for
     all three coordinate systems. These coordinate systems are specified
     relative to a &apos;target body&apos; which may be any solar system object (but
     for this orbital operations will Jupiter). In what follows we will
     reference Jupiter as the target body, but, for example, if observations
     near a satellite (such as Io) are desired in Io-centric coordinates,
     the satellite Io may be specified as the target body.
 
     The SE coordinate system is defined using the sun-spacecraft vector
     as the primary reference vector; sun&apos;s rotation axis  as the secondary
     reference vector (z).    The x axis lies along the sun-spacecraft
     vector, the z axis is in the plane defined by the Sun&apos;s rotation axis
     and the spacecraft-sun vector. The y axis completes the system.
 
     The ss coordinate system is defined using the instantaneous Jupiter-Sun
     vector as the primary reference vector (x direction). The X-axis lies
     along this vector and is taken to be positive toward the Sun. The
     Jupiter orbital velocity vector is the second vector used to define
     the coordinate system; the y axis lies in the plane determined by the
     Jupiter-Sun vector and the velocity vector and is orthogonal to the x
     axis (very nearly the negative of the velocity vector). The vector
     cross product of x and y yields a vector z parallel to the northward
     (upward) normal of the orbit plane of Jupiter. This system is sometimes
     called a sun-state (ss) coordinate system since its principal vectors
     are the Sun vector and the Jupiter state vector.
     The planetocentric (pc) coordinate system is body-fixed and rotates
     with the body as it spins on its axis. The body rotation axis is the
     primary vector used to define this coordinate system. Z is taken to
     lie along the rotation axis and be positive in the direction of
     positive angular momentum. The X-axis is defined to lie in the
     equatorial plane of the body, perpendicular to Z, and in the direction
     of the prime meridian as defined by the IAU. The Y axis completes the
     right-handed set.
 
     Data in the vicinity of the moons of Jupiter (Io, Europa, Ganymede,
     Callisto) may be provided in separate files in moon centered coordinate
     systems, if it turns out that the mission plan affords an opportunity
     to acquire data in the immediate vicinity of any of these bodies The
     planetocentric and SS data follows the definitions above with the
     reference body being the moon or target specified via option in the
     command line All of the archived data files are simple and readable
     ASCII files with attached documentation in a header that precedes the
     columns of data. Files using a coordinate system centered on a target
     body other than Jupiter are identified via the target body listed on
     the command line which appears in the header along with an audit trail
     of supplementary engineering (kernel) files.
 
     The output from the processing program is in Standard Time Series (STS)
     format. The Object Description Language (odl) header is included in the
     STS file.  There will also be a detached PDS label file describing the
     contents of the STS file.
 
     Each data file contains the observations collected on a given UTC day.
 
   Instrument Overview
   ===================
     The MAG Instrument Suite consists of two boom mounted observing
     platforms (MAG Optical Bench, or MOB) each supporting a vector
     Fluxgate Magnetometer (FGM) and two non-magnetic Advanced Stellar
     Compass (ASC) Camera Head Units (CHUs). The ASC determines the
     attitude of the MOB in inertial space and relative to the JUNO
     spacecraft&apos;s Stellar Reference Units (SRU). The FGM was built at
     the Goddard Space Flight Center (GSFC); the ASC was built at the
     Technical University of Denmark (DTU).
 
     The Juno FGM is fully redundant, with two identical power converters
     providing power to one of two identical field programmable gate array
     (FPGA)-based digital systems. Only one set (power converter and digital
     system) is powered at a time; the other is a cold back-up. Either set
     receives commands from, and transmits data to, either side of the
     spacecraft command and data handling (C&amp;DH) unit through redundant
     interfaces. Two identical sets of analog electronics, both continuously
     powered by either power converter, drive the outboard (OB) and inboard
     (IB) sensors, via separate cables connecting the remote FGM sensors and
     electronics box, and both are controlled by and communicate with either
     of the digital systems. No single point failure can result in loss of
     data from both OB and IB FGM sensors.
 
     Each FGM sensor block uses two miniature ring-core fluxgate sensors
     to measure the magnetic field in three components of the vector field.
     Each of the two ring-core sensors measures the field in two orthogonal
     directions in the plane of the ring core. With two such sensors,
     oriented in planes intersecting at 90 degrees, all three components
     of the vector field are measured (one component measured, redundantly,
     by both). The sensor electronics uses negative feedback to null the
     magnetic field in each core, providing linearity over the full dynamic
     range of the instrument. The field in each ring core is both sensed and
     nulled by a pair of nested coils within which the ring core resides.
     Each coil nulls the field in one of the two perpendicular axes that
     define the plane of the ring core sensing element. All elements are
     maintained in precise alignment by a sensor block assembly constructed
     of a machinable glass ceramic with low thermal expansion (MACOR) and
     excellent mechanical stability. The FGM sensor block attaches to the
     optical bench via a three point kinematic mount to maintain accurate
     alignment over the range or environments experienced. The FGM sensor
     block is designed to operate at about 0 degrees C, whereas the optical
     bench and CHUs are designed to operate at about -58 degrees C to
     minimize noise and radiation effects. The FGM sensor block is thermally
     isolated from the optical bench via the three point kinematic mount and
     individual thermal blanketing. The FGM sensor itself is impervious to
     radiation effects.
 
     The two FGM sensors are separated by 2 meters on the MAG boom, one
     sensor (inboard, or &apos;IB&apos; sensor) is located 2 m radially outward from
     the end of the solar array and the other sensor (outboard, or &apos;OB&apos;
     sensor) is located at the outer end of the MAG boom. This arrangement
     (&apos;dual magnetometer&apos;) provides the capability to monitor spacecraft-
     generated magnetic fields in flight. The MAG boom is located on the
     outermost end of one (+x panel) of three solar panels and is designed
     to mimic the outermost solar array panel (of the other two solar array
     structures) in mass and mechanical deployment. The OB and IB sensor
     packages are identical. The CHUs measure the attitude of the sensor
     assembly continuously in flight to 20 arcsec and are used to establish,
     and continuously monitor, the attitude of the sensor assembly with
     respect to the spacecraft SRUs through cruise, orbit insertion at
     Jupiter, and initial science orbits. In addition to the extraordinarily
     accurate attitude reference provided by the MAG investigation&apos;s multiple
     ASC CHUs, the spacecraft provides (reconstructed) knowledge of the FGM
     sensor assembly attitude to an accuracy of 200 arcsec throughout the
     mission, using sensors on the body of the spacecraft and knowledge of
     the attitude transfer between the ASC camera heads and spacecraft SRUs.
     This provides a redundant attitude determination capability that could
     be used if ASC attitude solutions are interrupted for any reason (e.g.,
     blinding by a sunlit Jupiter obscuring the field of view for certain
     geometries, radiation effects). If this redundant capability is required
     at any time, the stability of the mechanical system (MAG boom, solar
     array hinges, structure, and articulation strut) linking the body of
     the spacecraft (SRU reference) to the FGM sensors (and CHUs) is an
     important element in satisfying the spacecraft requirement.
 
     The Juno MAG sensors are remotely mounted (at approximately 10 m and
     12 m) along a dedicated MAG boom that extends along the spacecraft +x
     axis, attached to the outer end of one of the spacecraft&apos;s three solar
     array structures. This design provides the maximum practical separation
     between MAG sensors and spacecraft to mitigate spacecraft-generated
     magnetic fields which would otherwise contaminate the measurements.
     A comprehensive magnetic control program is in place to ensure that
     the spacecraft magnetic field at the MAG sensors does not exceed 2 nT
     static or 0.5 nT variable. The separated, dual FGM sensors provide
     capability to monitor spacecraft-generated magnetic fields in flight.
 
     The JUNO sensor design covers the wide dynamic range with six
     instrument ranges (see below) increasing by factors of four the
     dynamic range in successive steps. The analog signals are digitized
     with a 16 bit analog to digital (A/D) converter, which yields a
     resolution of +/- 32768 steps for each dynamic range. In the table
     below, resolution, equal to 1/2 the quantization step size for each
     range, is listed in parentheses.
 
 
        FGM Characteristics        Dual Tri-Axial Ring Core Fluxgate
 
        Dynamic range (resolution)       16.3840 G (+/-25.0 nT)
                                          4.0960 G (+/-6.25 nT)
                                          1.0240 G (+/-1.56 nT)
                                          0.2560 G (+/-0.391 nT)
                (1 G = 100,000 nT)         6400 nT (+/-0.10 nT)
                                           1600 nT (+/-0.02 nT)
        Measurement accuracy:       0.01% absolute vector accuracy
        Intrinsic noise level       &lt;&lt;1 nT (range dependent)
        Zero level stability        &lt;1 nT (calibrated)
        Intrinsic sample rate       64 vector samples/s
 
     The data from each sensor can be in one of eight data formats. The
     instrument intrinsic sample rate of 64 samples/second is supported
     in data formats 0 and 1; averages over 2 to the n power samples
     (n = 1,2,3,4,5,6) are supported in telemetry modes 2 through 7.
 
     See the JNO_FGM_INST.CAT file for more information and
     [CONNERNEYETAL2016] for full details.
 
   Parameters
   ==========
     The FGM powers up in operational mode and returns telemetry
     immediately every clock tic (2 seconds). The FGM may be operated
     in autoranging mode, or manual range commands may be sent to fix
     the instrument in any of its dynamic ranges. Likewise any telemetry
     mode may be selected, depending on telemetry resource allocation. In
     addition, packets of engineering telemetry (in addition to science
     telemetry packets) are telemetered at a variable rate, from one per
     2 seconds to one per 512 seconds, per commanded state.
 
   Calibration Overview
   ====================
     The FGMs were calibrated in the Planetary Magnetospheres Laboratory
     and the GSFC Mario H. Acuna (MHA) Magnetic Test Facility (MTF), a
     remote facility located near the GSFC campus. These facilities are
     sufficient to calibrate the FGMs to 100 parts per million (ppm)
     absolute vector accuracy. An independent measurement of the magnetic
     field strength in the 0.25, 1, and 4 Gauss ranges was provided by
     Overhausen Proton Precession magnetometers placed near the FGM. Scale
     factor calibration is extended to 16 Gauss using a specialized high
     field coil and measurement techniques (see JUNO Magnetic Field
     Investigation instrument paper). A nuclear magnetic resonance
     magnetometer (Virginia Scientific Instruments) provided the absolute
     field strength measurements in the 16 Gauss range.
 
     Two independent methods are used to calibrate the magnetometers. The
     vector fluxgates are calibrated in the 22&apos; facility using a method
     (&apos;MAGSAT method&apos;) developed by Mario Acuna and others. This technique
     uses precise 90 degree rotations of the sensing element and a sequence
     of applied fields to simultaneously determine the magnetometer
     instrument model response parameters (the &apos;A matrix&apos;) as well as a
     similar set of parameters (the &apos;B matrix&apos;) that describe the facility
     coil orthogonality [instrument paper reference]. The second calibration
     method (called the &apos;thin shell&apos; and &apos;thick shell&apos;) uses a large set of
     rotations in a known field (magnitude) to obtain the same instrument
     parameters, subject to an arbitrary rotation [Merayo 2000 &amp; 2001]. In
     the &apos;thin shell&apos; method, the sensor is articulated through all
     orientations in a fixed, or known field magnitude. This can be done in
     a facility like the GSFC 22 foot coil system, wherein any fixed field
     up to about 1.2 Gauss may be utilized, or it may be done in the Earth&apos;s
     field using the ambient field in a gradient-free region and a system
     to compensate for variations in the ambient field (normally corrected
     via a secondary reference magnetometer coupled with a Proton Precession
     total field instrument). Application of this method in a coil facility
     (with closed loop control for ambient field variations) allows for the
     &apos;thin shell&apos; to be performed at many field magnitudes (&apos;thick shell&apos;).
 
     The MAGSAT calibration method provides the instrument calibration
     parameters referenced to the optical cube mounted on the sensor
     (or MOB) which defines the instrument coordinate system. These
     parameters include the instrument scale factors, 3 by 3 instrument
     response matrix (or &apos;A&apos; matrix), and zero offsets for each instrument
     dynamic range. The &apos;thin shell&apos; method provides the same parameters,
     but since the method conveys no attitude information, only the
     symmetric part of the instrument response matrix is determined via
     &apos;thin shell&apos;. Nevertheless, it provides a useful independent verification
     of the MAGSAT calibration.
 
     Inflight calibration activities are designed to monitor instrument
     parameters, primarily zero offsets, and to monitor the relative
     alignment of the magnetic field sensor platforms (the MOBs) and the
     spacecraft attitude reference (Stellar Reference Units, or SRUs).
     Spacecraft generated magnetic fields will be monitored using the dual
     magnetometer technique and a series of magnetic compatibility tests
     designed to identify the source of any magnetic signals (if any)
     associated with spacecraft payloads. Since Juno is a spinning
     spacecraft, spinning at 1 or 2 rpm nominally, any field fixed in the
     frame of reference of the spacecraft (e.g., fixed spacecraft-generated
     magnetic fields, sensor offsets, etc.) is easily identified. In practice
     we apply an algorithm developed independently by several groups (Acuna,
     Reviews of Scientific Instruments, 2002) to estimate bias offsets using
     differences in the measured field. This method handily corrects for
     biases in the spacecraft x and y axes, but since the spacecraft spins
     about the z axis, biases in z must be estimated using different methods.
     One technique utilizes the Alfvenic nature of fluctuations in the solar
     wind, that is, the magnitude preserving nature of variations in the
     field. Of course, not all fluctuations are Alfvenic (preserving
     magnitude) so some care is taken in application of this method to select
     appropriate events.
 
LEFT OFF
   Coordinate Systems
   ==================
     The MAG data are represented in the following coordinate systems:
 
     - spacecraft-solar equatorial
     - payload
     - planetocentric
     - sun-state
 
     all described above.
 
   Data
   ====
     Data products contain the observations collected on a given
     UTC day.  Each coordinate system in a separate file.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
   Confidence Level Overview
   =========================
   Not applicable.
 
   Review
   ======
     The FGM data set was reviewed internally by the MAG team prior to
     release to the PDS. PDS also performed an external review of the MAG
     data.
 
 
   Limitations
   ===========
   The Juno magnetic field investigation was designed to measure fields
   to 16 Gauss per axis over 6 dynamic ranges of the instrument, the most
   sensitive of which is +/- 1600 nT with a quantization step size of
   0.05 nT (16 bit A/D). Moreover, the spacecraft magnetic requirement was
   not to exceed 2 nT static and 0.5 nT variable spacecraft-generated
   magnetic field. In very weak field environments, such as encountered in
   outer cruise, accuracy may be expected to be limited by sensor offset
   and spacecraft magnetic field variations. The combined (static)
   spacecraft-generated magnetic field and sensor offset may be continuously
   monitored in flight in the spacecraft x and y axis, since the spacecraft
   spins (nominally at 1 or 2 RPM) about an axis closely aligned with the
   spacecraft payload z axis. However, offsets in the z axis need be
   estimated using the Alfvenic properties in the solar wind (ref. Juno
   Magnetic field investigation paper in Space Science Reviews). Statistical
   in nature, estimates of z axis zeros are not continuously available and
   are less accurate than the x and y zeros. Also, variations in spacecraft
   field over a time span comparable to a spin period will also lead to
   larger errors.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>PRE_PEER_REVIEW</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

