<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mro-m-crism-4-6-cdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MRO CRISM CALIBRATION DATA RECORD V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:crism.mro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-crism-4-6-cdr-v1.0__browserp_mro-m-crism-4-6-cdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-crism-4-6-cdr-v1.0__browser_geo_mars_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-crism-4-6-cdr-v1.0__dvo_mro-m-crism-4-6-cdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Bugby, D., J. Garzon, M. Beres, C. Stouffer, D. Mehoke, and M. Wirzburger,
                   Cryogenic diode heat pipe system for cryocooler redundancy, in Proc. SPIE,
                   edited by J.B. Heaney and L.G. Burriesci, Vol. 5904, pp. 321-329, 2005.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BUGBYETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lees, J., E. Schaefer, and M. Fasold, Design of the CRISM cryogenic system and
                   focal plane assembly isolation system, in Proc. SPIE, edited by A.E. Hatheway,
                   Vol. 5877, pp. 265-275, 2005.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEESETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Murchie, S., R. Arvidson, P. Bedini1, K. Beisser, J.-P. Bibring, J. Bishop, J.
                   Boldt, T. Choo, R.T. Clancy, E.H. Darlington, D. Des Marais, R. Espiritu, M.
                   Fasold, D. Fort, R. Green, E. Guinness, J. Hayes, C. Hash, K. Heffernan, J.
                   Hemmler, G. Heyler, D. Humm, J. Hutchison, N. Izenberg, R. Lee, J. Lees, D.
                   Lohr, E. Malaret, T. Martin, R. Morris, J. Mustard, E. Rhodes, M. Robinson, T.
                   Roush, E. Schaefer, G. Seagrave, P. Silverglate, S. Slavney, M. Smith, K.
                   Strohbehn, H. Taylor, P. Thompson, and B. Tossman, CRISM (Compact
                   Reconnaissance Imaging Spectrometer for Mars) on MRO (Mars Reconnaissance
                   Orbiter), Proc. SPIE, edited by C.A. Nardell, P.G. Lucey, J. Yee, and J.B.
                   Garvin, Vol. 5660, pp. 66-77, 2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MURCHIEETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Murchie, S., R.E. Arvidson, P. Bedini, K. Beisser, J.-P. Bibring, J. Bishop, J.
                   Boldt, P. Cavender, T. Choo, R.T. Clancy, E.H. Darlington, D. Des Marais, R.
                   Espiritu, M. Fasold, D. Fort, R. Green, E. Guinness, J. Hayes, C. Hash, K.
                   Heffernan, J. Hemmler, G. Heyler, D. Humm, J. Hutcheson, N. Izenberg, R. Lee,
                   J. Lees, D. Lohr, E. Malaret, T. Martin, J.A. McGovern, R.V. Morris, J.
                   Mustard, S. Pelkey, E. Rhodes, M. Robinson, T. Roush, E. Schaefer, G. Seagrave,
                   F. Seelos, P. Silverglate, S. Slavney, M. Smith, K. Strohbehn, H. Taylor, P.
                   Thompson, B. Tossman , and M. Wolff, CRISM (Compact Reconnaissance Imaging
                   Spectrometer for Mars) on MRO (Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter), J. Geophys. Res.,
                   submitted, 2006.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MURCHIEETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Pelkey, S.M., J.F. Mustard, J.-P. Bibring, R.E. Milliken, Y. Langevin, B.
                   Gondet, A. Gendrin, F. Poulet, S. Erard, S. Murchie, R.E. Arvidson, and the
                   OMEGA and CRISM Science Teams, Global Spectral and Compositional Diversity of
                   Mars: A Test of CRISM Global Mapping with Mars Express OMEGA Data, Lunar and
                   Planetary Science XXXVI, Vol. 1458, 2005.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PELKEYETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Silverglate, P.R., and D.E. Fort, System design of the CRISM (compact
                   reconnaissance imaging spectrometer for Mars) hyperspectral imager, in Proc.
                   SPIE, edited by S.S. Shen and P.E. Lewis, Vol. 5159, pp. 283-290, 2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SILVERGLATE-FORT2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Troll, J., P. Thompson, and D. Humm, Boresight and gimbal axis alignment for
                   the CRISM instrument, in Proc. SPIE, edited by A.E. Hatheway, Vol. 5877, pp.
                   93-101, 2005.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TROLLETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MRO-M-CRISM-4/6-CDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MRO CRISM CALIBRATION DATA RECORD V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2006-01-01</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>SCOTT MURCHIE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Murchie, S., Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter Compact Reconnaissance
            Imaging Spectrometer for Mars Calibration Data Record,
            MRO-M-CRISM-4/6-CDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2006.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Calibration data records for IR and VNIR image cubes for CRISM
            (Compact Reconnaissance Imaging Spectrometer for Mars).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset contains CRISM VNIR and IR Calibration Data Records
            (CDRs), which are used to convert data from raw DNs to units of
            radiance or I/F for the CRISM instrument on MRO.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      This volume contains portions of the CRISM Calibration Data Record
      (CDR) Archive, a collection of calibration files from the Compact
      Reconnaissance Imaging Spectrometer for Mars on the Mars
      Reconnaissance Orbiter spacecraft.
 
      CDRs are created in two ways:
 
      (a) One type of calibration file, for example the wavelength
      calibration, is either invariant or expected to change only
      infrequently. These files are stored in directories named using a
      2-letter acronym for the contents of the file.
 
      (b) The other type of calibration file is a snapshot of some
      attribute of the instrument that is time-variable, for example the
      thermal background measured by the IR detector. These files are
      stored in directories named YYYY_DOY, each one of which contains
      subdirectories containing distinct types of calibration files.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      EDRs containing bias measurements or measurements of background,
      focal plane lamps, or the internal integrating sphere are
      processed into level-4 CDRs. A level-4 CDR contains derived values
      needed to convert a scene-viewing EDR into units of radiance.
      These are in image format, with multiple versions corresponding to
      different pixel binning states.  Other level 4 CDRs are derived
      from ground measurements. A level-6 CDR contains tabulated
      information, of two types: (a) a file list of level 4 CDRs
      generated inflight, or (b) tabulated information, for example, for
      correcting for detector non-linearity, converting housekeeping to
      physical units, or converting EDRs from 12 to the original
      at-sensor 14 bits prior to calibration.
 
 
    Data
    ====
 
      There are two types of calibration files. CODMAC level 4 CDRs
      (CDR4s) are in image format, and CODMAC level 6 CDRs (CDR6s) are
      text files in ASCII format. Both types have a file name that
      encodes the time at which they are applicable, and the
      configuration of the data used to derive them (detector, frame
      rate, binning, wavelength filter, exposure time parameter, etc.).
 
      YYYY_DOY/BI directory:
      ----------------------
      This directory contains CDR4s representing measurements of the
      response of each detector to zero signal, i.e., the detector bias.
      These are measured as dark frames for the VNIR detector. For the
      IR detector, these are the zero exposure-time intercept of a fit
      of dark measurements taken at several exposure times. For each
      detector there are separate files for each frame rate, wavelength
      filter, and binning state, time-stamped for their mean time of
      acquisition.
 
      YYYY_DOY/BK directory:
      ----------------------
      This directory contains CDR4s representing thermal background
      measured by the IR detector. These are measured as dark frames.
      There are separate files for each frame rate, exposure time, and
      binning state, time-stamped for their mean time of acquisition.
 
      YYYY_DOY/BP directory:
      ----------------------
      This directory contains CDR4s representing bad pixels. There are
      separate files for each frame rate, exposure time, wavelength
      filter, and binning state, time-stamped for their mean time of
      acquisition.
 
      YYYY_DOY/SP directory:
      ----------------------
      This directory contains CDR4s representing sphere output in DN/ms
      at the sphere&apos;s closed-loop setpoint. There are separate files for
      each sphere bulb. For the VNIR all data are taken at 1 Hz, but
      there are versions for each binning state. For the IR there are
      separate versions for each frame rate, wavelength filter, and
      binning state. Both the VNIR and IR files are time-stamped for
      their mean time of acquisition.
 
      YYYY_DOY/ST directory:
      ----------------------
      This directory contains a table of CRISM low-rate telemetry in raw
      counts, from the beginning of a UTC calendar day to its end. This
      is used in preference to the telemetry attached to each image for
      correction of thermal effects, because of uncorrectable artifacts
      in the raw values of critical temperature measurements in the
      image headers.
 
      YYYY_DOY/UB directory:
      ----------------------
      This directory contains CDR4s representing pixel-by-pixel
      uncertainties in VNIR bias or IR background images. There are
      separate files for each frame rate, exposure time, wavelength
      filter, and binning state, time-stamped for their mean time of
      acquisition. This product is not a part of the nominal data
      processing pipeline and instead is used to monitor detector
      health.
 
      YYYY_DOY/ATF directory:
      ----------------------
      This directory contains a table of EDRs containing scene data and
      the corresponding EDRs containing time-dependent calibration
      measurements needed to calibrate the scene EDRs. It is used to
      process calibration EDRs to CDRs, and scene EDRs to TRDRs. If
      there is a discrepancy between the actual EDRs used for
      calibration and the predicted EDRs (in the BTF directory), the
      TRDRs resulting from scene EDRs are quality-flagged.
 
      YYYY_DOY/BTF directory:
      ----------------------
      This directory contains a predicted table of EDRs containing scene
      data and the corresponding EDRs containing time-dependent
      calibration measurements.  It is constructed from uplinked
      commands.
 
      AS directory:
      -------------
      This CDR6 gives the maximum expected 14-bit scene or sphere 14-bit
      DN level (units from the detector, after correction for the pixel
      processing table and subtraction of bias) for core observation
      types to be made by CRISM.  There are 5 core observation types
      defined by combinations of frame rate, exposure time, and scene: 1
      Hz observation, exposure parameter 27, observing the internal
      integrating sphere; 3.75 Hz, exposure parameter 301, observing a
      nominally non-ice region of Mars; 3.75 Hz, exposure parameter 147,
      observing a potentially ice-containing region; 15 Hz, exposure
      parameter 425, observing any region; and 30 Hz, exposure parameter
      425, observing any region. The values given here are used with
      bias images in the YYYY_DOY/BI directories to generate masks of
      probably bad pixels (in the YYYY_DOY/BI directories).
 
      AT directory:
      -------------
      This CDR4 gives the atmospheric transmission as measured from a
      nadir-pointed hyperspectral scan across Olympus Mons, taken 27
      November 2006. It is not used during calibration to radiance or
      I/F; instead it is intended for subsequence correction for
      atmospheric attenuation. There is a different version for each
      detector, wavelength filter, and binning state.
 
      BS directory:
      -------------
      This CDR6 gives the amplitude of the bias step correction for each
      detector as a function of frame rate and quadrant. The bias step
      is a step function in detector bias that occurs at a row number
      (band) correlated with exposure time parameter.
 
      BW directory:
      -------------
      This CDR6 gives the parameters to calculate the spectral profile
      for each wavelength bin averaged over IR columns 270-369 or VNIR
      columns 260-359.  This represents the &apos;sweet spot&apos; of each
      detector at which spectral smile and keystone are minimum, and is
      the preferred detector location for extraction of overlapping data
      for analysis of emission phase functions.
 
      CM directory:
      -------------
      This CDR4 gives the along-slit angle measured from slit center for
      each detector. It is similar to the SPICE Instrument Kernel. There
      is a different version for each detector, wavelength filter, and
      binning state.
 
      CT directory:
      ------------
      This CDR6 gives the atmospheric transmission for each wavelength
      bin averaged over IR columns 270-369 or VNIR columns 260-359. This
      represents the &apos;sweet spot&apos; of each detector at which spectral
      smile and keystone are minimum, and is the preferred detector
      location for extraction of overlapping data for analysis of
      emission phase functions. It is a sample of the &apos;native&apos; atmospheric
      transmission images in the AT directory.
 
      DB directory:
      -------------
      This CDR6 gives the correction to detector bias for changes in
      detector temperature since the last bias measurement, as a
      function of frame rate and quadrant.
 
      DM directory:
      -------------
      This CDR4 is a mask of detector dark columns, scattered light
      columns, and scene columns for each detector. There is a different
      version for each wavelength filter and binning state.
 
      EB directory:
      -------------
      This CDR6 gives the correction to detector bias for differences in
      focal plane electronics temperature since the last bias
      measurement, as a function of frame rate and quadrant.
 
      GH directory:
      -------------
      This CDR6 gives the scaling factors needed for each frame rate to
      calculate and subtract the inter-quadrant electronics ghost in
      each detector, using bias-corrected signal.
 
      HD directory:
      -------------
      This CDR6 gives the coefficients for correcting raw housekeeping
      for perturbations due to changes in lamp or cooler state and frame
      rate. There is one file for both detectors.
 
      HK directory:
      -------------
      This CDR6 gives the coefficients to convert housekeeping
      parameters from raw counts to physical units.
 
      HV directory:
      -------------
      This CDR6 gives the coefficients to correct housekeeping voltages
      for perturbations due to changes in current.
 
      LC directory:
      -------------
      This CDR6 gives the coefficients to correct bias-subtracted DN
      from each detector at each frame rate for non-linearity in
      detector response.
 
      LI directory:
      -------------
      This CDR6 gives 8 to 12 bit lookup tables (inverse of 12 to 8).
      These are used to restore 8-bit to 12-bit DN values.
 
      LK directory:
      -------------
      This CDR6 gives 12 to 8 bit lookup tables loaded in the CRISM
      instrument.
 
      LL directory:
      -------------
      This CDR4 contains matrices to remove estimated leaked higher
      order light in the IR detector, by scaling shorter-wavelength
      signal and subtracting it from longer-wavelength signal.
 
      NU directory:
      -------------
      This CDR4 is a time-tagged, row-normalized measurement of detector
      nonuniformity. There is one version for each binning state,
      wavelength filter, and frame rate. It is only created for the VNIR
      detector.
 
      PP directory:
      -------------
      This CDR6 contains the gain and offset to use for each row to
      convert 12-bit DNs to the native 14-bit DNs produced by each
      detector, and the 12 to 8 bit lookup tables used for each detector
      row (band) when lossy compression is employed.
 
      PS directory:
      -------------
      This CDR4 is used for nearest neighbor spectral resampling. It
      gives the number of detector rows (bands) by which to shift each
      column (sample) of an image to minimize the effects of spectral
      smile. The effect of the pixel shift is to restore the wavelength
      at a detector element to within one-half detector element of the
      wavelength in the central columns of the detector.  (The
      wavelength and spectral bandwidth in the central columns are given
      in the SW and BW directories respectively.) There is a different
      version for each detector, wavelength filter, and binning.
 
      RA directory:
      -------------
      This CDR4 contains the ratio of focal plane lamp illumination to
      an external flat field, normalized on a row-by-row basis. This is
      a contingency and not part of the normal calibration pipeline, so
      its creation is TBD. There is a different version for each
      detector, wavelength filter, and binning.
 
      RF directory:
      -------------
      This CDR4 contains a nearest-neighbor resampled solar flux image.
      It is related to the &apos;native&apos; solar flux images in the SF
      directory by the pixel- shifting given in the PS directory. There
      is a different version for each detector, wavelength filter, and
      binning.
 
      RT directory:
      -------------
      This CDR4 gives the atmospheric transmission as measured from a
      nadir-pointed hyperspectral scan across Olympus Mons, taken 27
      November 2006. It has been nearest-neighbor resampled in the
      spectral direction. It is not used during calibration to radiance or
      I/F; instead it is intended for subsequence correction for
      atmospheric attenuation. It is related to the &apos;native&apos; atmospheric
      transmission images in the AT directory by the pixel- shifting
      given in the PS directory. There is a different version for each
      detector, wavelength filter, and binning. There is a different
      version for each detector, wavelength filter, and binning state.
 
      RW directory:
      -------------
      This CDR4 contains a nearest-neighbor resampled wavelength image.
      It is related to the &apos;native&apos; wavelength images in the WA
      directory by the pixel- shifting given in the PS directory. There
      is a different version for each detector, wavelength filter, and
      binning.
 
      SB directory:
      -------------
      This CDR4 contains the spectral bandpass width for each detector
      element.  There is a different version for each detector,
      wavelength filter, and binning.
 
      SF directory:
      -------------
      This CDR4 contains solar flux at 1 AU for each detector element.
      There is a different version for each detector, wavelength filter,
      and binning. It is used together with the solar distance given in
      an EDR or TRDR label to calculate I/F.
 
      SH directory:
      -------------
      This 2-layer CDR4 is used to correct flight measurements of the
      onboard integrating sphere for effects of shutter position
      irreproducibility. Layer 0 is a corrected sphere image from ground
      radiometric calibration in units of 14-bit DN.  Layer 1 is a
      shutter mirror non-repeatability correction image, a
      multiplicative correction that gets scaled by the ratio of layer 0
      to the measured flight sphere image. There is a different version
      for each detector, wavelength filter, and binning.
 
      SL directory:
      -------------
      This CDR6 gives the 14-bit DN at which each detector is saturated,
      as a function of quadrant and frame rate.
 
      SS directory:
      -------------
      This 3-layer CDR4 gives sphere spectral radiance at the
      closed-loop set point for each sphere bulb, as pixel by pixel
      coefficients to a 2nd order polynomial function of sphere
      temperature. There is a different version for each detector,
      wavelength filter, and binning.
 
      SW directory:
      -------------
      This CDR6 gives the center wavelength for each wavelength bin
      averaged over IR columns 270-369 or VNIR columns 260-359. This
      represents the &apos;sweet spot&apos; of each detector at which spectral
      smile and keystone are minimum, and is the preferred detector
      location for extraction of overlapping data for analysis of
      emission phase functions.
 
      TD directory:
      -------------
      This CDR4 gives temperature dependence of detector responsivity,
      as pixel by pixel coefficients to a 2nd order polynomial function
      of detector temperature. There is a different version for each
      detector, wavelength filter, and binning.
 
      UR directory:
      -------------
      This CDR6 gives uncertainty in absolute and relative sphere
      signal, for each bulb. This product is not a part of the nominal
      data processing pipeline and its creation is TBD; it is intended
      for end users of calibrated data as an indication of limits to
      data interpretation.
 
      VL directory:
      -------------
      This CDR6 gives the 14-bit DN at which each detector -
      ON AVERAGE - is saturated. It is used together with the predicted
      limiting case expected 14-bit scene DN levels (in the AS
      directory) to produce bad pixel maps. It also gives additional
      criteria for defining a bad pixel, thresholds for noise and
      relative pixel response.
 
      WA directory:
      -------------
      This CDR4 gives the center wavelength for each detector element.
      There is a different version for each detector, wavelength filter,
      and binning.
 
      WV directory:
      -------------
      This CDR6 gives the table of detector rows (bands) loaded into
      wavelength filters 0-3. There is one version for each detector.
 
 
    File Naming Convention
    ======================
 
      The file naming convention for level-6 CDRs is as follows.
 
      (ProductType)(Level)_(Partition)_(Time)_(Product)_
                                    (SensorID)_version.(Ext)
 
      where:
      Product Type = CDR
      Level = 6
      Partition = n, partition of the spacecraft clock.
      Time = nnnnnnnnnn, spacecraft start time of applicability of data
             product; units are spacecraft clock counts, in units of
             whole seconds.
      Product = nn, acronym describing data product listed above
      Sensor ID = S or L (or J=joint)
      Version = 0, 1,..., 9, a,..., z
      Ext = TAB
 
      The file naming convention for level-4 CDRs is as follows.
 
      (ProductType)(Level)(Partition)(Time)_
                  (Product)(FrameRate)(Binning)
                  (ExposureParameter)(WavelengthFilter)
                  (Side)(SensorID)_ version.(Ext)
 
      where:
      Product Type = CDR
      Level = 4
      FrameRate = n, rate in Hz at which data are taken (0=1 Hz,
                  1=3.75 Hz, 3=156 Hz, 4=30 Hz, 5 = N/A)
      Binning = n, number of spatial pixels binned
                  (0=unbinned, 1= 2x binned, 2= 5x binned,
                   3= 10x binned, 4=N/A)
      Exposure parameter = nnn, an integer 1-480 indicating commanded
                           exposure time in units of (inverse frame
                           rate)/480; 000 if inapplicable
      Wavelength filter = n, and integer 0-3 indicating which onboard
                          menu of rows of the detector are represented
      Side = #, 1 or 2 for focal plane or sphere bulbs; or 0 if N/A
      Ext  = IMG
 
      The tables in the YYYY_DOY/ATF and YYYY_DOY/BTF directories have a
      different file naming convention, as follows.
 
      (Product)_(Sensor)_(YYYY)_(DOY)_version
 
      where:
      Product Type = BTF for before-the-fact predicted or ATF for
                     after-the-fact actual
      Sensor = VN or IR
      YYYY = year
      DOY = day of year
      Version = nn
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
 
      The CRISM archive will be made available online via Web and FTP
      servers.  This will be the primary means of distribution.
      Therefore the archive will be organized as a set of virtual
      volumes, with each data set stored online as a single volume. As
      new data products are released they will be added to the volume&apos;s
      data directory, and the volume&apos;s index table will be updated
      accordingly. The size of the volume will not be limited by the
      capacity of the physical media on which it is stored; hence the
      term virtual volume.  When it is necessary to transfer all or part
      of a data set to other media such as DVD for distribution or for
      offline storage, the virtual volume&apos;s contents will be written to
      the other media according to PDS policy, possibly dividing the
      contents among several physical volumes.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      This is a TBD data set.  Known problems are TBD.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set will be examined by a peer review panel
      prior to its acceptance by the Planetary Data System (PDS).  The
      peer review will be conducted in accordance with PDS procedures.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
 
      The major data quality issue in the production of CDRs is the
      occurrence of cosmic rays.  All of the CDRs are generated from
      mulitiple frames in an EDR and, in some cases, from a combination
      of mulitple EDRs.
 
      The CDRs are generated by sampling multiple frames of an EDR.  In
      order to eliminate cosmic rays, the top and bottom two DN values
      at each pixel location are discarded.  This will also have the
      effect of removing extraneous noise.  Filtering of the cosmic rays
      by this method eliminates much of the systematic error in
      producing CDRs.
 
      If no valid data are available to create a particular CDR, the
      next closest CDR created in time must be used in the processing of
      EDRs to RDRs.  If this situation occurs, byte 12 of the Data
      Quality Index in the resulting RDR is populated according to
      section 2.5.2 of the Data Product Software Interface
      Specification.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      None.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

