<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.gio-c-epa-3-rdr-grigg-skjell-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GIOTTO EXTENDED MISSION ELECTRON PARTICLE ANALYSER V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.giotto_extended_mission::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.gio::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:epa.gio::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.26p-grigg-skjellerup_1_1922_k1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.gio-c-epa-3-rdr-grigg-skjell-v1.0__browserp_gio-c-epa-3-rdr-grigg-skjell-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Anderson, J.D., M.S.W. Keesey, E.L. Lau, E.M. Standish, Jr., and X.X. Newhall,
                   Tests of General Relativity Using Astrometric and Radio Metric Observations of
                   the Planets, Astronautica, 5, 43-61, 1978.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ANDERSONETAL1978</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   McKenna-Lawlor S., A. Thompson, D. O&apos;Sullivan, E. Kirsch, D. Melrose, and K.P.
                   Wenzel, The Giotto Energetic Particle Experiment, ESA SP-1077, 53-65, 1986.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MCKENNA-LAWLETAL1986</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   McKenna-Lawlor S., E. Kirsch, A. Thompson, D. O&apos;Sullivan, and K. Wenzel, The
                   lightweight energetic particle detector EPONA and its performance on Giotto, J.
                   Phys. E: Sci. Instrum. 20, 732-740, 1987.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MCKENNA-LAWLETAL1987</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GIO-C-EPA-3-RDR-GRIGG-SKJELL-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GIOTTO EXTENDED MISSION ELECTRON PARTICLE ANALYSER V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1995-02-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1992-07-09T16:20:00.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1992-07-11T03:14:00.000Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>PDS SMALL BODIES NODE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>Unknown</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This dataset contains count rates from the Energetic Particle
            Analyser (EPA) experiment aboard the Giotto spacecraft during its
            flyby of comet P/Grigg-Skjellerup during July of 1992. (SAVED
            DATA)
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset contains count rates from the Energetic Particle
            Analyser (EPA) experiment aboard the Giotto spacecraft during its
            flyby of comet P/Grigg-Skjellerup during July of 1992. These data
            were not formally reviewed by the PDS.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
      Data Set Overview
      =================
      This dataset contains count rates from the Energetic Particle Analyser
      (EPA) experiment aboard the Giotto spacecraft during its flyby of
      comet P/Grigg-Skjellerup during July of 1992.
 
      The solid-state detectors of the EPA detected energetic ionizing
      particles (electrons, protons, heavier ions), but no magnetic fields
      or time of flight indicators were included.  Thus it is difficult to
      determine what type of particles are being detected, and the
      calculation of the energy spectrum becomes rather complicated.  It
      is because of this that only count rates are included in the archive.
 
      Parameters
      ==========
      The dataset is broken into 4 separate tables, one for each energy
      channel of the instrument.  The tables list count rates per second,
      averaged over a one-minute interval, for each of eight geometric
      sectors.
 
      The thresholds in each energy channel depend on species.  Values for
      the two species most likely to be encountered near the comet during
      the flyby are given in this table:
 
            Channel      Protons        H(2)O+
            -------      -------        ------
               1         29-  46 keV   78- 115 keV
               2         40-  77       97- 145
               3         78- 215      144- 270
               4        217-3500      280-3500
 
      The two EPA detectors which produced the data for this archive are
      oriented at a 45 degree angle to the spin axis of the space craft,
      which was antiparallel to the motion of the spacecraft relative to
      the comet.  During the flyby data were taken so that odd-numbered
      sectors came from one detector and even-numbered sectors from
      another.
 
      The following table lists the look directions of each sector,
      relative to the spacecraft Z-axis.  Theta is the angle to the
      spin axis; phi is the rotation in the spin direction from the plane
      containing the sun and Z axis.  NOTE that the spin axis is equal
      to the spacecraft -Z (minus Z) axis.  All angles are in degrees.
 
           Sector     Detector    Theta      Phi
           ------     --------    -----      ---
              1          1         135     -102.5
              2          2          45      -57.5
              3          1         135      -12.5
              4          2          45       32.5
              5          1         135       77.5
              6          2          45      122.5
              7          1         135      167.5
              8          2          45     -147.5
 
      Modification History
      ====================
      This dataset was originally received as five separate ASCII files
      covering successive time segments of the flyby, with averages for
      all four channels appearing under headers with the start and stop
      time for the averages.  These files were concatenated in chronological
      order, split into four files by energy channel, and reformatted.  The
      stop time for each average which was included in the original file has
      been dropped from these files because it was invariably one minute
      later than the listed start time.
 
      Additionally, the invalid data flag in the original file (-100.000)
      has been changed to -999.999 to conform with the standard null data
      values in other PDS data sets.
 
      Data
      ====
      Each energy channel table covers the entire observation period in
      one minute intervals.  Sector averages are listed in the order given
      above.  Where data measurements were not recorded, a null value
      flags the drop-out.  There is also an extended data gap in all
      sectors of all channels during the period 1992 July 9 UT 1810 to
      July 10 UT 0420.  Records with all null count rates make this
      period.
 
      There are no time gaps in the records in the data files.
 
      NOTE: the count rates in energy channel 1 are contaminated by
            sunlight in sectors 2, 5, 6, 7 and 8.
 
      Ancillary Data
      ==============
      None known
 
      Coordinate System
      =================
      During the encounter, the spacecraft spin axis (the -Z axis) was
      oriented almost in the ecliptic plane, nearly perpendicular to the
      spacecraft-sun line.
 
      In the Comet Solar Ecliptic (CSE) coordinate system, the comet is
      at the origin, the X axis points toward the sun and Y is parallel
      to the ecliptic so that the positive Z axis is toward the North.
      Then theta is the angle from the Z axis and phi is azimuth in the
      XY plane, with phi=0 for the Sun.
 
      During closest approach, the orientation of the spin axis is:
 
          theta = 90.0 degrees     phi = 90.4 degrees    (CSE)
 
      In CSE, the look directions listed above become (alpha is the angle
      to the comet-sun line):
 
           Sector    Theta       Phi      Alpha
           ------    -----       ---      -----
              1       46.3     -101.8      98.5
              2       53.4       62.2      68.0
              3       81.2      -45.3      46.0
              4      112.3       50.3      53.7
              5      133.7      -77.4      80.9
              6      126.6      118.6     112.6
              7       98.8     -133.9     133.3
              8       67.7      130.5     127.0
 
      Software
      ========
      None
 
      Media/Format
      ============
      This dataset is to be included in the Giotto Extended Mission CDROM
      produced by the Small Bodies Node (SBN) of the Planetary Data System.
      Copies of the CD will be available to researchers from the SBN, or
      to others through the National Space Science Data Center.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
      Confidence Level Overview
      =========================
      Confidence level unspecified.
 
      Review
      ======
      Pending
 
      Data Coverage and Quality
      =========================
      Unknown
 
      Limitations
      ===========
      Because of the lack of species discrimination, the reduction and
      interpretation of these data are complex.  However, there was a
      third detector mounted at the same angle to the spin axis as the
      second detector, which was covered with an aluminized plastic foil.
      This covering absorbed low-energy protons (up to about 350 keV)
      but allowed electron with energy greater than 20 keV to penetrate.
 
      Count rates in the covered detector never exceeded those in the
      neighboring detector by more than 10 percent (the typical difference
      was less than 1 percent), indicating that EPA observed primarily
      positive ions during the flyby.
 
      The count rates from the covered detector are not included in this
      dataset.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SAFED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>85-056A-00E</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>PSSB-00025</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

