<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ch1-orb-l-m3-4-l1b-radiance-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CH1-ORB MOON M3 4 L1B RADIANCE NEAR-IR SPECTRAL IMAGES V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.chandrayaan-1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.ch1-orb::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:m3.ch1-orb::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ch1-orb-l-m3-4-l1b-radiance-v1.0__dvo_img_ch1-orb-l-m3-4-l1b-radiance-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Pieters, C.M., J.N. Goswami, R.N. Clark, M. Annadurai, J. Boardman, B. Buratti,
                   J.-P. Combe, M.D. Dyar, R. Green, J.W. Head, C. Hibbitts, M. Hicks, P.
                   Isaacson, R. Klima, G, Kramer, S. Kumar, E. Livo, S. Lundeen, E. Malaret, T.
                   McCord, J. Mustard, J. Nettles, N. Petro, C. Runyon, M. Staid, J. Sunshine,
                   L.A. Taylor, S. Tompkins, and P. Varanasi, Character and Spatial Distribution
                   of OH/H2O on the Surface of the Moon Seen by M3 on Chandrayaan-1, Science, Vol.
                   326, No. 5952, 568-572, 2009, doi:10.1126/science.1178658.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PIETERSETAL2009C</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CH1-ORB-L-M3-4-L1B-RADIANCE-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CH1-ORB MOON M3 4 L1B RADIANCE NEAR-IR SPECTRAL IMAGES V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2010-07-19</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2008-11-18T22:26Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>SARAH R. LUNDEEN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Lundeen, S., Chandrayaan-1 Moon Mineralogy Mapper Calibration
            Data Record, CH1-ORB-L-M3-4-L1B-RADIANCE-V1.0, NASA Planetary
            Data System, 2008.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Calibrated spectral image cubes collected by M3 (Moon Mineralogy
            Mapper).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset contains pixel located, radiometrically-calibrated
            data collected by M3 instrument on Chandrayaan-1.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      This volume contains portions of the M3 Level 1B (L1B) Archive,
      a collection of radiometrically-calibrated and pixel-located
      data products acquired in either global or target mode from
      the Moon Mineralogy Mapper for Moon on the Chandrayaan-1
      spacecraft.
 
      A M3 Level 1B Data Product consists of pixel-located, resampled,
      calibrated data in units of spectral radiance that make up one
      observation tagged by a unique file name. The data in one Level 1B
      Product represent a consistent instrument configuration (frame rate,
      pixel binning). There is a single multiple-band image
      (BIN; suffix *_RDN.IMG) stored in one file with a detached PDS label
      (ASCII; suffix *_L1B.LBL), and a detatched header file (ASCII;
      suffix *_RDN.HDR), plus several files containing data related to
      pixel location (BIN; suffix *_LOC.IMG), observation geometry (BIN;
      suffix *_OBS.IMG), and UTC timing for each image line (ASCII;
      suffix *_TIM.TAB).
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      Level 1B processing involves the following operations:
 
      - converts the decompressed, uncalibrated image cube data into
        resampled, scaled, calibrated spectral radiance image cubes
      - calculates the surface location of all pixel centers
      - calculates the observation geometry and illumination on a
        pixel-by-pixel basis
      - calculates the UTC time for the middle of the integration period
        for each frame of the image data
 
    Data
    ====
 
      Under the Data directory there is a separate subdirectory based on
      the start and end times of a 13-week imaging period. Each imaging
      period subdirectory is further divided into subdirectories for each
      month of an Optical Period (OP). Each OP month subdirectory is further
      divided based on the type of data product (e.g. Level 0 or Level 1B).
 
      YYYYMMDD_YYYYMMDD/YYYYMM/L1B directory:
      ----------------------------------
      This directory contains the following files:
 
      *RDN.IMG
      --------
      The L1B multiple-band spectral radiance image cube has
      dimensions of sample, line, and wavelength. The size and format of the
      M3 spectral radiance image cube depend on the observation mode
      (global/target).
 
      M3 calibration data such as wavelength centers,
      full-width half-max values and radiometric gain factors can be found in
      the CALIB directory of the archive volume.
 
      In target mode, the spectral radiance image cube has the following
      characteristics:
 
      32-bit floating point
      Little endian
      255 spectral channels
      600 spatial samples
      N image lines
      Band interleaved by line
 
      In global mode, the spectral radiance image cube has the following
      characteristics:
 
      32-bit floating point
      Little endian
      85 spectral channels
      304 spatial samples
      N image lines
      Band interleaved by line
 
      During the transmission and encoding/decoding of the
      data, some data elements may be lost.  Data lost to poor compression or
      complete packet loss are noted in the *.LOG files located in the EXTRAS
      directory.
 
      All M3 L1B spectral radiance image cubes are standardized to remove
      the different effects of the four possible orbit limb and flight yaw
      mode combinations: descending/forward; descending/reverse;
      ascending/forward and ascending/reverse.  In ascending limb data the
      lines/times are reversed, so all L1B spectral radiance image cubes
      have the northernmost image line first. In descending/reverse and
      ascending/forward modes the samples are reversed, so the first sample
      is on the west side of the image and do not appear left-right mirrored.
      In descending/forward no changes in lines or samples are performed;
      this is the only case that matches the Level 0 data.  Refer to the
      ORBIT_LIMB_DIRECTION and SPACECRAFT_YAW_DIRECTION keywords in the PDS
      label (*_L1B_LBL) to reconcile a specific Level 1B spectral radiance
      image cube with the associated Level 0 data.
 
      *RDN.IMG.HDR
      ------------
      Each L1B spectral radiance image cube file will be accompanied by a
      detached ASCII header file. A detached header provides compatibility
      with ENVI software.
 
      *L1B.LBL
      --------
      A spectral radiance image cube label (*_L1B.LBL) is detached and points
      to the following L1B data products:
 
      - the single multi-band image (*_RDN.IMG) and its respective detached
        header file (*_RDN.HDR),
      - the pixel location data (*_LOC.IMG) and its respective detached header
        file (*_LOC.HDR),
      - the observation geometry data (*_obs.img) and its respective detached
        header file (*_OBS.HDR),
      - the UTC timing data (*_TIM.TAB)
 
      *LOC.IMG
      --------
      The pixel location data for each image are stored in a three-band, band-
      interleaved-by-line, binary file of double precision 8-byte values, in
      little-endian byte order.  The three bands of the file, in order, are as
      follows:
 
      1) longitude (reported in decimal degrees)
      2) planetocentric latitude (reported in decimal degrees)
      3) radius (reported in meters from the Moon center)
 
      There are no embedded headers or other data in the file. Each
      location file will be accompanied by a detached header file.
      A detached header provides compatibility with ENVI software. The
      location file is, in essence, a three-band set of &apos;detached
      backplanes&apos; that match the sample and line spatial extent of the
      spectral radiance image cube data.  No map correction or resampling is
      applied to the radiance image cube; the file only reports the
      surface locations of the unadjusted pixel centers.
 
      *LOC.HDR
      --------
      Each location data file will be accompanied by a detached ASCII
      header file. A detached header provides compatibility with ENVI
      software.
 
      *OBS.IMG
      --------
      The observation geometry data for each image are provided in a ten-band,
      band-interleaved-by-line, binary file of single precision 4-byte values,
      in little-endian byte order. The ten bands of the file, in order, are as
      follows:
 
      1) to-sun azimuth angle (decimal degrees, clockwise from local north)
      2) to-sun zenith angle (decimal degrees, zero at zenith)
      3) to-sensor azimuth angle (decimal degrees, clockwise from local north)
      4) to-sensor zenith angle (decimal degrees, zero at zenith)
      5) observation phase angle (decimal degrees, in plane of to-sun and
         to-sensor rays)
      6) to-sun path length (decimal au with scene mean subtracted and noted
         in PDS label)
      7) to-sensor path length (decimal meters)
      8) surface slope from DEM (decimal degrees, zero at horizontal)
      9) surface aspect from DEM (decimal degrees, clockwise from local north)
      10) local cosine i (unitless, cosine of angle between to-sun and local
          DEM facet normal vectors)
 
      Similar to the location data, these files are, in essence,
      ten-band set of &apos;detached backplanes&apos; that match the sample and line
      spatial extent of the spectral radiance image cube data.  No map
      correction or resampling is applied to the radiance image cube; the
      file only reports the observation parameters of the unadjusted pixel
      centers.
 
     *OBS.HDR
     --------
     Each observation geometry data file will be accompanied by a detached
     header file. A detached header provides compatibility with ENVI software.
 
     *TIM.TAB
     --------
 
     The timing file (*TIM.TAB) is an ASCII file with four columns of data.
     The first column lists the line number of the multiple-band spectral
     radiance image cube (*RDN.IMG). The second column lists the corresponding
     UTC time for the middle of the integration period for each spectral
     radiance image cube line or major frame of the data and is expressed as:
     YYYY-MM-DDTHH:MM:SS.SSSSSS.
     The third column lists Year reference of Decimal Day of Year (DDOY) as
     extracted from the earliest time of each spectral radiance image cube
     line expressed as: YYYY.
     The fourth column lists DDOY which represents the number of days elapsed
     since 00:00 UTC of January 1 of the year associated with the time stamp
     of the first image line. The DDOY format is as follows: DDD.dddddddddddd
     where DDD represents the integer number of days and dddddddddddd
     represent the fractional part of the day of year value.
 
     Note that the M3 Level 0 data products have two representations of image
     frame times captured in the 1280-byte image frame header:
     1) a copy of the raw bytes of CH-1 and M3 binary clock tick data
     and 2) a nominal conversion of those raw clock ticks to a UTC time in an
     ASCII format.  This nominal conversion is built on the assumed
     operation of the clocks in a wholly stable manner with fixed tick
     rates and no drift or unexpected rate issues.  To achieve optimized
     timing for subsequent processing, the Level 1B code develops
     individual clock conversion models for each image of sufficient
     length.  This per-image modeling accommodates any clock drift or rate
     changes and provides the best possible frame times for the Level 1B
     data products.  As such, the ASCII UTC times in the Level 0 data products
     may differ from those in the Level 1B data products.  The Level 0 data
     product times should be considered deprecated and are only approximate
     UTC frame times.  The per-image optimized conversion used in the Level 1B
     processing yields the most accurate image frame times and these are the
     times reported in the timing file.
 
    File Naming Convention
    ======================
 
      The file naming convention for L1B data products is as follows.
 
      M3GYYYYMMDDTHHMMSS_VNN_PT.EXT
 
      Or
 
      M3TYYYYMMDDTHHMMSS_VNN_PT.EXT
 
      M3:       The instrument.
      G or T:   The imaging mode; G for global mode and T for target mode.
      YYYY:     The year of the time stamp from the first image frame of the
                image cube.
      MM:       The month of the time stamp from the first image frame of the
                image cube.
      DD:       The day of the time stamp from the first frame of the image
                cube.
      T:        A single character string that precedes the UTC time of the
                time stamp from the first frame of the image cube.
      HH:       The hour in UTC of the time stamp from the first frame of the
                image cube.
      MM:       The minute within the hour in UTC of the time stamp from the
                first frame of the  image cube.
      SS:       The second within the minute in UTC of the time stamp from the
                first frame of the image cube.
      VNN:      The version number of the product.
      PT:       The type of data product:
                L0 = Level 0
                L1B = Level 1B
                RDN = Spectral Radiance data
                LOC = Pixel Location data
                OBS = Observation geometry data
                TIM = Observation timing data
      EXT:      The file name extension:
                IMG = Image object
                HDR = Detached header file
                LBL = Detached label file
                TAB = ASCII text file
 
      All fields must occupy the allotted number of characters. Thus, if fewer
      digits are required to express a number than are allotted, the
      convention fills the unneeded spaces with leading zeroes.
 
    Coordinate Systems
    ==================
 
      The coordinate system used is the new &apos;Standardized Lunar Coordinate
      System for the Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter&apos; (LRO Working Group, 2007).
      This new lunar coordinate system is being adopted as an international
      standard and will greatly facilitate the direct integration of data
      from multiple missions and among international partners.  The
      coordinate system is based on planetocentric coordinates in the Mean
      Earth/Polar Axis (ME) reference frame.  The z-axis is the mean axis
      of rotation with the positive direction pointing north.  The x-axis is
      the intersection of the Equator and Prime Meridian, as defined by the
      mean Earth direction.  The y-axis completes the frame in a right-handed
      sense and points in the direction of +90 degrees longitude.  Latitude
      ranges from +90 to -90 form the North Pole to the South Pole.
      Longitude will be reported as 0 to 360 degrees increasing to the East.
 
    Software
    ========
 
    The M3 team uses the commercial software packages ENVI and IDL to display
    and analyze M3 data products. ENVI and IDL are distributed by ITT Visual
    Information Solutions and are available at http://www.ittvis.com/.
    Nevertheless, the data are in no way in any proprietary format. Instead
    they are arranged as simply and as openly as possible. The provision of
    both ENVI and PDS labels will guarantee the data will be readily
    accessible to the widest possible audience.
 
    Media/Format
    ============
 
      The M3 archive will be made available online via Web and FTP
      servers.  This will be the primary means of distribution.
      Therefore the archive will be organized as a set of virtual
      volumes, with each data set stored online as a single volume. As
      new data products are released they will be added to the volume&apos;s
      data directory, and the volume&apos;s index table will be updated
      accordingly. The size of the volume will not be limited by the
      capacity of the physical media on which it is stored; hence the
      term virtual volume.  When it is necessary to transfer all or part
      of a data set to other media such as DVD for distribution or for
      offline storage, the virtual volume&apos;s contents will be written to
      the other media according to PDS policy, possibly dividing the
      contents among several physical volumes.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
 
      Confidence level information will be provided after more thorough
      analysis of the data.
 
    Review
    ======
 
      Prior to creation of the final version of this archival data set,
      its keys elements including samples of data products, PDS labels
      and catalog files, and the Software Interface Specifications, were
      examined during a peer review held by PDS Imaging Node in January 2010.
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
 
      The M3 image acquisition time will be divided into peak periods or
      Optical Periods (OP) when lighting is optimal for observation. The
      Optical Periods occur twice a year and are understood to have two
      central months of optimal illumination (solar beta angles -30 deg to
      +30 deg) with two optional two-week wing periods (solar beta angles
      +/-30 deg to +/-45 deg) on either side of the optimal 2 months (thus,
      one Optical Period equals 13 weeks). Each 13 week optical period is
      followed by a 13-week hiatus. The original instrument operations plan
      included the acquisition of the entire surface of the Moon in
      low-resolution Global Mode during the first Optical Period (OP1)
      while OP2, OP3, OP4 were reserved for high resolution Target Mode
      data acquisition.
 
      However, the mission was cut short, just before the halfway point, in
      August, 2009 when the spacecraft ceased operations. Despite the
      abbreviated mission and numerous technical and scientific challenges
      during the flight, M3 was able to cover more than 95% of the Moon in
      Global Mode. Only minimal high-resolution Target Mode images were
      acquired, as these were to be the focus of the second half of the
      mission. The technical challenges encountered during the mission
      have complicated the data processing and calibration. These challenges
      include thermal issues, loss of the spacecraft star trackers and a
      raising of the orbit from 100 km to 200 km on May 19, 2009. Details
      of these challenges are currently being documented and will be
      referenced and/or included in the delivery of the M3 PDS Archive
      Volume. Nonetheless, the data products released in the M3 PDS Archive
      Volume will contain optimal calibration and characterization.
      (NOTE: If these docs are included in the archive, put them in
      DOCUMENT directory, not EXTRAS.)
 
      M3 operations were sustained for two Optical Periods. (For more
      detailed information regarding the spacecraft operation schedule,
      please see the MISSION.CAT.) Please see the M3 Data Product SIS for
      more detail/information.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      None.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

