<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.clem1-l-lwir-3-rdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CLEMENTINE LWIR BRIGHTNESS TEMPERATURE V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_space_program_science_experiment::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.clem1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:lwir.clem1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.sky::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-lwir-3-rdr-v1.0__browserc_clem1-l-lwir-3-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-lwir-3-rdr-v1.0__browserp_clem1-l-lwir-3-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-lwir-3-rdr-v1.0__dvo_geo_clem1-l-lwir-3-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lawson, S.L., B.M. Jakosky, H.-S. Park, and M.T. Mellon, Brightness
                   temperatures of the lunar surface: Calibration and global analysis of the
                   Clementine long-wave infrared camera data, J. Geophys. Res., 105,
                   4273-4290, 2000.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LAWSONETAL2000</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CLEM1-L-LWIR-3-RDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CLEMENTINE LWIR BRIGHTNESS TEMPERATURE V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2002-07-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1994-02-27T07:04:02.174Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STEFANIE L. LAWSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Lawson, S.L., B.M. Jakosky, and E.A. Guinness. &quot;Clementine
            Long-Wave Infrared (LWIR) Brightness Temperature Data Set&quot;,
            NASA Planetary Data System, CLEM1-L-LWIR-3-RDR-V1.0, 2000.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Clementine Long-Wave Infrared (LWIR) Brightness Temperature
            data set contains calibrated brightness temperature images that
            provide information on physical properties of the lunar surface.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This volume contains the archive of Lunar brightness temperature
            data derived from images acquired by the Clementine Long
            Wavelength Infrared (LWIR) camera. The LWIR camera acquired
            approximately 220,000 thermal-infrared images of the lunar
            surface that were used to generate the brightness temperature
            images within this archive. The procedure for generating
            brightness temperature values can be summarized as follows: 1)
            original LWIR digital numbers were converted to radiance; 2) the
            dark current signal was subtracted from the radiance values; 3) a
            flat field correction was applied; 4) bad pixels were identified
            and smoothed over; and 5) calibrated radiance values were
            converted to brightness temperatures using the Planck function.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
Data Set Overview
=================
The scientific payload on the Clementine spacecraft included a
Long-Wave Infrared (LWIR) camera with a single passband of width
1.5 microns centered at a wavelength of 8.75 microns.  The LWIR
spatial resolution ranged from 200 m per pixel near the poles to
55 m per pixel at the equator.  Contiguous pole to pole imaging
strips were obtained with approximately 10% overlap between
adjacent frames.  However, significant longitude gaps exist
between successive orbital passes.  During the systematic mapping
phase of the Clementine mission, approximately 220,000 thermal-
infrared images of the lunar surface were obtained.  This data
set contains LWIR images where the observed radiance has been
converted to brightness temperature, which provides information
on various physical properties of the lunar surface.
 
Processing
==========
Preflight calibration for the LWIR instrument was performed at
Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory in an effort to measure
camera characteristics such as radiometric sensitivity, gain and
offset scale factors, temporal/spatial noise, and the dependence
of dark-noise on focal plane array (FPA) temperatures.  Several
steps were involved in the generation of brightness temperature
values which included converting measured data number (DN) values
to radiance values; identifying and eliminating bad pixels;
correcting for pixel response variation across the detector
array; determining the zero-flux background of the instrument;
comparing LWIR measured radiance of the Apollo 17 landing site to
in situ temperature measurements in order to derive absolute
calibration adjustments; and finally, converting measured
radiance values to brightness temperatures via the Planck
function [LAWSONETAL2000].
 
The first step in the routine to determine brightness temperature
from LWIR images involved converting measured DN values (ranging
from 0 to 255) to equivalent radiance values through a preflight
calibration equation.  This equation corrected for the changing
gain and offset states used throughout an imaging orbit in order
to account for the increase in surface thermal emission near the
equator.
 
The primary uncertainty in the calibration was the subtraction of
a zero-flux radiance.  The dark-frame signal was extremely large
and varied with time in orbit and probably with lens and FPA
temperatures.  Through the 1.5 hours of a lunar imaging orbit,
the heat input to the spacecraft by the cryocooler increased the
surrounding temperature and decreased the cooling effectiveness,
resulting in rising FPA temperatures with time.  This zero-level
background increase was much less pronounced in the first month
of systematic mapping than in the second.  At the mid-lunar-
mapping-mission orbital-correction burn, fuel was expended and
the overall thermal mass of the spacecraft was reduced.  This
resulted in an increased operational temperature and caused the
LWIR background counts generated from the pixel dark current and
the thermal emission from within the optical path to increase.
Thus, after the mid-lunar-mapping orbital burn, the number of
LWIR images taken during an orbital pass was reduced to avoid
saturation of the detector.  In order to subtract a zero-flux
radiance from the LWIR images, a series of space-looking frames
(away from the Sun, Moon, and Earth) was used that were acquired
at the beginning and end of many lunar mapping orbits.  The
increasing background level through an orbit was accounted for by
fitting a line, on a pixel-by-pixel basis, to the pre-mapping
space and post-mapping space radiance values as a function of
time.
 
The next step in the process was to create bad-pixel maps and
flat fields.  After subtracting a zero-level image from each
lunar image, hundreds of lunar images from a single orbit were
averaged together on a pixel-by-pixel basis.  Thus a lunar mean
image and an associated lunar standard deviation image were
generated.  Lunar images at latitudes higher than 70 deg were
neglected in the calculation of the mean image because they were
often either saturated (due to excessively high gain states) or
they had values less than zero after the zero-level image
subtraction.  Bad pixels were identified on the mean and standard
deviation images as pixels that did not vary (low or zero
standard deviation), varied randomly (high standard deviation),
or were pegged at high values such that their dynamic range was
limited (high mean).  Pixels with low means also appeared bad on
lunar images.  An average of approximately 11% of the 16,384
detector array pixels was characterized as consistently bad.
There were approximately 10 orbits where at least one map had
more than 20% bad pixels.
 
In order to correct for pixel response variation across the
detector array, a flat field frame was created by multiplying the
lunar mean image and the bad-pixel map, smoothing over the bad
pixels, and normalizing the resultant image to unity.  For an IR
camera, the FPA signal comes not only from the signal generated
from the lunar surface, but also from dark current generated
internally within each pixel detector and from thermal emission
generated from the camera optical path.  For the LWIR the
magnitude of these contributions was very large and varied both
through an orbit and through the mission.  Thus three separate
bad-pixel maps and flat fields were required for each orbit.  The
number created was constrained by the number of lunar images over
which to average.  The minimum number of images to average was
controlled by the need to eliminate structure due to scene
variations that result from surface topography.  The maximum
number of images to average was limited by the varying thermal
emission of the lunar surface through an orbit; the measured
radiance values were much higher near the equator than near the
poles.  To create the mean and standard deviation images,
latitude bins were averaged together in the following way: 70S to
20S, 20S to 20N, and 20N to 70N.  Lunar images from latitudes
higher than 70 degrees used flat fields and bad-pixel maps from
adjacent latitude bins.
 
Inflight absolute calibration was accomplished by comparing the
LWIR-derived temperatures at the Apollo 17 landing site to
temperatures determined in situ from the heat-flow experiment.
Although in situ temperatures were also measured at the Apollo 15
site, LWIR frames are available only for the Apollo 17 site.  The
difference between Apollo temperatures and LWIR temperatures was
approximately 17 K, corresponding to a 22% difference in
radiance.  This 22% change in radiance reflects both the
limitations of the preflight calibration and the differences
between prelaunch and inflight calibrations. Therefore, all of
the LWIR-derived radiance values were multiplied by 0.82.
Brightness temperatures were then calculated using the Planck
function assuming unit emissivity.
 
The bad pixel routine did not identify all bad pixels due to
their shifting locations from image to image.  The few remaining
bad pixels were eliminated via a sigma-filter routine that
replaced pixels that were greater than 3-sigma away from the mean
of a 3 x 3 pixel region around each pixel.   Finally, the LWIR
temperatures were corrected for the varying Sun-Moon distance
throughout the mission.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
Preflight calibration data were acquired with an automated
calibration facility at Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory.
The preflight calibration measurements included radiometric
sensitivity; FPA uniformity; gain and offset scale factors;
temporal/spatial noise; dark noise dependence on FPA
temperatures, integration times, input voltage levels, and
spectral response of FPA; optical distortion map; point spread
function; electronic warm-up time; and cryocooler cool-down time.
 
Absolute uncertainties were found from the zero-level radiance
determination and are constant in radiance but vary in equivalent
temperature throughout an orbit, being lower near the equator
where the surface temperatures are higher.  For the entire
mission, a typical 2-sigma uncertainty is 7 K or greater.
Absolute uncertainties were propagated on a pixel-by-pixel basis
throughout the calibration routine, and then image-averaged.
Adjacent LWIR frames overlap and there is consistently less than
a 1% difference in brightness temperature between overlapping
regions.  Thus, the statistical uncertainty of a single
measurement is much less than the absolute uncertainties through
an orbit.
 
The LWIR camera cannot measure temperatures below approximately
150 K.  In the calibration routine, a zero-level image is
subtracted from each lunar radiance image.  Sometimes this
results in pixel values less than zero, particularly near the
poles where the temperatures are low.  All pixel values that are
less than zero in radiance are set to 0.0001 and then converted
to temperature.  This results in temperatures around 45 K that
are not real and have large associated uncertainties.
Temperatures below 150 K are not to be trusted.
 
Several orbits worth of data were not reduced, either because
there were no space images taken for that orbit or because the
detector saturated.  LWIR images from 95% of the orbits from the
first month of lunar mapping and from 77% of the orbits from the
second month of lunar mapping were reduced.  Thus data from a
total of 86% of the 266 Clementine systematic mapping orbits was
reduced.
 
For more information on the LWIR calibration routine, see
[LAWSONETAL2000].
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>1994-004A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

