<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.iras-a-fpa-3-rdr-imps-v4.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>IRAS MINOR PLANET SURVEY ASTEROIDS V4.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.infrared_astronomical_satellite::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.iras::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:fpa.iras::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.asteroid::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.iras-a-fpa-3-rdr-imps-v4.0__browserp_iras-a-fpa-3-rdr-imps-v4.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Beichman, C.A., G. Neugebauer, H.J. Habing, P.E. Clegg, and T.J. Chester,
                   1988, Infrared Astronomical Satellite Catalog and Atlases, Volume 1,
                   Explanatory Supplement, NASA RP-1190.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BEICHMANETAL1988</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kleinmann, S., R. Cutri, E. Young, F. Low, and F. Gillett, Explanatory
                   Supplement to the IRAS Serendipitous Survey Catalog, JPL, Pasadena, 1986.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLEINMANETAL1986</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Infrared Astronomical Satellite Asteroid and Comet Survey, Preprint
                   Version No. 1, D. Matson, Ed., JPL D-3698, 1986.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MATSON1986</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Moshir, M., et al., Explanatory Supplement to the IRAS Faint Source Survey
                   Version 2, JPL D-10015, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MOSHIRETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Neugebauer, G., H.J. Habing, R. van Duinen, H.H. Aumann, B. Baud, C.A.
                   Beichman, D.A. Beintema, N. Boggess, P.E. Clegg, T. de Jong, J.P. Emerson, T.N.
                   Gautier, F.C. Gillett, S. Harris, M.G. Hauser, J.R. Houck, R.E. Jennings, F.J.
                   Low, P.L. Marsden, G. Miley, F.M. Olnon, S.R. Pottasch, E. Raimond, M.
                   Rowan-Robinson, B.T. Soifer, R.G. Walker, P.R. Wesselius, and E. Young, The
                   Infrared Astronomical Satellite (IRAS) Mission, Astrophysica Journal 278,
                   L1-L6, 1984.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NEUGEBAUERETAL1984</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tedesco, E., G. Veeder, J. Fowler, and J. Chillemi, The IRAS Minor Planet
                   Survey, Phillips Lab PL-TR-92-2049, Hanscom Air Force Base, MA, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TEDESCOETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>IRAS-A-FPA-3-RDR-IMPS-V4.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>IRAS MINOR PLANET SURVEY ASTEROIDS V4.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1998-03-23</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1983-01</start_time>
        <stop_time>1983-11</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>MARK SYKES</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Derived diameters and albedoes of asteroids, plus associated data
            on sightings and non-sightings, extracted from the IRAS archives
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The data presented with this data set include: (a) 8210
            individual sightings associated with 2004 asteroids, (b) averaged
            radiometric diameters and geometric albedos derived from
            individual observations for 1796 numbered asteroids and 88
            unnumbered asteroids (as of 1983) whose orbital elements were
            determined using astrometry from two or more apparitions; (c) an
            entry for each of 120 asteroids for which there is an accepted
            sighting; (d) entries for each of 4677 numbered asteroids and
            2632 unnumbered asteroids (as of 1985) for which associations
            were sought in the IRAS data; (e) A summary of the number of
            times each asteroid was predicted to be scanned, and possible
            reasons for any failure to be detected.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The data presented with this data set include:
 
    1) SIGHTING.TAB - contains a listing of 8210 individual sightings
       associated with 2004 asteroids. SIGHTING.TAB contains the
       observation index, the identification of asteroids sighted,
       information pertaining to observation times, positional information
       on the observations of asteroids detected, geometric albedos,
       diameters and their associated uncertainties, input values used in
       the calculations of the geometric albedos and diameters using the
       asteroid standard thermal model, the observed flux densities in
       each band, detector crossing information, correlation coefficients,
       and status flags for reduction steps.
 
    2) DIAMALB.TAB - contains averaged radiometric diameters and
       geometric albedos derived from individual observations for 1796
       numbered asteroids and 88 unnumbered asteroids (as of 1983) whose
       orbital elements were determined using astrometry from two or more
       apparitions.
 
    3) SINGLE.TAB - contains an entry for each of 120 asteroids for
       which there is an accepted sighting, but in one band only.  This
       file includes the absolute visual magnitude of the asteroid, the
       albedo and diameter derived from the measurement and their
       associated uncertainties, and the accepted status word.
 
    4) GRNDDAT.TAB - contains entries for each of 4677 numbered
       asteroids and 2632 unnumbered asteroids (as of 1985) for which
       associations were sought in the IRAS data.  Asteroids 719 Albert
       and 878 Mildred were still lost as of 1985 and are not included.
       These entries include an initial estimate of geometric albedo and
       diameter used in processing IRAS survey observations of asteroids,
       the adopted taxonomic classification, and the orbital elements at
       three epochs.  The Julian dates of the epochs are 2445400.5,
       2445500.5, and 2445600.5. For further information regarding these
       data see Tedesco, et. al., 1992 [TEDESCOETAL1992].
 
    5) IMPSSTAT.TAB - contains a summary of the number of times each
       asteroid was predicted to be scanned, and possible reasons for any
       failure to be detected.  It contains entries for each of 4677
       numbered asteroids and 2632 unnumbered asteroids (as of 1985) for
       which associations were sought in the IRAS data.  Asteroids 719
       Albert and 878 Mildred were still lost as of 1985 and are not
       included.  These entries include the number of predicted sightings,
       number of accepted sightings, number of rejected sightings, number
       of missed predicted sightings, number of missed predicted faint
       sightings, number of dead 25 micron detector non-detections, number
       of noisy 25 micron detector non-detections, number of missed
       predictions in the galactic center region, and other
       non-detections.
 
    6) REJECT.TAB - summarizes the number of rejected sightings for
       each asteroid and possible reasons for rejection.
 
    7) MISSED.TAB - contains a summary of those asteroids which were
       predicted to pass across the IRAS focal plane during survey mode,
       but which generated no accepted associations.  Entries include the
       number of times an asteroid was predicted to be scanned but was
       missed, and the derived greatest lower limit on the albedo and
       least upper limit on the diameter, plus a status word detailing the
       circumstances of the observation failure.
 
    8) STMODEL.TAB - contains the flux look-up table used to generate the
       IMPS albedos.  This table was provided by L. Lebofsky and was
       derived from the IRAS standard thermal model.
 
 
  Modification History
  --------------------
    The IMPS data set was ingested in 1994 and updated to correct a minor
    error in 1995.  These versions included only FP102, the diameters and
    albedos.  The data set has now been updated to include FP103, FP104,
    FP105, FP 106, FP107, FP108, and the flux lookup table used tto
    generate the IMPS albedos.
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Review
  ======
    This data set underwent peer review on March 23, 1998.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SUPERSEDED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XD-B3B</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

