<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.hay-a-amica-3-amicageom-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>HAYABUSA AMICA IMAGES WITH GEOMETRY BACKPLANES V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.hayabusa::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.hay::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:amica.hay::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.asteroid::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.hay-a-amica-3-amicageom-v1.0__browserp_hay-a-amica-3-amicageom-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Barnouin-Jha, O., A. Cheng, T. Mukai, S. Abe, H. Naru, R. Nakamura, R.W.
                   Gaskell, J. Saito, and B.E. Clark, Small-scale topography of 25143 Itokawa from
                   the Hayabusa laser altimeter, Icarus 198, 108-124, 2008.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BARNOUIN-JHAETAL2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Cheng, A.F., O. Barnouin-Jha, L. Prockter, M. T. Zuber, G. Neumann, D. E.
                   Smith, J. Garvin, M. Robinson, J. Veverka, and P. Thomas, Small-scale
                   topography of 433 Eros from laser altimetry and imaging. Icarus 155, 51-74,
                   2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CHENGETAL2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Gaskell, R.W., O. Barnouin-Jha, D.J. Scheeres, A.S. Konopliv, T. Mukai, S. Abe,
                   J. Saito, M. Ishiguro, T. Kubota, T. Hashimoto, J. Kawaguchi, M. Yoshikawa, K.
                   Shirakawa, T. Kominato, N. Hirata, and H. Demura, Characterizing and navigating
                   small bodies with imaging data, Meteoritics and Planetary Science, 43, Nr 6,
                   1049-1061, 2008.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GASKELLETAL2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Gaskell, R., J. Saito, M. Ishiguro, T. Kubota, T. Hashimoto, N. Hirata, S. Abe,
                   O. Barnouin-Jha, and D. Scheeres, Gaskell Itokawa Shape Model V1.0.
                   HAY-A-AMICA-5-ITOKAWASHAPE-V1.0. NASA Planetary Data System, 2008.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GASKELLETAL2008B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Ishiguro, M., R. Nakamura, D.J. Tholen, N. Hirata, H. Demura, E. Nemoto, A.M.
                   Nakamura, Y. Higuchi, A. Sogame, A. Yamamoto, K. Kitazato, Y. Yokota, T.
                   Kubota, T. Hashimoto, and J. Saito, The Hayabusa Spacecraft Asteroid Multi-Band
                   Imaging Camera: AMICA, Icarus (2010), doi: 10.1016/j.icarus.2009.12.035, 2010.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ISHIGUROETAL2010</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mukai, T., S. Abe, O. Barnouin-Jha, and A. Cheng, Hayabusa LIDAR V1.0.
                   HAY-A-LIDAR-3-HAYLIDAR-V1.0. NASA Planetary Data System, 2008.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MUKAIETAL2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Saito, J., T. Nakamura, H. Akiyama, H. Demura, B. Dermawan, M. Furuya, T. Fuse,
                   R. Gaskell, T. Hashimoto, Y. Higuchi, K. Hiraoka, N. Hirata, C. Honda, T.
                   Honda, M. Ishiguro, K. Kitazato, S. Kobayashi, T. Kubota, N. Matsumoto, T.
                   Michikami, H. Miyamoto, A. Nakamura, R. Nakamura, E. Nemoto, S. Sasaki, C.
                   Shinohara, P. Smith, A. Sogame, J. Terazono, D. Tholen, A. Yamamoto, Y. Yokota,
                   F. Yoshida, and A. Yukishita, Hayabusa AMICA V1.0. HAY-A-AMICA-3-HAYAMICA-V1.0.
                   NASA Planetary Data System, 2010.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SAITOETAL2010</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>HAY-A-AMICA-3-AMICAGEOM-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>HAYABUSA AMICA IMAGES WITH GEOMETRY BACKPLANES V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2012-01-23</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2005-09-11T06:20:08Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2005-11-19T20:26:36Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>CAROL NEESE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Barnouin, O. and Kahn, E., Hayabusa AMICA Images with Geometry
            Backplanes V1.0. HAY-A-AMICA-3-AMICAGEOM-V1.0. NASA Planetary
            Data System, 2012.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Hayabusa AMICA images of 25143 Itokawa, with geometry backplanes.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Asteroid Multi-band Imaging Camera (AMICA) of the Hayabusa
            mission to the asteroid 25143 Itokawa obtained 1662 images from
            May 11, 2003, shortly after launch, until November 19, 2005,
            after Itokawa encounter. This data set provides derived data
            products for 1339 of those images that includes geometric
            information for each pixel.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
    =================
 
      The HAYABUSA spacecraft is the first mission to have successfully
  sampled an asteroid, returned in June 2010. This Japanese mission included
  the Asteroid Multi-band Imaging Camera (AMICA) which imaged the surface of
  the sampled asteroid. This camera is a charge-coupled device (CCD) camera
  with a refractive telescope producing an effective field of view of 5.83 x
  5.69 degrees.  In the course of the mission, AMICA obtained 1662 images
  which are archived in PDS as Saito et al. (2010).  For information about the
  design, performance and calibration of the AMICA camera, see Ishiguro et al.
  (2010).
 
 
      The AMICA Derived Data Record (DDR) contains geometric information for
  each pixel of 1339 images that views the surface of 25143 Itokawa. The DDR
  includes the location of each pixel on the surface of the asteroid, the
  solar incidence angle, emission angle and phase angle at each pixel when the
  image were acquired, and data on the local slope relative to gravity, the
  acceleration due to gravity and the elevation relative to a reference
  gravitational potential at each pixel, assuming a constant density asteroid.
 
 
    Data
    ====
 
      These DDR are broken out into 2 groups. A very high quality group (in
  directory data/ddr_gaskell) where the locations, illumination and geometric
  parameters for each AMICA pixel are calculated from parameters derived using
  geometry obtained while constructing the shape model for Itokawa using
  stereophotoclinometry (SPC) [see Gaskell et al. 2008a,b]. The second set of
  DDRs is of lesser quality (in directory data/ddr_spice), but remains
  nevertheless very useful and is derived from geometric information while
  preparing filtered version 1 of the Hayabusa LIDAR dataset [see Barnouin-Jha
  et al. (2008); Mukai et al. (2008) for details on how those data were
  derived].
 
      Both SPC and LIDAR data provide the location of the HAYABUSA spacecraft
  relative to the asteroid. In the case of the data derived by SPC, SUMFILES
  are generated that solve for the same data that exists in NAIF SPK and CK
  kernels, namely the spacecraft trajectory and attitude. These solutions were
  used the make the SPC derived DDR backplanes.
 
      In the case of the AMICA DDRs derived using LIDAR data, the LIDAR
  solutions were used for the spacecraft ephmeris. These are archived at NAIF
  as hay_osbj_050911_051118_v1n.bsp. The spacecraft attitude or pointing data
  was obtained from the current attitude kernels available at the PDS for the
  pointing data delivered to the PDS by the HAYABUSA project. All the SPICE
  kernels used are listed in detail in the next Ancillary Data section.
 
      The DDRs generated using Stereophotoclinometry are listed in the text
  file backplanes_filelist_gaskell.asc, while those derived from the SPICE
  data currently available at the PDS are listed in the file
  backplanes_filelist_spice.asc. Both these list files are located in the
  document directory.  Also located in the document directory are two pdf
  files with images of all the backplanes for each of the two sets of images.
  These files are backplanes_summary_gaskell.pdf and
  backplanes_summary_spice.pdf.
 
      Each of the AMICA DDR files is essentially a 16-layered image cube. The
  first layer or band of this cube has the pixel values of the original fits
  images delivered to the PDS by the Hayabusa team. The second, third and
  fourth layers provide the x, y and z coordinates of each pixel center
  located on the surface of the asteroid. The prime meridian for Itokawa,
  which defines the x-axis or zero Longitude of Itokawa, is given by a black
  boulder observed on the &apos;head&apos; of Itokawa, and is defined in the Itokawa
  planetary kernel listed below in the &apos;Ancillary Data Section&apos;. The
  x,y,z,locations of each pixel are determined from the intersect of the field
  of view of each pixel with an Itokawa shape model generated by [Gaskell et
  al. 2008b]. The fifth, sixth, and seventh layers show the location of this
  pixel center using latitude, East longitude and radial distance from the
  center of figure of the asteroid. The eighth, ninth, and tenth layers of the
  DDR cube give the average Solar incidence, emission and phase angle across
  each one of the pixels. The eleventh and twelfth layers provide the
  horizonal and vertical pixel scale of AMICA across the surface of Itokawa.
  The thirteenth, fourteenth, fifteenth, and sixteenth layers provide the
  average surface slope relative to gravity, the average elevation relative to
  gravity, the average gravitational acceleration, and the average
  gravitational potential at each pixel on the surface of the asteroid.
 
      These last four values were calculated using the method described in
  Cheng et al. (2002) using a constant density for Itokawa of 1.95 g/cc and a
  rotation rate of 0.000144 rad/s. With this density and rotation rate the
  gravitational potential on the surface can be computed via integration (see
  Cheng et al. 2002; Barnouin-Jha et al., 2008 for details). From the
  resulting gravitational potential, a reference gravitational potential
  equiavlent to a &apos;geoid&apos; on Earth can be obtained from the area averaged root
  mean square of this gravitational potential. This reference potential
  provides the elevation on the surfcae of the asteroid once divide by the
  local magnitude of the gravitational acceleration. The  density and rotation
  also provides via integration the magnitude and direction of the
  gravitational acceleration at the surface. The slope given is obtained by
  taking the acosine of the dot product of the normal to each plate model
  facet with the vector describing the direction of the gravitational
  accleration at the center of each plate model facet.
 
 
      All the AMICA Derived data records are 32-bit binary images, using the
  standard PDS image (.IMG) format.  They may be read into ISIS version 3.2
  using the command pds2isis:
 
  &apos;pds2isis from=st_2445206532_v_ddr.lbl to=6532.cub&apos;
 
  This will generate an ISIS cube called 6532.cub.  The ISIS package called
  &apos;qview&apos; allows you to view the image and any back planes.
 
      It should be noted that use of x, y, z locations to analyze Itokawa
  images is better then analyzing the data using latitude and longitude and
  radius as more typical when working with planets. This is becuase there are
  areas of Itokawa where one latitude and longitude can define more than one
  asteroid radius.
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
 
     The Ancillary data used to compute the backplanes for AMICA include
  several SPICE kernels. All these kernels are available through PDS at
  ftp://naif.jpl.nasa.gov/pub/naif/pds/data/hay-a-spice-6-v1.0/
 
    The exact kernesl used include :
     (1) The following leap second kernel (lsk):
              naif0009.tls
     (2) The following planetary constants kernel (pck):
              pck00008.tpc
              itokawa_gaskell_n3.tpc
     (3) The following spacecraft clock kernel (sclk):
              hayabusa.tsc
     (4) The following frame kernels (fk):
              itokawa_fixed.tf
              hayabusa_hp.tf
     (5) The following instrument kernel (ik)
              amica31.ti
     (6) The following ephemeris kerenls (spk)
              de403s.bsp
              sb_25143_140.bsp
              hay_jaxa_050916_051119_v1n.bsp
              hay_osbj_050911_051118_v1n.bsp
     (7) The following spacecraft attitude kernels (ck):
             hayabusa_itokawarendezvous_v02n.bc
     (8) The plate models used for the purpose of determining the DDR
         backplanes of AMICA has been archived at the PDS (Gaskell
         et al. 2008b).  The shape model closest in resolution to the
         pixel scale of a particular AMICA image were employed while
         generating that image&apos;s backplane.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
 
      A planetocentric coordinate system is employed, which is body-centered,
  using the center-of-figure as the origin. The actual vector from the center
  of Itokawa to the surface should be primarily employed for scientific
  purposes because of the important curvature of Itokawa where some locations
  can possess more than one latitude and longitude. However, latitude and
  longitude data are also provided, but should be used with caution. The
  latitude is defined by the angle between the equatorial plane and a vector
  extending from the origin of the coordinate system to the relevant point on
  the surface.  Latitude is measured from -90 degrees at the south pole to +90
  degrees at the north pole.  Longitude extends from 0 to 360 degrees, with
  values increasing eastward (i.e., it is a right-handed coordinate system)
  from the prime meridian. This coordinate system is preferred for use in
  navigation and geophysical studies in which, for example, estimates of
  elevation or gravitational potential are provided (as in the AMICA DDR bands
  13-16).
 
 
    References
    ==========
 
      Barnouin-Jha, O., A. Cheng, T. Mukai, S. Abe, H. Naru, R. Nakamura, R.W.
  Gaskell, J. Saito, and B.E. Clark.  Small-scale topography of 25143 Itokawa
  from the Hayabusa laser altimeter.  Icarus 198, 108-124, 2008.
 
      Cheng, A.F., O. Barnouin-Jha, L. Prockter, M. T. Zuber, G. Neumann, D.
  E. Smith, J. Garvin, M. Robinson, J. Veverka, and P. Thomas, Small-scale
  topography of 433 Eros from laser altimetry and imaging. Icarus 155, 51-74,
  2002.
 
      Gaskell, R.W., O. Barnouin-Jha, D.J. Scheeres, A.S. Konopliv, T. Mukai,
  S. Abe, J. Saito, M. Ishiguro, T. Kubota, T. Hashimoto, J. Kawaguchi, M.
  Yoshikawa, K. Shirakawa, T. Kominato, N. Hirata, and H. Demura,
  Characterizing and navigating small bodies with imaging data, Meteoritics
  and Planetary Science, 43, Nr 6, 1049-1061, 2008.
 
      Gaskell, R., Saito, J., Ishiguro, M., Kubota, T., Hashimoto, T., Hirata,
  N., Abe, S., Barnouin-Jha, O., and Scheeres, D., Gaskell Itokawa Shape Model
  V1.0. HAY-A-AMICA-5-ITOKAWASHAPE-V1.0. NASA Planetary Data System, 2008b.
 
      Ishiguro, M., R. Nakamura, D.J. Tholen, N. Hirata, H. Demura, E. Nemoto,
  A.M. Nakamura, Y. Higuchi, A. Sogame, A. Yamamoto, K. Kitazato, Y. Yokota,
  T. Kubota, T. Hashimoto, and J. Saito, The Hayabusa Spacecraft Asteroid
  Multi-Band Imaging Camera: AMICA, Icarus (2010),
  doi:10.1016/j.icarus.2009.12.035, 2010.
 
      Mukai, T., Abe, S., Barnouin-Jha, O., and Cheng, A., Hayabusa LIDAR
  V1.0. HAY-A-LIDAR-3-HAYLIDAR-V1.0. NASA Planetary Data System, 2008.
 
      Saito, J., Nakamura, T., Akiyama, H., Demura, H., Dermawan, B., Furuya,
  M., Fuse, T., Gaskell, R., Hashimoto, T., Higuchi, Y., Hiraoka, K., Hirata,
  N., Honda, C., Honda, T., Ishiguro, M., Kitazato, K., Kobayashi, S., Kubota,
  T., Matsumoto, N., Michikami, T., Miyamoto, H., Nakamura, A., Nakamura, R.,
  Nemoto, E., Sasaki, S., Shinohara, C., Smith, P., Sogame, A., Terazono, J.,
  Tholen, D., Yamamoto, A., Yokota, Y., Yoshida, F., and Yukishita, A.,
  Hayabusa AMICA V1.0. HAY-A-AMICA-3-HAYAMICA-V1.0. NASA Planetary Data
  System, 2010.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    Timing Uncertainty
    ==================
 
        The clock aboard Hayabusa possesses an estimated uncertainty of +/- 12
    seconds due to a periodicity in the control and operation of the analog
    signal processing unit.  This effect was somewhat remedied by the analysis
    used by the LIDAR science team. The relative pointing between the ONC-W2
    camera and AMICA were statiscally adjusted so that a simulated image using
    the Hayabusa shape model would match the location of Itokawa observed by
    AMICA. Both data sets suffer from the same timing problem and our approach
    would thus have minimized their effect over the lifetime of the mission,
    and these also influence AMICA derived data products.
 
    Pixel Location Uncertainty
    ===========================
 
        The Amica Derived Data Records, also possess two levels of quality.
    The higher quality data are listed in
    amica_backplanes_file_list_gaskell.txt.  For these data obtained while
    generating the shape model of Itokawa, uncertainties in the location are
    on the order of 0.2 times the pixel sampling size. At 20km range from the
    surface of the asteroid this implies an uncertainty in position of 0.5m.
    At 4 km, this unceratinty measures ~0.1m.
 
        The Derived Data products generated combined the LIDAR spacecraft
    ephemeris solutions and Hayabasa project delivered attitude (listed in
    backplanes_file_list_spice.asc) uncertainties in pixel location are
    somewhat larger. At most these can be 10m.  However, in general the errors
    are much less, probably on the order of ~ 0.5m, based on the excellent
    match between the location of topography observed on Itokawa with AMICA,
    and the estimated location of those topography using the combined LIDAR
    spacecraft ephmeris solutions and the HAYABUSA attitude data.  See
    Barnouin-Jha et al. (2008) for additional details.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
 
        The HAYABUSA Derived Data Records were obtained for the majority (81%)
    of the AMICA images obatianed, but not all. This is in part becuase many
    of the images were not of Itokawa, or were taken when Itokawa was smaller
    than a few pixel and the spacecraft was too far for the LIDAR to acquire
    its surface. In these latter two cases it was impossible to derive the
    location of the spacecrfat relative to Itokawa in any meaningful way and
    thus obtain a Derived Data Product.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

