<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mro-m-sharad-4-rdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MRO SHARAD REDUCED DATA RECORD V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:sharad.mro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-sharad-4-rdr-v1.0__browserp_mro-m-sharad-4-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-sharad-4-rdr-v1.0__browser_geo_mars_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-sharad-4-rdr-v1.0__dvo_geo_mro-m-sharad-4-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Orosei, R., and S. Slavney, Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter Shallow Radar
                   Reduced Data Record Software Interface Specification, Version 0.1, April
                   28, 2006.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.OROSEI2006B</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MRO-M-SHARAD-4-RDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MRO SHARAD REDUCED DATA RECORD V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2006-01-01</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>ROBERTO OROSEI</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Orosei, R., Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter Shallow Radar Reduced
            Data Record, MRO-M-SHARAD-4-RDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2006.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Reduced data records for the SHARAD (Shallow Radar) instrument on
            Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset contains RDR (derived) data from the SHARAD (Shallow
            Radar) instrument on Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter. SHARAD is the
            sub-surface sounding radar provided by the Italian Space Agency
            (ASI).
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
 
      Data Set MARS RECONNAISSANCE ORBITER MARS SHARAD REDUCED DATA
      RECORD V1.0 (Level 1B data) consists of received echoes that have
      been Doppler filtered, range compressed, and converted to complex
      voltages, correlated with the auxiliary information needed to
      locate observations in space and time and to process data further.
      Level 1B data users are expected to be mainly geologists
      interested in determining the structure of the shallow Martian
      subsurface. Data users must be aware that processed echoes may
      contain artifacts due to off-nadir surface reflections, the so-
      called clutter, reaching the radar after nadir surface echoes, and
      thus appearing as subsurface reflections.
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      SHARAD RDR Data Products are generated at the SHARAD operation
      center in Rome, Italy, under the responsibility of the Team Leader
      Institution (INFOCOM Department, University of Rome &apos;La
      Sapienza&apos;).
 
      In the processing producing RDRs, data are range- and Doppler-
      processed. The software used to produce RDR data products requires
      a configuration file containing values for parameters used by the
      processing algorithms. Once the parameters are set, data
      processing proceeds in a fully automated way. Level 1B processing
      consists of the following functions:
 
      1) Auxiliary data loading
      2) Data selection
      3) Data healing
      4) Phase distortion compensation
      5) Doppler parameters estimation
      6) Range-Doppler processing
      7) Multi-look processing
      8) Output generation
 
      Auxiliary data loading consists in the loading of files needed in
      the processing. Such files are part of the SHARAD Level 1A (EDR)
      archive, which thus constitutes the sole input for the production
      of RDR data products. They are the antenna pattern file,
      describing the SHARAD antenna relative gain as a function of the
      spacecraft high-gain antenna and solar panels position; the
      reference function file, that is the complex conjugate of the FFT
      of the discretely-sampled transmitted signal; and the spurious
      frequencies file, reporting the spectrum of coherent noise
      produced by the spacecraft electronics within the SHARAD operation
      bandwidth.
 
      Data selection consists in the loading of the Level 1A data
      products to be processed and of the configuration file setting
      parameters required by processing algorithms. During this phase,
      each sample of each raw echo, compressed on-board into a 4-, 6- or
      8- bit integer, is decompressed according to two different
      algorithms, depending on the selection of either static
      compression or dynamic compression for on-board processing. If a
      static compression has been adopted, then the uncompressed value
      is given by
 
      S32 = S4,6,8 / 2N
 
      where S32 is the sample in 32-bit floating point notation, S4,6,8
      is the compressed value of the sample, and N is the number of pre-
      summed echoes. If dynamic compression has been adopted, then
 
      S32 = S4,6,8 / 2p
 
      where p is the SDI Bit-Field parameter reported into the Science
      Ancillary Data.
 
      Data healing consists of the compensation of antenna pattern
      variations caused by the movement of the spacecraft high-gain
      antenna and solar panels during the data take, and of the removal
      of spurious signals introduced by the spacecraft electronics.
 
      Phase distortions may occur due to interaction between the radar
      signal and the Martian ionosphere plasma, whose refraction index
      is a function of frequency. Phase distortion compensation is a
      fully automated function implementing the Phase Gradient Autofocus
      (PGA) algorithm.
 
      Doppler parameters estimation produces estimates of the Doppler
      centroid frequency and of the Doppler bandwidth for the raw data.
      Doppler centroid estimation determines the average Doppler
      frequency of received echoes in order to perform an optimum
      azimuth filtering. The centroid frequency is the frequency
      dividing the energy spectra of averaged signals in two equal
      parts. The Doppler bandwidth determines the maximum possible
      azimuth resolution of the output echoes, and the amount of data
      overlapping from one synthetic aperture to the next.
 
      Range-Doppler processing consists of range compression followed by
      Doppler processing. Range compression consists in the matched or
      inverse filtering of each raw echo. The filtering is performed by
      multiplying the raw signal FFT spectrum by the reference function
      (matched filtering) or by its inverse (inverse filtering). Doppler
      processing is performed through the Chirp Scaling Algorithm (CSA)
      for SAR processing, which allows also for Range Cell Migration
      Compensation (RCMC). CSA guaranties good performances in terms of
      computational speed and achievable azimuth resolution.
 
      Multi-look processing aims at reducing speckle: the random
      fluctuations of received power due to coherent reflections, by
      averaging the values of neighboring range-Doppler pixels within a
      given window around each pixel. Such filtering will increase the
      radiometric resolution, but the spatial resolution will decrease
      as a result. The window size is fixed, while the window weight is
      selectable by means of the configuration file.
 
      In the generation of the output files, the processed echoes, now a
      complex quantity because of the processing taking place in the
      Fourier spectral domain, are complemented with the original
      auxiliary data contained in the scientific telemetry of the
      instrument, with parameters characterizing the ground processing
      of the echoes, with geometric quantities generated on-ground from
      spacecraft navigation data, and with parameters extracted from
      instrument and spacecraft housekeeping telemetry. All this
      auxiliary information, with the exception of processing
      parameters, is copied from the input Level 1A files used to
      produce the RDR data product.
 
    Data
    ====
 
      Each SHARAD RDR data product is the result of the processing all
      echoes acquired continuously in time using the same operation
      mode, instrument status and on-board processing scheme. There is
      one RDR data product for every SHARAD Experiment Data Record data
      product acquired in subsurface sounding mode, which in fact
      constitutes the input for the RDR product generation.
 
      The content of each SHARAD RDR data product is highly variable in
      terms of number of processed echoes, and depends on how operations
      for the instrument were planned during a given data collection
      period.
 
      Each processed radar observation in an RDR data product is the
      result of range and azimuth processing of a variable number of raw
      echoes. Thus, although there is a one-to-one correspondence
      between EDRs and RDRs, such correspondence does not hold between
      individual raw and processed echoes: in general, many raw echoes
      (of the order of several tens or a few hundred) result in the
      production of a single processed echo.
 
      Because each processed echo is a sequence of time samples of a
      received signal, complemented by ancillary information, the
      natural organization for processed echoes within a Data Product is
      a table, in which each line contains data from a single processed
      echo, and each column contains the value of a single parameter or
      time sample across different processed echoes.
 
      Each Data Product consists of two files:
 
      1) A binary file containing the scientific data of the instrument:
      a sequence of processed echoes, each of which is preceded by a
      header containing information on the instrument setting and on-
      board processing of the data, and followed by parameters
      characterizing the ground processing of the echoes, by geometric
      quantities generated on-ground from spacecraft navigation data,
      and by parameters extracted from instrument housekeeping
      telemetry.
 
      2) A detached ASCII PDS label file describing the content of the
      data product.
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
 
      Ancillary data describe the instrument settings during data
      acquisition and report parameters used in on-board processing.
      Scientific data consist of the processed complex echo, expressed
      as a vector for the real part of the complex echo, followed by a
      second vector of the same length containing the imaginary part of
      the echo. Processing parameters have been computed by the ground
      processing software, and contain information such as the Doppler
      centroid and Doppler bandwidth of original raw echoes. Geometric
      parameters have been computed on ground from spacecraft trajectory
      and attitude data, and allow the location of each processed echo
      in space and time. Instrument engineering parameters are extracted
      from SHARAD housekeeping telemetry and report quantities such as
      currents and temperatures within the instrument.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
 
      SHARAD RDR data products conform to a Project-determined set of
      cartographic standards. All map-projected data use planetocentric
      coordinates and east-positive longitudes in the range 0 to 360
      degrees, computed w.r.t. the IAU 2000 reference ellipsoid. Vector
      quantities such as spacecraft positions are expressed in a
      Cartesian planetocentric reference frame.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
 
      Each SHARAD RDR data product consists of a binary file in fixed
      record-length format, and a detached PDS label containing
      information on source data, production process, relation between
      stored bytes and physical quantities, product identification,
      storing and organizing of ancillary data and descriptive
      information needed to interpret and process the data. The
      structure of data contained in the binary file is that of a PDS
      Table object. The PDS label contains pointers to a file containing
      definitions of the columns of such Table object.
 
      Each record in a binary file is a processed echo: the result of
      the Doppler filtering and range compressing of a variable number
      of raw echoes, and is expressed as a time series of complex
      voltages. Each record also contains a number of parameters
      describing the operation of the instrument during data
      acquisition, together with engineering and spacecraft information.
      Specifically, each record is subdivided into five parts, each of
      which contains a different type of information: ancillary data,
      scientific data, processing parameters, geometric parameters and
      instrument engineering parameters.
 
      PDS labels are written in Object Description Language (ODL). PDS
      label statements have the form of &apos;keyword = value&apos;. Each label
      statement is terminated with a carriage return character (ASCII
      13) and a line feed character (ASCII 10) sequence to allow the
      label to be read by many operating systems. The labels contained
      in SHARAD EDR files conform to the general structure used for all
      PDS detached labels.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      TBD
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This data set was examined by a peer review panel in accordance
      with PDS procedures. At this writing (May 21, 2007), some liens
      placed on the data set as a result of the review are still
      unresolved.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      TBD
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      TBD
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

