<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lp-l-mag-4-summ-lunarcrds-5sec-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LP MAGER SPINAVG MAGNETIC FIELD LUNAR COORDS 5SEC V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_prospector::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mag.lp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lp-l-mag-4-summ-lunarcrds-5sec-v1.0__browserc_lp-l-mag-4-summ-lunarcrds-5sec-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lp-l-mag-4-summ-lunarcrds-5sec-v1.0__browserp_lp-l-mag-4-summ-lunarcrds-5sec-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Acuna, M.H., J.E.P. Connerney, P. Wasilewski, R.P. Lin, K.A. Anderson, C.W.
                   Carlson, J. McFadden, D.W. Curtis, H. Reme, A. Cros, J.L. Medale, J.A. Sauvaud,
                   C. d&apos;Uston, S.J. Bauer, P. Cloutier, M. Mayhew, and N.F. Ness, Mars Observer
                   Magnetic Fields Investigation, J. Geophys. Res., 97, 7799-7814, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ACUNAETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Binder, A.B., W.C. Feldman, G.S. Hubbard, A.S. Konopliv, R.P. Lin, M.H. Acuna,
                   and L.L. Hood, Lunar Prospector searches for polar ice, a metallic core, gas
                   release events, and the moon&apos;s origin, Eos, Trans. AGU, 79, 97, 1998.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BINDERETAL1998</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Carlson, C., D. Curtis, G. Paschmann, and W. Michael, An instrument for rapidly
                   measuring plasma distribution functions with high resolution, Adv. Space Res.,
                   2, 67, 1983.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CARLSONETAL1983</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LP-L-MAG-4-SUMM-LUNARCRDS-5SEC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LP MAGER SPINAVG MAGNETIC FIELD LUNAR COORDS 5SEC V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2002-07-11</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1998-01-16</start_time>
        <stop_time>1999-07-29</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. MARIO ACUNA</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>not applicable</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Magnetic field data from the Lunar Prospector Magnetometer,
            averaged in 5-second intervals, in SEL and SSE coordinates in
            units of nanotesla for dates 1998-01-16 to 1999-07-29, plus
            spacecraft position data.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>not applicable</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    Magnetometer data records are time-ordered series of magnetic vector
    measurements. Each record consists of a time tag followed by six
    scalar values representing the magnetic field vector, measured in
    nanoteslas, in two different coordinate systems: selenocentric solar
    ecliptic (SSE) and body-fixed selenographic (SEL), followed by the rms
    deviation of the field magnitude, which is independent of the
    coordinate system.  The spacecraft position is given in both of the
    above coordinate systems.  These data are obtained continuously at 9
    Hz and are averaged in 5-second intervals for this data archive.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    Magnetic field data are provided in units of nanotesla (nT).
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    Magnetic field data are sampled onboard at 18 Hz and averaged to 9 Hz
    before being placed into telemetry. In order to cover a very large
    dynamic range with 12-bit values, the full range of the instrument is
    divided into 8 sub-ranges. Range changing is performed dynamically
    onboard based on the ambient field strength. The first step in the
    processing is to extract the data from telemetry and form time-tagged
    magnetic field vectors.  Then, occasional data spikes due to range
    changes or bad telemetry are flagged; these data points are not used in
    the offset determination.  The instrumental offsets for Bx and By are
    calculated simultaneously for 1 minute data windows using a technique
    developed by M. Acuna.  Time varying offsets are needed because the
    offsets drift slightly as the magnetometer temperature changes. (The
    MAG temperature is modulated as the spacecraft goes in and out of the
    Moon&apos;s shadow.) A constant offset is used for the Z component, because
    lack of spin modulation in that component precludes routine offset
    determination. Offsets are calculated separately for each data range
    and subtracted from the data. This correction reduces systematic errors
    in the X and Y components to less than ~0.1 nT. Since the Z component
    cannot be corrected in this way, systematic errors in that axis (due to
    temperature-induced offset drifts) can be as large as 0.5 nT.
    Instrumental gains, different for each of the 8 ranges, are then
    applied to convert to nanotesla. Next, the data are corrected for a
    slight misalignment between the magnetometer sensor axes and the
    spacecraft axes. The resulting sensor (SEN) coordinate system has its
    Z-axis parallel to the spacecraft spin axis, and its X-axis aligned
    with the magnetometer boom. The SEN coordinate system rotates as the
    spacecraft spins. The next step is to flag spurious data values. The
    first measurement following a range change is flagged, since the finite
    time needed to make the change often corrupts the first measurement in
    the new range. Other false spikes also appear in the data, most of
    which are attributable to occasional noise in the telemetry. A
    comparison technique is used to remove outliers.  In practice, this
    effectively removes most  spurious data values without eliminating any
    valid data. The next step is to &apos;&apos;despin&apos;&apos; the data from SEN to
    &apos;&apos;despun spacecraft&apos;&apos; (SCD) coordinates, which are defined such that
    the Z-axis is parallel to the spacecraft spin vector, and the direction
    of the sun is in the half-plane defined by X &gt; 0, Y = 0. Despinning is
    performed using the reconstructed sunpulse data, which are corrected
    for spacecraft spin-up in the Moon&apos;s shadow.  Next, the data are
    averaged in 5-second intervals; this reduces the data volume by a
    factor of 45.  Finally, a rotation is performed from SCD coordinates to
    selenocentric solar ecliptic (SSE) and body-fixed selenocentric (SEL)
    coordinates using the spacecraft ephemeris data (the latitude and
    longitude of the spin axis obtained from files included in the PDS
    distribution of the LP Level-1 magnetic field data) and lunar ephemeris
    data obtained from the Jet Propulsion Laboratory&apos;s Horizons system
    (&lt;http://ssd.jpl.nasa.gov/horizons.html&gt;). SSE coordinates are defined
    such that the X-axis points from the center of the Moon to the center
    of the Sun, the Z-axis is parallel to Earth&apos;s ecliptic north, and the
    Y-axis completes the right-handed coordinate system. SEL coordinates
    are defined such that the Z-axis is parallel to the Moon&apos;s spin vector
    (north pole) and the X and Y axes intersect the lunar equator. The
    X-axis intersects the lunar equator at 0 degrees longitude, and is thus
    nearly aligned with the Moon-Earth line. (It is not exactly aligned
    because of the Moon&apos;s libration.) The Y-axis intersects the lunar
    equator at 90 degrees EAST longitude: SEL coordinates are right handed.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    Data are archived on CDROMs in level 1 compliance with the ISO 9660
    standard. Three CDROMs cover the entire mission. The data are provided
    as ASCII &apos;&apos;tables&apos;&apos; of 1-day duration in Selenocentric Solar Ecliptic
    (SSE) and Selenographic (SEL) coordinates.  Date/time are given in 2
    formats as described below.
 
 
  MAG Data
  ========
    Naming convention: MAyymmdd.TAB
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
    1) time parameter 1:  PDS date-time format of the mid-time of the
       5-sec averaging window in spacecraft event time, i.e.,
       Universal Time at the spacecraft.  Example: 1998-11-08T05:50:42.5
 
    2) time parameter 2:  decimal day of the mid-time of the 5-sec
       averaging window in spacecraft event time, i.e.,
       Universal Time at the spacecraft.
 
    3) mag_field_SEL:  Array[3] giving B-field components (nT) in the
       SEL coordinate system
 
    4) mag_field_SSE: Array[3] giving B-field components (nT) in the
       SSE coordinate system
 
    5) mag_field_RMS: RMS deviation (nT) of the field magnitude.
       Provides an indication of field variability for the 5-sec window.
 
    6) Spacecraft SEL coordinates: coordinate array[3]  (km)
 
    7) Spacecraft SSE coordinates: coordinate array[3] (km)
 
    8) ISUN - a parameter from the sunpulse file indicating whether the
       spacecraft is in the sun (0), in eclipse (1), or, if the sunpulse
       file was not available, the data were processed using the less
       accurate determination of the sunpulse time in the Level-0 data
       file and ISUN is set to 2.  Note that this parameter contains
       erroneous values (0 &lt;-&gt; 1) from time to time.  To reduce the
       occurrence of bad ISUM values the parameter was median-filtered
       with a 9-point window, which removes most of the errors.
 
    These parameters could be named PDS_time, decimal_day, Bx_sel, By_sel,
    Bz_sel, Bx_sse, By_sse, Bz_sse, B_rms, x_sel, y_sel, z_sel, x_sse,
    y_sse, z_sse, isun
 
    An appropriate format for reading the data is:
 
    format=&apos;( A21, f12.6, f9.3, 2(f8.3), f9.3, 2(f8.3), f9.3, f10.2,
    2(f9.2), f10.2, 2(f9.2), I3 )&apos;
 
    however, the records contain blanks between each parameters so that a
    format statement will not be required by most languages.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    There are several ancillary data files provided with this archive.
    These include:
 
    Spacecraft Attitude data LP-L-ENG-6-ATTITUDE-V1.0
    Spacecraft Ephemeris data LP-L-6-EPHEMERIS-V1.0
    Spacecraft Position data LP-L-6-POSITION-V1.0
    Spacecraft Command logs LP-L-ENG-6-COMMAND-V1.0
 
    These data sets provide additional information about the state of the
    spacecraft and the instrument during data acquisition that may aid in
    the scientific analysis of this data set.
 
 
  Coordinate Systems
  ==================
    The SSE coordinate system has its X-axis along the Moon-Sun line,
    positive towards the Sun. The Z-axis is parallel to the northward
    normal to the Earth&apos;s ecliptic plane, and Y completes the right-handed
    set. The SEL coordinate system used here is a Cartesian representation
    that places the Z-axis along the rotation axis of the moon, positive
    in the direction of angular momentum. The X-axis lies in the lunar
    equatorial plane at 0 degrees longitude, and Y completes the
    right-handed set.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    There are no software provided with this data archive.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Review
  ======
    Magnetometer data quality was reviewed by D.L. Mitchell (UC-Berkeley),
    M.H. Acuna (NASA-GSFC), and L.L. Hood (LPL-Univ. Arizona). Further
    review was conducted by R.J. MacDowall (NASA-GSFC), E. Guandique
    (NASA-GSFC-Emergent), M. Kaelberer (NASA-GSFC-Emergent), and
    M.H. Acuna (NASA-GSFC).
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    The magnetometer data should be used in conjunction with spacecraft
    ephemeris data so that perturbations to the ambient magnetic field
    vector due to crustal sources can be localized in selenographic
    coordinates. It is also important to evaluate the plasma environment
    using electron reflectometer data, since the Moon can be in the solar
    wind, in the Earth&apos;s magnetosheath, in a geomagnetic tail lobe, or in
    the geotail current sheet. The plasma environment can strongly
    influence the usefulness of the data for probing lunar crustal
    magnetic fields. By far, the best (steadiest) data are obtained in the
    geomagnetic tail lobes.
 
 
  Data Quality
  ============
    Magnetometer data are of excellent quality. Systematic errors in the
    magnetic field component orthogonal to the spacecraft spin vector have
    been reduced to ~0.1 nT by time-variable offset corrections (see
    above). Systematic errors in the magnetic field component parallel to
    the spin axis can be as large as ~0.5 nT.  The B_RMS value provides an
    indication of the field variability during the 5-sec window.  A single,
    large value for the B_RMS would likely indicate that bad-telemetry or
    some similar problem had caused large variability during a single
    averaging window.
 
 
  Data Coverage
  =============
    Magnetic field data are obtained continuously; however, telemetry gaps
    do occur. A table of gaps in the raw merged telemetry data OUTAGES.TAB)
    is available in the Level 0 Lunar Prospector archive, but is not part
    of the present Level 1 archive. Other gaps may exist due to data
    contamination or processing limitations.  In particular, we list in
    Appendix A, times when we have explicitly removed data from the dataset
    for reasons such as corrupted sun pulse data preventing the despinning
    of the magnetic field data.   There are also a number of data gaps that
    result because the MAG/ER instruments were telemetering burst mode
    data; these intervals are listed in Appendix B.
 
 
    APPENDIX A - Time intervals for which Magnetic field data were deleted
    from this archive
 
    Year    Month   Day     Start decday    Stop decday
    1998      4      8       98.407899       98.412240
    1998      5      1      121.704774      121.733883
    1998      5     15      135.739902      135.743721
    1998      5     16      136.570399      136.586314
    1998      8     15      227.220689      227.232726
    1998      8     17      229.684809      229.712471
    1998     12      3      337.314265      337.314612
    1999      1     29       29.313513       29.338455
    1999      2     25       56.501591       56.521962
    1999      3      3       62.877170       62.954948
    1999      3     24       83.758767       83.782089
    1999      4     16      106.511603      106.515480
    1999      4     17      107.210503      107.211429
    1999      5      1      121.045168      121.080874
    1999      5     12      132.137703      132.149334
 
 
    APPENDIX B - Approximate times of data gaps due to MAG/ER burst mode
    telemetry
 
    Year  Month  Day  Day of year: time of day
    1998   12    03   day 337: 3 intervals from 5:20-10:15
    1999   03    03   day  62: 21:00-24:00
    1999   03    04   day  63:  0:00- 0:35
    1999   03    18   day  77: 3 intervals from 11:30-24:00
    1999   03    19   day  78: 4 intervals from  0:00-24:00
    1999   03    20   day  79: 4 intervals from  0:00-24:00
    1999   03    21   day  80: 4 intervals from  0:00-13:30
    1999   04    14   day 104: 22:30-24:00
    1999   04    15   day 105: 4 intervals from  0:00-24:00
    1999   04    16   day 106: 5 intervals from  0:00-24:00
    1999   04    17   day 107: 5 intervals from  0:00-24:00
    1999   06    08   day 159: 2 intervals from 15:20-24:00
    1999   06    09   day 160: 4 intervals from  0:00-24:00
    1999   06    10   day 161: 5 intervals from  0:00-24:00
    1999   06    11   day 162: 2 intervals from  0:00-17:30
    1999   07    05   day 186: 2 intervals from 16:00-24:00
    1999   07    06   day 187: 4 intervals from  0:00-24:00
    1999   07    07   day 188: 5 intervals from  0:00-24:00
    1999   07    08   day 189: 4 intervals from  0:00-18:00
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

