<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dawn-a-rss-1-vegr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DAWN VESTA RAW GRAVITY SCIENCE V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.dawn_mission_to_vesta_and_ceres::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.4_vesta::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dawn-a-rss-1-vegr-v1.0__browserp_dawn-a-rss-1-vegr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Konopliv, A.S., S.W. Asmar, R.S. Park, B.G. Bills, F. Centinello, A.B.
                   Chamberlin, A. Ermakov, R.W. Gaskell, N. Rambaux, C.A. Raymond, C.T. Russell,
                   D.E. Smith, P. Tricarico, and M.T. Zuber, The Vesta gravity field, spin pole
                   and rotation period, landmark positions, and ephemeris from the Dawn tracking
                   and optical data, Icarus 240, 103-117, doi:10.1016/j.icarus.2013.09.005, 2014.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KONOPLIVETAL2014B</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DAWN-A-RSS-1-VEGR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DAWN VESTA RAW GRAVITY SCIENCE V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2011-07-10</start_time>
        <stop_time>2012-09-05</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DUSTIN R. BUCCINO</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Buccino, D.R., Konopliv, A.S., Park, R.S., Asmar, S.W., DAWN
            VESTA RAW GRAVITY SCIENCE 1 V1.0 Data Set,
            DAWN-A-RSS-1-VEGR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2014.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw Vesta gravity science data and ancillary files from the Dawn
            mission to Vesta.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains archival raw, partially processed, and
            ancillary/supporting gravity science data acquired during the
            Dawn mission while the spacecraft was in orbit around the
            asteroid Vesta. The radio observations were carried out using the
            Dawn spacecraft and Earth-based receiving stations of the NASA
            Deep Space Network (DSN). The data set was designed primarily to
            support generation of high-resolution gravity field models for
            Vesta. Of most interest are likely to be the Orbit Data Files in
            the ODF directory, which provided the raw input to gravity
            investigations, as well as the ionospheric and tropospheric media
            calibration files in the ION and TRO directories, respectively.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Dawn Mission to Vesta and Ceres (DAWN) Gravity Science (GR) Raw
      Data Archive (RDA) is the set of raw and partially processed
      radio science data collected during the Dawn mission to Vesta.
 
      The earliest data in this data set were collected
      on 2011-07-10.
 
      The closed-loop system used a phase-lock loop in the ground receiver
      to track the downlink signal, reporting both amplitude and frequency at
      rates typically of 1-10 times per second. Closed-loop data are efficient
      for characterizing slowly changing signals and are the input to
      operational navigation and orbit-determination processes.
 
      The data set includes one type of primary data, the ODF. TNFs (Tracking
      and Navigation Service Data Files) are the output of the closed-loop
      receiver. Orbit Data Files (ODFs) are compressed versions of TNFs. ODFs
      are specifically targeted to spacecraft navigators and scientists
      interested in gravity fields.
 
      Typical users of these data might analyze range and Doppler
      measurements in ODFs to reconstruct the spacecraft trajectory.
      Relevant questions would include the measurement uncertainties
      in range and Doppler at different DSN antennas; the uncertainties
      could set constraints on any model of Vesta&apos;s gravity field developed
      later, for example.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      The ODF is a minimally processed output of the closed-loop receiver.
      It contains the most important information (range, Doppler and frequency
      ramps) needed by spacecraft investigators, and investigators interested
      in determining gravity fields. Each ODF is accompanied by a full
      PDS label which describes both the content and format of the
      associated file. ODF data fields include:
 
           Narrowband spacecraft VLBI, Doppler mode (cycles)
           Narrowband spacecraft VLBI, phase mode (cycles)
           Narrowband quasar VLBI, Doppler mode (cycles)
           Narrowband quasar VLBI, phase mode (cycles)
           Wideband spacecraft VLBI (nanoseconds)
           Wideband quasar VLBI (nanoseconds)
           One-way Doppler (Hertz)
           Two-way Doppler (Hertz)
           Three-way Doppler (Hertz)
           One-way total count phase (cycles)
           Two-way total count phase (cycles)
           Three-way total count phase (cycles)
           PRA planetary operational discrete spectrum range (range
                units)
           SRA planetary operational discrete spectrum range (range
                units)
           RE(GSTDN) range (nanoseconds)
           Azimuth angle (degrees)
           Elevation angle (degrees)
           Hour angle (degrees)
           Declination angle (degrees)
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      ODFs are abstracted from subsets of TNF data, the uncompressed output
      of the closed-loop receiver at the Deep Space Network.  A full PDS label
      accompanies each ODF file and gives a bit level description of
      the content and format.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      The data set contains primary data and secondary data.  Primary
      data are those files which would normally be used to derive science
      products and investigation results.  Secondary data are needed
      for the processing or interpretation of primary data but are
      not usually considered to have science value of their own.
      For gravity science, there is one type of primary data.
      Listings of primary and secondary files can be found in INDEX/INDEX.TAB
      for the data set (as of the most recent delivery).
 
      ODFs are stored in the ODF directory. ODFs contain the output of the
      closed-loop tracking system of the Deep Space Network. File names are
      of the form DAWNVEGRyyyy_ddd_hhmmXuuwVn.odf where &apos;DAWNVEGR&apos; identifies
      the mission and the data set; &apos;yyyy&apos; is the four-digit year, &apos;ddd&apos;
      is the three-digit day-of-year, &apos;hh&apos; is the two-digit hour,
      and &apos;mm&apos; is the two-digit minute at the beginning of the file;
      &apos;X&apos; indicates an X-Band uplink (&apos;N&apos; denotes no uplink);
      &apos;uu&apos; indicates the uplink station (set to &apos;NN&apos; for no uplink or
      &apos;MM&apos; for two or more uplinking stations during the time interval
      covered), &apos;w&apos; indicates the downlink mode (&apos;1&apos;, &apos;2&apos;, &apos;3&apos;, or &apos;M&apos;
      for 1-way, 2-way, 3-way, or &apos;multiple&apos;, respectively), and &apos;Vn&apos;
      indicates the version number of the file.  Dates and times in the
      file name are UTC. The ODF label has file name
      DAWNVEGRyyyy_ddd_hhmmXuuwVn.lbl. The typical ODF contains about
      100 Kbytes.
 
      A sample ASCII dump of an ODF file is available in the DOCUMENTS
      directory.
 
 
    Secondary Data
    ==============
      An extensive set of ancillary files is needed for proper analysis
      and interpretation of the data.  In the paragraphs below
      &apos;yyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd&apos; gives the start and end dates of the data in
      the file.  All dates in the file names unless otherwise specified are
      UTC dates. All ASCII files have records delimited by an ASCII
      carriage-return (ASCII 13) line-feed (ASCII 10) pair.  In some cases
      (especially for NAIF files) the &lt;CR&gt;&lt;LF&gt; may need to be converted to
      either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt; before the file is used on the local machine.
 
      Antenna Phase Center File (APC Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Antenna Phase Center files were produced by the JPL Dawn Gravity
        Science team for release. The Dawn spacecraft utilizes four antennas
        during operations (1 high gain antenna and 3 low gain antennas). The
        Antenna Phase Center files contain the start times and stop times when
        any of the low gain antennas were being used. During times not
        specified in these files, the high gain antenna is being used. These
        are ASCII format with a detached PDS label describing the format of
        the data. File names have the form DAWNVEGR_yyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.APC.
        The accompanying PDS label describes the content and structure of the
        file.
 
      Ionosphere Calibration Files (ION Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Ionosphere Calibration files are ASCII files produced by the Tracking
        System Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL. They provide
        historical and predicted Earth ionospheric conditions. File
        names have the form DAWNVEGR_yyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.ION. Each ION
        file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        DAWNVEGR_yyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.LBL. Typical file size is 24 KB.
 
      Spacecraft Mass History Files (SCM Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Spacecraft Mass History files were produced by the Dawn Spacecraft
        Team. They contain the estimates of the spacecraft mass, center of
        mass, and propellant usage. These are ASCII files of variable length
        records. File names have the form DAWNVEGR_yyyy_ddd.SCM, where
        yyyy_ddd is the applicable start date of the file. Files are
        accompanied by a PDS label describing the format of the data. Typical
        file size is 8 KB. The accompanying PDS label describes the content
        and structure of the file.
 
      Small Forces File (SFF Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Small Forces Files were created from the Dawn spacecraft
        engineering telemetry stream. These are ASCII files of
        variable length records.  File names have the form
        DAWNVEGR_yyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.SFF.  Each SFF file is accompanied by a
        PDS minimal label with file name DAWNVEGR_yyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.LBL.
        Typical file sizes are 2.5 MB. File content and
        structure is defined by DAWN_SFF_SIS in the DOCUMENT
        directory.
 
      Troposphere Calibration Files (TRO Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Troposphere Calibration files are ASCII files produced by the Tracking
        System Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL. They provide
        historical and predicted Earth tropospheric conditions. File
        names have the form DAWNVEGR_yyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.TRO. Each TRO
        file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        DAWNVEGR_yyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.LBL. Typical file size is 150 KB.
 
      DSN Weather Files (WEA Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        DSN Weather files were produced by the Tracking System
        Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL. Files give weather
        calibration information for DSN complexes. These are ASCII
        files of variable length records.  File names have the form
        DAWNVEGR_yyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd_ss.WEA, where &apos;ss&apos; is the DSN complex
        where weather data were acquired. WEA files are typically
        released weekly and contain all weather data for the complex
        since 1 January. The files retained in the archive cover 365 days
        in 2011 and 366 days in 2012. Each WEA file is accompanied by a PDS
        minimal label with file name DAWNVEGR_yyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd_ss.LBL.
        The files grow at the rate of approximately 90 KB  per month.
 
 
    Relevant Data Archived At Other Sites
    =====================================
    The Navigation and Ancillary Information Facility (NAIF) is the
    navigation node of the PDS. NAIF provides the archives for spacecraft
    navigation, attitude, events, clock conversion, and planetary
    ephemerides for most NASA missions. Additionally, NAIF provides the
    SPICE toolkit, containing useful algorithms to utilize and manipulate
    data NAIF provide.
 
    Relevant to gravity science are the following types:
     * CK: Spacecraft and solar array attitude orientation files
     * EK: Spacecraft events kernel
     * FK: Reference frame specification
     * SCLK: Conversion between spacecraft time and ephemeris time
     * SPK: Spacecraft and Planetary ephemeris data
 
    The NAIF PDS archive for Dawn is located at:
    naif.jpl.nasa.gov/pub/naif/pds/data/dawn-m_a-spice-6-v1.0/
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      For the APC and SCM files, unless otherwise specified, the coordinate
      system is the spacecraft-fixed coordinate frame as described in the
      Dawn instrument host catalog file.
 
      Other data types are not dependent on definition of a
      coordinate system.
 
    Software
    ========
      Software for parsing, reducing, and analyzing data such as
      these has been developed at several institutions.
      Because such software must usually operate at the bit-level and
      is written for a narrow range of platforms, it is not suitable
      for general distribution.  No software is included with this
      archival data set.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      These data have been delivered to the PDS Small Bodies Node
      electronically.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this archival data set have been collected to support
      radio science investigations, including derivation of the
      gravity field of Vesta.  These are similar to data collected
      using other spacecraft at different targets and are believed
      to be generally of good quality.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      The ODFs in this archive contain data from all nominal Dawn
      passes suitable for gravity science. They are primarily for
      the gravity investigation of Vesta.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The limitations in this data set follow from the quality of
      the execution, which is described above under Data Coverage
      and Quality.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

