<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.msl-m-rems-2-edr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MSL MARS ROVER ENVIRONMENTAL MONITORING STATION 2 EDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_science_laboratory::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.msl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rems.msl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.msl-m-rems-2-edr-v1.0__browserp_msl-m-rems-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.msl-m-rems-2-edr-v1.0__dvo_atmos_msl-m-rems-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.msl-m-rems-2-edr-v1.0__pds.geo.msl.analysts_notebook::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Gomez-Elvira J, Armiens C, Castaner L, Dominguez M, Genzer M, Gomez F, Haberle
                   R, Harri A-, Jimenez V, Kahanpaa H, Kowalski L, Lepinette A, Martin J,
                   Martinez-Frias J, McEwan I, Mora L, Moreno J, Navarro S, de Pablo MA, Peinado
                   V, Pena A, Polkko J, Ramos M, Renno NO, Ricart J, Richardson M,
                   Rodriguez-Manfredi J, Romeral J, Sebastian E, Serrano J, de la Torre Juarez M,
                   Torres J, Torrero F, Urqui R, Vazquez L, Velasco T, Verdasca J, Zorzano M-,
                   Martin-Torres J. REMS: The environmental sensor suite for the mars science
                   laboratory rover. Space Science Reviews 2012:1-58, 2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GOMEZELVIRAETAL2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MSL-M-REMS-2-EDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MSL MARS ROVER ENVIRONMENTAL MONITORING STATION 2 EDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2015-07-31</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2012-08-07T04:01:16.534Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-03-27T02:38:56.480Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JOSE A RODRIGUEZ-MANFREDI</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Gomez-Elvira, J., Mars Science Laboratory Rover Environmental
            Monitoring Station EDR Data V1.0, MSL-M-REMS-2-EDR-V1.0, NASA
            Planetary Data System, 2013.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            MSL Rover Environmental Monitoring Station Experiment Data Record
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Raw, unprocessed scientific and housekeeping engineering data
            taken from the Rover Environmental Monitoring Station (REMS)
            aboard the Mars Science Laboratory.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The REMS instrument is a meteorological package designed to
    provide measurements of air and ground temperatures, wind speed
    and direction, pressure, humidity and ultraviolet radiation.
 
    This data set contains the raw unprocessed data stored in the REMS
    internal memory, as received from telemetry and formatted
    according to the REMS EDR SIS. It consists of a collection of
    tables that include the sensors readings as well as engineering
    data and instrument configurations parameters.
 
    The information included in this data set needs to be combined
    using calibration and other ancillary information to get the
    physical magnitudes. The required ancillary information can be
    found in the RDR archive volumes.
 
    Each data product in this data set contains one sol of activity
    time, in a time ordered fashion and taken at maximum resolution of
    one second.
 
    This data set should be useful for anyone interested in knowing
    the actual sensors electrical readings and status before any
    processing is applied. The actual environmental magnitudes can be
    found in the REMS RDRs.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    Raw data consists of measurements from all REMS sensors which have
    been digitized from electrical data, such as voltages and
    resistances, to digital numbers or counts using a resolution of 12
    bits. Engineering data and instrument configuration parameters are
    also included because some of them are required for data
    processing, although their primary function is monitoring and
    health assessment.
 
    Data as stored in the REMS internal memory is a time ordered mixed
    sequence of entries of the following data types:
 
    Sensor Acquisition
    Engineering
    Humidity Sensor Regeneration Acquisition
    Humidity Sensor Regeneration Report
    Humidity Sensor Defrost Acquisition
    Humidity Sensor Defrost Report
    Ground Temperature Sensor Calibration
    Reset
    Sleep
    Event Entry
    Ground Temperature Sensor Gain Management
    Error
 
    Sensors data are included in the Sensor Acquisition
    entries. Engineering entries contains some of their configuration
    modes. Additional instrument configuration parameters are stored
    in a separated area called the System Parameters. Detailed
    specification of the data contained in each type and in the System
    Parameters can be found in the REMS EDR SIS.
 
    Sampling is taken at 1Hz maximum, for a baseline operation of 5
    minutes every hour. Additional measurements can be taken on an
    on-demand basis beyond those hourly observations. These additional
    measurements can also be triggered automatically if event mode is
    active, in which case the REMS computer will decide whether to
    continue operating after the 5 minutes session by comparing the
    measurements taken and the expected trend. The objective is to
    capture any ongoing transitory atmospheric event.
 
    During the first 72 sols, for each 5 minutes block, the wind
    sensor is set off for the first minute and the last 5 seconds,
    because it was believed it was causing noise to the rest of the
    sensors. After sol 73, the wind sensor is always on each time REMS
    is taking measurements.
 
    From sol 793 onwards, a new measurement strategy for Humidity
    Sensor was introduced. It is called HS HRIM (Humidity Sensor High
    Resolution Interval Mode) and is only used on selected one-hour
    long observations. This new strategy intends to minimize heating
    of the Humidity Sensor, and consists of alternately switching on
    and off the sensor at periodic intervals. At the same time, Boom 2
    is switched off, which means that there are no Wind Sensor and Air
    Temperature Sensor measurements.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The REMS EDR data products will be generated by the MIPL
    (Multimission Image Processing Laboratory) at JPL, under the OPGS,
    using the telemetry processing software called MSLEdrGen. This
    software will convert the binary data received from telemetry to
    ASCII and will generate a separate table for each of the data
    types mentioned above. This means that there will be a table for
    Sensor Acquisition entries, another for Engineering entries, and
    so on. Entries will be kept in time order.
 
    System Parameters tables will be generated from data provided by
    the REMS team. In nominal operation mode, they don&apos;t need to be
    downloaded from the instrument, since they are set from earth by
    means of Spacecraft Commands and therefore their values are
    known. Only on special situations data may be obtained directly
    from the instrument.
 
    Meta-data acquired from the telemetry data headers will be used to
    populate the PDS labels. If telemetry packets are missing during
    the initial downlink from the rover memory, partial data sets will
    be created. The data will be reprocessed after all data are
    received and a new version of the EDR (with a new version number)
    will be created. With the exception of NAIF provided ancillary
    data, all meta data stored in the label is acquired from the
    telemetry data stream.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    REMS EDRs included in this data set are a series of ASCII tables
    converted from the instrument&apos;s internal memory and accompanied
    with detached PDS labels. This makes it easy to load them in a
    spreadsheet program or in a database.
 
    There is a table for each of the data types entries stored in the
    REMS memory. As for the System Parameters, instead of having one
    big table containing all of them, they are broken down into
    several tables for easier usage.
 
    The tables for their corresponding REMS data types are:
 
    ACQ                         Sensor acquisition
    ENG                         Engineering
    ERROR                       Error
    EVENT                       Event Entry
    GTS_CAL                     GT sensor calibration
    GTS_GAIN                    GT sensor gain management
    HS_DEF_ACQ                  Humidity sensor defrost acquisition
    HS_DEF_REPORT               Humidity sensor defrost report
    HS_REG_ACQ                  Humidity sensor regen acq
    HS_REG_REPORT               Humidity sensor regen report
    RESET                       Reset
    SLEEP                       Sleep
 
    The System Parameters tables are:
 
    SP_ASICS                    ASIC configuration
    SP_EVENTS                   Event mode configuration
    SP_GTS                      Ground temperature sensor configuration
    SP_HS_DEF_REG               Humidity Sensor defrost configuration
    SP_HS_PS                    Humidity and Pressure sensors configuration
    SP_MIS                      Miscellaneous configuration
    SP_WS                       Wind sensor configuration
 
    Each table contains one sol of activity time and data is time
    ordered, with a timestamp reflecting the beginning of each each
    data acquisition. System Parameters are stored for each of the
    acquisition sessions, since their status is necessary to process
    acquisition data.
 
    One data product is created for each table, with the exception of
    Humidity Sensor regeneration acquisition and report one side,
    which are on the same data product, and Humidity Sensor Defrost
    Acquistion and Report on the other side, which are also on the
    same data product.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    Ancillary data required to process EDRs and subsequent RDRs to get
    environmental magnitudes are:
 
    Laboratory calibration data
    Solar azimuth an elevation
    Rover azimuth, elevation, altitude, pitch, yaw and roll
    Rover speed
    Masthead azimuth and elevation
    Temperature closest to power supply
    Deck temperature
    Front-right side temperature
    UV sensor dust attenuation
 
    Although some of these data can be obtained from external sources,
    all of them are included in the RDR archive volumes, either as
    RDRs or as separate files.
 
  Software
  ========
    No software is provided in this data set. The EDR tables are simple
    ASCII files that can be displayed on UNIX, Macintosh, and PC
    platforms with common software.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The data presented in the REMS EDR is intended to be the least
    processed, most primitive data set released for REMS. Data
    presented here are an accurate representation of REMS data as
    received from the rover.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    Data reported are the minimally processed data received from the
    orbiter during nominal REMS operations. All data received is
    reformatted into one of the EDR data types. Data are by definition
    of good quality, as damaged telemetry packets are sequestered upon
    receipt from the spacecraft. We do not expect to receive many (if
    any) damaged data packets.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    The major limitation of this data set is that this is level 0,
    minimally processed data. The data are received from the
    spacecraft telemetry and ingested into a database. If gaps exist
    in the telemetry, data are lost.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

