<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lro-l-mrflro-5-cdr-mosaic-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LRO MOON MINI-RF 5 POLAR MOSAIC CALIBRATED DATA REC V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mrflro.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-mrflro-5-cdr-mosaic-v1.0__browserp_lro-l-mrflro-5-cdr-mosaic-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-mrflro-5-cdr-mosaic-v1.0__dvo_geo_lro-l-mrflro-5-cdr-mosaic-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-mrflro-5-cdr-mosaic-v1.0__pds.geo.lro.orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Nozette, S., P. Spudis, B. Bussey, K. Raney, H. Winters, C.L. Lichtenberg, W.
                   Marinelli, J. Crusan, and M. Gates, The LRO Miniature Radio Frequency (Mini-RF)
                   technology demonstration, Space Sci. Rev., submitted, 2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NOZETTEETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LRO-L-MRFLRO-5-CDR-MOSAIC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LRO MOON MINI-RF 5 POLAR MOSAIC CALIBRATED DATA REC V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2009-07-19T12:27:42.7853Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2011-01-11T01:32:11.7200Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>MINI-RF POC</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            LRO Mini-RF Calibrated Level 3 Data Set V1.0,
            LRO-L-MRFLRO-5-CDR-MOSAIC-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2008.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Calibrated Level 3 data product and ancillary files from the LRO
            Mini-RF lunar mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains lunar polar mosaics composed of calibrated
            data acquired from the Mini-RF instrument during the LRO mission.
            The mosaics are made from data collected during multiple orbits.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Level 3 Burst mode data products are Derived Data Records (DDRs)
      generated from multiple Level 1 products.  Four Level 3 mosaics are
      produced of each lunar pole (i.e., regions above 70 deg. latitude)
      Unlike the lower-level products, these are composed of data sets
      collected during multiple acquisitions. Please see the Mini-RF data
      product SIS document (MRFLRO_DP_SIS) in the DOCUMENT directory of this
      archive for additional information on the data files and their format.
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      See individual SIS documents, which are located in the
      DOCUMENT directory, for detailed descriptions of each file
      contained in this data archive.
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The mosaics are produced manually by ingesting the Level 1 stokes (S1)
      parameter products and the Level 1 circular polarization ratio (CPR)
      products into the ISIS software provided by the Astrogeology branch
      of the USGS. A set of 32 pixels per degree (PPD) and 256 PPD S1 and
      CPR mosaics are provided for each of the poles resulting in a total
      of 8 image products. Each image product is accompanied by a detached
      full PDS label and a JPEG browse image.
 
    Data
    ====
      These data are stored in the DATA/SAR/MOSAICS directory on
      archival volumes. File names are described in MRFLRO_DP_SIS.PDF.
 
      Every file in the directory has PDS label. Except for files
      in the root, the CATALOG and EXTRAS directories, the label is a
      separate file in the same directory with the same name but a LBL
      extension.
 
      Reduced-size browse images of each mosaic are provided in the
      EXTRAS/QUIKVIEW/MOSAICS/ directory within the archive.
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      The mosaics are produced from Level 1 products which are oriented in
      reference to the Moon Principle Axis (PA) coordinate system, as
      realized using NASA&apos;s SPICE products (Frames Kernel).
 
    Software
    ========
      No software is included with this archival data set.
 
    Media/Format
    ============
 
      These products are delivered on a hard-drive or by ftp and
      not on a specific formatted medium.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this data are collected from orbits around the Moon.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was reviewed by the LRO Mini-RF
      Team prior to submission to the Planetary Data System (PDS).
 
      Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data
      set, key elements of the archive were distributed for
      preliminary review.  These included electronic versions of
      example PDS labels, CATALOG files, and Software Interface
      Specifications.  These materials were distributed to PDS
      personnel, the experiment investigator, and others,
      as appropriate.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
    Data reported are the minimally processed data received from the
    spacecraft during five mission phases: Launch, Cruise,
    Lunar_Orbit_Acquisition, Commissioning, and Exploration_Mission.
    These mission phases are defined as:
 
    Start time               End time
    Phase Name               Date (DOY)               Date (DOY)
    -----------------        ----------------         ----------------
    LAUNCH                   18 Jun 2009 (169)        18 Jun 2009 (169)
    CRUISE                   18 Jun 2009 (169)        23 Jun 2009 (174)
    LUNAR ORBIT ACQUISITION  23 Jun 2009 (174)        23 Jun 2009 (174)
    COMMISSIONING            23 Jun 2009 (174)        14 Sep 2009 (257)
    NOMINAL MISSION          15 Sep 2009 (258)        14 Sep 2010 (257)
    SCIENCE MISSION          15 Sep 2010 (258)        14 Sep 2012 (258)
 
    No Mini-RF data were collected during Launch, Cruise, or
    Lunar_Orbit_Acquisition phases. The Mini-RF collected data during each of
    the other two mission phases. During these planned operational periods,
    the Mini-RF functioned nominally and the data quality was good.
 
    A S-Band receive calibration test was conducted on 20 August, 2009.
    S-Band transmit calibration tests were conducted on 22-23 August, 2009.
    These calibrations permit the characterization of both transmit
    polarization purity as well as determining how precisely polarization can
    be measured by the instrument.
 
    Communications demonstration.  Mini-RF experiments to demonstrate
    half-duplex communications were conducted on 16 August and
    20 August, 2009.
 
    The Mini-RF began collecting data over the lunar south polar region
    13 July 2009 to support LCROSS targeting by characterizing the surfaces
    of permanently shadowed regions.  This data collection phase continued
    until the LCROSS impact on 9 October. 2009.
 
    From Oct 14 through Dec. 17, Mini-RF was largely restricted to collecting
    data over non-polar sites that lie equatorward of 63 degrees latitude
    North and South.
 
    Since 26 December 2010, the Mini-RF instrument has not transmitted the RF
    energy required to create radar images of the lunar surface. The Mini-RF
    team looked at the initial 13 collects attempted from that date forward
    and noted that in all but one collect the data appeared bad, looking like
    noise. The team continued to attempt data collections at a reduced rate
    (about 1 collect per day) through January 23, 2011. Products included in
    this data set made from data collected after 26 December 2010 do not
    contain scientifically usefull data.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
    This data set is produced multiple strips of calibrated data. The source
    data strips are received from the spacecraft telemetry, ingested into the
    LRO Missions Operations Center (MOC) and then transferred to the APL
    Payload Operations Center (POC).
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

