<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.msl-m-chemcam-libs-4-5-rdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MSL MARS CHEMCAM LIBS SPECTRA 4/5 RDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_science_laboratory::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.msl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:chemcam_libs.msl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.msl-m-chemcam-libs-4-5-rdr-v1.0__browserp_msl-m-chemcam-libs-4-5-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.msl-m-chemcam-libs-4-5-rdr-v1.0__dvo_geo_msl-m-chemcam-libs-4-5-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.msl-m-chemcam-libs-4-5-rdr-v1.0__pds.geo.msl.analysts_notebook::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Maurice, S., R.C. Wiens, et al., The ChemCam instrument suite on the Mars
                   Science Laboratory (MSL) Rover: Science objectives and mast unit description,
                   Space Sci. Rev. doi:10.1007/s11214-012-9912-2, 2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MAURICEETAL2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Wiens, R.C., S. Maurice, et al., The ChemCam instrument suite on the Mars
                   Science Laboratory (MSL) Rover: Body unit and combined system tests, Space Sci.
                   Rev. doi:10.1007/s11214-012-9902-4, 2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.WIENSETAL2012A</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MSL-M-CHEMCAM-LIBS-4/5-RDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MSL MARS CHEMCAM LIBS SPECTRA 4/5 RDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2013-12-13</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2012-08-06T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>ROGER WIENS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Wiens, R., MSL ChemCam Laser Induced Breakdown Spectrometer
            derived data, MSL-M-CHEMCAM-LIBS-5-RDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2013.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The MSL ChemCam LIBS RDR data set contains calibrated spectra and
            higher level products derived from raw data collected by the
            ChemCam Laser Induced Breakdown Spectrometer on the Mars Science
            Laboratory rover.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The MSL ChemCam LIBS RDR data set contains calibrated spectra and
            higher level products derived from raw data collected by the
            ChemCam Laser Induced Breakdown Spectrometer on the Mars Science
            Laboratory rover. Standard derived products include summed
            calibrated spectra (RDR), CCS (Intermediate Clean Calibrated
            Spectra), and MOC (Multivariate Prediciton of Oxide Composition)
            tables. Special products, which may be generated as needed and as
            resources permit, are UEC (Univariate Prediction of Elemental
            Composition) tables, UOC (Univariate Prediction of Oxide
            Composition) tables, MEC (Multivariate Prediction of Elemental
            Composition) tables, and RSM (Sammon&apos;s Map) tables.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
      ChemCam LIBS RDR data set contains calibrated spectra and higher level
      products derived from raw data collected by the ChemCam Laser Induced
      Breakdown Spectrometer on the Mars Science Laboratory rover. Standard
      derived products include summed calibrated spectra (RDR),
      CCS (Intermediate Clean Calibrated Spectra) and MOC (Multivariate
      Prediciton of Oxide Composition) tables.
 
      The MOC results are based on the average of the CCS.  Shot to shot
      MOC results can be requested from the chemcam team.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
      The Committee On Data Management and Computation (CODMAC) data
      level numbering system is used to describe the processing level
      of the EDR data product.  ChemCam LIBS data products are considered
      CODMAC Level 4/5(equivalent to NASA level 1B/level 2) products.
 
      ChemCam processed data products are generated by the ChemCam team.
      They consist of an RDR (reduced data record) spectrum produced by
      averaging spectra from all but the first five laser pulses at each
      observation point, subtracting a background, removing high-frequency
      noise, and removing the white-light continuum; a clean calibrated
      spectrum (CCS) produced by correcting for the instrument optical
      response in addition to the RDR processing mentioned above; and mean
      oxide compositions (MOC) for the major elements SiO2, TiO2, Al2O3,
      FeOT, MgO, CaO, Na2O, and K2O determined by using a partial least
      squares (PLS) regression algorithm trained on a LIBS spectral library.
      Data processing details are given in Wiens et al., 2013. In place of
      the PLS2 algorithm described in Wiens et al., 2013, the ChemCam team
      now uses a PLS1 algorithm. Whereas PLS2 regresses against all elements
      simultaneously, PLS1 regresses each element separately. Using PLS1 has
      several advantages due to the fact that elements can be treated
      separately.  The number of components used in determining the
      oxide wt. % abundances can be optimized individually for each element.
      This is helpful, as the major elements manifest themselves very
      differently in the spectra, with some elements like Na and K having
      very few major emission lines and other elements like Fe having
      hundreds of emission lines.  Optimizing the number of components
      separately for each element thus makes sense. Secondly, the list of
      standards used in the training set can be changed for different
      elements. This is important because a few elements, especially among
      minor or trace elements, do not have certified values for all of the
      standards. PLS1 also allows different normalization treatments for the
      different elements. We have found that normalizing each spectrometer
      output separately improves the results in a few cases over normalizing
      to the combined output of all three spectrometers together.
 
      The number of components and normalization (1 = normalization to total
      emission sum; 3 = separate normalization of total emission for each
      spectrometer) is given below, as well as statistics on the
      compositional ranges and distributions for the training set, and the
      root mean square error (RMSE) are given in the table below:
 
                           SiO2 TiO2 Al2O3 FeOT   MgO  CaO Na2O K2O Total
TRAINING SET MIN.           0.2    0     0    0     0  0.1    0   0
TRAINING SET 1ST QUARTILE  40.8 0.27     5  2.7   0.8  2.5  0.3 0.3
TRAINING SET MEDIAN        48.6 0.68  13.1    6   2.2  7.1  2.4 0.8
TRAINING SET 3RD QUARTILE  59.3 1.47  16.1 12.1   6.4 12.8  3.4 1.8
TRAINING SET MAX.          75.4  5.9  38.8 36.2  49.2 54.9  5.9 6.4
NORMALIZATION                 3    1     1    1     1    3    1   3
NUMBER OF COMPONENTS          8   10     4    7     8    8   10   4
RMSEP                       7.1 0.55   3.7    4     3    3  0.7 0.9 10
 
 
 
  Data
  ====
      Each ChemCam LIBS RDR data file is a table. Columns are
      variable length and are delimited with commas. Each row is
      terminated with a carriage return and line feed character.
 
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
       CCS: slight issues with continuum removal. See Wiens et al., 2013.
       MOC:
 
  Review
  ======
      This ChemCam archive has undergone a standard Planetary Data System
      peer review.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

