<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.vg2-u-pls-5-summ-elebr-48sec-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>VG2 URA PLS DERIVED SUMM ELECTRON BROWSE 48SEC V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.comet_sl9-jupiter_collision::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.voyager::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vg2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:pls.vg2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.uranus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vg2-u-pls-5-summ-elebr-48sec-v1.0__browserp_vg2-u-pls-5-summ-elebr-48sec-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Sittler, E.C., Jr., K.W. Ogilvie and R.S. Selesnick,
                   Survey of Electrons in the Uranian magnetosphere: Voyager 2
                   Observations, J. Geophys. Res., 92, 15263-15281, 1987.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SITTLERETAL1987</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>VG2-U-PLS-5-SUMM-ELEBR-48SEC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>VG2 URA PLS DERIVED SUMM ELECTRON BROWSE 48SEC V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1993-02-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1986-01-24T07:06:31.204Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1986-01-24T23:59:19.137Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JOHN D. RICHARDSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            VG2 URA PLS DERIVED SUMM ELECTRON BROWSE 48SEC V1.0
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains the thermal electron density and
            temperature in the PLS energy range (10-5950 eV) from Voyager 2
            at Uranus derived by fitting the low energy electron component
            with a Maxwellian distribution, and the moment density and
            temperature of the hot electrons calculated after the signal from
            the thermal component is subtracted from the electron spectra.
            The moment density and temperature obtained by integrating over
            the entire measured distribution function are also given. This is
            a subset of the data set VG2-U-PLS-5-RDR-ELEFIT-48SEC which
            should be obtained before this data is used, since it contains
            information on the type of fit performed and LECP contamination
            of the data. Spacecraft charging may result in underestimation of
            thermal electron density in some regions. The first six columns
            are the time tag (year, day, hour, min, sec, msec), columns 7 and
            8 are the total moment density and temperature, columns 9 and 10
            are the fit density and temperature of the thermal electron
            component, and 11 and 12 are the moment density and temperature
            of the suprathermal electrons. Each row has the format
            (6I4,6E12.4). Values of 1.E32 indicate that the parameter could
            not be obtained from the data using the standard analysis
            technique. Additional information about this dataset and the
            instrument which produced it can be found elsewhere in this
            catalog. An overview of the data in this data set can be found in
            Sittler et al. (1987) and a complete instrument description can
            be found in bridge (1977).
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      This data set contains the thermal electron density and
      temperature in the PLS energy range (10-5950 eV) from Voyager 2
      at Uranus derived by fitting the low energy electron component
      with a Maxwellian distribution, and the moment density and
      temperature of the hot electrons calculated after the signal
      from the thermal component is subtracted from the electron
      spectra.  The moment density and temperature obtained by
      integrating over the entire measured distribution function are
      also given.  This is a subset of the data set
      VG2-U-PLS-5-RDR-ELEFIT-48SEC which should be obtained before
      this data is used, since it contains information on the type of
      fit performed and LECP contamination of the data.  Spacecraft
      charging may result in underestimation of thermal electron
      density in some regions.  The first six columns are the time
      tag (year, day, hour, min, sec, msec), columns 7 and 8 are the
      total moment density and temperature, columns 9 and 10 are the
      fit density and temperature of the thermal electron component,
      and 11 and 12 are the moment density and temperature of the
      suprathermal electrons.  Each row has the format (6I4,6E12.4).
      Values of 1.E32 indicate that the parameter could not be
      obtained from the data using the standard analysis technique.
      Additional information about this dataset and the instrument
      which produced it can be found elsewhere in this catalog.  An
      overview of the data in this data set can be found in Sittler
      et al.  (1987) and a complete instrument description can be
      found in bridge (1977).
 
 
      Processing Level Id            : 5
      Software Flag                  : Y
      Processing Start Time          : UNK
      Processing Stop Time           : UNK
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;ELECTRON DENSITY&apos;
      -------------------------------------
        A derived parameter equaling the number of electrons per unit
        volume over a specified range of electron energy.  Different
        forms of electron density are derived distinguished by method
        of derivation (Maxwellian fit, method of moments) or by the
        some selection criteria (ie., hot electron and cold electron
        density).  In general, if more than one electron component is
        analyzed, either by moment or fit, a total density will be
        provided which is the sum of the electron densities.  If the
        electron do not have a Maxwellian distribution the actual
        distribution can be represented as the sum of several
        Maxwellians, in which case the density of each Maxwellian is
        given.
 
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Data Set Parameter Name        : ELECTRON DENSITY
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 48.000000
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : 48.000000
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : 48.000000
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : CM-3
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND
 
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;ELECTRON TEMPERATURE&apos;
      -----------------------------------------
        A derived parameter giving an indication of the mean
        energy/electron, assuming the shape of the electron energy
        spectrum to be Maxwellian (i.e.highest entropy shape).  Given
        that the electron energy spectrum is not exactly Maxwellian,
        the electron temperature can be defined integrally (whereby
        the mean energy obtained by integrating under the actual
        electron energy spectrum is set equal to the integral under a
        Maxwellian, where the temperature is a free parameter for
        which to solve), or differentially (whereby the slopes of the
        actually electron energy spectrum at various energies are
        matched to the slopes of a corresponding Maxwellian).  The
        temperature parameter is often qualified with a range of
        applicable energies.  temperatures can be angularly
        anisotropic.  If the electrons do not have a Maxwellian
        distribution the actual distribution can be represented as
        the sum of several Maxwellians, each with a separate
        temperature.
 
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Data Set Parameter Name        : ELECTRON TEMPERATURE
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 48.000000
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : 48.000000
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : 48.000000
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : CM-3
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND
 
 
    Source Instrument Parameters
    ============================
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : ELECTRON DENSITY
      Instrument Parameter Name       : ELECTRON RATE
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : ELECTRON DENSITY
      Instrument Parameter Name       : ELECTRON CURRENT
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : ELECTRON TEMPERATURE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : ELECTRON RATE
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : ELECTRON TEMPERATURE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : ELECTRON CURRENT
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      Processing History
      ------------------
        Source Data Set ID       : N/A
        Software                 : UNK
        Product Data Set ID      : VG2-U-PLS-5-SUMM-ELEBR-48SEC-V1.0
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      This data set provides an estimate of the electron parameters
      in the PLS energy range (10-5950 eV).  The thermal electron
      parameters may be underestimated in some regions due to
      negative spacecraft charging which is not corrected for.
      Electron parameters may also be unreliable between 1736 and
      1854 scet on Jan 24 where electron temperatures are below the
      instrument energy threshold.  Between 1920 and 2150 scet on Jan
      24 the spacecraft had a large (several hundred volt) negative
      potential, so electron parameters in this region should also be
      treated with caution.  The instrument threshold for detecting
      electrons is a density of about 0.001 cm-3.  At times when the
      density is near this value all derived parameters are suspect.
      From 1621 to 1649 on Jan.  24 sunlight created an artificial
      signal so this data should be discarded.  The LECP stepper
      motor is also creates a spurious signal in the PLS detector.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XM-11A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

