<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dif-c-hrii-5-tempel1-surf-temp-maps-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>SURFACE TEMPERATURE MAPS OF COMET 9P/TEMPEL 1 V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_impact::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:hrii.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.9p-tempel_1_1867_g1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dif-c-hrii-5-tempel1-surf-temp-maps-v1.0__browserp_dif-c-hrii-5-tempel1-surf-temp-maps-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Groussin, O., M.F. A&apos;Hearn, J.-Y. Li, P.C. Thomas, J.M. Sunshine, C.M. Lisse,
                   K.J. Meech, T.L. Farnham, L.M. Feaga, and W.A. Delamere, Surface temperature of
                   the nucleus of Comet 9P/Tempel 1, Icarus, 187, 16-25, 2007,
                   doi:10.1016/j.icarus.2006.08.030.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GROUSSINETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., M.F. A&apos;Hearn, M. Baca, A. Delamere, M. Desnoyer, T. Farnham, O.
                   Groussin, D. Hampton, S. Ipatov, J. Li, C. Lisse, N. Mastrodemos, S.
                   McLaughlin, J. Sunshine, P. Thomas, and D. Wellnitz, Deep Impact Instrument
                   Calibration, Rev. Sci. Instrum., 79, 091301, 2008, doi:10.1063/1.2972112.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DIF-C-HRII-5-TEMPEL1-SURF-TEMP-MAPS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>SURFACE TEMPERATURE MAPS OF COMET 9P/TEMPEL 1 V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2006-11-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2005-07-04T05:25:23.325Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2005-07-04T05:40:20.251Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>Stephanie A. McLaughlin</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Groussin, O. and J-Y. Li, SURFACE TEMPERATURE MAPS OF COMET
            9P/TEMPEL 1 V1.0, DIF-C-HRII-5-TEMPEL1-SURF-TEMP-MAPS-V1.0, NASA
            Planetary Data System, 2006.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Surface temperature maps and a plate temperature table of comet
            9P/Tempel 1 derived from spectra acquired by the Deep Impact
            High-Resolution Instrument Infrared Spectrometer on 4 July 2005
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains two-dimensional infrared thermal maps of
            the surface of comet 9P/Tempel 1. The maps were derived from
            three spatially resolved scans of the nucleus acquired by the
            Deep Impact High Resolution Infrared Spectrometer (HR II) about
            19, 12, and 5 minutes before the impact on 4 July 2005. A
            high-resolution, 120 m/pixel, thermal composite map is also
            included. Surface temperatures were derived from 1.0- to
            4.0-micron data and ranged from 272K to 336K +/- 7K. This data
            set also includes the incidence and emission angle maps
            associated with each thermal map and a table of temperatures
            assigned to plates in the Tempel 1 shape model that were
            illuminated and visible near the time of impact.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set contains two-dimensional infrared thermal maps of the
    surface of comet 9P/Tempel 1.  The maps were derived from three
    spatially resolved scans of the nucleus acquired by the Deep Impact
    High Resolution Infrared Spectrometer (HRII) about 19, 12, and 5
    minutes before the impact on 4 July 2005.  A high-resolution,
    120-m/pixel, thermal composite map is also included.  Surface
    temperatures were derived from 1.0- to 4.0-micron data and ranged
    from 272K to 336K +/- 7K.  This data set also includes the incidence
    and emission angle maps (mu0 and mu) associated with each thermal map
    and a table of temperatures assigned to plates in the Tempel 1 shape
    model that were illuminated and visible around the time of collecting
    the thermal data.  For a thorough discussion of the maps, see
    Groussin, et al. 2007 [GROUSSINETAL2007].
 
 
    Observations
    ------------
      The characteristics of the three HRII scans acquired of the nucleus
      and used to derive the three temperature maps were extracted from
      Groussin, et al. 2007 [GROUSSINETAL2007] and provided below.  The
      given values are with respect to the mid-point of a scan.  An impact
      time of 05:44:34.265 UT 4 July 2005, at the flyby spacecraft, was
      used to calculate the time before impact.  During the scans,
      9P/Tempel 1 had a heliocentric distance of 1.5 AU.
 
        Exposure (scan) ID                    : 9000031   9000036   9000039
        Image mode                            : 3         1         2
        Number of frames in scan              : 32        40        84
        Percentage of visible nucleus covered : 90        100       50
        Time at spacecraft (h:m:s UT)         : 05:25:36  05:32:55  05:39:18
        Time before impact (min)              : 19.0      11.7      5.3
        Scan duration (s)                     : 23        113       120
        Slit length* (km)                     : 13        41        15
        Minimum spectral resolution           : 216       216       216
        Target distance (km)                  : 20400     15900     12000
        Spatial resolution (m/pixel)          : 204       159       120
        Phase angle (deg)                     : 62.88     62.89     62.91
 
          *  There is not correlation between the slit length and the
             resolution.  The slit length only refers to the number of
             rows that are read out from the IR focal plane array (FPA);
             the physical length of the slit never changes.  Therefore,
             as the spacecraft moved closer to the target, the spatial
             resolution improved.  The value for slit length changes
             between the scans because the image mode is different
             for each set of frames.  The image mode specifies the
             number of rows readout from the IR FPA in the along-slit
             (spatial) dimension.  For image mode 1 the slit width is
             256 2x2-binned pixels, for mode 2 it is 128 2x2-binned
             pixels, and for mode 3 it is 64 2x2 binned pixels.
             Additionally, the physical width of the slit is fixed at
             10 microradians and cannot be changed.
 
          ** Please note the map associated with exposure ID 9000039
             is truncated because of impact activities by the spacecraft.
 
    Related Data Sets
    -----------------
      The following PDS data sets are related to this one:
 
        DIF-C-HRII-3-4-9P-ENCOUNTER-V2.0        : Calibrated HRII encounter
                                                  data, version 2.0
        DIF-C-HRIV/ITS/MRI-5-TEMPEL1-SHAPE-V1.0 : Tempel 1 shape model
        DI-C-HRII/HRIV/MRI/ITS-6-DOC-SET-V1.0   : Mission documentation
 
      Please note that the temperature maps were derived from version 2.0
      of the calibrated HRII data.  Version 2.0 includes improved geometric
      parameters, dark subtraction, and bad pixel identification.
 
 
  Data
  ====
 
    Individual Thermal Maps and Related Geometry Maps
    -------------------------------------------------
      Three individual thermal maps of the surface of Tempel 1 along
      with the related incidence- and emission-angle maps were generated
      from data for HRII scans 9000031, 9000036, and 9000039.  Please note
      the map for scan 9000039 is truncated because of impact activities
      by the spacecraft.  These two-dimensional maps are presented in the
      FITS image format. The data values in the maps have units of kelvin.
      The data files are listed here:
 
        map_9000031.fit           : Temperature maps derived from the
        map_9000036.fit             scans with exposure IDs of 9000031,
        map_9000039.fit             9000036, and 9000039
 
        map_9000031_mu0.fit       : Registered maps of the values of mu0
        map_9000036_mu0.fit         (cosine of the incidence angle) for
        map_9000039_mu0.fit         each temperature map listed above
 
        map_9000031_mu.fit        : Registered maps of the values of mu
        map_9000036_mu.fit          (cosine of the emission angle) for
        map_9000039_mu.fit          each temperature map listed above
 
      For context, a deconvolved image acquired by the HRI visible CCD
      is included in the documentation for this data set.
 
 
    Composite Thermal Map and Related Geometry Maps
    -----------------------------------------------
      The composite thermal map and its related geometry maps for mu0
      (cosine of the incidence angle) and mu (cosine of the emission
      angle) were generated from the highest-resolution thermal maps
      derived from data for scans 9000036 and 9000039.  The
      two-dimensional maps are presented in the FITS image format.
      The data values in the maps have units of kelvin.
 
        thermal_composite.fit     : Composite thermal map at 120 m/pixel
                                    made from the highest-resolution
                                    thermal maps (map_9000036.fit and
                                    map_9000039.fit)
 
        thermal_composite_mu0.fit : Registered map of values of mu0
                                    (cosine of the incidence angle) for
                                    the composite thermal map
 
        thermal_composite_mu.fit  : Registered map of values of mu
                                    (cosine of the emission angle) for
                                    the composite thermal map
 
 
    Plate Temperature Table
    -----------------------
      The plate_temp.tab file is a fixed-width, ASCII table that provides
      a temperature for each plate of the Tempel 1 shape mode that was
      visible near impact. The first column in the table identifies the
      plate index (0-based) within the archived shape model for Tempel 1.
      The second column provides the corresponding temperature in units
      of Kelvin.
 
      The PDS data set, DIF-C-HRIV/ITS/MRI-5-TEMPEL1-SHAPE-V1.0, includes
      the Tempel 1 shape model used for this analysis.  It is available
      online at the Small Bodies Node.
 
 
    Map Orientation
    ---------------
      When displaying the thermal or geometry maps, a true-sky view can
      be achieved by displaying the image using the standard FITS
      convention where the fastest-varying axis (samples) increase to
      the right in the display window and the slowest-varying axis
      (lines) increases to the top.  This convention is also defined by
      these keywords in the PDS data labels:
 
        SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION = RIGHT
        LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION   = UP
 
      When using this convention to display the maps, the Sun is to the
      right, ecliptic north is toward the right, celestial north is toward
      the upper-right, and celestial east is toward the upper-left.  The
      projected positive spin axis of the nucleus points toward the top.
      This is the orientation used by Groussin, et al. (2007)
      [GROUSSINETAL2007].
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
 
    Thermal Maps
    ------------
      Frames for each scan (9000031, 9000036, and 9000039) were
      selected from version 2.0 of HRII reversibly calibrated data in
      units of radiance (W/(m**2 micron steradian)).  Because scattered
      light is not negligible for the HRII spectrometer, the calibrated
      data were then manually corrected (cleaned) for bad pixels and
      scattered light for this analysis.  The contribution from the coma
      was negligible compared to that of the nucleus and was therefore
      not subtracted.  See Groussin, et al. (2007) [GROUSSINETAL2007]
      for details about the scattered light model and the analysis of
      the coma contribution.   See the Deep Impact Instrument Calibration
      document by Klaasen, et al. (2006) [KLAASENETAL2006] for a
      discussion of the stray light for the HRII instrument and the
      calibration pipeline.
 
      To derive the temperature maps from the spectra of the nucleus, a
      process that combined the scattered light from the Sun with the thermal
      infrared emission of the nucleus was used to fit the data.  The best
      fit was achieved by using a least squares method in the thermal
      infrared range of 3.0 to 4.0 microns.  This method was applied to each
      frame of one scan to derive a temperature map of the nucleus for that
      scan.  Details about the process and the analysis of the maps using
      a thermal model are described by Groussin, et al. (2007)
      [GROUSSINETAL2007]
 
 
    Geometry Maps (mu0 and mu) for the Thermal Maps
    -----------------------------------------------
      The mu0 and mu maps were calculated with the shape model of Tempel
      1 archived in PDS for the time of impact.  The sub-spacecraft
      longitude and latitude are 295 deg and -26 degrees, respectively.
      The sub-solar longitude and latitude are 349 deg and 9.2 degrees,
      respectively.  The thermal data used to construct the thermal maps
      were collected 19, 12, and 5 minutes before the impact, when the
      change in the viewing geometry was less than 2 degrees.  To
      register the geometry maps with thermal maps as precisely as
      possible, the geometry maps were first rendered at a pixel scale of
      16m/pix, and the thermal maps were rescaled to this resolution for
      the purpose of registration.  The geometry maps and thermal maps
      were then registered by shifting and slightly rotating according to
      the limb/terminator and a few large features.  Finally the
      registered geometry maps were scaled down to the original pixel
      scale of their corresponding thermal maps. If a pixel was in
      shadow, its value was set to zero.
 
      The uncertainty of these geometry maps was affected by the
      uncertainty of the shape model and registration error.  Close to
      the limb and terminator, the uncertainty of angles can be large.
      Thus pixels with value less then 0.17 (80 deg angle) should
      probably be discarded for practical purposes.
 
 
    Composite Thermal Map
    ---------------------
      The composite thermal map was constructed from the two
      highest-resolution thermal maps for scans 9000036 and 9000039.
      First, the thermal map for 9000036 at 159 m/pixel was scaled to
      120 m/pixel, the scale of the thermal map for exposure 9000039.
      Then the rescaled map for 9000036 was registered against the
      thermal map for 9000039 by shifting and rotating to align the limb
      and terminator profile and some large surface thermal features.
      Six lines (35-40) of thermal map 9000039 appeared to be bad during
      a visual inspection and were therefore discarded.  Finally the
      upper half of the nucleus in thermal map 9000036 that was covered
      by map 9000039 was replaced by lines from the latter and were
      therefore not used.  The geometry maps (mu0 and mu) for the
      composite thermal map were calculated using the procedure as
      described above for each individual thermal map.
 
 
    Plate Temperature Table
    -----------------------
      As in the plate shape model, the surface of the nucleus of Tempel 1
      was represented by a collection of triangle plates.  From the
      thermal maps, the temperatures of the illuminated and visible
      plates at the time of impact could be calculated.  To do this, the
      composite thermal map with pixel scale 120 m/pixel was used.  A map
      of plate numbers was rendered using the geometry of impact, where
      the value of a pixel represented the index of the plate that was
      projected onto this pixel in the composite thermal map.  The pixel
      scale of the resulting plate map was 16m/pix, a scale that was
      finer than the sizes of most plates (so that every pixel fell into
      one plate).  The composite thermal map was then rescaled to this
      resolution, so that the plate map could be registered to it by
      comparing the limb/terminator profile and a few large features.
      Comparing the composite thermal map with the registered plate map,
      the temperatures of illuminated and visible plates were extracted.
 
      Due to the uncertainty of the plate shape model and the low signal
      close to the limb and terminator of the nucleus in the thermal map,
      the edge of the plate map and thermal map could not be aligned
      everywhere.  Therefore, all plates with their average values of mu0
      or mu smaller than 0.17 (80 degrees) were discarded from this data
      table.  For the plates included, the uncertainties in the
      temperature were dominated by the composite thermal map, which was
      in turn affected by the registration error during composition, as
      well as by the uncertainty of original thermal maps.
 
    This data set overview was provided by O. Groussin and J.-Y. Li.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The overall uncertainty for the reduction processes was estimated to
    be 20 percent.  See Groussin, et al. (2007) [GROUSSINETAL2007].
    This corresponds to an overall uncertainty of 7K for the surface
    temperatures.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    This data set was originally peer-reviewed in November 2006 and
    accepted for the PDS archive pending the resolution of liens which
    were resolved in June 2007.  Because new data products (the mu0 and
    mu files) were added, this data set was peer reviewed again in June
    2008 and was accepted for the PDS archive pending the resolution
    of minor, cosmetic liens which were resolved in late June 2008.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
 
    Known Deficiencies for the IR Calibration
    -----------------------------------------
      There are known deficiencies with the version of the IR calibration
      pipeline that reduced these data.  These are described in the
      HRII calibration limitations document included on the Deep Impact
      documentation data set, DI-C-HRII/HRIV/MRI/ITS-6-DOC-SET-V1.0.
 
 
    HRI Telescope Focus
    -------------------
      Early images of stars using the HRI visible CCD indicated the HRI
      telescope was out of focus.  However, this focus problem minimally
      affected the HRII instrument because the IR spectrometer was over
      sampled by a factor of five when compared to the visible CCD.
      For more details, please see the instrument calibration paper by
      Klaasen, et al. (2006) [KLAASENETAL2006] included on the Deep Impact
      documentation data set, DI-C-HRII/HRIV/MRI/ITS-6-DOC-SET-V1.0.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

