<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-e-v-h-mascs-2-virs-edr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER E/V/H MASCS 2 VIRS UNCALIBRATED DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mascs.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-2-virs-edr-v1.0__browserp_mess-e-v-h-mascs-2-virs-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-2-virs-edr-v1.0__browser_geo_mercury_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-2-virs-edr-v1.0__browser_mess-e-v-h-mascs-2-virs-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-2-virs-edr-v1.0__dvo_geo_mess-e-v-h-mascs-2-virs-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   McClintock, W.E., and M.R. Lankton, The Mercury Atmospheric and Surface
                   Composition Spectrometer for the MESSENGER mission, Space Science Reviews, 131,
                   481-521, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MCCLINTOCK-LANK2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-E/V/H-MASCS-2-VIRS-EDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESSENGER E/V/H MASCS 2 VIRS UNCALIBRATED DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2015-03-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-09-13</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>NOAM IZENBERG</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Izenberg, N., MESSENGER E/V/H MASCS 2 VIRS UNCALIBRATED DATA
            V1.0, MESS-E/V/H-MASCS-2-VIRS-EDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2007.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The MESSENGER MASCS VIRS uncalibrated observations consist of
            science and instrument data collected by the VIRS detector.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== This data set consists of the MESSENGER MASCS
            VIRS uncalibrated observations, also known as EDRs. The MASCS
            VIRS experiment is a fixed concave grating spectrograph with a
            beam splitter that simultaneously disperses the spectrum onto two
            photodiode arrays. There are two VIRS EDR data products, one for
            each array, which result in coverage of the wavelength ranges of
            the visible (VIS) and near infrared (NIR).
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
   Data Set Overview
   =================
     This data set consists of the MESSENGER MASCS VIRS uncalibrated
     observations, also known as EDRs. Each VIRS observation results
     in data from two spectral regions. The spectra cover the
     wavelength ranges of the visible (VIS)(300-1050 nm) and near
     infrared (NIR) (850-1450 nm), with a resolution of 5 nm. There
     are three standard data products: VIS data, NIR data, and
     Housekeeping data. The housekeeping EDR contains instrument
     parameters that may be useful in analyzing the VIRS data.
 
   Instrument Overview
   ===================
     The MASCS instrument consists of a small Cassegrain telescope
     that simultaneously feeds the UVVS and VIRS experiments. MASCS
     VIRS experiment is a fixed concave grating spectrograph with a
     beam splitter that simultaneously disperses the spectrum onto
     two solid-state array detectors: a 512-element silicon
     photodiode array, with a sensitivity to visible wavelengths
     (300-1050 nm), and a 256-element indium-gallium-arsenide
     photodiode array, to measure near infrared wavelengths
     (850-1450 nm). The VIRS detector will help to measure the
     surface reflectance and search for ferrous bearing minerals,
     Fe-Ti bearing phases, and ferrous iron on the surface of
     Mercury.
 
     See the INST.CAT file for more information and
     [MCCLINTOCK&amp;LANK2007] for full details.
 
   Calibration Overview
   ====================
     This data set is NOT calibrated; it only provides the
     uncalibrated detector measurements.
 
   Parameters
   ==========
     The principal parameters when observing with the MASCS VIRS are
     as follows:
 
     * Integration Time: The amount of time that the array detectors
     will integrate photon counts. Unit is 50 milliseconds.
 
     * Integration Count: The amount of integrations that will be
     taken.
 
     * Period: The interval time after which another integration
     will be started. Integrations are started at the top of every
     period. Time between integrations is the period time minus the
     integration time. Unit is 0.05 second.
 
     * Dark Frequency: The frequency at which dark counts will be
     collected during a VIRS observation. For an entered number n,
     dark counts will be collected every nth integration.
 
     * NIR Gain: Sets of the gain of the NIR array detector, to
     either low, high, or N/A when the VIS detector is enabled.
 
     * NIR Lamp On: The NIR flat field lamp is powered on or off.
 
     * VIS Lamp On: The VIS flat field lamp is powered on or off.
 
     * Binning: The number of pixels that were binned together in
     the data.
 
     * Start Pixel: Start pixel of data captured by the detector
     array. For VIS, the value can be from 0-511. For NIR, the value
     can be from 0-255.
 
     * End Pixel: End pixel captured by the detector array. The end
     pixel value must be greater than the start pixel value.
 
   Data
   ====
     There are two VIRS EDR data products, one for each detector
     (VIS, NIR). There is also a MASCS housekeeping EDR data product
     generated by the MASCS instrument, which is the same for both
     the UVVS and VIRS components of the MASCS experiment.
 
     The EDR for either the VIS or NIR detector consists of entries
     for the spacecraft time and orientation, target location,
     values for the observing parameters set for the given
     observation, information about the observation, and is followed
     by the science spectral data. On each detector, the pixel
     number can be mapped to a specific wavelength, allowing a
     resulting spectra to be created. One observation can generate a
     variable number of spectra. All of the data from one commanded
     observation are contained in one EDR.
 
     A separate EDR is created for the VIS and NIR data. Normal
     MASCS operations will acquire data for both VIS and NIR
     detectors simultaneously.
 
     The MASCS Housekeeping EDR provides data about the voltage,
     current, and temperature readings, as well as record and
     software status, hardware settings, instrument status, and
     integration and reporting times. The MASCS Housekeeping EDR
     will contain all housekeeping packets generated in a given day.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
   Confidence Level Overview
   =========================
     The MASCS VIRS EDR data are the least processed data set released
     for the VIRS.  Data presented here are an accurate representation
     of the VIRS data as received from the spacecraft, with minimal
     timing and spatial processing.
 
   Review
   ======
     The VIRS EDR was reviewed internally by the MASCS team prior to
     release to the PDS. PDS also performed an external review of the
     MASCS VIRS EDRs (both VIS and NIR detectors have seperate EDR
     types).
 
   Data Coverage and Quality
   =========================
     Data reported are the minimally processed data received from the
     spacecraft during the eighteen mission phases: Launch,
     Earth Cruise, Earth Flyby, Venus 1 Cruise, Venus 1 Flyby,
     Venus 2 Cruise, Venus 2 Flyby, Mercury 1 Cruise, Mercury 1 Flyby,
     Mercury 2 Cruise, Mercury 2 Flyby, Mercury 3 Cruise,
     Mercury 3 Flyby, Mercury 4 Cruise, Mercury Orbit, Mercury Orbit
     Year 2, Mercury Orbit Year 3, and Mercury Orbit Year 4. These
     mission phases are defined as:
 
                             Start time         End time
     Phase Name              Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)
     -----------------       -----------------  -----------------
     Launch                  03 Aug 2004 (216)  12 Sep 2004 (256)
     Earth Cruise            13 Sep 2004 (257)  18 Jul 2005 (199)
     Earth Flyby             19 Jul 2005 (200)  16 Aug 2005 (228)
     Venus 1 Cruise          17 Aug 2005 (229)  09 Oct 2006 (282)
     Venus 1 Flyby           10 Oct 2006 (283)  07 Nov 2006 (311)
     Venus 2 Cruise          08 Nov 2006 (312)  22 May 2007 (142)
     Venus 2 Flyby           23 May 2007 (143)  20 Jun 2007 (171)
     Mercury 1 Cruise        21 Jun 2007 (172)  30 Dec 2007 (364)
     Mercury 1 Flyby         31 Dec 2007 (365)  28 Jan 2008 (028)
     Mercury 2 Cruise        29 Jan 2008 (029)  21 Sep 2008 (265)
     Mercury 2 Flyby         22 Sep 2008 (266)  20 Oct 2008 (294)
     Mercury 3 Cruise        21 Oct 2008 (295)  15 Sep 2009 (258)
     Mercury 3 Flyby         16 Sep 2009 (259)  14 Oct 2009 (287)
     Mercury 4 Cruise        15 Oct 2009 (288)  03 Mar 2011 (062)
     Mercury Orbit           04 Mar 2011 (063)  17 Mar 2012 (077)
     Mercury Orbit Year 2    18 Mar 2012 (078)  17 Mar 2013 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 3    18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 4    18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)
 
     MASCS VIRS data were collected during all phases except
     Venus 1 Flyby. During these planned operational periods, the VIRS
     functioned nominally and the data quality was good. Additional
     numbered notes added as necessary. This is a high-level
     presentation of EDR validation. Lower level EDR (and CDR)
     details, including, e.g. dark observations, temperature alarms,
     and footprints on/off planet are best obtained through the Data
     Quality Index (DQI) of the VIRS CDR. Specific MASCS operational
     periods were:
 
                         Start time         End time
   Phase Name            Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)         Operations
   --------------------  -----------------  -----------------  -------------
 
   Launch                03 Aug 2004 (216)  12 Sep 2004 (256)  Checkout
   Earth Cruise          13 Sep 2004 (257)  18 Jul 2005 (199)  Starcals (1)
                                                               Cover Open
   Earth Flyby           19 Jul 2005 (200)  16 Aug 2005 (228)  Earth/Moon
   Venus 1 Cruise        17 Aug 2005 (229)  09 Oct 2006 (282)  Starcals
   Venus 1 Flyby         10 Oct 2006 (283)  07 Nov 2006 (311)  n/a
   Venus 2 Cruise        08 Nov 2006 (312)  22 May 2007 (142)  Starcals (2),
                                                               Venus,
                                                               Operation Tests
   Venus 2 Flyby         23 May 2007 (143)  20 Jun 2007 (171)  Venus
   Mercury 1 Cruise      21 Jun 2007 (172)  30 Dec 2007 (364)  Starcals (3),
                                                               Operation Tests
   Mercury 1 Flyby       31 Dec 2007 (365)  28 Jan 2008 (28)   Mercury,
                                                               Lyman Alpha
   Mercury 2 Cruise      29 Jan 2008 (029)  21 Sep 2008 (265)  Starcals,
                                                               Operation Tests
   Mercury 2 Flyby       22 Sep 2008 (266)  20 Oct 2008 (294)  Mercury,
                                                               Lyman Alpha
   Mercury 3 Cruise      21 Oct 2008 (295)  15 Sep 2009 (258)  Starcals (4),
                                                               Venus
   Mercury 3 Flyby       16 Sep 2009 (259)  14 Oct 2009 (287)  Mercury (5),
                                                               Lyman Alpha
   Mercury 4 Cruise      15 Oct 2009 (288)  03 Mar 2011 (062)  Starcals,
                                                               Venus,
                                                               Operation Tests
   Mercury Orbit         04 Mar 2011 (063)  17 Mar 2012 (077)  Mercury (6),
                                                               Starcals (7),
                                                               Venus
   Mercury Orbit Year 2  18 Mar 2012 (078)  17 Mar 2013 (076)  Mercury (8),
                                                               Starcals (9)
   Mercury Orbit Year 3  18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)  Mercury (10),
                                                               Starcals
   Mercury Orbit Year 4  18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)  Mercury (10),
                                                               Comet Encke,
                                                               Comet ISON,
                                                               Starcals
 
   Notes:
     (1)  Starcals before June &apos;05 viewed through cover window.
     (2)  One Starcal missed target due to star tracker error.
     (3)  S/C event during starcal, Instrument turned off during
          Starcal.
     (4)  Pointing error during May &apos;09 Starcal. Star not observed.
     (5)  Flyby anomaly - no Data after Mercury Closest Approach until
          post-flyby Mercury-as-star observations. Safing event cut off
          one Mercury-as-star observation in the middle.
     (6)  Elevated operational temperatures in orbit. Packet-packing
          error caused lost packets approximately 0.03% of the time.
          Known single lost packets are described in Extras directory.
          Flight software patch on 11208 solved issue. 58 total
          observations affected. Data is good, but VIS and NIR files
          don&apos;t match due to missing spectra in VIS.
     (7)  Lost data Events during Orbit.
          11123: FPP &apos;High Temperature&apos; warning, Instrument off for 2
            days, setting set too low. FPP temps reset to higher value.
          11216-11215: Single event upset garbled VIRS data from
            MET 220978448 to MET 221033678. CDRs exist for this time,
            but with no valid science data. Data all shutter closed.
          11249-11250: Single event upset garbled VIRS data from
            MET 223767753 to MET 223882987. CDRs exist for this time,
            but with no valid science data. Occurrence at the same
            time as X class solar flare. Dark currents in VIRS
            elevated after this event.
     (8)  Occasional single event upsets, usually related to solar
          activity, usually resulted in either instrument shutdown, or
          accumulation of corrupted/useless data that is not
          delivered. Slowly increasing IR dark current as a function
          of age, with additional step functions coinciding with large
          solar particle events.
     (9)  During hot seasons, when detector temps exceed ~44 deg. C,
          the VIRS shutter begins to fail to close in some
          observations, resulting in commanded dark observations that
          are not dark in a subset of observations. These data are
          excluded from CDR and DDR delivery until a compensatory
          calibration is derived. A table of excluded observations has
          been created.
     (10) Single event upsets and &apos;VIRS stuck in scanning mode&apos;
          incidents continue, but more rarely during this period after
          VIRS reset is commanded every orbit.
 
     Cruise operations/observations have additional details in the
     Master Cruise Operations Table (a Microsoft Excel file) in the
     Extras directory.
 
   Limitations
   ===========
     This data set is minimally processed data.  The data are received
     from the spacecraft telemetry and ingested into the MESSENGER
     Science Operations Center (SOC).  No data gaps have been
     identified for any of the MASCS operational periods.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

