<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ear-c-ids-lcs-3-rdr-borrelly-mcdnld-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MCDONALD OBS. COLUMN DENSITY OBSERVATIONS OF 19P/BORRELLY</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.support_archives::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.mcd27m::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:ids.mcd27m::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:lcs.mcd27m::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.19p-borrelly_1_1904_y2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-c-ids-lcs-3-rdr-borrelly-mcdnld-v1.0__browserp_ear-c-ids-lcs-3-rdr-borrelly-mcdnld-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Arvesen, J.C., R.J. Griffin, Jr., and B.D. Pearson, Jr., Determination of
                   Extraterrestrial Solar Spectral Irradiance from a Research Aircraft, Appl.
                   Opt., 8, 2215, 1969.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ARVESENETAL1969</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Cochran, A.L. and E.S. Barker, McDonald Observatory Spectral Observations
                   of Comet 19P/Borrelly, Icarus, 141, 307, 1999.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.COCHRAN-BARKER1999</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Cochran, A.L., E.S.Barker, and A.D.Storrs, The McDonald Observatory Faint Comet
                   Survey: Gas Production in 17 Comets, Icarus, 98, 151, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.COCHRANETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>EAR-C-IDS/LCS-3-RDR-BORRELLY-MCDNLD-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MCDONALD OBS. COLUMN DENSITY OBSERVATIONS OF 19P/BORRELLY</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1999-03-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1981-01-03T03:45Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1994-12-06T09:51Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>TONY FARNHAM</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>TBD</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            McDonald Observatory (IDS and LCS) column density observations of
            19P/Borrelly during the 1981, 1987-8 and 1994 apparitions.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            McDonald Observatory (IDS and LCS) column density observations of
            19P/Borrelly during the 1981, 1987-8 and 1994 apparitions.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
 
        Spectral observations of Comet 19P/Borrelly
 
    This data set includes the raw column densities of several gas
    species observed in the spectra of comet Borrelly, as a function
    of position in the coma.  All measurements were made with the
    2.7-m Harlan J Smith Telescope at McDonald Observatory.  During
    the 1981 and 1987-1988 apparitions, the data were obtained with
    the Intensified Dissector Scanner (IDS), and during the 1994
    apparition, the data were obtained with the Large Cassegrain
    Spectrograph (LCS).
 
    The IDS and LCS tables give up to 4100 measurements of the column
    densities of different species at various positions in the coma.
    The species measured from the IDS data are C2 (two bands), CN, C3,
    CH and NH2.  The species measured from the LCS data are C2 (two
    bands) OH, NH, CN, C3 and CH.  The raw column density measurements
    as a function of position are presented here so that researchers
    can apply their own models to the data.
 
    The manuscript describing the data set in detail can be found in
    Cochran, A.L. and E.S. Barker (1999) &apos;&apos;McDonald Observatory
    Spectral Observations of Comet 19P/Borrelly&apos;&apos; Icarus 141, 307-315.
    [COCHRAN&amp;BARKER1999] Table IV from that paper lists the production
    rates and Afrho values derived from the column densities.  The
    information in this table was not submitted for inclusion in this
    data set.
 
 
    Modification History
    ====================
    The data were received as two flat ASCII tables (one each for IDS
    and LCS data), which were slightly reformatted to add the date of
    observation to each record.  PDS labels were written by SBN
    personnel, and the table of observational parameters was keyed in
    and labeled to complement the two data tables.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
    The IDS data file lists the date, the offset, in RA and
    declination, of the slit from the optocenter (as measured at 5000
    Angstroms), and the logarithmic offsets, column densities and
    error flags for each species of interest.  Specific offsets are
    listed for each species because atmospheric dispersion causes
    slightly different regions of the coma to be observed at different
    wavelengths.  The species listed in the IDS data file are C2 (two
    bands), CN, C3, CH and NH2.
 
    The LCS data file lists the same parameters for C2 (two bands) OH,
    NH, CN, C3 and CH.
 
    The observational parameters table lists geometric parameters for
    each of the observing dates in the data tables.  These include the
    date, observation time range (UT), heliocentric distance and
    velocity, geocentric distance, plate scale at the comet, position
    angle of the anti-solar direction and comments regarding observing
    conditions and LCS slit orientation.
 
    Note that the data tables contain multiple entries for each
    observation date.  These entries correspond to measurements from
    multiple spectra obtained during the listed range of times, as
    well as to different spatial positions along those spectra.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
    The data were reduced in a standard manner, by removing the bias
    level from the CCD data and flat fielding to remove the
    pixel-to-pixel variations.  Wavelength calibration was done using
    an argon lamp with the same instrumental setup used to observe the
    comet.  Flux calibration was obtained via observations of standard
    stars.
 
    Sky measurements were obtained from a region of the sky well
    removed from the comet, to avoid cometary contaminations.  These
    observations were used to remove the night sky contribution to the
    comet spectra.
 
    Underlying continuum (sunlight reflected from the dust) was
    removed in one of two ways.  For some of the LCS data, a solar
    analogue star was observed, and used to remove the underlying
    continuum.  For the IDS data and the rest of the LCS data, the
    solar spectrum from Arvesen et al. (Applied Optics 8, 2215, 1969)
    [ARVESENETAL1969] were convolved with the instrumental profile and
    removed from the comet spectrum.
 
    The extraction of the gas fluxes and column densities were
    performed as described in Cochran et al. (Icarus 98, 151 1992),
    [COCHRANETAL1992] using the conversion constants from that
    manuscript.
 
 
    Data
    =====
    The data consist of three tables.  The first table, OBSPARM.TAB
    describes the observational parameters relating to each of the
    observing runs in the data set.
 
    The other tables, IDS.TAB and CLS.TAB list the column densities at
    various locations in the coma.
 
    Media/Format
    ============
    The data tables are given in the form of ASCII files.  These
    tables do not use any sub-or super-script characters and so are
    readable in any format.  The data set is available by electronic
    transfer.
 
    Spectra
    ========
    The spectra used for measuring the column densities have not yet
    been submitted to the PDS for archiving.  They have been requested,
    but are awaiting sufficient resources to complete their preparation.
    If and when the spectra become available, this data set will be
    updated to include them.
 
    Any researcher interested in using the spectra should contact
    Anita Cochran directly (Anita Cochran, Department of Astronomy,
    University of Texas, 78712).
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Review
    ======
    This data set was peer-reviewed on 6 December 2002.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
 
    There are no uncertainties quoted on the column density
    measurements, but three grades are used to denote the quality of
    the measurements.  First, no footnote on a measurement means it is
    a good quality result.  A colon (:) following the column density
    indicates that the result is less certain (estimated to have up to
    50% larger uncertainties), and two colons (::) indicate that the
    measurement is much less certain (as much as 100 0gher
    uncertainties).
 
    The uncertainties are dependent on the particular molecule of
    interest, but for the high quality measurements, the random errors
    are 5-10%, with absolute errors ranging from 10-25%.  The
    systematic errors very much depend on the molecule because if the
    wrong oscillator strengths are being used, then the result could
    be off by a factor of 2.  However, this would affect all data for
    a given species in the same way.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

