<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.co-s-inms-3-l1a-u-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CASSINI S INMS LEVEL 1A EXTRACTED DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:inms.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.saturn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.dione::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.enceladus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.hyperion::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.iapetus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.mimas::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.phoebe::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.rhea::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.tethys::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.titan::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.co-s-inms-3-l1a-u-v1.0__browserp_co-s-inms-3-l1a-u-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Seidelmann, P.K. (ed.) (1992), Explanatory Supplement to the Astronomical
                   Almanac, University Science Books, Sausalito, CA, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SEIDELMANN1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Waite, J.H., W.S. Lewis, W.T. Kasprzak, V.G. Anicich, B.P. Block, T.E. Cravens,
                   G.G. Fletcher, W.-H. Ip, J.G. Luhmann, R.L. McNutt, H.B. Niemann, J.K. Parejko,
                   J.E. Richards, R.L. Thorpe, E.M. Walter, and R.V. Yelle, The Cassini Ion and
                   Neutral Mass Spectrometer (INMS) Investigation, Space Sci. Rev. 114, 113-231,
                   2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.WAITEETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CO-S-INMS-3-L1A-U-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CASSINI S INMS LEVEL 1A EXTRACTED DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-07-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-07-01T00:00:00.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-10-01T00:00:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. DAVID A. GELL</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Waite,J.H, W.T. Kasprzak, J.G. Luhman, T.E. Cravens, R.V. Yelle,
            R.L. McNutt, W.-H. Ip, R.L. Thorpe, D.A. Gell, CASSINI S INMS
            LEVEL 1A EXTRACTED DATA V1.0, CO-S-INMS-3-L1A-U-V1.0, NASA
            Planetary Data System, 2005.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Cassini INMS Level 1A data includes all the data from both
            the high and the low sensitivity counters annotated with selected
            spacecraft position, spacecraft attitude and instrument state
            information.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Cassini Ion and Neutral Mass Spectrometer (INMS) level 1A
            data set includes all mass samples for the entire Cassini
            mission. The data set includes mass spectra data from the
            instrument checkout periods, SOI and the entire Saturn tour. The
            data is organized as a spread sheet with one row for each sample
            period. Each column in the spread sheet contains the ancillary
            data and the output of the counters.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  DATA SET OVERVIEW
  =================
 
    The Cassini Ion and Neutral Mass Spectrometer (INMS) level 1A data
    set includes all mass samples for the entire Cassini mission. The
    data set includes mass spectra data from the instrument checkout
    periods, SOI and the entire Saturn tour. The data is organized as
    a spread sheet with one row for each sample period. Each column in
    the spread sheet contains the ancillary data and the output of the
    counters.
 
 
  PARAMETERS
  =================
 
    The data set includes both high sensitivity (C1) and low
    sensitivity (C2) count rates collected during the tour. The count
    rates are reported as total counts per integration period. The
    integration period, at full telemetry rate, is 31 ms with samples
    collected at a 34 ms cadence. When telemetry bandwidth is limited,
    measurements are accumulated by the instrument software prior to
    construction of the telemetry packet. In this case the integration
    period is equal to the number of measurements accumulated to form
    the telemetry packet times the basic 31 ms integration period.
 
 
  PROCESSING
  =================
 
    The data in this data set is minimally processed. The counter sums
    are extracted from the instrument telemetry and the values of the
    included ancillary data are computed. The ancillary data comes
    from a number of sources including instrument science telemetry,
    instrument housekeeping telemetry, instrument command tables,
    spacecraft attitude and ephemerides of the spacecraft and
    planetary body and moons.
 
 
  COORDINATE SYSTEM
  =================
 
    Position, velocity and orientation information contained in this
    data set is provided with respect to a number of coordinate
    systems.  Saturn relative information expressed in the IAU Saturn
    frame is always included. When the spacecraft is within one hour
    of a targeted flyby, target relative position, velocity and
    orientation information is provided expressed in the target&apos;s IAU
    frame. The spacecraft velocity with respect to a target body,
    expressed in the spacecraft body frame is also included within one
    hour of a targeted flyby.
 
    The IAU frames are centered at the center of the reference body,
    Saturn, Titan, or another object of interest. They are rotating
    coordinate frames which, in the case of Saturn, rotates with the
    magnetic field.  For other bodies, the frame rotates with the
    surface. Definitions of the coordinate frames may be found in &apos;The
    Explanatory Supplement to the Astronomical Almanac&apos;
    [SEIDELMANN1992]
 
    Longitudes are positive westward.
 
  SOFTWARE
  ========
 
 
 
  MEDIA FORMAT
  ============
 
    The data are archived on either CDROM or DVDROM media. The data
    files are stored in a comma-separated ASCII spreadsheet form that
    is described in the detached PDS label (Spreadsheet Object). The
    structure of the spreadsheet is specified in the format file
    included, by pointer, in the PDS label.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  CONFIDENCE LEVEL OVERVIEW
  =========================
 
    This data set contains all of the counter data for the Cassini
    INMS instrument for the intervals described in the labels of the
    individual data files.
 
 
  REVIEW
  ======
 
    The INMS L1A complete data set will be reviewed internally by the
    Cassini INMS team prior to release to the PDS. The data set will
    also undergo a PDS peer review prior to release.
 
 
  DATA COVERAGE AND QUALITY
  =========================
 
    PRIOR TO SOI
    ------------
      Prior to SOI the INMS instrument was evacuated and the aperture
      was closed by a cover installed prior to launch. The instrument
      was operated during in-flight check-outs (ICO) collecting
      baseline calibration data. During the approach science phase,
      INMS was operated nearly continuously to obtain operational
      experience and to validate data collection tables.
 
      The INMS cover was jettisoned immediately after SOI, permitting
      measurements of the ion and neutral constituents.
 
 
    POST SOI
    -------
      INMS science data collection began at SOI. From SOI onwards, the
      instrument was essentially in continuous operation.  Until a software
      patch was installed during S16, the instrument processor would
      unexpectedly reset, causing a loss of science data to occur until
      the flight software was re-loaded. These occurrences are noted below.
 
      An issue with velocity compensation exists from launch through
      2005-058 which results in differences between the flight
      software computed quad lens bias voltages and ground computed
      values for the same velocity. This issue results in signal level
      changes when switching between velocity compensated scans and
      energy scans with ground computed quad lens voltages. The issue
      is resolved in data collected after TBS-DATE by correcting the
      ground computation of lens bias voltages.
 
      Prior to 2005-058 the flight software velocity compensation
      algorithm clipped only the lens voltage that reached its limit,
      allowing the other three voltages to be adjusted. This resulted
      in the voltages failing to maintain their proper relationships.
      This was corrected by insuring that once one voltage reached its
      limit, all four voltages were frozen.
 
      The spacecraft background sequence was halted just after SOI,
      during this period, from day 2004-186 through 2004-194 no L1A
      data was produced.
 
      Flight software checkout was performed between 2004-252T19:25:00.044
      and 2004-255T19;10:10.044 and as a result no L1A data was
      produced.
 
      No L1A data was produced on days 2004-309 and 2004-310 due to an
      interrupted flight software load.
 
      During S5, one unexpected processor reset occurred at
      2004-310T10:03:45, with a data loss until 2004-311T00:00:00
 
      No L1A data was produced during the Probe mission from 2005-007
      through 2005-014 and the period following from 2005-015 through
      2005-022 while the solid state recorder was being protected until
      the the Probe mission data was validated.
 
      During S10, one unexpected processor reset occurred at
      2005-105T17:32:07. No science data was collected from that instant
      until the next planned reset at 2005-106T07:00:00.
 
      During S11, three unexpected processor resets occurred at
      2005-135T05:10:27, 2005-139T13:15:44 and 2005-148T02:46:22. No
      science data was collected from between the unexpected processor
      resets and the following planned resets. As a result no science data
      was collected from 2005-135T05:10 through 2005-163T23:59:59 except
      for short periods following each of the planned resets.
 
      During S15 there was one unexpected processor reset, which occurred
      at 2005-289T17:06:55. No science data was collected from between the
      unexpected and the planned reset at 2005-300T18:39:00. Another gap
      occurred beginning at approximately 2005-309:18:00:00 and extended
      until approximately 2005-314T17:00:00. This gap was the result of
      data policing by the spacecraft command and data system.
 
      During S16, S17, S18 and S19 there were no unexpected processor
      resets. Telemetry gaps of more than 1 file occurred on 2006-006,
      007, 036, 037, 044, 045 and 081 resulting in one or more L1A files
      being absent from the data for those days.
 
      During S20 and S21 there were no unexpected processor resets.
      Data gaps of more than one hour occurred on days 2006-096,
      120, 121, 122, 124, 145, 158, 159 162 and 167, resulting in one
      or more L1A files being absent from the data for those days. The data
      gaps on days 096, 124, 158 and 159 were due to the instrument being
      placed in sleep for the orbit trim maneuvers. The remaining were due
      to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S22, S23, S24 there were no unexpected process resets. Data
      gaps of more than one hour occurred on days 2006-191, 195, 213, 249,
      253, 257, 267, resulting in one or more L1A files being absent from the
      data for those days. The data gaps on days 213 and 253 were the result
      of placing the instrument in sleep mode during orbit trim maneuvers.
      The gap on day 257 was due to a software update and a planned
      instrument reset. The remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S24 (end), S25, S26 (beginning) there were no unexpected
      processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour occurred on days
      2006-274, 286, 287, 288, 290, 298, 299, 311, 312, 313, 344, 349, 354,
      363, 364, 365, resulting in one or more L1A files being absent from
      the data for those days. The data gaps on days 274, 290, 313, 349,
      354, and 365 were the result of placing the instrument in sleep mode
      during orbit trim maneuvers. The remaining gaps were due to telemetry
      gaps.
 
      During S26 (end), S27, S28, S29 (beginning) there were no unexpected
      processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour occurred on days
      2007-004, 005, 021, 038, 048, 049, 052, 053, 054, 061, 072, 077, 085,
      086, 087, 088, resulting in one or more L1A files being absent from the
      data for those days. The data gaps on days 021, 038, 061, 072, 077 and
      087 were the result of placing the instrument in sleep mode during
      orbit trim maneuvers. The remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S29 (end), S30, S31 (beginning) there were no unexpected
      processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour occurred on days
      2007-092, 093, 094, 095, 109, 122, 124, 139, 141, 152, 156, 159, 160,
      168, 170, 172, 173, resulting in one or more L1A files being absent
      from the data for those days. The data gaps on days 109, 124, 141, 152,
      156, 168, 172, and 173 were the result of placing the instrument in
      sleep mode during orbit trim maneuvers. The remaining gaps were due to
      telemetry gaps.
 
      During S31 (from 2007-182), S32, S33, and S34 (to 2007-273) there were
      no unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour
      occurred on days 218, 245, 252, 254, 255, 256, 257, 258, 259, 269, 270,
      and 273 resulting in one or more L1A files being absent from the data
      for those days. The gaps on days 254 through 259 were the result of
      spacecraft safing. The data gaps on days 218 and 245 were the result of
      placing the instrument in sleep mode during orbit trim maneuvers. The
      remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S34 (from 2007-274), S35, and S36 (to 2007-365) there were
      no unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour
      occurred on days 274, 276, 278, 279, 280, 281, 282, 283, 284, 285, 286,
      287, 288, 289, 290, 291, 292, 293, 294, 295, 305, 323, 324, 326, 331,
      334, 342, 346, 347, 348, 353 and 363 resulting in one or more L1A files
      being absent from the data for those days. The gaps on days 279 through
      295 were the result of spacecraft flight software activities including
      a spacecraft flight software upload. The data gaps on days 305, 326,
      331, 342, 353 and 363 were the result of placing the instrument in
      sleep mode during orbit trim maneuvers.  The remaining gaps were due
      to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S36 (from 2008-001), S37, S38, and S39 (to 2008-091) there were
      no unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour occurred
      on days 002, 003, 015, 016, 027, 037, 041, 050, 061, 065, 067, 070, 073,
      and 074 resulting in one or more L1A files being absent from the data
      for those days. The gap on day 065 was the result of placing
      the instrument in sleep mode to allow sufficient data volume
      for an MRO. The gaps on days 015, 016, and 027 were the result
      of placing the instrument in sleep mode for an RSS experiment
      (an orbit trim maneuver followed the RSS experiment on day 016,
      so INMS remained in sleep mode until 07:15:15).
      The gaps on days 037, 050, 061, 067, 073, and 074 were the result of
      placing the instrument in sleep mode during orbit trim maneuvers. The
      remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S39 (from 2008-092), S40, and S41 (to 2008-182) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour occurred on
      days 092, 102, 111, 113, 117, 123, 129, 138, 139, 168, and 175 resulting
      in one or more L1A files being absent from the data for those days. The
      gap from day 138 17:29:28 to day 139 22:45:12, as well as the gaps on
      days 092 and 168 were the result of placing the instrument in sleep mode
      for an RSS experiment. The gaps on days 102, 117, 138 (00:48:56 to
      03:21:13), and 175 were the result of placing the instrument in sleep
      mode during orbit trim maneuvers. The remaining gaps were due to
      telemetry gaps.
 
      During S41 (from 2008-183), S42, S43, and S44 (to 2008-274)
      there were no unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of
      more than one hour occurred on days 189, 195, 202, 216,
      217, 232, 233, 234, 235, 236, 237, 238, and 264
      resulting in one or more L1A files being absent from the data for those
      days. The gaps on days 189, 217, 232, 233, 234, 235, and 236 05:49:48 to
      238 05:49:47 were the result of placing the instrument in sleep mode.The
      gaps on days 216 21:38:17 to 217 00:16:09, 236 02:00:28 to 04:51:08
      and 264 were the result of placing the instrument in sleep mode during
      orbit trim maneuvers. The remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S44 (from 2008-275), S45, S46 (to 2008-366) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour occurred on
      days 275, 276, 287, 291, 305, 313, 317, 328, 330, 331, 344, 348, 349,
      351, 352, 353, and 354 resulting in one or more L1A files being absent
      from the data for those days. The gaps on days 276, 287, 291, 313, 317,
      328, 344, and 348 were the result of placing the instrument in sleep
      mode during orbit trim maneuvers. The remaining gaps were due to
      telemetry gaps.
 
      During S46 (from 2009-001), S47, S48, S49 (to 2009-090) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour occurred on
      days 024, 032, 041, 058, 063, 064, 068, 071, 072, 073, 074, 075, 076,
      077, and 088 resulting in one or more L1A files being absent
      from the data for those days. The gaps on days 024, 041, 068, and 088,
      were the result of placing the instrument in sleep mode during
      orbit trim maneuvers. The gaps on day 071 02:00:00 to
      077 03:15:00 were the result of placing the instrument in sleep mode
      during a thruster swap. The remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S48 (from 2009-091), S49, S50, S51 (to 2009-181) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour occurred on
      days 098, 102, 108, 118, 123, 124, 125, 134, 150, 161, 165, 169, 170,
      and 177 resulting in one or more L1A files being absent
      from the data for those days. The gaps on days 102, 118, 123, 134, 150,
      161, and 177 06:25:04 to 177 09:09:19 were the result of placing the
      instrument in sleep mode during orbit trim maneuvers.
      The remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S51 (from 2009-182), S52, S53 (to 2009-273) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour
      occurred on days 193, 209, 221, 222, 228, 234, 241, 248, 258, and 259
      resulting in one or more L1A files being absent
      from the data for those days. The gaps on days 193, 209, 228, 241,
      and 248 were the result of placing the instrument in sleep mode
      during orbit trim maneuvers.
      The remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S53 (from 2009-274), S54, S55, S56 (to 2009-365) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour
      occurred on days 289, 294, 309, 326, 349, 354, and 355,
      resulting in one or more L1A files being absent
      from the data for those days. The gaps on days 289, 294, 309, 326, 349,
      and 354 (05:59:48-08:41:54) were the result of placing the instrument
      in sleep mode  during orbit trim maneuvers.
      The remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S56 (from 2010-001), S57, S58 (to 2010-090) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour
      occurred on days 002, 003, 004, 005, 006, 007, 008, 016, 021, 032,
      046, 065, and 085 resulting in one or more L1A files being absent
      from the data for those days. The gaps on days 016, 021, 032, and 085
      were the result of placing the instrument in sleep mode during
      orbit trim maneuvers.  The gaps on days 002 10:12:05 to 006 02:43:36
      were the result of the instrument being turned Off because of an SSPS
      Trip on the spacecraft. The gaps on days 006 02:43:36 to 007 15:24:57
      were the result of the instrument being in sleep mode to run
      diagnostics on the instrument.
      The remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S58 (from 2010-091), S59, S60, S61 (to 2010-181) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour
      occurred on days 100, 101, 107, 108, 109, 119, 131, 141, 142, 143,
      148, 164, 175, and 181 resulting in one or more L1A files being absent
      from the data for those days. The gaps on days 100, 101, 119, 131,
      143, 148, 164, 175, and 181 were the result of placing the instrument
      in sleep mode during orbit trim maneuvers.
      The remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S61 (from 2010-182), S62, S63 (to 2010-273) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour
      occurred on days 188, 189, 191, 199, 230, 231, 232, 233, 246, and 256.
      resulting in one or more L1A files being absent
      from the data for those days. The gaps on days 191, 199, and 246
      were the result of placing the instrument
      in sleep mode during orbit trim maneuvers.
      The remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S63 (from 2010-274), S64, S65 (to 2010-365) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour
      occurred on days 274, 275, 276, 285, 299, 306-328, 337, 338, and 339
      resulting in one or more L1A files being absent
      from the data for those days. The gaps on days 306 21:29:41 to
      319 20:00:10 were the result of the instrument being turned Off because
      of a spacecraft safing event. The gaps on days 319 20:00:10
      to 328 19:35:00 were the result of the instrument being in sleep mode
      to run diagnostics on the instrument.
      The remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S65 (from 2011-001), S66, S67 (to 2011-090) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour
      occurred on days 010, 014, 024, 025, 059, 060, and 072
      resulting in one or more L1A files being absent
      from the data for those days. The gap on day 014 was the result of
      placing the instrument in sleep mode during an orbit trim maneuver.
      The remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S67 (from 2011-091) and S68 (to 2011-181) there were no
      unexpected processor resets.  Data gaps of more than one hour occurred
      on day 131 resulting in one or more L1A files being absent fron the data
      for that day.  The gap on day 131 was due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S68 (from 2011-182), S69, and S70 (to 2011-273) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour
      occurred on days 220, 222-226, 228, 232, 235, 236, 250, 263, and 268
      resulting in one or more L1A files being absent from the data for those
      days.  The gap on day 263 was the result of placing the instrument in
      sleep mode during an orbit trim maneuver.  The remaining gaps were due
      to telemetry gaps.
      During S70 (from 2011-274) and S71 (to 2011-365) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour
      occurred on days 279, 313, 320, 328, 351, 357, 358, and 359
      resulting in one or more L1A files being absent from the data for those
      days.  The gaps on days 328 and 351 were the result of placing the
      instrument in sleep mode during an orbit trim maneuver.  The remaining
      gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
      During S71 (from 2012-001) and S72 (to 2012-091) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour
      occurred on days 006, 024, 027, 028, 029, 070, and 077
      resulting in one or more L1A files being absent from the data for those
      days.  The gap on day 070 was the result of placing the
      instrument in sleep mode during an orbit trim maneuver.  The remaining
      gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S72 (from 2012-092) , S73, and S74 (to 2012-182) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour
      occurred on days 110, 111, 115, 135, 151, 152, 162, 167, 170,
      and 173-177 resulting in one or more L1A files being absent from the
      data for those days.  The gaps on days 115, 135, 151, 162, and 173 were
      the result of placing the instrument in sleep mode during an orbit trim
      maneuver.  The remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S74 (from 2012-183) and S75 (to 2012-274) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour
      occurred on days 185, 190-192, 196, 220, 230, 233, 234, and 270
      resulting in one or more L1A files being absent from the data for those
      days.  The gap on day 220 were the result of placing the instrument in
      sleep mode during an orbit trim maneuver.  The remaining gaps were due
      to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S75 (from 2012-275) and S76 (to 2012-366) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour
      occurred on days 283, 293-303, 304, 318, 319, 322, 327, and 335
      resulting in one or more L1A files being absent from the data for those
      days.  The gaps on days 283, 322, and 327 were the result of placing
      the instrument in sleep mode during an orbit trim maneuver.  The gaps
      on days 293-303 were the result of the instrument being turned off
      during the Cassini Propellant Guage Test.  The remaining gaps were due
      to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S76 (from 2013-001), S77, and S78 (to 2013-090) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour occurred on
      days 011, 030, 055, and 061 resulting in one or more L1A files being
      absent for those days.  The gaps on days 030, 055, and 061 were the
      result of placing the instrument in sleep mode during an orbit trim
      maneuver.  The remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S78 (from 2013-091) and S79 (to 2013-181) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour occurred on
      days 120, 134, 158, 162, 169, and 174 resulting in one or more L1A files
      being absent for those days.  The gaps on days 120 and 162 were the
      result of placing the instrument in sleep mode during an orbit trim
      maneuver.  The remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S79 (from 2013-182) and S80 (to 2013-273) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour occurred on
      days 196, 200, 219, and 258 resulting in one or more L1A files
      being absent for those days.  The gaps on days 196, 200, and 219 were
      the result of placing the instrument in sleep mode during an orbit trim
      maneuver.  The remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S80 (from 2013-274), S81, and S82 (to 2013-365) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour occurred on
      days 306, 309-310, 312-315, and 351-352 resulting in one or more L1A
      files being absent for those days.  The gaps on days 306, 351, and 352
      were the result of placing the instrument in sleep mode during an orbit
      trim maneuver.  The remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
      During S82 (from 2014-001), and S83 (to 2014-090) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour occurred on
      days 010-011, 048, 079, and 082 resulting in one or more L1A files being
      absent for those days.  The gaps on days 048 and 079 were the result of
      placing the instrument in sleep mode during an orbit trim maneuver.  The
      remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S83 (from 2014-091) and S84 (to 2014-181) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour occurred on
      days 108, 109, and 127-129 resulting in one or more L1A files being
      absent for those days.  All of the gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
      During S84 (from 2014-182) and S85 (to 2014-273) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour occurred on
      days 221, 236, 250, 254, and 255 resulting in one or more L1A files
      being absent for those days.  The gaps on days 221 and 250 were the
      result of placing the instrument in sleep mode during an orbit trim
      maneuver.  The remaining gaps were due to telemetry gaps.
      During S85 (from 2014-274) and S86 (to 2014-365) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour occurred on
      days 282, 284, 287-288, 295-296, 302-303, 306-307, 342, and 364
      resulting in one or more L1A files being absent for those days. The gaps
      on days 282 and 364 were a result of placing the instrument in sleep
      mode during an orbit trim maneuver.  The larger quantity of gaps were
      associated with the STEREO-B spacecraft emergency.  The remaining gaps
      due to telemetry gaps.
 
      During S87 (from 2015-001) and S88 (to 2015-090) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour occurred on
      days 031, and 046 resulting in one or more L1A files being absent for
      those days.  All of the gaps were due to OTM step down and recovery.
      During S88 (from 2015-091) and S89 (to 2015-181) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour occurred on
      days 096, 121, 151, and 152 resulting in one or more L1A files being
      absent for those days.  One gap was due to either OTM step down or start
      of sequence reboot.  The others were due to DSN issues.
 
      During S89 (from 2015-182), S90, and S91 (to 2015-273) there were no
      unexpected processor resets. Data gaps of more than one hour occurred on
      days 187, 192, 224, 234, 235, and 273 resulting in one or more L1A files
      being absent for those days.  The gap on day 273 was due to data
      policing after an Ops Table Load.  All other gaps were due to DSN
      issues.
 
  LIMITATIONS
  ===========
 
    During the period from launch through 2004-256, a flight software
    error caused data corruption when mass scans were accumulated to
    reduce data rates. These data are identified by a value of the
    COADD_CNT greater than 1.
 
    Prior to 2005-058 the flight software velocity compensation
    algorithm clipped only the lens voltage that reached its limit,
    allowing the other three voltages to be adjusted. This resulted in
    the voltages failing to maintain their proper relation- ships. This
    was corrected by insuring that once one voltage reached its limit,
    all four voltages were frozen.
 
    Data collected at low altitudes at Titan must be used with
    caution. There appears to be significant contamination due to
    thruster exhaust scattering into the instrument.
 
    Velocity compensation was incorrectly configured and the data labeled
    OSNT is invalid for time periods 2008-004T03:15:00 to 2008-004T04:45:00,
    2008-015T14:30:00 to 2008-015T16:00:00, and 2008-039T20:15:00 to
    2008-039T21:45:00.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>PRE_PEER_REVIEW</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

