<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.msl-m-rems-3-telrdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MSL MARS ROVER ENV MONITORING STATION 3 TELRDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_science_laboratory::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.msl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rems.msl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.msl-m-rems-3-telrdr-v1.0__browserp_msl-m-rems-3-telrdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.msl-m-rems-3-telrdr-v1.0__dvo_atmos_msl-m-rems-3-telrdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.msl-m-rems-3-telrdr-v1.0__pds.geo.msl.analysts_notebook::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Gomez-Elvira J, Armiens C, Castaner L, Dominguez M, Genzer M, Gomez F, Haberle
                   R, Harri A-, Jimenez V, Kahanpaa H, Kowalski L, Lepinette A, Martin J,
                   Martinez-Frias J, McEwan I, Mora L, Moreno J, Navarro S, de Pablo MA, Peinado
                   V, Pena A, Polkko J, Ramos M, Renno NO, Ricart J, Richardson M,
                   Rodriguez-Manfredi J, Romeral J, Sebastian E, Serrano J, de la Torre Juarez M,
                   Torres J, Torrero F, Urqui R, Vazquez L, Velasco T, Verdasca J, Zorzano M-,
                   Martin-Torres J. REMS: The environmental sensor suite for the mars science
                   laboratory rover. Space Science Reviews 2012:1-58, 2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GOMEZELVIRAETAL2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MSL-M-REMS-3-TELRDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MSL MARS ROVER ENV MONITORING STATION 3 TELRDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2015-07-31</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2012-08-07T04:04:38.536Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-03-27T02:38:51.479Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JOSE A RODRIGUEZ-MANFREDI</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Gomez-Elvira, J., Mars Science Laboratory Rover Environmental
            Monitoring Station RDR Data V1.0, MSL-M-REMS-3-TELEDR-V1.0, NASA
            Planetary Data System, 2013.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            MSL Rover Environmental Monitoring Station Thermal and Electrical
            Reduced Data Record
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Data taken by the sensors of the Rover Environmental Monitoring
            Station (REMS) aboard the Mars Science Laboratory, in electrical
            and thermal units.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The REMS instrument is a meteorological package designed to
    provide measurements of air and ground temperatures, wind speed
    and direction, pressure, humidity and ultraviolet radiation.
 
    The REMS TELRDR data set contains processed REMS data where the
    counts given by the analog/digital converters from the instrument
    sensors have been converted to their corresponding thermal and
    electrical values, taking into account calibration information,
    gains and other possible electrical altering factors (such as the
    ASIC temperature). All these data can be found in the REMS EDR
    data set with the exception of calibration information. Whenever
    it is possible, temperatures instead of resistances are given,
    since conversion between them is straightforward. This implies
    that air temperatures from the Air Temperature Sensor are already
    present at this level.
 
    Data is a time ordered sequence of rows organized into a table,
    taken at a maximum resolution of one second. Each data product
    contains one sol worth of activity and has information from all
    sensors.
 
    This data set represents the first intermediate processing step to
    calculate environmental magnitudes. No external models or
    corrections have been applied.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The information included for each sensor is the following:
 
    - Wind Sensor: convective powers and hot temperatures from the 12
      transducers for each boom. Cold temperatures from the 3 boards
      in each boom where the transducers are allocated.
    - Ground Temperature Sensor: temperatures and voltages from the
      3 thermophiles. Calibration plate temperature.
    - Air Temperature Sensor: temperatures measured by each one of the
      PT1000 sensors on each boom. There is no sensor at the base of
      the rod at boom 1, so for that boom the third temperature is the
      mean of the three thermopiles temperatures.
    - Ultraviolet Sensor: photodiodes output currents and sensor
      operating temperature.
    - Humidity Sensor: sensor capacities for each of the 8 channels.
    - Pressure Sensor: sensor capacities for each of the 8 channels.
 
    Sampling is at 1Hz maximum, with a baseline operation of 5 minutes
    every hour. Additional measurements can be taken on an on-demand
    basis beyond those hourly observations. For these additional
    measurements, and besides tactical day to day conditions and
    resources, there is a general pattern that covers selected hours
    of the day built by the scientific team during operations. That
    pattern is shifted from sol to sol to cover the whole 24 hours
    after a few sols.
 
    Additionally, extended measurements can also be triggered
    automatically if event mode is activated, in which case the REMS
    computer will decide or not to continue measuring after the
    regular cadence, by comparing the previous measurements with the
    expected trend. The objective is to capture any ongoing transitory
    atmospheric event.
 
    During the first 72 sols, for each 5 minute block, the following
    measurement strategy was used: Wind Sensor is switched off for 60
    seconds, then it is switched on for 235 seconds, and then it is
    switched off again for the final 5 seconds. The rest of the
    sensors are switched on all the time. This strategy was based on
    results obtained during pre-flight testing. However, after
    evaluating flight data, it was determined that this strategy was
    not necessary, so from sol 73 onwards all sensors are switched on
    for each 5 minute block.
 
    From sol 793 onwards, a new measurement strategy for Humidity
    Sensor was introduced. It is called HS HRIM (Humidity Sensor High
    Resolution Interval Mode) and is only used on selected one-hour
    long observations. This new strategy intends to minimize heating
    of the Humidity Sensor, and consists of alternately switching on
    and off the sensor at periodic intervals. At the same time, Boom 2
    is switched off, which means that there are no Wind Sensor and Air
    Temperature Sensor measurements.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    Processing starts with the generation of the REMS EDRs. The REMS
    EDR data products are generated by the MIPL (Multimission Image
    Processing Laboratory) at JPL, under the OPGS, using the telemetry
    processing software called MSLEdrGen. This software will convert
    the binary data received from telemetry to ASCII. EDRs will then
    be retrieved at Centro de Astrobiologia (INTA-CSIC) using the File
    Exchange Interface (FEI).
 
    EDR data products have a first automatic process using calibration
    data. The result of this is the TELRDR data set, which contains
    electrical magnitudes and thermal data. In parallel, using
    ancillary data provided by JPL (such as rover location, sun
    position) the ADRs (Ancillary Data Records) are generated. EDRs,
    TELRDRs, ADRs, and calibration data are processed together to
    obtain the ENVRDRs.
 
    The level of processing of the ENVRDRs includes environmental
    magnitudes with minimal corrections (mainly based on the
    degradation of the sensors). Finally, applying models developed by
    the REMS team and refining them with the confidence levels, the
    MODRDR data set is created.
 
    In the process to convert EDRs to TELRDR, the procedure to
    calculate the electrical magnitudes from counts varies from sensor
    to sensor. These counts are the result of a digitization from an
    Analog/Digital Converter, so the reverse process is done using
    data obtained during the calibration of the instrument. These data
    are included in the CALIB directory.
 
    Three of the sensors (Wind Sensor, Ground Temperature Sensor and
    the Air Temperature Sensor) are handled through an ASIC
    (Application-Specific Integrated Circuit), and are affected by its
    temperature and power conditions. These ASIC values and their
    effects are included in the processing in addition to the
    digital-analogical conversion. ASIC information is also included
    in the EDRs.
 
    Finally, with a one to one time match between EDRs and TELRDRs,
    the resulting data is integrated into a single table.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    Each REMS TELRDR product in the data set is an ASCII table
    containing all sensors data, accompanied by a detached PDS
    label. Each row contains an acquisition session, while columns
    contain the sensors values. This makes it easy to load the data
    products in a spreadsheet program or in a database.
 
    Columns with related information are placed together, in the
    following order: time references (REMS clock, LMST and LTST), Wind
    Sensor, Ground Temperature Sensor, Air Temperature Sensor,
    Ultraviolet Sensor, Humidity Sensor and Pressure Sensor.
 
    REMS clock is synced with the spacecraft clock (SCLK) with a
    maximum deviation of 30 sg. LTST is given with respect to the
    rover position, in contrast with LTST given in REMS EDR labels and
    in other MSL data, which is given with respect to landing site.
 
    Columns are delimited by commas and are of fixed length. Rows are
    time ordered and are separated by a carriage return/line
    feed. Each table contains a sol of measurements.
 
    Data may be set to UNK if their value is not known and it will
    never be (such as saturation, or a specific sensor switched off
    during acquisition). They may also be set to NULL if their value
    is not known at the moment of the release of the data set, but it
    is expected to be known in a future release.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    The ancillary data used in the generation of this data set is
    laboratory calibration data, all of which can be found in the
    CALIB directory.
 
    Calibration files are in plain ASCII text format. They are
    structured in a PDS label-like structure, with the form DATA =
    VALUE, each value taking up one line. A file per sensor is
    provided.
 
    The following ancillary data are needed to generate higher level
    data and to estimate its quality:
 
    Laboratory calibration data
    Solar azimuth and elevation
    Rover azimuth, elevation, altitude, pitch, yaw and roll
    Rover speed
    Masthead azimuth and elevation
    Rover temperatures
    UV sensor dust attenuation
 
    These data can be found as part of the REMS ADR records.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    No software is provided in this data set. The RDR tables are simple
    ASCII files that can be displayed on UNIX, Macintosh, and PC
    platforms with common software.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The data presented in this data set has been processed by applying
    laboratory calibration data and formulas derived from the REMS
    electronic design. Accuracy of these data is the correspondent to
    that one of the calibration process, although extensive tests in
    representative conditions have been done to ensure its
    reliability. Wind Sensor data of boards 2 and 3 in boom 1 are not
    provided as they were damaged during landing.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    The REMS RDRs were reviewed internally by the REMS team prior to
    release to the PDS. PDS also performed an external peer review of
    the REMS RDRs.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    Data reported are processed data derived from raw data received
    during nominal REMS operations. Each TELRDRs table provides
    sensors values measured during one sol, which are dependent of
    pre-flight calibration data.
 
    Sensors switched off at the time of measurement are set to UNK.
    Saturated Wind Sensor data or those correspondent to damaged
    boards are set to UNK. When the Pressure Sensor is acquiring in
    high resolution mode, the channels not in use are set to UNK.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    The major limitation of this data set is that most of the data is
    at the electrical level.
 
    Missing information from Wind Sensor in the boom 1 makes it
    difficult to estimate wind data when it is coming from behind the
    rover mast in the boom 2 direction.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

