<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.pvo-v-orpa-5-ele-ion-photo-uads-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>PVO RPA PROC THERM ELEC, ION, PHOTOELEC, LOW RES. V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.pioneer_venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.pvo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:orpa.pvo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.pvo-v-orpa-5-ele-ion-photo-uads-v1.0__browserp_pvo-v-orpa-5-ele-ion-photo-uads-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Knudsen W.C. , Evaluation and demonstation of the use of retarding
                   potential analyzers for measuring several ionospheric quantities, J.
                   Geophys. Res., vol. 71, pp. 4669-4678, 1966.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KNUDSENETAL1966</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Knudsen, W.C., J. Bakke, K. Spenner, and V. Novak, Retarding Potential
                   Analyzer for the Pioneer Venus Orbiter, Space Sci. Inst., 4, 351, 1979.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KNUDSENETAL1979</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Knudsen, W.C., K. Spenner, J. Bakke, and V. Novak, Pioneer Venus Orbiter
                   Planar Retarding Potential Analyzer Plasma Experiment, IEEE Trans. on
                   Geosci. Remote Sens., 18, 1, 60, 1980.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KNUDSENETAL1980</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>PVO-V-ORPA-5-ELE/ION/PHOTO/UADS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>PVO RPA PROC THERM ELEC, ION, PHOTOELEC, LOW RES. V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1997-09-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1978-12-05T14:41Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1992-10-07T20:16Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. WILLIAM C. KNUDSEN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>TBD</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Pioneer Venus Orbiter (PVO) processed data from the retarding
            potential analyzer (ORPA), including thermal and superthermal
            electrons, ions, and a key parameters file for all 5055 orbits
            (Dec 5, 1978 - Oct 7, 1992).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>not applicable</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
Overview:
============
 
The ORPA processed data consist of 4 file types: high resolution
thermal electrons, high resolution superthermal electrons, high
resolution ions, and a key parameters file at 12 second sampling. High
resolution data are provided (for the entire orbit / only the portion
of the orbit near periapsis) The sample rate of the high resolution
data is variable and dependent on the telemetry rate and other
operational considerations. All of these data are derived from the
reformatted EDR data (RDR) which contains the raw I-V curve values.
The moments of the distributions have been computed by a least squares
fitting algorithm. The low resolution data are resampled from the high
resolution files. All 5055 orbits of the mission,
(Dec 5, 1978 - Oct 7, 1992) are included in the data set. The PV RPA
is described in considerable detail by Knudsen et al. [1979-1980]. The
principles of measurement are also described therein together with
some of the factors affecting the accuracy of the derived quantities.
Additional information on the theory of measurement by an RPA is
presented by Knudsen [1966].
 
Sampling:
=========
 
    The ORPA instrument sweeps through the ion, electron, and
photoelectron modes in an EIIIP sequence covering 5 spacecraft spin
periods spending one spin period in each mode. A single retarding scan
can be completed approximately 40 times in a spin period (0.3 sec).
There are various algorithms by which the instrument can decide which
scan to place in the telemetry frame.
Please read the instrument description for more details.
 
Data Processing:
================
 
High resolution data were processing by using an automated least
squares fitting procedure. Values derived from these fits are provided
in the archive. Some of the quantities contained in this submittal of
RPA data to the PDS are erroneous because of bad least-squares fits to
the I-V curves. These bad fits were not detected by the data reduction
algorithms and have not been removed by a trained observer viewing the
I-V curves and making an educated judgment. A trained observer,
looking at an I-V plot, can rather quickly recognize data that will
produce erroneous fit results but it is difficult to write an
algorithm that can recognize all the possible situations and make the
necessary adjustments.
 
   High Resolution Electrons:
 
In the electron mode, the ion current to the collector is negligible
with the collector at 47 V,  A potential difference of 20 V between G-4
and C was found sufficient to suppress most of the secondary electrons
produced by ion or electron impact at the collector.  The three front
grids G-0, G-1 and G-2 are the energy analyzing grids.  They are stepped
together from +6.8 to -4.2 V in the coarse scan. The corresponding
collector current is measured by an electrometer and then digitized. The
straight line portion is the retarding region, and the logarithmic slope
determines the electron temperature by the relation:
 
       e        Delta(V)
Te = - -  --------------------
       k   Delta( log (- Ie) )
 
where e is the electron charge; k, the Boltzmann constant; and Ie, the
electron current.  The left side with larger positive voltage is the
attractive region.  The voltage Vp at which these two portions of the
curve join is the potential of plasma relative to spacecraft.  Vp is
expected to vary from a few volts negative in interplanetary space to 1
or 2 V positive in the Venusian ionosphere.  For the simulation it was
set to zero. The lower portion of the curve bends away from the
straight-line portion because the velocity distribution is not a true
Maxwellian distribution.  An additional population of suprathermal
electrons exists with higher energies than the thermal distribution.
 
 
   High Resolution Ions:
 
The algorithm that scans the data in an ion I-V curve and computes
the initial estimates of the ion quantities must also make a decision
as to what ion mass is represented by a peak in DI [Knudsen et al.,
1979; 1980]. The voltage at which the DI peak occurs for a given mass
may be substantially smaller or larger than the nominal value because
the Venus ionosphere is moving relative the planet with a velocity
that can approach that of the spacecraft.  Consequently, some peaks
in DI have been assigned the wrong mass. The result is not only an
erroneous concentration for that mass but also an erroneous ion
velocity and total ion density. It is possible to recognize the
incorrect assignments when comparing several I-V curves which are
adjacent to each other in time, but the analysis algorithms are not
this sophisticated. A few errors in ion quantities are present in the
PDS files resulting from this difficulty. The uncertainties in the
ion fitting process are included in an ancillary file.
 
  High Resolution Suprathermal Electrons:
 
The analysis of a suprathermal electron I-V curve is similarly
difficult. The interpretation of the electron distributions
contributing to the I-V curve depends on the potential of the
spacecraft relative to the ambient plasma which, in turn, depends on
the location of the spacecraft and the properties of the ambient
plasma. The spacecraft is negative in the dense ionospheric plasma.
It is positive in the low density solar wind plasma provided the
spacecraft is not in the umbra of the planet. An additional
complication arises in that the sign of the current to the
electrometer occasionally changes from negative to positive during a
sweep. This can occur because the background current, with maximum
retarding potential applied to the retarding grids, is compensated
close to the noise level of the electrometer just before the sweep
begins [Knudsen et al., 1979]. If the background current that has
been compensated is significant relative to the saturation current
and changes in the right direction during the ensuing sweep, the
total current will go through zero and the sign change. The
background current can change because the orientation of the rotating
spacecraft relative to the sun changes, because a purely temporal
change occurs or because the location of the spacecraft changes.
Switching of the current from one sign to the other with the
electrometer in its most sensitive mode produces a noise spike in
-the electrometer that is digitized and becomes part of-the I-V
curve. Writing an algorithm that recognizes the noise spike and the
change in current sign is difficult because the sign of only the
saturation current and background current of a sweep has been
retained in the I-V data for reasons of minimizing the telemetry
requirements of the RPA. A trained observer, looking at an I-V plot,
can rather quickly recognize in most cases when this condition has
occurred, but it is difficult to write an algorithm that can
recognize all the possible situations and make the necessary
adjustments.
 
   Low Resolution Data:
 
The PV PDS LFD SEDR tapes have time tags at 12 second intervals from
30 minutes prior to periapsis to 30 minutes after periapsis. These
time tags are the tags specified in the first four quantities of each
of the EDR data records. All PV instruments are to report their data
at these common time tags for the purpose of easy intercomparison of
data. Principal Investigators (PIs) with instruments with a sampling
period much less that 12 seconds are to report the average of
measured quantities over a 12 second interval centered on the time
tags. The RPA, because of a low telemetry word assignment, records at
most one current-voltage (I-V) characteristic curve per spacecraft
spin period.  Except for one set of 14 orbits, the spin period of the
PV spacecraft has been about 12 seconds. Thus, RPA physical
quantities are derived at intervals of 12 seconds or more. Since the
RPA operates in several modes, a particular quantity such as thermal
electron temperature may be typically measured at much longer
intervals. The thermal electron temperature is typically measured at
either approximately 48 or 60 second intervals. In a few orbits, it
was measured at 12 second intervals.
 
The quantities TOTI,- H+, O+, M29+, CO2+, TI, VX, VY, VZ, N1, TL, N2,
and T2 are derived by least-squares fitting a strongly non-linear
numerical algorithm to an I-V curve. It is necessary in performing
such a fit to supply an initial estimate of the quantities that are
to be derived. If the estimates are not sufficiently close to the
true least-squares values, the algorithm may yield a grossly
erroneous value by converging to a relative minimum of the variance
and not to the absolute minimum. Also, it may not converge at all.
Although some such erroneous values have been eliminated from our
basic tables tapes by checking for the magnitude of the variance,
some erroneous value are known to be present. Such values can be way
outside the nominal uncertainty quoted in Table 1.
 
ASCII low resolution data are included as part of the high resolution
data archive to facilitate browsing of the key parameters of the
dataset.
 
Missing values:
 
RPA quantities may be unavailable for assigning to a specific time
tag for several reasons as follows: The spacecraft data format in use
at the time may not have contained any words for the RPA. The RPA may
have been turned off for power conservation reasons. The spacecraft
telemetry bit rate and/or data format may have been such that an RPA
I-V curve was recorded only at long time intervals. RPA data for an
interval of time, including the time tag, has not been reduced. (RPA
data at the time of this submission have been reduced for only a
small time interval about periapsis: plus and minus approximately 15
minutes for the first 800 orbits, plus and minus approximately 30
minutes for orbits 800-1300, plus and minus 60 minutes for orbits
1300-2890.)
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
Some of the quantities contained in this submittal of RPA data to the
PDS are erroneous because of bad least-squares fits to the I-V
curves.  These bad fits have not been detected by our current
algorithms for reduction of the data and have not been removed by a
trained observer viewing the I-V curves and making an educated
judgment.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>1978-051A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XD-B3A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

