<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.co-e-j-s-sw-caps-2-uncalibrated-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CASSINI E/J/S/SW CAPS UNCALIBRATED V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:caps.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.saturn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:plasma_stream.solar_wind::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.co-e-j-s-sw-caps-2-uncalibrated-v1.0__browserp_co-e-j-s-sw-caps-2-uncalibrated-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Furman, J., F. Crary, and S.P. Joy, CAPS standard data products and archive
                   volume software interface specification, Version 1.9, JPL SIS ID: IO-AR-017,
                   Southwest Research Institute, San Antonio, TX 78250, 2005.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FURMANETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Young, D.T., J.J. Berthelier, M. Blanc, J.L. Burch, A.J. Coates, R. Goldstein,
                   M. Grande, T.W. Hill, R.E. Johnson, V. Kelha, D.J. McComas, E.C. Sittler, K.R.
                   Svenes, K. Szego, P. Tanskanen, K. Ahola, D. Anderson, S. Bakshi, R.A.
                   Baragiola, B.L. Barraclough, R.K. Black, S. Bolton, T. Booker, R. Bowman, P.
                   Casey, F.J. Crary, D. Delapp, G. Dirks, N. Eaker, H. Funsten, J.D. Furman, J.T.
                   Gosling, H. Hannula, C. Holmlund, H. Huomo, J.M. Illiano, P. Jensen, M.A.
                   Johnson, D.R. Linder, T. Luntama, S. Maurice, K.P. McCabe, K. Mursula, B.T.
                   Narheim, J.E. Nordholt, A. Preece, J. Rudzki, A. Ruitberg, K. Smith, S. Szalai,
                   M.F. Thomsen, K. Viherkanto, J. Vilppola, T. Vollmer, T.E. Wahl, M. Weust, T.
                   Ylikorpi and C. Zinsmeyer, Cassini Plasma Spectrometer Investigation, Space
                   Sci. Rev. 114, 1-112, 2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.YOUNGETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CO-E/J/S/SW-CAPS-2-UNCALIBRATED-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CASSINI E/J/S/SW CAPS UNCALIBRATED V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1999-01-04T00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JUDITH D. FURMAN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>Unknown</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set consists of all of the uncalibrated data collected
            by the Cassini Plasma Spectrometer on-board the CO spacecraft
            during the entire mission. For more information about the
            instrument and data sets, see [YOUNGETAL2004] and
            [FURMANETAL2005].
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>Unknown</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
     This data set consists of all of the uncalibrated data collected by the
     Cassini Plasma Spectrometer (CAPS) on-board the Cassini spacecraft
     during the entire Cassini mission.  CAPS produces the following data
     products:
     Electron Spectrometer data (ELS)
     Ion Beam Spectrometer data (IBS)
     Ion Mass Spectrometer ion data (ION)
     Ion Mass Spectrometer singles data (SNG)
     Ion Mass Spectrometer logicals data (LOG)
     Ion Mass Spectrometer &apos;time of flight&apos; (TOF) linear electric field (LEF)
       and straight through data (ST)
     Actuator data (ACT)
     Ancillary information (ANC)
 
     These data were acquired in a mix of CAPS operating modes beginning with
     the first instrument checkout in January 1999 and continuing throughout
     the Cassini Tour and through the end of prime mission.  The data set
     covers the time period from 1999-004T03:07:47 UT until end of prime
     mission (July 2008).  In addition, it will cover any data received
     during an extended mission.  Sampling rates were variable and depended
     upon the downlink capabilities and other activities on-board.
 
     For times when CAPS is not producing data due to being turned off or
     due to communication issues, the data set will not contain data.
     This effect can be sensor/data type specific.
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
     Data Sampling
     -------------
       Data acquistion strategies varied throught the mission.  During the
       cruise phase, the instrument was only capable of 2 distinct rates. In
       addition, the spacecraft telemetry modes were not fully developed
       which lead to peculiar recording strategies as well.  As the mission
       progressed, the flight software for both the CAPS instrument and the
       Cassini spacecraft matured.  During the Jupiter period, the spacecraft
       implemented data policing, where an instrument was assigned a data
       allocation and the spacecraft would not record any more data from an
       instrument who had reached their negotiated limit.  This strategy was
       useful during the planning process, but careful control had to be
       exercised to not run over the allocation.  Data gaps in the CAPS data
       can come from a variety of sources:  instrument was off, specific
       sensors were off, ground communication problems, CAPS over-allocation
       issues, the instrument was in sleep mode for Probe activities, or
       there was a problem with commanding on-board the spacecraft.
 
       During the cruise phase, the average data rate for CAPS was low.  If
       at all possible, the instrument was set to cycle between our lowest
       rate in order to get contiguous data) and a higher rate (for higher
       resolution data).  The combined high &amp; low rate were designed to give
       us the average low rate data.  This scheme did not change as we
       entered Approach Science and Tour, but the average data rate was
       increased.  In addition to running in survey mode, we also acquired
       data in higher resolution modes around Magnetospheric boundaries,
       Titan flybys, icy satellite flybys, ring &amp; satellite campaigns, and
       distant torus observations.   n addition, any data volume allocation
       that was not allocated to other instruments was distributed to those
       who could take advantage of the increase in data volume (and hence
       data resolution).
 
       At the maximum CAPS telemetry rate of 16 kbits/s all data products
       coming out of the science and calibration modes can be accommodated
       without the need for compression. The exception is the compressed
       extraction of ions by the SAM algorithm, and a semi-logarithmic
       collapse of all data words. The collapse replaces 16-bit data words
       stored in the DPU with 8-bit data words to be returned to Earth.  For
       small data numbers, the 8-bit values are equal to the 16-bit values,
       but for higher values the scale is logarithmic. A similar 32- to
       16-bit compression is used for TOF data. As a result of this
       compression, the uncertainty in the higher data numbers is
       roughly +/- 0.015N rather than the statistical +/- N^(1/2).  No
       attempt was made to carry out more exotic on-board compression
       routines such as moment calculations or image-like compressions, with
       the exception of a run-length compression of the sparse, IBS data.
 
       The contents of the CAPS data products at 16 kbits/s are distributed
       among the three sensors, the ACT and housekeeping channels as
       indicated below.  Data products are organized along A-cycle (32.0 s)
       boundaries. Acquisition and formation of B-cycle data products is
       more complex than the A-cycle process: The CPU2 extracts TOF data in
       the form of 512 channels each of ST and LEF data.  In the default
       mode, adjacent energy steps are sampled to produce
       2RES x 32E x 512TOF = 32,768 words. In the standard CAPS telemetry
       mode of 16 kbits/s, each word of B-cycle data is summed over 8
       A-cycles, whereas for some lower rate modes it is summed over 16
       A-cycles (i.e., the B-cycle is 8 A-cycles long for the 16 kbits/s mode
        and 16 A-cycles long for these other modes).  In the
       very early CAPS data, there was even a mode where it is summed over 32
       A-cycles.  Most CAPS data products are generated at lower data rates
       by collapsing (summing) the 16 kbps data over adjacent energy,
       elevation and/or azimuth bins. In addition, snapshots (uncollapsed
       subsets of the 16 kbps data) may be included. The subset of data
       included in the snapshot can be determined on the spacecraft, so that
       the snapshot contains the peak of the velocity distribution. Leaving
       out certain products entirely produces the smallest possible datasets.
       The modes used by the CAPS instrument were revised prior to the
       Cassini Jupiter encounter to include 0.25, 0.5, and 1 kbps rates, in
       addition to the original 2 and 16 kbps modes. These modes were further
       revised before reaching Saturn, to add 4 and 8 kbps modes and
       incorporate experience from analysis of the Jupiter data. Other data
       products that can be included as options (at the expense of sensor
       data) are memory readout of control tables for diagnostic purposes.
       Sequential event data that are used to verify IMS operations can also
       be included.
 
 
         Telemetry products in 16 kbits/s mode
         --------------------------------------
                            Data channels
                       -----------------------
           Product     EQ  EL  AZ  MQ LOG  TOF
         ---------------------------------------
            ELS        63   8  16   .   .    .
            IBS       255   3  16   .   .    .
         IMS ION       63   8   8   7   .    .
         IMS TDC LOG   63   .   8   .   4    .
         IMS TDC SNG   63   8   8   .   .    .
         IMS TOF LEF   32   .   .   .   .  512
         IMS TOF ST    32   .   .   .   .  512
          ACTUATOR         32 position samples
         HOUSEKEEPING     164 bytes of data
         ---------------------------------------
         EQ=energy/charge, EL=elevation,
         AZ=azimuth, MQ=mass/charge, LOG=logical,
         and TOF=time-of-flight
 
       Data are collected as raw counts.  For the ELS sensor, the 63 energy
       steps are swept through every 2 seconds.  For the IBS sensor, the 225
       energy steps are swept through every 2 seconds.  For the IMS sensor,
       the 63 energy steps are swept through every 4 seconds.  To learn more
       about the energy range covered by each of the sensors and any other
       details regarding data acquisition, please see [YOUNGETAL2004].
 
  Processing
  ==========
 
    The uncalibrated counts are collected, collapsed, and compressed on board
    the spacecraft.  The data is then downlinked to the Jet Propulsion Query
    Servers where it is queried from the server (in standard data unit
    format, SFDU) and ingested into the CAPS oracle database and stored as
    CCSDS packets.  From this point, the data is collected into blocks of
    CCSDS packets which comprise an A-cycle (32 seconds) of data.  These
    data are then decompressed into their separate sensor pieces and stored
    as raw, decompressed counts in tables in the database.  From this point,
    archive files are generated with the raw, decompressed counts, into
    uncalibrated data set files.
 
    For the ancillary files (ANC), the reconstructed c-kernel is used to get
    the most accurate pointing information into the file for team use.
    Daily, automated checking is performed to make sure we have the most
    recent files that are available.  Any other information necessary is
    found in the CAPS database, which has been populated from the raw CCSDS
    packets.
 
    For the actuator data product (ACT), in December 2004 the position
    monitor became unreliable.  Based on our understanding of the position
    at the time the monitor failed, the actuator file was updated with an
    estimated value.  This estimation continued until TBD time, at which
    point the actuator was moved and began reporting reliable readings again.
    While trying to move the actuator to +90 degrees on March 21, 2005, we
    again encountered a time period where the position was adjusted to
    account for the monitor reading unreliably.  On May 26, 2005 at 10:00:00,
    the actuator position monitor was modified in the flight software to be
    the estimated position instead of the hardware position.  This data is
    also corrected before being placed into the archive file to account for
    any drift in the estimated position.
 
    For information about the calibrated files, please see the
    CALIBRATED_DATA_SET.CAT.
 
  Data
  ====
    The data are stored in multiple data files and have been organized by
    sensor type, and further subdivided by data type.  Each file contains a
    maximum of 6 hours of data, with only 4 files being generated per day per
    product.  Format of the data files can be found in the CAPS instrument
    archive specification [FURMANETAL2005].  The format can also be found in
    the .FMT files in the FM/UNCALIBRATED directory.  The timestamps,
    position data, and other spacecraft information were processed using
    SPICE kernels.  The Cassini SPICE kernels are archived at TBD.
 
  Coordinate Systems
  ==================
    The data are provided in the instrument frame.  In the ancillary data
    files, you can find the spacecraft orientation, spacecraft-sun position
    and velocity data, and spacecraft-Saturn position and velocity data.
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    Most ancillary data needed can be found in the ANC data file provided
    with the data.  In addition, there are other files that are necessary to
    process the data.  These include sweep tables for each sensor and a table
    of instrument anomalies and resolutions.
 
  References
  ========
    [FURMANETAL2005] CAPS standard data products and archive volume software
       interface specification, Version 1.9, JPL SIS ID: IO-AR-017, Southwest
       Research Institute, San Antonio, TX 78250, 2005.
    [YOUNGETAL2004] Cassini Plasma Spectrometer Investigation, Space Sci.
    Rev. 114, 1-112, 2004.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Review
  ======
    These data have been reviewed by the instrument team and are of the
    highest quality that can be generated at this time. Science results based
    on these data have been published in several journals (Science, Nature,
    JGR, etc.). After submission to the PDS, these data will be approved
    through the peer review process.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
 
    Gaps
    ----
      There are many gaps in the CAPS data stream and there are many
      different sources for these gaps.  Sources of gaps are as follows:
         a. telemety outages
         b. data policing violations (CAPS data volume higher than allocated)
         c. incorrect spacecraft data mangement commanding
         d. telemetry commanding during Cruise
         e. instrument anomalies
         f. instrument modes which don&apos;t return all data products
         g. planned instrument power-off and/or sleep periods
      When there is no data for a time period, one of the above sources is
      the reason behind the gap.  There is no indicator to which of the
      sources is responsible for the gap in data coverage.
 
    Poor Data
    ---------
      When the instrument transmitts the data, there is an associated
      checksum that is checked during decompression.  If the checksum is
      incorrect, the data are flagged as having a &apos;bad checksum&apos;.  The other
      way to get poor data is when we are missing part of the data product
      and use fill data to complete the product.  The data product is then
      labelled as having both a &apos;bad checksum and fill&apos;.  There is an
      inidicator for &apos;no data&apos;, but the indicator does not tell why the data
      is missing.  The &apos;no data&apos; indicator is only used if there is data for
      any of the other sensors. This information can be found in the ancillay
      data file.  Each sensor and/or data type has its own quality flag.
      Fill values for each sensor can be found in [FURMANETAL2005] or in the
      corresponding .FMT file.
 
    Sensor Gains
    ------------
      Sensor gains were set for each sensor based upon calibration
      information determined on the ground.  While in-flight, sensor
      calibrations were performed and adjustments were made to the gain of a
      sensor, based upon interpretation of the data by the team and the
      leader of the sensor.  During the tour phase, calibrations were
      performed roughly once every 50 days.  The change in gain can&apos;t be
      tracked with the current archive data, but is done with
      housekeeping information.
 
    Anomalies
    ---------
      There are currently way to many anomalies to put in at the moment.
      I&apos;ll start working on it.  I plan to describe the time coverage of the
      anomaly, the affect on the data, diagnosis of the problem, and when (if
      at all) we were able to fix the problem.
 
  Limitations
  ===========
      The main limitation to using this data set is that the data are not
      calibrated.  Please use the CALIBRATED data set for calibrated data.
      A secondary limitation is to make sure to use the ancillary data files
      to avoid using any poor data.  In addition, care should be taken around
      calibration periods as the sweep table and gain levels are changing.
      Data around anomaly periods also needs to be carefully considered.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

