<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ear-c-cs2-5-rdr-devico-atlas-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>HIGH SPECTRAL RESOLUTION ATLAS OF COMET 122P/DEVICO</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.support_archives::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.mcd27m::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:cs2.mcd27m::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.122p-devico_1_1846_d1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-c-cs2-5-rdr-devico-atlas-v1.0__browserp_ear-c-cs2-5-rdr-devico-atlas-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Cochran, A.L. and W.D. Cochran, High Spectral Resolution Atlas of Comet
                   122P/deVico, Icarus, 157, 297, 2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.COCHRAN-COCHRAN2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>EAR-C-CS2-5-RDR-DEVICO-ATLAS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>HIGH SPECTRAL RESOLUTION ATLAS OF COMET 122P/DEVICO</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2002-06-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1995-10-03T11:37:30Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1995-10-04T11:42:21Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>ANITA L. COCHRAN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Cochran, A. L., T. Farnham, and A.C. Raugh, HIGH SPECTRAL
            RESOLUTION ATLAS OF COMET 122P/DEVICO,
            EAR-C-CS2-5-RDR-DEVICO-ATLAS-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2002.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Atlas of cometary spectral lines from high resolution
            measurements of comet deVico.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Atlas of cometary spectral lines from high resolution
            measurements of comet deVico.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
 
        A High Spectral Resolution Atlas of Comet 122P/deVico
 
    This data set presents an atlas of 12,219 identified and 4,055
    unidentified spectral lines from high resolution spectra of comet
    122P/deVico.  The spectra were obtained at the McDonald
    Observatory using the 2D Coude cross-dispersed echelle spectrograph
    (CS2) at the Coude f/32.5 focus of the 2.7m Harlan J. Smith telescope.
 
    The CS2 was used in R=60,000 mode through a 1.2x8.2 arcsec slit to
    obtain the observations in this dataset.  Continuous spectral
    coverage was obtained between the wavelengths 3800-5776 Angstroms,
    while increasing interorder gaps are present from 5776-10192
    Angstroms.  In addition to spectra on the optocenter, one spectrum
    was obtained at a point 100 arcsec in the tailward direction.
 
    The atlas identifies lines from five molecular species (C2, C3,
    CH, CN and NH2), two atomic species (O, H) and three ions (CH+,
    CO+ and H2O+), as well as listing the wavelengths of lines that
    were not identified.
 
    The manuscript describing the data set in detail can be found in
    Cochran and Cochran (2002) [COCHRAN&amp;COCHRAN2002].
 
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
    The atlas is presented as a table of spectral lines.  Each entry
    contains the relevant parameters including the wavelength, vacuum
    frequency, species name, electronic band, vibrational transition
    and rotational transition.
 
    Note that the authors devised an encoding scheme for translating
    electronic transition notation, which involves superscipts,
    subscripts, and non-ASCII characters, into a flat ASCII notation
    for use in the data tables.  The description of this transformation
    is in Cochran and Cochran (2002) [COCHRAN&amp;COCHRAN2002].  An HTML-
    formatted excerpt from this document describing the transitional
    states included and the flat ASCII notation used, is included with
    the data set documents.  (HTML format was used to preserve the
    original subscripted and superscripted notation as far as possible.)
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
    Spectra of an incandescent lamp were used to flat field the data,
    and wavelength calibration was done by fitting a two dimensional
    function to observations of a ThAr hollow-cathode lamp.  Over
    3100 lines were fit, with a fourth order fit along an order and
    a fifth order fit across orders, resulting in an rms error of
    2.5 mAngstroms in the wavelength. The spectra presented here are
    doppler shifted by a velocity equal to the comet&apos;s geocentric
    radial velocity, so the listed wavelengths are in the comet&apos;s rest
    frame.  (Telluric lines in the spectrum are, therefore, shifted
    relative to the rest frame.)
 
    Spectra were extracted using variance weighting along the spatial
    dimension, with no attempt to preserve the spatial information.
    Information needed for an absolute calibration was not available,
    so it was not possible to convert the spectra to absolute flux
    units.
 
    The spectra presented here are doppler shifted by a velocity equal
    to the comet&apos;s geocentric radial velocity, so they are in the rest
    frame of the wavelength scale.  (Telluric lines in the spectrum are,
    therefore, shifted relative to the rest frame.)
 
    To minimize introduction of noise into the spectrum, the continuum
    level was not removed.  Fortunately, the high gas-to-dust ratio in
    comet DeVico means that the continuum is essentially negligible at
    all wavelengths.
 
 
    Data
    ====
    The line lists consist of ASCII tables that give the wavelength
    and transition information for each entry, if known.
 
     1) format.dat:   format of line list tables
     2) all.txt:      combined list of all spectral lines
     3) atomic.txt:   list of atomic lines
     4) c2.txt:       list of C2 lines
     5) c3.txt:       list of C3 lines
     6) ch.txt:       list of CH lines
     7) ch_plus.txt:  list of CH+ lines
     8) cn.txt:       list of CN lines
     9) co_plus.txt:  list of CO+ lines
    10) h2o_plus.txt: list of H2O+ lines
    11) nh2.txt:      list of NH2 lines
    12) unid.txt:     list of unidentified lines
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
    In addition to the line lists, this PDS submission includes a
    large number of plots to help put the line lists into a broader
    context.  These plots are presented in two formats.
 
    The first format, given in the &apos;identify&apos; directory, consists of a
    series of plots of each spectral order, with the y scale expanded
    to emphasize the weaker features.  Two spectra are shown in each
    panel, one from 3 October 1995 and the other from 4 October 1995.
    A feature must appear in both spectra to be considered real.
    These &apos;ident&apos; plots also include marks identifying the spectral
    lines, with different species displayed in different colors.
 
    The second series of plots, given in the &apos;context&apos; directory,
    shows the spectral orders with the y axis scaled to the maximum
    strength line in that region.  This allows the relative strengths
    of the strong and weak lines to be compared.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
    The line list tables are given in the form of ASCII files.  These
    tables do not use any sub- or super-script characters, and so are
    readable in any format.  The plots are presented in both pdf and
    postscript format.
 
 
    Spectra
    ========
    The spectra used to generate the atlas have not yet been submitted
    to the PDS for archiving.  Any researcher interested in using the
    spectra should contact Anita Cochran directly (Anita Cochran,
    Department of Astronomy, University of Texas, 78712).
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
    See Cochran and Cochran (2002) [COCHRAN&amp;COCHRAN2002] for a
    discussions of coverage and confidence level.
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
    Spectral coverage is continuous from 3830-5776 Angstroms.  From
    5777-10,192 Angstroms, there are increasing interorder gaps.  There
    is no correction for these gaps, but their locations can be
    estimated using the plots that are included.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
    There was no data to perform an absolute flux calibration of the
    spectra so line strengths are not listed.  The relative line
    strengths within an order (as shown in the plots) are probably
    accurate, but a comparison of lines from different spectral orders
    is less meaninful.
 
    Review
    ======
    A PDS peer review of this data set was held on 6 December 2002.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>PSSB-00141</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

