<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.near-a-nlr-5-eros-shape-gravity-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>NEAR EROS NLR DERIVED PRODUCTS - SHAPE MODEL V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.near_earth_asteroid_rendezvous::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.near::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:nlr.near::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.eros::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.near-a-nlr-5-eros-shape-gravity-v1.0__browserp_near-a-nlr-5-eros-shape-gravity-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Konopliv, A.S., J.K. Miller, W.M. Owen, D.K. Yeomans, J.D. Giorgini, R.
                   Garmier, J.-P. Barriot, &apos;A Global Solution for the Gravity Field, Rotation,
                   Landmarks, and Ephemeris of Eros,&apos; 16th International Symposium on Space
                   Dynamics, Pasadena, CA, USA, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KONOPLIVETAL2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Miller, J.K., A.S. Konopliv, P.G. Antreasian, J.J. Bordi, S. Chesley, C.E.
                   Helfrich, W.M. Owen, D.J. Scheeres, T.C. Wang, B.G. Williams, and D.K. Yeomans,
                   Determination of Shape, Gravity, and Rotational State of Asteroid 433 Eros,
                   Icarus, in press, 2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MILLERETAL2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>NEAR-A-NLR-5-EROS/SHAPE/GRAVITY-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>NEAR EROS NLR DERIVED PRODUCTS - SHAPE MODEL V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2001-09-30</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2001-04-30</start_time>
        <stop_time>2001-08-27</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JAMES MILLER</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Neumann G., Giorgini J.D., Miller J.K., A. Konopliv, and E.
            Grayzeck, NEAR EROS NLR DERIVED PRODUCTS - SHAPE MODEL V1.0,
            NEAR-A-NLR-5-EROS/SHAPE/GRAVITY-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2001.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            NEAR Eros shape/gravity science derived data from NEAR NAV team
            at JPL.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            NEAR Eros shape/gravity science derived data from NEAR NAV team
            at JPL.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
    This file contains a shape model for the asteroid Eros derived from
    NEAR Laser Rangefinder observations. The NLR measurements were made
    over the period 30 April 2000 to 27 August 2000 from orbits of 35
    and 50 km.
 
    The gravity model (16 x 16 elements) obtained from this shape model
    is provided as a separate companion file (&apos;GR_101.TXT&apos;) to this
    file.
 
    The shape model (34 x 34) files and information regarding the file
    formats and contents were kindly supplied by J.K. Miller of the NEAR
    navigation team, in response to user requests made at the NEAR PDS
    archive review.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
    SH_101.TXT    A multi-part table giving X, Y, and Z vertices of the
                  shape model, the plate model, and parameters.
 
    The shape table lists a serial number and coordinates for each
    vertex comprising the plate model of the shape of Eros. The vertex
    numbers are referenced in the following table.
 
    NOTE that the first row of this table contains only a single integer
    in the first column, giving the total number of vertices in the
    table.
 
    The index number of the vertex. This number is used in the plate
    table.
 
    Following rows contain (x,y,z) position of the vertex
 
    The shape table further defines the triangular plates comprising the
    Eros shape model. For each plate three vertices are listed by vertex
    number. The positions corresponding to each vertex number are
    defined in the preceding vertex table.
 
    NOTE: The first row of this table contains only a single integer
          indicating the total number of plates defined.
 
    Subsequent rows have the index number for the triangular plate
    defined along with the index numbers of the three vertices defining
    this plate
 
    Then there is a single-row table contains two constants relating to
    the table of harmonic coefficients: first the degree of the harmonic
    solution. The total number of coefficients in the solution is
    (NDEGREE+1)^2. Second there is a Normalization flag. This value is
    &apos;1&apos;, indicating that the following solution has been fully
    normalized.
 
    The last part of the table lists several parameters and the harmonic
    coefficients constituting the shape model solution. The format, an
    in-house format used by the NAV team, is not tied to logical
    records, but rather makes use of a repeating, 3-column physical
    record structure as needed to hold the various parameters. The
    contents of the rows of the table are as follows:
 
    The first two records contain the volume of the model and the vector
    offset from the center of the shape model to the true center of
    gravity:
 
      Record 1:
        Column 1   Volume in km^3
        Column 2   -blank-
        Column 3   -blank-
 
      Record 2:
        Column 1   Xcg  in km
        Column 2   Ycg  in km
        Column 3   Zcg  in km
 
    The next two record contain the coefficients for the inertia tensor.
    Note that this is a symmetric matrix, so only the unique elements are
    specified here:
 
      Record 3:
        Column 1   Ixx  in km^2
        Column 2   Iyy  in km^2
        Column 3   Izz  in km^2
 
      Record 4:
        Column 1   Ixy  in km^2
        Column 2   Ixz  in km^2
        Column 3   Iyz  in km^2
 
    The subsequent records contain the shape model harmonic coefficients
    Cij and Sij. All the Si0 are = 0, and are thus omitted from this file.
    The remaining coefficients are stored three to a record, in this
    logical sequence:
 
      C00
      C10  C11  S11
      C20  C21  C22  S21  S22
      C30  C31  C32  C33  S31  S32  S33
      etc.
 
    which becomes this physical sequence:
 
      Record 5:  C00  C10  C11
      Record 6:  S11  C20  C21
      Record 7:  C22  S21  S22
      Record 8:  C30  C31  C32
      Record 9:  C33  S31  S32
      etc.
 
    The total number of coefficients stored is (NDEGREE+1)^2, where
    NDEGREE is found as the first integer (i.e., COLUMN 1) in the first
    row of the HDR_TABLE, above,
 
    The last record in the file contains only a single entry in the first
    column.
 
    GR_101.TXT  ASCII coefficients for the gravity model.
 
    The gravity model table starts as one row with three integer
    parameters: The degree of the harmonic solution presented and two
    processing flags. The degree of the harmonic solution, i.e., the
    number of harmonic cooefficient stored in this file is
    (NDEGREE+1)^2. The first flag indicating that the result has been
    normalized. It is equal to &apos;1&apos;.  A second flag as an internal
    processing flag, equal to &apos;1&apos;
 
    Next this table lists the various parameters and harmonic
    coefficients of the gravity solution. The format, an in-house format
    used by the NAV team, is not based on logical records, but rather
    makes use of a repeating, 3-number physical record structure as
    needed to hold the various parameters. The contents of the rows of
    the table are as follows.
 
    The first two records contain general model parameters:
 
      Record 1:
        Column 1   Volume in km^3 of the model
        Column 2   Density in g/cm^3 (assumed constant)
        Column 3   Mass in kg
 
      Record 2:
        Column 1   The gravitational potential, GM, in km^2/s^3
        Column 2   R0, the average radius used in the model - in this case
                   selected to be the maximum radius
        Column 3   -blank-
 
    The next two records contain the coefficients for the inertia tensor.
    Note that this is a symmetric matrix, so only the unique elements are
    specified here:
 
      Record 3:
        Column 1   Ixx  in km^2
        Column 2   Iyy  in km^2
        Column 3   Izz  in km^2
 
      Record 4:
        Column 1   Ixy  in km^2
        Column 2   Ixz  in km^2
        Column 3   Iyz  in km^2
 
    The subsequent records contain the gravitational harmonic coefficients
    Cij and Sij. All the Si0 are = 0, and are thus omitted from this file.
    The remaining coefficients are stored three to a record, in this
    logical sequence:
 
      C00
      C10  C11  S11
      C20  C21  C22  S21  S22
      C30  C31  C32  C33  S31  S32  S33
      etc.
 
    which becomes this physical sequence:
 
      Record 5:  C00  C10  C11
      Record 6:  S11  C20  C21
      Record 7:  C22  S21  S22
      Record 8:  C30  C31  C32
      Record 9:  C33  S31  S32
      etc.
 
    The total number of coefficients stored is (NDEGREE+1)^2, where
    NDEGREE is found as the first integer in the first row of the file
    (that is, in column 1 of the INTEGER_TABLE defined above).
 
    The last record in the file contains only a single entry in the first
    column.
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
    The shape model include both a triangular plate model and a set
    of spherical harmonics. The plate model is comprised of two lists:
    a list of (x,y,z) vertex positions relative to the center of the
    model; and a list of the triples of vertices defining each of the
    triangular plate.
 
    The spherical harmonics are provided as a set of coefficients
    with corresponding values for volume, center-of-gravity offset
    and the inertia tensor (KONOPLIVETAL2001, MILLERETAL2002).
 
    The gravity model obtained by integrating this shape model is
    provided as a separate companion file (&apos;gr_101.dat&apos;) to this
    file in the same form as the shape model.
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      None.
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
    The Eros coordinate system is defined as follows: prime meridian
    fixed at 326.06 deg, IAU 1994 right ascension at 11.369 deg,
    declination at 17.227 degrees, and rotation rate at 1639.38885
    deg/day.
 
    Software
    ========
      None.
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      CD
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this archive have been reduced as part of mission data
      analysis activities of the NEAR Navigation Team.  Data of
      questionable validity have been omitted from the solutions.
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was not reviewed by the NEAR NLR or RSS
      Teams prior to submission to the Planetary Data System (PDS).
      It was not one of the data sets included in a comprehensive
      review by the PDS Small Bodies Node in August 2001.   Instead
      a separate onlinbe review was performed for PDS acceptance.
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      The data included in this archive were collected during the
      NEAR orbital phase from 2000-04-30 to 2000-08-27.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      None.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>1996-008A-4</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

