<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.di-iras-c-fpa-5-9p-images-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DEEP IMPACT: IRAS IMAGES OF COMET 9P/TEMPEL 1</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_impact::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.infrared_astronomical_satellite::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.iras::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:fpa.iras::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.9p-tempel_1_1867_g1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.di-iras-c-fpa-5-9p-images-v1.0__browserp_di-iras-c-fpa-5-9p-images-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Aumann, H.H., J.W. Fowler, and M. Melnyk, A Maximum Correlation Method
                   Image Construction of IRAS Data, 2003, AJ, 99, 1674-1681.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.AUMANNETAL1990</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Beichman, C.A., G. Neugebauer, H.J. Habing, P.E. Clegg, and T.J. Chester,
                   1988, Infrared Astronomical Satellite Catalog and Atlases, Volume 1,
                   Explanatory Supplement, NASA RP-1190.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BEICHMANETAL1988</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Calabretta, M.R. and Greisen, E.W., 2002, Representations of Celestial
                   Coordinates in FITS, Astronomy and Astrophysics, 395, 1077-1122.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CALABRETTA-GREIS2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Greisen, E.W., and Calabretta, M.R., 2002, Representations of World
                   Coordinates in FITS, Astronomy and Astrophysics, 395, 1061-1075.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GREISEN-CALABRET2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Melnyk, M. and Rice, W., 1991, High Resolution Processing, IPAC User&apos;s
                   Guide, Edition 4, Part VI, California Institute of Technology.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MELNYK-RICE1991</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Melnyk, M., 1990, Technical Reference to the Full Resolution Survey
                   Coadder (FRESCO), IPAC User&apos;s Guide,Edition 4, Part VR, California
                   Institute of Technology.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MELNYK1990</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Wheelock, S.L., T.N. Gautier III, J. Chillemi, D. Kester, H. McCallon, C.
                   Oken, J. White, D. Gregorich, F. Boulanger, J. Good, and T. Chester, 1994,
                   IRAS Sky Survey Atlas Explanatory Supplement, JPL Publication 94-11
                   (Pasadena: JPL).
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.WHEELOCKETAL1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   YOUNG, E.T., G. NEUGEBAUER, E.L. Kopan, R.D. Benson, T.P. Conrow, W.L.
                   Rice, and D.T. Gregorich, A User&apos;s Guide to IRAS Pointed Observation
                   Products, IPAC Preprint No. PRE-008N, 1985.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.YOUNGETAL1985</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DI/IRAS-C-FPA-5-9P-IMAGES-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DEEP IMPACT: IRAS IMAGES OF COMET 9P/TEMPEL 1</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2003-10-30</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1983-06-18</start_time>
        <stop_time>1983-10-08</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STEPHANIE MCLAUGHLIN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Walker, R.W. and S.A. McLaughlin, IRAS IMAGES OF 9P/TEMPEL 1
            REPROCESSED FOR DEEP IMPACT V1.0, DI/IRAS-C-FPA-5-9P-IMAGES-V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 2003.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Reprocessed IRAS images from 1983 of Comet 9P/Tempel 1 in support
            of the NASA Deep Impact Mission
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains radiance and noise maps based on
            reprocessed IRAS images from 1983 of comet 9P/Tempel 1 in support
            of the NASA Deep Impact Mission.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  This data set description was prepared by Stephanie McLaughlin and
  is based on the documentation provided by Russell Walker and
  included in this archive.
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
 
    This data set contains radiance and noise maps based on reprocessed
    images of comet 9P/Tempel 1 acquired by IRAS during months before
    and after its perihelion on July 9, 1983.  The purpose of this data
    set is to archive the maps that will be used for photometry of the
    dust coma of Tempel 1, in support of the NASA Deep Impact Mission.
 
    IRAS spent the majority of its observing time in the survey mode
    that systematically mapped the sky with a series of overlapping and
    and confirming scans (Wheelock et al. 1994 [WHEELOCKETAL1994]).
    However, IRAS also devoted time to making pointed observations of
    selected fields of interest (Young et al. 1985 [YOUNGETAL1985]).
    IRAS observations were acquired by its Focal Plane Array, a
    multi-wavelength detector with spectral bands centered nominally
    at 12, 25, 60, and 100 microns (Beichman et al. 1988
    [BEICHMANETAL1988]).
 
    To support analysis of the dust coma of comet 9P/Tempel 1, Russell
    Walker queried the IRAS data archives held at the Infrared Processing
    and Analysis Center (IPAC).  He determined that the IRAS Additional/
    Pointed Observations (AO) and the IRAS Sky Survey Atlas (ISSA)
    contained mages of the comet. He extracted both sets of observations,
    then pplied a different method to each set to produce the radiance and
    noise maps.  Walker also extracted images from the ISSA Reject Set,
    contaminated by zodiacal light, that show the dust trail of Tempel 1.
    These trail images are included in this data set as JPEG files for
    future reference.
 
 
  Additional (Pointed) Observations
  =================================
 
    Processing
    -----------
 
      This data set contains the radiance and noise maps for reprocessed
      AO observations at 12, 25, 60, and 100 microns for the following
      five combinations of IRAS satellite observation plans (SOP) and
      observation numbers (OBS):
 
        SOP  OBS   UTC Date
        ---  ---   ---------------------------
        287   13   1983-06-18, pre-perihelion
        407   12   1983-08-17, post-perihelion
        407   43   1983-08-17, post-perihelion
        509   40   1983-10-07, post-perihelion
        510   22   1983-10-08, post-perihelion
 
      Perihelion occurred at UTC 1983-07-09T19:08:11 (Julian date
      2445525.2973512).  The explanatory supplement for AO provides
      tables that further describe the details of the observations.
 
      Images of the comet were selected from the IRAS AO archive,
      then processed by IPAC&apos;s HIRES, LAUNDR, and YORIC algorithms to
      construct resolution-enhanced, co-added, images of the observed
      fields (Melnyk and Rice 1991 [MELNYK&amp;RICE1991], Melynk 1990
      [MELNYK1990], and Aumann et al. 1990 [AUMANNETAL1990]).
 
    The IPAC YORIC algorithm uses an iterative process to make
    progressively better models of the sky.  Surface brightness (radiance)
    and noise maps were produced for 20 iterations.  For this data set,
    the first iteration and final, best, twentieth iteration of the
    radiance and noise maps were provided for each AO and spectral band
    combination.  For each radiance map, the effective resolution table
    generated by YORIC was provided.  These tables show how the effective
    resolution or beam size varies across the final reprocessed image.
 
      All AO radiance and noise images are 241 x 241 square, 15-arcsecond
      pixels.  Each image size is about 1 degree by 1 degree but the IRAS
      scan is only about 30 arcminutes wide and therefore does not fill
      the image area.  Image array elements that lie outside the scanned
      area havea value of -9999.0.
 
    The comet is not centered in an AO image.  The B1950_RIGHT_ASCENSION
    and B1950_DECLINATION in the PDS label identify the location of the
    target.  The images have a Plate Carree projection for right ascension
    and declination.  For a discussion of Plate Carree, see Calabretta
    and Greisen 2002 [CALABRETTA&amp;GREIS2002] and Greisen and Calabretta
    2002 [GREISEN&amp;CALABRET2002].
 
      A detailed description of the reduction methodology is described
      in the explanatory supplement included with this data set.  PDS
      strongly recommends all users read the supplement before using
      this data set.
 
    Parameters
    ----------
 
      The naming convention for the radiance and noise map images is
      sSOP_oOBS_BANDum_ITERATION_TYPE.fit, where SOP is the satellite
      operations plan number, OBS is the observation number, BAND is
      the band wavelength in microns, ITERATION is the processing
      iteration number, and TYPE identifies a radiance or noise map.
      A similar naming convention is used for the effective resolution
      tables:  sSOP_oOBS_BANDum_ITERATION_effres.tab.
 
      Radiance and noise map images are in units of in-band radiance,
      Watts/cm^2/steradian.  The noise maps provide the standard deviation
      of contributions to each pixel and can be used to the show the
      relative noise across an image.  The noise maps do not give the
      absolute level of the photometric noise.
 
 
  Sky Survey Scans
  ================
 
    Processing
    -----------
 
      This data set contains radiance and noise maps reconstructed from
      sets of Survey Scans at 12, 25, 60, and 100 microns.  The IRAS
      mean satellite operations plan (SOP) number identifies a specific
      survey scan:
 
        Mean SOP   Mean UTC Date
        --------   ---------------------------
          339      1983-07-14, post-perihelion
          368      1983-07-28, post-perihelion
          389      1983-08-08, post-perihelion
          421      1983-08-24, post-perihelion
          493      1983-09-28, post-perihelion
 
      Perihelion occurred at UTC 1983-07-09T19:08:11 (Julian date
      2445525.2973512).  The Explanatory Supplement for Survey Scans
      document, archived with this data set, provides tables that further
      describe the details of the observations.
 
      IRAS spent the majority of its observing time in the survey mode
      that systematically mapped the sky with a series of overlapping and
      confirming scans.  This redundancy can be used to produce an image of
      fainter limiting magnitudes to improve the spatial resolution in the
      scanned fields.
 
      Walker searched the ISSA and identified scans which contained
      Tempel 1.  He developed and used a computer algorithm based on the
      Maximum Correlation Method (Aumann et al. 1990 [AUMANNETAL1990])
      and similar to the IPAC HIRES program (Melynk and Rice, 1991
      [MELNYK&amp;RICE1991]), to construct radiance and noise maps from sets
      of overlapping scans.  The major departure from the IPAC scheme
      occurs when the coordinates of each data sample are transformed
      to a moving Sun-referenced coordinate system with the comet at
      the origin.
 
      Like the IPAC scheme, the algorithm iteratively builds better sky
      models, saving statistics relating to pixel noise and convergence
      for each iteration.  A typical image will converge after 15 to 40
      iterations.  The radiance and noise maps from the first iteration
      and the final, best iteration were provided for survey scan and
      band combination.  The radiance maps are surface brightness images.
      The noise maps are images of the standard deviation of the radiance
      in a pixel as a result of averaging overlapping detector samples.
 
    All ISSA radiance and noise maps are 150 x 75 pixels.  The square,
    24-arcsecond pixels yield an image size of about 1.0 x 0.5 degrees.
    The images were constructed by referencing the samples to the orbital
    position of the comet at the time of the sample.  Thus, the comet is
    always located in the center of the image.  Since a map was constructed
    from several scans, it is a time-averaged image of the emission history
    of the comet.
 
      A detailed description of the reduction methodology is described
      in the explanatory supplement included with this data set.  PDS
      strongly recommends all users read the supplement before using
      this data set.
 
    Parameters
    ----------
 
      The naming convention for ISSA radiance and noise maps is
      sSOP_BANDum_ITERATION_TYPE.fit where SOP is the satellite operations
      plan number, BAND is the band wavelength in microns, ITERATION is the
      processing iteration number, and TYPE identifies a radiance or noise
      map.
 
      The radiance and noise map images are in units of in-band radiance,
      Watts/cm^2/steradian.  The noise maps provide the standard deviation
      of contributions to each pixel and can be used to the show the
      relative noise across an image.  The noise maps do not give the
      absolute level of the photometric noise.
 
 
  Data
  ====
 
    The AO and ISSA radiance and noise images are provided as FITS files
    with attached FITS headers and detached PDS labels.  The AO effective
    resolution data are provided as fixed-width, ASCII tables with
    detached PDS labels.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
 
    While searching the ISSA, 56 images that show the dust trail
    of comet 9P/Tempel 1 were discovered and extracted.  Mark Sykes
    (PDS-SBN) concluded that the reduction level of these data is
    such that the images should not be used for surface photometry
    of the trail.  Therefore, the images were converted from
    FITS to JPEG and included in this data set only as documentation
    for future reference.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
 
    For OA images, the coordinate system is FK4, equatorial right
    ascension and declination in the B1950 coordinate frame.
    North is up and East is to the left when an AO image is
    displayed using the values for SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION and
    LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION.  The projected direction to the Sun is
    towards the upper left corner of the image.
 
    For ISSA images, the coordinate system is solar elongation and
    inclination of the observation which is the natural coordinate
    system for IRAS.  Solar elongation is the angle between the line
    of site and the Sun.  Inclination is the azimuth angle about the
    Earth-Sun axis (that is, the angle between the ecliptic plane
    and the plane containing the Earth, Sun, and observing direction).
    The inclination, measured when facing the Sun, increases clockwise,
    from 0 to 360 degrees, around the Earth-Sun axis.  An inclination
    of 0 degrees indicates IRAS is looking at the ecliptic plane and
    in the direction opposite to the motion of the Earth.  The inclination
    is 90 degrees when IRAS is over north ecliptic pole and 180 degrees
    when IRAS is looking at the ecliptic plane in the direction of the
    motion of the Earth.  The inclination angle increases opposite the
    direction of IRAS&apos;s polar orbit about Earth.  The documentation
    for the survey scans includes an illustration of this IRAS-specific
    coordinate system.
 
    North is down and East is to the right when an ISSA image is
    displayed using the values for SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION and
    LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION.  The projected direction to the Sun is
    towards the lower right corner of the image.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
 
    This data set is released as a logical data volume.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    1) Although the first iteration of radiance and noise maps are provided
       for each Additional Observations and Sky Survey Scans, the final
       iteration should be used for photometry and analysis.
 
    2) Although the noise maps do not provide the absolute level of the
       photometric noise, these data can be used to show the relative
       noise across an image.
 
    3) Images in this data set were used extensively by the Deep Impact
       science team to develop a model of the dust coma of Tempel 1.
       These data were reviewed during an external peer review in
       October 2003 and were approved for ingestion into the PDS, pending
       the resolution of liens.  Liens were resolved in August 2005.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

