<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.near-a-nlr-5-cdr-eros-orbit-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>NEAR NLR LEVEL 2 DATA PRODUCTS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.near_earth_asteroid_rendezvous::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.near::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:nlr.near::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.eros::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.near-a-nlr-5-cdr-eros-orbit-v1.0__browserp_near-a-nlr-5-cdr-eros-orbit-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.near-a-nlr-5-cdr-eros-orbit-v1.0__browser_geo_near-a-nlr-5-cdr-eros_orbit-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.near-a-nlr-5-cdr-eros-orbit-v1.0__dvo_geo_near-a-nlr-5-cdr-eros_orbit-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Cheng, A.F., O. Barnouin-Jha, L. Prockter, M.T. Zuber, G. Neumann, D.E. Smith,
                   J. Garvin, M. Robinson, J. Veverka, and P. Thomas, Small Scale Topography of
                   433 Eros from Laser Altimetry and Imaging, Icarus, in press, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CHENGETAL2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>NEAR-A-NLR-5-CDR-EROS/ORBIT-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>NEAR NLR LEVEL 2 DATA PRODUCTS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2001-07-16</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2000-03-05T00:00:04Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2001-02-12T19:42:43Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID E. SMITH</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Neumann G., and D.E. Smith, NEAR NLR LEVEL 2 DATA PRODUCTS V1.0,
            NEAR-A-NLR-5-CDR-EROS/ORBIT-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2001.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            NLR Level 2 Data Products include
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            NLR Level 2 Data Products include the along-track profiles of NLR
            data in SI units, together with spacecraft position, orientation,
            and timing data.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
    The NEAR Laser Rangefinder (NLR) Level 2 Data Products include
    the along-track profiles of NLR data in SI units, together with
    spacecraft position, orientation, and timing data. The radius of
    433 Eros with respect to its center of mass is the primary profile
    parameter.
 
    Surface slope and topographic relief are not as easily defined on an
    irregular object as on the Earth. We provide the geopotential
    arising from the mass of the asteroid and its rotation, based on the
    NLR shape model NLR125AR.IMG, a rotation rate of 3.3166E-04 rad s^(-
    1), and an assumed homogeneous density of 2670 kg m^(-3).
    Geophysical studies may use the potential as a proxy for topographic
    height, scaled by a regional average gravitational acceleration
    [CHENGETAL2001].
 
    Ranges from level 1 NLR data are the source of the level 2 data
    product. Precision orbits were generated at NASA-GSFC, and
    supplemented where appropriate by JPL navigation team orbits,
    ancillary timing and attitude information supplied by the NEAR SDC
    and instrument data derived from in-flight analysis. These data were
    merged to create the calibrated profile data. Each level 2 data
    product is a text format table corresponding to a daily level 1 EDR
    file, and is described by a detached label. The file naming
    convention is LyydddNv.TAB, where L=laser, and yyddd contains the
    two-digit year and the three-digit day of observation. The letter v
    stands for processing version. Version &apos;D&apos; is based on the most
    recent JPL navigation team orbits, version &apos;G&apos; and &apos;J&apos; on GSFC&apos;s
    precision orbit series 393, where version &apos;J&apos; is supplemented by JPL
    orbits at times of spacecraft maneuvers. There is only one version
    of the data for each specific orbit on the volume.
 
    The orbital mission phase employed only normal format packets. In
    these packets, the spacecraft mission elapsed time (MET) is recorded
    at the time of the first major frame in the packet. A normal rate
    packet contains up to 56 observations, so that the last observation
    may occur up to 55 seconds after the nominal packet time in the case
    of 1 Hz data. The SPACECRAFT_CLOCK_STOP_COUNT and STOP_TIME values
    reflect the time recorded in the last packet for a given UTC day.
    Thus the last observation may occur later than the nominal
    STOP_TIME.
 
    Parameters
    ==========
    Profiles are tables of longitude, latitude, and radius at the laser
    bounce point, together with time stamps, the spacecraft position, and
    instrument threshold setting.
 
    Processing
    ==========
    Ranges are converted from counts to meters of one-way range from NLR
    to 433 Eros as described in the calibration document NLRCALIB.TXT.
    Precision orbit data for the NEAR-Shoemaker spacecraft is provided
    by the NASA-GSFC analysis team and the JPL navigation team, and is
    archived in the form of SPICE format spacecraft ephemeris (SPK)
    files. The MET time associated with each shot, with minor frame
    given in decimal seconds, is converted to Ephemeris Time in seconds
    past J2000 (ET) using the project&apos;s time conversion (SCLK) file. The
    spacecraft position at the ET shot time is interpolated from the SPK
    file. The spacecraft orientation SPICE file (CK) is resampled at 1-
    second intervals of whole seconds. Its quaternions are convolved
    with a 9-point, centered, finite-impulse-response filter to reduce
    high-rate gyro noise before conversion to matrix form.
 
    The filtered spacecraft orientation matrix transforms vectors from
    the J2000 inertial reference frame to the instrument deck
    (NEAR_SC_BUS_PRIME) frame. Observations are directed toward the
    positive X&apos;-axis in this frame.  A fixed boresight offset with
    respect to this frame is assumed.  The Euler angles of the boresight
    are provided as a SPICE instrument kernel (IK) file, from which a
    transformation matrix from NEAR to NLR frame is derived.
 
    The J2000-to-NLR frame matrix is calculated from the smoothed CK by
    matrix composition.  The one-way time-of-flight from the laser range
    is added to the laser fire time to obtain the bounce point time, and
    the calibrated one-way range vector is projected from the spacecraft
    state at this time along the boresight to obtain the surface bounce
    point position in inertial coordinates with respect to the asteroid
    center of mass.  The inertial position is then rotated to the
    asteroid body-fixed coordinate system using satellite/planet
    position and orientation files (PCK) supplied by the project.
 
    The asteroid-located radius vector is given in both radial
    coordinates and as a Cartesian position vector. The angle subtended
    by the bounce point to NEAR spacecraft position vector and the
    radius vector is calculated. This angle is loosely termed the
    EMISSION_ANGLE, assuming a spherical body. Normally an emission
    angle greater than 90 degrees would indicate a missed shot, but due
    to the irregular shape of 433 Eros, emission angles &gt;120 degrees
    were obtained. The angle subtended by the NEAR to Eros center vector
    and the NEAR to bounce point vector (OFF_NADIR angle) is also
    provided.
 
    Lastly, the potential due to gravity and rotation at the shot
    location is calculated [CHENGETAL2001] assuming a uniform density of
    2670 kg m^-3 and the  NLR125AR.IMG shape model. The potential is
    evaluated via a surface integral over a 2 by 2 degree grid, refined
    to 1/4 by 1/4 degree in the vicinity of the shot.
 
    Data
    ====
      Data are stored on CD-WO volumes. A CD volume was created
      for delivery of data to PDS.
 
      ASCII profiles are stored in the /LEVEL2/TOPO directory with file
      names of the form LyydddNv.TAB, where yy and ddd are numeric year
      and day-of-year, v is a version identifier, and TAB denotes that
      this is an ASCII table.
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      None.
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      NLR data files use an EROS centered body-fixed coordinate
      system with positive east longitude. The transformation from
      inertial (J2000) coordinates to body-fixed is represented by the
      project-supplied SPICE format attitude and orientation files
      used to generate level 2 data products.
 
    Software
    ========
      None.
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The archival data set was written on CD-WO by the NEAR/NLR
      Project.  The CD-WO volumes conform to ISO 9660 Level 2
      standards.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this archive have been reduced as part of mission data
      analysis activities of the NEAR/NLR Science Team.
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was reviewed by the NEAR/NLR Science
      Team prior to final submission to the Planetary Data
      System (PDS).
 
      Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data
      set, key elements of the archive were distributed for
      preliminary review.  These included electronic versions of
      example PDS labels, example data files, CATALOG files, and other
      relevant documentation.  These materials were distributed to
      PDS personnel, the experiment investigator, and others, as
      appropriate.
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
       The data coverage was determined by the orientation of the
       instrument X&apos; axis during science data acquisition by several
       instruments. NLR did not control pointing for the bulk of the
       time, so the coverage is largely unplanned. Nevertheless,
       sufficient density of coverage was obtained in all of the orbit
       phases to resolve topography of features greater than 50 m
       in extent.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The limitations in this data set follow from the quality of
      the execution, which is described above under Data Coverage
      and Quality.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>1996-008A-4</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

