<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.a16l-l-lsrp-2-3-soil-mechanics-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>APOLLO 16 LSRP SOIL MECHANICS DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.apollo_16::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.a16l::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:lsrp.a16l::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.a16l-l-lsrp-2-3-soil-mechanics-v1.0__browserp_a16l-l-lsrp-2-3-soil-mechanics-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.a16l-l-lsrp-2-3-soil-mechanics-v1.0__dvo_a16l-l-lsrp-2-3-soil-mechanics-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Apollo 16 Preliminary Science Report, NASA SP-315, 622 pages, published by
                   NASA, Washingtion, D.C., 1972.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.APOLLO16A1972</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Costes, N.C., G.T. Cohron, and D.C. Moss, Cone penetration resistance test - An
                   approach to evaluating in-place strength and packing characteristics of lunar
                   soils, Proceedings of Second Lunar Science Conference, 3, 1973-1987, M.I.T.
                   Press, 1971.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.COSTESETAL1971</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mitchell, J.K., L.G. Bromwell, W.D. Carrier, III, N.C. Costes, and R.F. Scott,
                   Soil mechanics experiment, Apollo 16 Preliminary Science Report, NASA SP-315,
                   8-1, published by NASA, Washington D.C., 1972.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MITCHELLETAL1972B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Scott, R.E., Apollo program soil mechanics experiment, Final Report California
                   Inst. of Tech., Pasadena, 1975.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SCOTT1975</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>A16L-L-LSRP-2/3-SOIL-MECHANICS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>APOLLO 16 LSRP SOIL MECHANICS DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2011-10-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1972-04-19T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1972-05-12T23:59:59Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID WILLIAMS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            added J.Plescia to because he went well beyond the callMitchell,
            J., D. Carrier, N. Costes, L. Bromwell, D. Williams, and
            J.Plescia, APOLLO 16 LSRP SOIL MECHANICS DATA V1.0,
            A16L-L-LSRP-2/3-SOIL-MECHANICS-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2012.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Tables of raw readings and reduced data from ten runs on 22 April
            1972 of the Lunar Self-Recording Penetrometer (LSRP) on the
            surface of the Moon for the Apollo 16 Soil Mechanics experiment.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset contains tables of raw readings and reduced data
            from ten runs on 22 April 1972 of the Lunar Self-Recording
            Penetrometer (LSRP) on the surface of the Moon for the Apollo 16
            Soil Mechanics experiment. Supporting documentation includes
            digitized scans in JPEG and PDF format of the original LSRP soil
            mechanics dataset on microfilm, videos and transcripts of the
            LSRP as it was operated on the Moon, diagrams and maps of the
            experiment areas, and photography of the Apollo 16 Stations 4 and
            10 where the experiment was performed.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This dataset contains tables of raw readings and reduced data from ten
    runs on 22 April 1972 of the Lunar Self-Recording Penetrometer (LSRP)
    on the surface of the Moon for the Apollo 16 Soil Mechanics experiment.
    Supporting documentation includes digitized scans in JPEG and PDF
    format of the original LSRP soil mechanics dataset on microfilm, videos
    and transcripts of the LSRP as it was operated on the Moon, diagrams
    and maps of the experiment areas, and photography of Apollo 16 Stations
    4 and 10 where the experiment was performed.
 
    The Apollo 16 penetrometer runs were done near Station 4, Bench Crater,
    and Station 10, the ALSEP site.  The runs were performed near the end of
    the second EVA (extra-vehicular activity) on 22 April 1972.  The flight
    unit S/N 2004 and lunar drum S/N 2008 were used for all runs.  The
    drum was returned to Earth and the etchings made by the penetrometer
    were read and recorded on hand-written charts by the investigators.
    Copies of the charts were sent to the National Space Science Data
    Center (NSSDC), where they were microfilmed and archived.  For more
    information about the experiment see the Chapter 8 of the Apollo 16
    Preliminary Science Report, which is provided in the DOCUMENT
    directory.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The raw readings and reduced data from each of the ten runs of the
    penetrometer are provided as fixed-width ASCII text tables and are
    reproductions of the lunar penetration data reduction charts, in the
    handwritten LSRP report, which were taken from the penetrometer drum
    returned to Earth.  (The handwritten report was scanned from the
    microfilm archived at the NSSDC.)  The tables are named in the form
    A16_SMSS_72_M016936_nnn.TAB, where A16 denotes Apollo 16, SMSS is for
    soil mechanics, 72 is the year of data acquisition, M016936 is the
    microfilm reel, and nnn is the sequential frame number corresponding
    to a page that contained the data chart in the report.  Each table
    (*.TAB) is accompanied by an ASCII text file (*.TXT) that provides
    the header records for that data chart.  Each table and header
    combination is described by a detached PDS label.
 
    The header records contained in the *.TXT file for a data table
    give the mission, date, flight unit, lunar drum, index number (from
    5 to 16 and designating penetrometer runs 1 to 11), and notes on the
    cone or plate used.  The columns in the data records of a table give
    the drum load (the angle of  deflection of the stylus on the drum) in
    degrees/minutes, the drum load in decimal degrees, the drum
    circumference deflection in  millimeters (decimal degrees multiplied
    by .5542), the load in Newtons (calculated from a calibration curve),
    and the stress in Newtons per square centimeter (load divided by the
    cone or plate base area).  This is the value plotted for stress on
    the plots.  A second set of columns starts with a column labeled
    initial drum depth/final in cm and gives a running total of the drum
    reading.  The next column, delta Drum Depth Reading in cm gives the
    difference between the current drum depth reading and the previous
    value.  The next column, penetration depth in cm, is the drum depth
    reading multiplied by 31.3 (index 5, Apollo 16).
 
    The ten penetrometer runs and associated tables in the DATA directory
    are described below.  The Mission Elapsed Time (MET) and UT values
    were taken from the Apollo Lunar Surface Journal (ALSJ at
    http://history.nasa.gov/alsj/) because the values were not available
    in the mission notes.  The index numbers are from the handwritten
    LSRP report; index 5 is the first one that is available and is
    assigned run number 1.
 
      Station 4, Bench Crater
      -----------------------
        Run 1 - Index 5** - A16_SMSS_72_M016936_017.TAB
        Uphill, south of rover, top part of crater
        18:24:05 UT, 144:30:05 MET
 
        Run 2 - Index 6 - A16_SMSS_72_M016936_019.TAB
        Few meters south of rover near edge of crater
        18:27:00 UT, 144:33:00 MET
 
        Run 3 - Index 7 - A16_SMSS_72_M016936_021.TAB
        Few meters SW of rover near edge of crater
        18:28:12 UT, 144:34:12 MET
 
        Run 4 - Index 8 - A16_SMSS_72_M016936_022.TAB
        Downhill, north of rover, next to double-core tube site
        18:29:24 UT, 144:35:24 MET
 
          ** Indexes 1 through 4 skipped, started on 5
 
      Station 10, ALSEP Site
      ----------------------
        Run 5 - Index 10** - A16_SMSS_72_M016936_024.TAB
        23:00:48 UT, 149:06:48 MET
 
        Run 6 - Index 11 - A16_SMSS_72_M016936_026.TAB
        Using 0.2 tip, next to last penetrometer hole
        23:03:39 UT, 149:09:39 MET (very approximate)
 
        Run 7 - Index 12 - A16_SMSS_72_M016936_028.TAB
        Fourth of the way from the rover to the deep core site, using 0.2 tip
        23:04:45 UT, 149:10:45 MET (very approximate)
 
        Run 8 - Index 13 - A16_SMSS_72_M016936_030.TAB
        Halfway between rover and deep core site, using 0.2 tip
        23:05:50, 149:11:50 MET (very approximate)
 
        Run 9 - Index 14**
        2 to 4 meters towards central station, using 0.2 tip
 
        Run 10 - Index 15 - A16_SMSS_72_M016936_031.TAB
        Using flat plate, near the double core
        23:11:20 UT, 149:17:20 MET (very approximate)
 
        Run 11 - Index 16 - A16_SMSS_72_M016936_032.TAB
        Using flat plate, a couple of meters away
        23:11:45 UT, 149:17:45 MET (very approximate)
 
          ** Index 9 skipped; Index 14 is listed in the ALSJ but the
             corresponding data chart is not in the handwritten LSRP
             report.
 
    Known Problems with Penetrometer Runs
    -------------------------------------
      According to the Apollo 16 Preliminary Science Report [APOLLO16A1972]
      there were some problems with the lunar reference plane riding up the
      penetrometer shaft after initial indexing and positioning.  This
      resulted in an intercept for zero stress on the penetration axis from
      1.9 to 9.0 cm.  The penetration curves will therefore not represent
      soil conditions above the intercept point, but are correct below it.
 
 
  Supplementary Information
  ==========================
    The DOCUMENT directory contains supplementary information about the
    Soil Mechanics experiment, including the following items.
 
    Handwritten LSRP Report
    -----------------------
      In addition to the data tables, it is important to note that the
      handwritten LSRP report includes hand-drawn plots and notes from the
      experiment.  The Stress versus Penetration plots give the stress in
      Newtons per square centimeter versus the penetration depth in
      centimeters on a linear scale.  These are plotted from the data in
      the lunar penetration data reduction tables found in the report and
      in this dataset.  A few of the frames, such as 43, have sections that
      are difficult to read because they were not clear on the microfilm.
      In most cases the information can be read with some difficulty or
      calculated from the surrounding values.
 
      Additionally sets of handwritten notes in the LSRP report give
      information on the sampling locations and other aspects of the
      sampling, including diagrams.  The Post-Flight Calibration plots
      give load in Newtons versus drum circumferential deflection in mm.
      The first plot shows calibrations based on 12 preflight measurements
      and postflight calibrations before and after washing.  The second
      plot gives the postflight penetration calibration of drum movement
      versus actual penetration.  The next four tables give the numbers
      used to make these plots.  The Pre-Flight Calibration section has
      the load versus deflection for the 12 pre-flight calibration runs
      and an enlarged detail of the table which was very faint.  The
      detail includes values which were filled in by enlarging the scans
      and using the legible values on the chart.
 
    Site Diagrams, Maps, and Images
    -------------------------------
      The DOCUMENT directory contains several diagrams and maps of the
      experiment areas including high resolution images taken by the
      Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter Camera of the entire Apollo 16 area
      and the landing site, Station 4, and Station 10.
 
    Videos
    ------
      Most of the index runs of the penetrometer were captured on video
      with audio and are included in the DOCUMENT directory.
 
    Photography
    -----------
      Still photos were taken for the Soil Mechanics experiment and are
      included in the DOCUMENT directory.  Most of the photos apply to
      the index runs performed at Station 4, Bench Crater.  One panoramic
      view of the Station 10 ALSEP site is included.
 
    Annotated Photography of Station 4 Sample Sites
    -----------------------------------------------
      The DOCUMENT directory includes annotated photos taken by the
      astronauts and one mosaic of the site of the four index runs Soil
      Mechanics experiment at Stations 4.
 
    Transcript
    ----------
      Transcripts of the recorded audio commentary as the astronauts
      performed the experiment at Apollo 16 Stations 4 and 10 are included
      in the DOCUMENT directory.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      This data set passed an external peer review that was held on
      9 July 2012.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

