<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.msl-m-rad-2-edr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MSL MARS RADIATION ASSESSMENT DETECTOR EDR</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_science_laboratory::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.msl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rad.msl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.msl-m-rad-2-edr-v1.0__browserp_msl-m-rad-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hassler, D.M., C. Zeitlin, R.F. Wimmer-Schweingruber, S. Bottcher, C. Martin,
                   J. Andrews, E. Bohm, D. E. Brinza, M. A. Bullock, S. Burmeister, B. Ehresmann,
                   M. Epperly, D. Grinspoon, J. Kohler, O. Kortmann, K. Neal, J. Peterson, A.
                   Posner, S. Rafkin, L. Seimetz, K. D. Smith, Y. Tyler, G. Weigle, G. Reitz, and
                   F.A. Cucinotta, The Radiation Assessment Detector (RAD) Investigation, Space
                   Sci. Rev, Vol. 170, pp. 503-558, 2012, doi:10.1007s/11214-012-9913-1
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HASSLERETAL2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MSL-M-RAD-2-EDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MSL MARS RADIATION ASSESSMENT DETECTOR EDR</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2011-11-20T18:16:19.455Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JPL OPGS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            S. Rafkin, J. Peterson, C. Zeitlin, B. Ehresmann, E. Weigle, and
            D.M. Hassler, MSL MARS RADIATION ASSESSMENT DETECTOR EDR V1.0,
            MSL-M-RAD-2-EDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2013.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Mars Science Laboratory Radiation Assessment Detector Experiment
            Data Record
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains the EDR data from the MSL Radiation
            Assessment Detector (RAD) instrument. The EDR data are raw data
            reconstructed from telemetry data products.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
   Data Set Overview
   =================
 
This data set contains data that is useful for determining
the energetic particle environment experienced by the Mars Science
Laboratory rover at the surface of Mars. The EDR data products are
raw data reconstructed from telemetry data products and formatted
according to the RAD EDR Software Interface Specification (EDR
SIS).
 
 
   Processing
   ==========
 
The Committee On Data Management and Computation (CODMAC) data
level numbering system is used to describe the processing level of
the EDR data product.  RAD EDR data products are considered CODMAC Level
2 or Edited Data (equivalent to NASA level 0) products.  The EDR
data files are generated from Level 1 or Raw Data, which are the
telemetry packets.  After stripping away telemetry wrappers, the binary
RAD observational data packets are split into individual data
products and then concatenated in chronological order. The data
are further organized into sols.  Therefore, an EDR data file contains a
single data product from all the RAD observations taken over a
Mars sol, as determined by the start time of the observation. It is
possible that an observation may begin in one sol and extend into
the next, 	but it will be archived only as data within the
starting sol.  If data from one or more sols is incomplete, missing, or
corrupted, the file will exclude these data.  An updated EDR will
be generated if and when the data becomes available.
 
 
   Data
   ====
 
Each RAD EDR product consists of two files.  The first file is an
ASCII formatted detached PDS label. The second file is a binary
data file for a RAD product.  The data in a RAD EDR file is a copy of
what was in the RAD memory buffer. That is, the EDR consists of
unprocessed experiment data stored in binary format.  EDR data products
are of one of two types, as identified in the EDR SIS:
 
   High Priority Science Data = &apos;EHP&apos;
   Science Data = &apos;ESD&apos;
 
 
   Software
   ========
 
No software support is provided.
 
 
   Media/Format
   ============
 
The data set will be delivered and kept online.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
EDR Data have been reviewed by the RAD team to check for data set
completeness and screened for non-physical values such as negative
energy.  RAD finds no obvious errors in the data at this time.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>IN_LIEN_RESOLUTION</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

