<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.vg2-u-lecp-4-summ-scan-24sec-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>VG2 URA LECP RESAMPLED SUMMARY SCAN AVERAGED 24SEC V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.comet_sl9-jupiter_collision::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.voyager::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vg2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:lecp.vg2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.uranus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vg2-u-lecp-4-summ-scan-24sec-v1.0__browserp_vg2-u-lecp-4-summ-scan-24sec-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Krimigis, S.M., J.F. Carbary, E.P. Keath, C.O. Bostrom, W.I. Axford, G.
                   Gloeckler, L.J. Lanzerotti, and T.P. Armstrong, Characteristics of the hot
                   plasma in the Jovian magnetosphere: Results from the Voyager spacecraft,
                   J. Geophys. Res., Vol. 86, p. 8227, 1981.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KRIMIGISETAL1981</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mauk, B.H., S.M. Krimigis, E.P. Keath, A.F. Cheng,
                   T.P. Armstrong, L.J. Lanzerotti, G. Gloeckler, and
                   D.C. Hamilton, The Hot Plasma and Radiation Environment
                   of the Uranian Magnetosphere, Journal of Geophysical
                   Research, 92, 15283, 1987.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MAUKETAL1987</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>VG2-U-LECP-4-SUMM-SCAN-24SEC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>VG2 URA LECP RESAMPLED SUMMARY SCAN AVERAGED 24SEC V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1993-02-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1989-01-24T00:00:00.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1989-01-27T00:00:00.000Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. BARRY MAUK</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            VG2 URA LECP RESAMPLED SUMMARY SCAN AVERAGED 24SEC V1.0
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Description of the PDS LECP Uranus Scan data.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      Description of the PDS LECP Uranus Scan data.
 
      This data consists of resampled data from the Low Energy
      Charged Particle (LECP) Experiment on the Voyager 2 Spacecraft
      for the period when Voyager 2 was in the vicinity of the planet
      Uranus.  The period covered is 1986/day 24/0000 SCET to
      1986/day 27/0000 SCET.  This data approximates a time series of
      charged particle fluxes from a selection of channels available
      from the instrument.  The word approximates is used because the
      angle scanning modes of the instrument complicates the nature
      of the data.  At times the instrument mechanically scans, and
      at times it is fixed to look at a specific direction.  With the
      type of data given here, the fluxes are angle averaged for
      those time periods when the instrument is scanning, and are
      time averaged over an arbitrary period (24 seconds) for the
      periods when the detectors are stationary.  The angle averaged
      records represent periods of time equal to 96 or 384 sec (see
      below).  This kind of data presentation has been called the
      LECP Scan data.  Another form that is also available is the
      LECP Step data that gives the angle distributions sampled
      during the scanning periods.
 
      Two scanning situations occurred during the time of this data.
      They are: 1) continuous 48 sec stepping (48 seconds for each of
      8 look directions for a total of 6.4 minutes per scan; note
      that sector 8 is shielded with 2 mm Al), and 2) a special
      Uranus scan cyclic with the following sequence: 7, scan, scan,
      7, scan, scan, repeat; where the 7 represents a 10.4 minute
      period when the instrument is fixed in sector 7, and where the
      word scan represents a period of scanning (6 sec stepping for a
      total scan time of 48 sec).  For this Uranus Scan data the two
      adjacent scans within the Uranus scan cyclic have been averaged
      together into a single, 96 sec record.  The records of the 48
      sec stepping mode (Mode 1 above) are for 6.4 minutes.  As
      stated in the first paragraph, the records for the periods of
      no stepping during the Uranus scan cyclic (mode 2 above) are
      for 24 sec
 
         The schedule of mode changes is as follows:
 
         prior to day 24/0420:      Mode (1)
 
         24/0420  to  25/ 1357:     Mode (2)
 
         after day 25/1357:         Mode (1)
 
      Please note that the change-over between modes is not
      instantaneous, and that for a few minutes the state of the
      scanning is not regular.  Not also that there were brief
      interruptions to, and changes in time phase in, the Mode (2)
      scan cyclic during the transitions into and out of the movable
      block periods that bracketed the close approach position (not
      shown above).
 
      Obviously these stepping mode changes, and the angle sample
      switching that occurs during stepping mode (2), gives the
 
      The LECP channels utilized with this data set are:
 
           EB01:          electrons,  22 to  35 keV
           EB02:          electrons,  35  to  61 keV
           EB03:          electrons,  61 to  112 keV
           EB04:          electrons, 112 to 183 keV
           EG06-EG07:     electrons, 252 to 480 keV
           EG07-EG08:     electrons, 480 to 853 keV
           EG08-EG09:     electrons, 853 to 1200 keV
           PL01:          ions,       28 to  43  keV
           PL02:          ions,       43 to  80  keV
           PL03:          ions,       80 to 137  keV
           PL04:          ions,      137 to 215  keV
           PL05:          ions,      215 to 540  keV
           PL06:          ions,      540 to 990  keV
           PL07:          ions,      990 to 2140 keV
           PL08:          ions,     2140 to 3500 keV
 
      Please note that 3 of the electron channels are derived from 4
      of the instrumental channels by taking differences between
      adjacent (in energy) channels.
 
      The channel data is given in units of intensity:
      counts/(cm^2.sec.str.keV).  For the ions, it has been assumed
      that they consist only of protons.  Intensity is derived from
      the raw count rates via the relation:
 
                        I  =  CR/(eG.(E2-E1),
 
      where eG is geometric factor times detector efficiency, and
      (E2-E1) is the band pass of the channel in energy.  The proton
      values of these parameters were used in deriving the
      intensities for this data set.  To obtain the Intensities under
      the assumption that some other mass species dominates, one must
      convert back to count rate (CR) utilizing the proton
      parameters, and then convert to intensity using the parameters
      corresponding to the mass species in question.  The parameters
      can be found in Table 1 of Krimigis et al.  (Journal of
      Geophysical Research, V.  86, page 8227, 1981).  The
      corresponding parameters for electrons can be found in Mauk et
      al.  (Journal of Geophysical Research, V.  92, page 15283,
      1987).  Prior to the conversion to intensity, the count rates
      have been corrected for: (1) Background, (2) electron
      contamination of the lower energy ion channels, and (3) solar
      UV contamination of the lowest energy ion channel.
 
      The uncertainty parameters given with the data associated with
      each channel (expressed as a percent) is the largest of the two
      quantities: (i) one standard deviation Poisson statistical
      error, and (ii) a percentage assigned by the data supplier
      based on the amount of contamination correction that has been
      performed on each data channel.
 
      Also supplied with each record of this data set is the fraction
      of the data accumulations that correspond to each of the 8
      angle sectors.  For example, during a sector 7 stow period,
      this number will be 1.0 for sector 7 and 0.0 for all of the
      other sectors.  A sector 9 has also been defined corresponding
      to those accumulations with no known sector assignment.
 
      Additionally supplied for each data channel is a one bit code
      that tells whether that channel had any accumulations at all
      associated with it (1 = yes; 0 = no).  This code must be used
      to distinguish between accumulations that yielded no counts and
      situations where the channel simply had no accumulations
      (results in Intensity = 0.0).
 
 
      Processing Level Id            : 4
      Software Flag                  : Y
      Processing Start Time          : 1991-07-24
      Processing Stop Time           : 1991-07-25
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;PARTICLE FLUX INTENSITY&apos;
      --------------------------------------------
        The channel data is given in units of intensity:
        counts/(cm^2.sec.str.keV).  For the ions, it has been assumed
        that they consist only of protons.  Intensity is derived from
        the raw count rates via the relation:
 
                          I = CR/(eG.(E2-E1),
 
        where eG is geometric factor times detector efficiency, and
        (E2-E1) is the band pass of the channel in energy.  The
        proton values of these parameters were used in deriving the
        intensities for this data set.  To obtain the Intensities
        under the assumption that some other mass species dominates,
        one must convert back to count rate (CR) utilizing the proton
        parameters, and then convert to intensity using the
        parameters corresponding to the mass species in question.
        The parameters can be found in Table 1 of Krimigis et al.
        (Journal of Geophysical Research, V.  86, page 8227, 1981).
        The corresponding parameters for electrons can be found in
        Mauk et al.  (Journal of Geophysical Research, V.  92, page
        15283, 1987).  Prior to the conversion to intensity, the
        count rates have been corrected for: (1) Background, (2)
        electron contamination of the lower energy ion channels, and
        (3) solar UV contamination of the lowest energy ion channel.
 
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Data Set Parameter Name        : PARTICLE FLUX INTENSITY
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 24.000000
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : 24.000000
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : 6.000000
        Data Set Parameter Unit        :
                        COUNTS/(CM**2*SECOND*STERRADIAN*KEV)
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND
 
 
    Source Instrument Parameters
    ============================
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : PARTICLE FLUX INTENSITY
      Instrument Parameter Name       : PARTICLE MULTIPLE PARAMETERS
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      Processing History
      ------------------
        Source Data Set ID        : N/A
        Software                  : UNK
        Product Data Set ID       : VG2-U-LECP-4-SUMM-SCAN-24SEC-V1.0
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      Confidence note for the PDS Uranus LECP Scan data.
 
      High quality data is available from the LECP instrument
      throughout the time period addressed with this data set.  The
      data is subject to errors associated with Poisson statistics
      and associated with various kinds and levels of contamination.
      The known contaminations are: i) penetrating background, ii)
      Solar UV contamination within the lowest energy ion channel
      when the detector faces sunward, and iii) electron
      contamination of the lower energy ion channels (the
      contaminating electrons are measured).  Corrections have been
      made to the data in attempts to remove the effects of these
      contaminations.
 
      An error parameter is given for each particle intensity value
      given in the data set.  This error is expressed as a
      percentage.  This number is the larger of the following items:
      1) the one standard deviation Poisson error, and 2) a value
      assigned by the data supplier associated with the degree of
      correction that was required with regard to the contaminations
      listed above.
 
      Missing data is indicated with a binary flag associated with
      each energy channel.  Each channel&apos;s flag will read 1 if at
      least one instrumental accumulation occurred for that channel
      and for that record.  The flag reads 0 for no accumulations.
      This parameter must be utilized to distinguish between
      accumulations that yielded no counts, and the situation where
      there simply were no accumulations (the error parameter reads
      100 for both cases).
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XM-11A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

