<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.grail-l-lgrs-5-rdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GRAIL MOON LGRS DERIVED GRAVITY SCIENCE DATA PRODUCTS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.gravity_recovery_and_interior_laboratory::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.grail-a::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:lgrs-a.grail-a::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.grail-l-lgrs-5-rdr-v1.0__browserp_grail-l-lgrs-5-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.grail-l-lgrs-5-rdr-v1.0__dvo_grail-l-lgrs-5-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Acton, C., SPK-MM-SIS, Multimission Software Interface Specification, SPICE
                   Spacecraft and Planetary Ephemeris Kernel, NAIF Document No. 367, 25 May 2000.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ACTON2000</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Folkner, W.M., The Planetary and Lunar Ephemeris DE 421, IPN Progress Report
                   42-178. http://ipnpr.jpl.nasa.gov/progress_report/42-178/178C.pdf, 2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FOLKNER2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Folkner, W.M., J.G. Williams, D.H. Boggs, R.S. Park, and P. Kuchynka, The
                   Planetary and Lunar Ephemerides DE 430 and DE431, IPN Progress Report 42-196.
                   http://ipnpr.jpl.nasa.gov/progress_report/42-196/196C.pdf, 2014.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FOLKNERETAL2014</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Konopliv. A.S., C.F. Yoder, E.M. Standish, D.N. Yuan, and W.L. Sjogren, A
                   Global Solution for the Mars Static and Seasonal Gravity, Mars Orientation,
                   Phobos and Deimos Masses, and Mars Ephemeris, Icarus, 182(1), May 2006, pp.
                   23-50.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KONOPLIVETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Konopliv, A.S., et al., The JPL lunar gravity field to spherical harmonic
                   degree 660 from the GRAIL Primary Mission, J. Geophys Res., 118, 1415-1434,
                   doi:10.1002/jgre.20097, 2013.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KONOPLIVETAL2013</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lemoine, F.G., D.E. Smith, D.D. Rowlands, M.T. Zuber, G.A. Neumann, D.S. Chinn,
                   and D.E. Pavlis, An Improved Solution for the Gravity Field of Mars (GMM-2B)
                   from Mars Global Surveyor, Journal of Geophysical Research, 106, 23359-23376,
                   2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEMOINEETAL2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lemoine, F.G., S. Goossens, T.J. Sabaka, J.B. Nicholas, E. Mazarico, D.D.
                   Rowlands, B.D. Loomis, D.S. Chinn, D.S. Caprette, G.A. Neumann, D.E. Smith, and
                   M.T. Zuber, High-degree gravity models from GRAIL primary mission data, J.
                   Geophys Res., 118, 1676-1698, doi:10.1002/jgre.20118, 2013.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEMOINEETAL2013</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   MOYER, T., Formulation for Observed and Computed Values of Deep Space Network
                   Data Types for Navigation, JPL Publication 00-7, Jet Propulsion Laboratory,
                   Pasadena, 2000
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MOYER2000</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Pavlis, D.E., S. Poulose, C. Deng, and J.J. McCarthy, GEODYN II System
                   Documentation, SGT-Inc., Greenbelt, Maryland, Contractor report, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PAVLISETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Thornton, C.L. and J.S. Border, Radiometric Tracking Techniques for Deep Space
                   Navigation, John Wiley and Sons, Hoboken, NY, 2003.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.THORNTON-BORDER2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tyler, G.L., G. Balmino, D.P. Hinson, W.L. Sjogren, D.E. Smith, R. Woo, S.W.
                   Asmar, M.J. Connally, C.L. Hamilton, and R.A. Simpson, Radio Science
                   Investigations with Mars Observer, Journal of Geophysical Research, 97,
                   7759-7779, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TYLERETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Yuan, D.N., W.L. Sjogren, A.S. Konopliv, and A.B. Kucinskas, Gravity Field of
                   Mars: A 75th Degree and Order Model, Journal of Geophysical Research, 106,
                   23377-23401, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.YUANETAL2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GRAIL-L-LGRS-5-RDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GRAIL MOON LGRS DERIVED GRAVITY SCIENCE DATA PRODUCTS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2013-10-11</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2012-03-01</start_time>
        <stop_time>2012-12-18</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DANIEL S. KAHAN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            KAHAN, D.S., GRAIL Moon LGRS Derived Gravity Science Data
            Products V1.0, GRAIL-L-LGRS-5-RDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2013.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Derived science data originating from the Lunar Gravity Ranging
            System (LGRS) on each of the two spacecraft comprising the
            Gravity Recovery and Interior Laboratory (GRAIL) mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains archival derived science data, acquired
            from the Lunar Gravity Ranging System (LGRS) on the two
            spacecraft comprising the Gravity Recovery and Interior
            Laboratory (GRAIL) mission. Measurements were made using the
            GRAIL spacecraft and Earth-based stations of the NASA Deep Space
            Network (DSN). The data set includes high-resolution spherical
            harmonic models of the Moon&apos;s gravity field, covariance
            matrices for some models, and maps for some models. It also
            contains a complete set of SPICE SPK Files (&apos;kernel
            files&apos;), which can be accessed using SPICE software. The SPK
            products in this data set differ from those archived by GRAIL
            navigation, as they were created by the GRAIL SDS and make use of
            the LGRS to provide a more refined solution of the spacecraft
            ephemerides than those provided by GRAIL navigation.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
    The Gravity Recovery and Interior Laboratory (GRAIL) Lunar Gravity
    Ranging System (LGRS) Reduced Data Record (RDR) archive includes
    data products generated from gravity investigations conducted by
    members of the GRAIL Gravity Team.
 
    Gravity RDRs include spherical harmonic models and acceleration
    maps of those models. A team at JPL, under the direction of Alex
    Konopliv, and another team at the Goddard Space Flight Center
    (GSFC), under the direction of Frank Lemoine, independently
    generated those products.
 
    The DATA_SET_ID &apos;GRAIL-L-LGRS-5-RDR-V1.0&apos; includes the following
    components:
          Instrument host (i.e., &apos;GRAIL&apos;)
          Target (i.e., &apos;L&apos; for Lunar)
          Instrument (i.e., &apos;LGRS&apos; for Lunar Gravity Ranging System)
          CODMAC Data processing level number (i.e., &apos;5&apos;)
          Description (i.e., &apos;RDR&apos; for Reduced Data Record)
          Version number (i.e., &apos;V1.0&apos;)
 
    The data upon which these results were derived were collected
    between March and December 2012.
 
    The Science Phase of the mission was conducted from a
    near-circular, near-polar orbit with a mean altitude of 55 km.
    There were three different mapping cycles during the Science
    Phase, each covering a sidereal month (27.32 days). The first
    mapping cycle started while the science orbit had low periapsis
    altitudes with an orbiter separation distance of approximately 85
    kilometers. Over the course of the first mapping cycle, and into
    the second mapping cycle, the periapsis altitudes of the science
    orbit increased, and the mean separation distance slowly drifted
    to 225 kilometers. A small Orbit Trim Maneuver (OTM) was performed
    during the second mapping cycle to decrease the separation drift
    rate. Following this OTM to the end of the third mapping cycle,
    the periapsis altitudes decreased, and the mean separation between
    the orbiters slowly drifted from 225 km back to 65 km. DSN
    coverage was nearly continuous.
 
    GRAIL proposed (and NASA approved) an Extended Mission, since
    there was sufficient fuel in the two spacecraft to acquire
    additional science data.  The mean spacecraft altitude was
    lowered by about a factor of 2 to increase the sensitivity of the
    gravity measurements, and GRAIL defined a new set of science
    objectives.  As in the Science Phase, the spacecraft separation
    distance was variable.  DSN coverage was comparable.
 
    Parameters
    ==========
    Spherical harmonic models are tables of coefficients GM, Cmn, and
    Smn -- as in equation (1) of [TYLERETAL1992].  These can be used
    to represent gravitational potential of the Moon, for example.
    Both ASCII (data type SHA) and binary (data type SHB) formats are
    defined, with the latter being preferred for large files which
    also include covariance terms.  Each file contains up to four
    tables: a header table containing general parameters for the model
    (gravitational constant, its uncertainty, degree and order of the
    field, normalization state, reference longitude, and reference
    latitude); a names table, giving the order in which coefficients
    appear; a coefficients table (degree m, order n, coefficients Cmn
    and Smn, and their uncertainties); and a covariances table giving
    the covariances of CijCmn, SijSmn, CijSmn, and SijCmn.
 
    Radio Science Digital Map files are image representations of
    gravity and other parameters.  Free air gravity, geoid, Bouguer
    anomaly, isostatic anomaly, and topographic values may be
    displayed using this data type.  Data are formatted as PDS image
    objects.
 
    The SPK kernels contain ephemerides for spacecraft, planets,
    satellites, comets, and asteroids as well as for moving or fixed
    spacecraft and instrument structures. They provide position and
    velocity, given in a Cartesian reference frame.
 
    Processing
    ==========
    Spherical harmonic models and maps are derived from raw radio
    tracking data in several steps.
 
    The LGRS data are processed in large orbit determination programs
    that integrate the equations of motion (Mirage at JPL [MOYER2000],
    and GEODYN at NASA GSFC [PAVLISETAL2007]), and model
    mathematically the radio science observables (ramped Doppler and
    range data). The observations are related to the geophysical
    parameters through the numerical integration and the detailed
    mathematical modeling of the radio science observables, and of all
    forces acting on the spacecraft trajectory, including planetary
    and third body gravity, solar radiation pressure, planetary
    radiation pressure, atmospheric drag, solid body tides, and
    relativity.
 
    The gravity field coefficients are obtained by accumulating normal
    equations from often hundreds of data arcs, and solving these
    systems of linear equations with thousands of unknowns. The
    unknowns include arc parameters, particular to one data arc (such
    as the spacecraft state, radiation pressure scale factors,
    atmospheric drag scale factors, etc.) and common parameters. Radio
    tracking data are processed in arcs delimited by propulsive
    maneuvers, occultations, etc.
 
    The Moon orbiting spacecraft perform regular angular momentum
    desaturation (AMD) maneuvers to remove the angular momentum that
    has accumulated in the spacecraft momentum wheels. On GRAIL, these
    AMD maneuvers occur usually every 2-3 days, and arcs may be
    delimited by these maneuvers. The times of the AMDs are specified
    in the LGRS instrument catalogs in this archive.
 
    Maps of free air gravity and other quantities are generated from
    the spherical harmonic model(s) evaluated at regular grid points.
 
    Useful references which describe the procedures applied in general
    to processing GRAIL orbiter tracking data include [YUANETAL2001],
    [LEMOINEETAL2013], and [KONOPLIVETAL2013]. [THORNTON&amp;BORDER2003]
    is a general reference for Orbit Determination.
 
    Data
    ====
    Data are available online through the Planetary Data System
    (http://pds.nasa.gov) and encompass the primary and extended
    mission phases.
 
    ASCII spherical harmonic models are stored in the SHADR directory
    with file names of the form GTsss_nnnnvv_SHA.TAB, where
 
    &apos;G&apos;      denotes the generating institution
                  &apos;J&apos;  for the Jet Propulsion Laboratory
                  &apos;G&apos;  for Goddard Space Flight Center
                  &apos;M&apos;  for Massachusetts Institute of Technology
    &apos;T&apos;      indicates the type of data represented
                  &apos;G&apos;  for gravity field
    &apos;sss&apos;    is a 3-character modifier specified by the data producer.
             This modifier is used to indicate the source spacecraft
             or project, such as GRX (the pair of GRAIL spacecraft).
    &apos;_&apos;      the underscore character is used to delimit modifiers in
             the file name for clarity.
    &apos;nnnnvv&apos; is a 4- to 6-character modifier specified by the data
             producer.  Among other things, this modifier may be used
             to indicate the target body, whether the SHADR contains
             primary data values as specified by &apos;T&apos; or
             uncertainties/errors, and/or the version number.  For
             GRAIL, this modifier indicates the degree and order of
             the solution for the gravity field.
     &apos;_&apos;     the underscore character is used to delimit information
             in the file name for clarity.
     &apos;SHA&apos;   denotes that this is an ASCII file of Spherical Harmonic
             coefficients
     &apos;.TAB&apos;  indicates the data are stored in tabular form.
 
    Bouguer gravity data products have the name &apos;Bouguer&apos; following
    the degree and order identifier, i.e. GTsss_nnnnvv_BOUGUER_SHA.TAB.
 
    Each SHADR file is accompanied by a detached PDS label; that label
    is a file in its own right, having the name GTsss_nnnnvv_SHA.LBL.
 
 
    Binary spherical harmonic models are stored in the SHBDR directory
    with file names of the form GTsss_nnnnvv_SHB_Lccc.DAT where
 
    &apos;G&apos;      denotes the generating institution
                  &apos;J&apos;  for the Jet Propulsion Laboratory
                  &apos;G&apos;  for Goddard Space Flight Center
                  &apos;C&apos;  for Centre National d&apos;Etudes Spatiales
    &apos;T&apos;      indicates the type of data represented
                  &apos;G&apos;  for gravity field
    &apos;sss&apos;    is a 3-character modifier specified by the data producer.
             This modifier is used to indicate the source spacecraft
             or Project, such as GRX (the pair of GRAIL spacecraft).
    &apos;nnnnvv&apos; is a 4- to 6-character modifier specified by the data
             producer.  Among other things, this modifier may be used
             to indicate the target body, whether the SHBDR contains
             primary data values as specified by &apos;T&apos; or
             uncertainties/errors, and/or the version number. For
             GRAIL, this modifier indicates the degree and order of
             the solution for the gravity field.
    &apos;SHB&apos;    denotes that this is a binary file of Spherical Harmonic
             coefficients and error covariance information
    &apos;Lccc&apos;   is a 2- to 4-character modifier specified by the data
             producer to indicate the degree and order to which degree
             (L) the gravity covariance has been truncated, if
             applicable.
    &apos;.DAT&apos;   indicates the data are stored in binary format.
 
    Each SHBDR file is accompanied by a detached PDS label; that label
    is a file in its own right, having the name
    GTsss_nnnnvv_SHB_Lccc.LBL.
 
 
    Radio Science Digital Map products are stored in the RSDMAP
    directory with file names of the form GTsss_ffff_nnnn_cccc.IMG,
    where
 
    &apos;G&apos;      denotes the generating institution
                  &apos;J&apos;  for the Jet Propulsion Laboratory
                  &apos;G&apos;  for Goddard Space Flight Center
                  &apos;S&apos;  for Stanford University
    &apos;T&apos;      indicates the type of mission data represented
                  &apos;G&apos;  for gravity field
    &apos;sss&apos;    is a 3-character modifier specified by the data producer.
             This modifier is used to indicate the source spacecraft
             or project, such as GRX (the pair of GRAIL spacecraft).
    &apos;ffff&apos;   is a 4-character modifier specified by the data producer
             to indicate the degree and order of the solution for the
             gravity field.
    &apos;nnnn&apos;   is a 4- to 8-character modifier indicating the type of
             data represented
                    &apos;ANOM&apos;      for free air gravity anomalies
                    &apos;ANOMERR&apos;   for free air gravity anomaly
                                errors (1)
                    &apos;GEOID&apos;     for geoid
                    &apos;GEOIDERR&apos;  for geoid errors (1)
                    &apos;BOUG&apos;      for Bouguer anomaly
                    &apos;ISOS&apos;      for isostatic anomaly
                    &apos;TOPO&apos;      for topography
                    &apos;MAGF&apos;      for magnetic field
                    &apos;DIST&apos;      for gravity disturbances
                    &apos;DEGSTR&apos;    for degree strength
 
             (1) Geoid and gravity anomaly errors are computed from a
                 mapping of the error covariance matrix of the gravity
                 field solution.
      &apos;cccc&apos; is a 4-character modifier specified by the data producer
             to indicate the degree and order to which the potential
             solution (gravity, topography or magnetic field) has been
             evaluated. In the case of the error maps for the gravity
             anomalies or geoid error, this field indicates to which
             maximum degree and order the error covariance was used to
             propagate the spatial errors
      &apos;.IMG&apos;  indicates the data are stored as an image.
 
    Each RSDMAP file is accompanied by a detached PDS label; that
    label is a file in its own right with name GTsss_ffff_nnnn_cccc.LBL.
 
 
    Spacecraft and Planet Ephemeris Kernels (SPK) files are stored in
    the SPK directory with file names of the form
    sssttaaYYYY_DDD_yyyy_ddd.SPK, where
 
    sss      3-character spacecraft identifier
                  GRA  GRAIL-A
                  GRB  GRAIL-B
                  GRX  both
    tt       Target ID, e.g., LU = Moon
    aa       Activity/Experiment ID, e.g. GF = gravity field
    YYYY     start year
    DDD      start day of year
    yyyy     end year
    ddd      end day of year
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
    GRAIL Gravity RDR files use a lunar body-fixed frame as defined in
    the DE 421 planetary ephemeris [FOLKNER2009]. GRGM1200A files use
    the DE 430 ephemeris [FOLKNERETAL2014].
 
    See labels of specific gravity products for details.
 
    Software
    ========
    The SPICE Toolkit contains software modules needed to read SPICE
    kernel files. SPICE software is highly documented via internal
    headers. Additional documentation is available in separate ASCII
    text files called Required Reading files. The S- and P- Kernel (SPK)
    Required Reading File, name SPK.REQ, describes the use of the SPK
    kernel file readers and contains sample programs.
 
    The latest SPICE Toolkit for a variety of computer platforms such
    as PC, Mac, SUN, etc. is available at the NAIF Node of PDS
    electronically (via anonymous FTP and WWW servers).
    Each version of the Toolkit is also archived at the NASA National
    Space Science Data Center.
 
    Media/Format
    ============
    This data set is stored online at the Planetary Data System
    (http://pds.nasa.gov/) and may be downloaded using a web browser
    or FTP software. A copy may be requested on physical media if
    downloading is not possible. The Planetary Data System maintains
    backup copies of this data set on various media.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this archive have been reduced as part of mission data
      analysis activities of the GRAIL Gravity Team.  Products of
      questionable validity have been flagged or omitted.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was reviewed by the GRAIL Gravity
      Team prior to submission to the Planetary Data System (PDS).
      Data set design, documentation, and sample products have passed
      a PDS peer review.
 
      Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data
      set, key elements of the archive were distributed for
      preliminary review.  These included electronic versions of
      example PDS labels, example data files, CATALOG files, and
      Software Interface Specifications.  These materials were
      distributed to PDS personnel, the experiment investigator,
      and others, as appropriate.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
 
      This volume contains gravity models and maps generated from
      GRAIL data collected during the primary and extended mission.
 
      GGGRX_0660PM_SHA.TAB is an ASCII file of coefficients and related
      data for the GSFC Lunar gravity field GRGM660PRIM, a degree and
      order 660 spherical harmonic model. It is a GSFC gravity field
      that includes the entire nominal mission of GRAIL tracking data
      (March 1, 16:30 to May 29, 16:36, 2012).
 
      JGGRX_0420A_SHA.TAB and JGGRX_0660B_SHA.TAB are ASCII files of
      coefficients and related data for the JPL Lunar gravity fields
      GL0420A and GL0660B, respectively, 420th and 660th degree and
      and order spherical harmonic models. They are JPL gravity fields
      that include the entire primary mission of GRAIL tracking data
      (March 1, 16:30 to May 29, 16:36:00, 2012).
 
      GGGRX_0660PM_SHB_L50.DAT, GGGRX_0660PM_SHB_L180.DAT,
      GGGRX_0660PM_SHB_L420.DAT, and GGGRX_0660PM_SHB_L660.DAT are
      binary files of coefficients and related data for the GSFC Lunar
      gravity field GRGM660PRIM, a 660th degree and order spherical
      harmonic model. It is a GSFC gravity field that includes the
      entire nominal mission of GRAIL tracking data (March 1, 16:30 to
      May 29, 16:36, 2012).
 
      JGGRX_0660B_SHB_L50.DAT, JGGRX_0660B_SHB_L180.DAT,
      JGGRX_0660B_SHB_L420.DAT, and JGGRX_0660B_SHB_L660.DAT are binary
      files of coefficients and related data for the JPL Lunar gravity
      field GL0660B, a 660th degree and order spherical harmonic
      model. It is a JPL gravity field that includes the entire
      primary mission of GRAIL tracking data (March 1, 16:30 to
      May 29, 16:36:00, 2012).
 
      GGGRX_0660PM_ANOM_L320.IMG is a map of the gravity anomalies (in
      mGal) of the Moon at a resolution of 4 pix/deg by 4 pix/deg. It
      is based on a GRAIL gravity field of the Moon produced by NASA
      GSFC. The gravity field is a degree and order 660 spherical
      harmonic model, which includes the entire nominal mission of
      GRAIL tracking data (March 1, 16:30 to May 29, 16:36, 2012). The
      field was truncated to degree and order 320 for the expansion in
      the spatial domain, to reduce remaining artifacts.
 
      JGGRX_0660B_ANOM_L320.IMG is a map of the gravity anomaly derived
      from the JPL GL0660B model of the Moon&apos;s gravity field. Each
      point gives the Lunar gravity anomaly in milligals, which is the
      difference of the model gravity on the geoid from the gravity on
      a reference sphere with semi-major-axis = 1738.0 km,
      GM = 4902.8003055554 km**3/s**2, and zero rotation rate. The
      JGGRX_0660B_ANOM_320 gravity anomaly is computed from a
      truncated GL0660B solution (from degree 2 up to degree 320).
 
      See the SHADR, SHBDR, and RSDMAP directories for additional data
      products for the GRGM900C, GL0900C, GL0900D, GL1500E, and GRGM1200A
      models.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The limitations in this data set follow from the quality of
      the execution, which is described above under Data Coverage
      and Quality.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

