<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.hp-ssa-dwe-2-3-descent-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>HUYGENS PROBE DWE RESULTS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.hp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:dwe.hp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.titan::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.hp-ssa-dwe-2-3-descent-v1.0__browserp_atmos_hp-ssa-dwe-2-3-descent-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.hp-ssa-dwe-2-3-descent-v1.0__dvo_hp-ssa-dwe-2-3-descent-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Bird, M.K., M. Allison, S.W. Asmar, D.H. Atkinson, I.M. Avruch, R. Dutta-Roy,
                   Y. Dzierma, P. Edenhofer, W.M. Folkner, L.I. Gurvits, D.V. Johnston, D.
                   Plettemeier, R.A.; Progrebenko, R.A. Preston, and G.L. Tyler, The vertical
                   profile of winds on Titan, Nature 438, 800-802, 2005
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BIRDETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Folkner, W.M., S.W. Asmar, J.S. Border, G.W. Franklin, S.G. Finley, J. Gorelik,
                   D.V. Johnston, V.V. Kerzhanovich, S.T. Lowe, R.A. Preston, M.K. Bird, R.
                   Dutta-Roy, M. Allison, D.H. Atkinson, P. Edenhofer, D. Plettemeier, and G.L.
                   Tyler, Winds on Titan from ground-based tracking of the Huygens probe, JGR 111,
                   E07S02, doi:10.1029/2005JE002649, 2006.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FOLKNERETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lebreton, J.P., O. Witasse, C. Sollazzo, T. Blancquaert, P. Couzin, A.M.
                   Schipper, J.B. Jones, D.L. Matson, L.I. Gurvits, D.H. Atkinson, B. Kazeminejad,
                   and M. Perez-Ayucar, An overview of the descent and landing of the Huygens
                   Probe on Titan, Nature, Volume 438, pp 758-764, 2005
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEBRETONETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Pogrebenko, S.V., L.I. Gurvits, I.M. Avruch, J.P. Lebreton, and C.G.M. van&apos;t
                   Klooster, VLBI tracking of the Huygens probe in the atmosphere of Titan, in
                   Proceedings of the International Workshop on Planetary Atmospheric Entry and
                   Descent Trajectory Analysis and Science, ESA-SP-544, edited by A. Wilson, ESA
                   Publications Division, Noordwijk, The Netherlands, 197-204, 2004
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.POGREBENKOETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>HP-SSA-DWE-2-3-DESCENT-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>HUYGENS PROBE DWE RESULTS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2006-07-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2005-01-14T10:19:27.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2005-01-14T15:52:46.500Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>ROBINDRO DUTTA-ROY</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>blank</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The DWE data set consists of the sky frequencies measured at the
            Green Bank and Parkes telescopes.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The DWE data set consists of the sky frequencies measured at the
            Green Bank and Parkes telescopes (data from other stations may be
            included when they become available; see [BIRDETAL2005]), the
            retrieved zonal wind speed along the descent path, geometrical
            parameters used to separate the Huygens velocity components and
            documentation.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
Data Set Overview
=================
 
On January 14, 2005, the Huygens Probe, part of the joint NASA/ESA Cassini-
Huygens mission to Saturn, entered the atmosphere of Titan, descended for
2.5 hours under a parachute and eventually landed softly on the surface of
Titan [LEBRETONETAL2005].
 
Six experiments collected data during the descent and on ground. The data
set, which this data set catalog belongs to, is the archive of the Huygens
Doppler Wind Experiment (DWE), which was designed to measure Titan&apos;s zonal
winds by Doppler tracking Huygens from Cassini and from Earth
[BIRDETAL2005].
 
In contrast to the other five experiments, DWE was not designed to collect
data aboard Huygens. Instead, it was designed to measure the frequency of
the Huygens carrier signal received aboard Cassini and on Earth.
 
The radio link between Huygens and Cassini had two independent and
partially redundant channels. One of them (channel A) was used for DWE
Doppler tracking of Huygens.
 
The accuracy desired by DWE required the use of special Ultra-Stable
Oscillators (USO) for the channel A transmitter aboard Huygens and for the
channel A receiver aboard Cassini. For the reception on Earth, a USO was
not required, as the accuracy of the H-maser driven radio antennas is much
higher than that of a USO.
 
The data rate of the Huygens signal was 8 kHz. It was recorded, decoded and
stored aboard Cassini in real-time for later transmission to Earth via the
Cassini High Gain Antenna. The Huygens signal level was, however, to weak
to be decoded on Earth. The minimum integration time for the detection of
the Huygens signal on Earth was of the order of 1 sec.
 
Due to an error in the sequence, which was executed by Cassini during the
Huygens mission, the receiver USO was not switched on for the mission.
Consequently, the channel A receiver aboard Cassini could not lock onto the
channel A signal from Huygens and all data transmitted via this channel
including the DWE frequency measurement were lost. Due to this flaw, DWE
relies now entirely on the data collected by Earth based telescopes.
 
The DWE data set consists of the sky frequencies measured at the Green Bank
and Parkes telescopes (data from other stations may be included when they
become available; see [BIRDETAL2005]), the retrieved zonal wind speed along
the descent path, geometrical parameters used to separate the Huygens
velocity components and documentation.
 
It is organized in six directories, which we describe in the following.
 
 
DATA Directory
==============
 
The DATA directory contains the measured sky frequencies after signal
processing in two files, one for Green Bank and one for Parkes. It is not
intended to archive raw recordings of the signal. The signal processing
method is described in [FOLKNERETAL2006]. Furthermore, it contains the
retrieved zonal wind speed, the primary DWE result.
 
The zonal wind speed was computed from each frequency sample, so that the
total number of rows in the zonal wind table matches the sum of the
frequency samples from Green Bank and Parkes.
 
The time tags for the frequencies is Earth Received Time (ERT), whereas the
time tags for the zonal wind speed is Spacecraft Event Time (SCET). (By the
way: Also START_TIME and STOP_TIME of this object, the
DATA_SET_INFORMATION, are given in ERT.) The latter is a derived quantity,
computed by subtracting the one-way-light-time from ERT.
 
The one-way-light-time between Titan and the receiving antenna during the
Huygens mission was 67 min and 6.4 sec at the beginning of the mission,
decreasing by approximately 0.1 sec over the duration of DWE data
recordings. For the computation of the zonal wind speed, we used its
precise value determined by our software, which made use of the SPICE
toolkit (available from JPL).
 
The precise value for the one-way-light-time can be reconstructed by
subtracting our SCET time tags from the ERT time tags e.g., in the files
HUYGENS_STATE.TAB and ANTENNA_STATE.TAB in the GEOMETRY directory (all data
and geometry files have an identical number of rows that corresponds to the
number of DWE sky frequency samples).
 
The data collected at Green Bank have a mean integration time of 2 sec. At
Parkes, the mean integration time was 3 sec before landing and 5 sec
thereafter.
 
There is a 25-min gap between the last sample from Green Bank and the first
sample from Parkes, which may possibly be filled by measurements of other
VLBA stations in the future, albeit with a lower time resolution as the
gain of those stations is significantly smaller than that of Green Bank or
Parkes.
 
After launch, it was decided that in addition to the DWE Doppler tracking
Huygens should also be tracked using a technique known as Very Long
Baseline Interferometry (VLBI) [POGREBENKOETAL2004]. The VLBI group used a
number of radio antennas, among them also Green Bank and Parkes, which were
jointly used by the VLBI and DWE teams. The VLBI techique requires a
continuous calibration with an extragalactic radio source, i.e., a quasar.
As no quasar was in the beam when the antennas were pointed towards
Huygens, they had to be nodded continuously. It was agreed among the teams
that, in order to meet the requirements for the VLBI tracking, the antennas
were pointed about 100 sec towards Huygens and 80 sec towards the VLBI
calibration source in a 3-min cycle. These interruptions can consequently
also be seen in the DWE data set.
 
 
GEOMETRY Directory
==================
 
This directory contains state vectors of Huygens and the receiving antennas
and the resulting projection angles for the various velocity components.
 
The time tags of the state vectors of Huygens and the projection angles are
given as SCET, whereas the time tags for the state vectors of the receiving
antennas is given as ERT to account for retardation. See the file
GEOMINFO.TXT in the GEOMETRY directory for more information.
 
The altitude and meridional drift profiles of Huygens used for the
generation of these files were provided by the Huygens Descent Trajectory
Working Group (DTWG; see corresponding archive). The initial longitude
(longitude at the time of the first DWE sky frequency sample) was taken
from DTWG as well, whereas the subsequent longitude values were obtained by
integration of the measured zonal wind speed.
 
It is clear that any change of the DTWG profile will affect the retrieved
zonal wind. For this version of the archive, we used the 4th DTWG delivery
(DTWG#4), published in May 2006. Thus far, all DTWG deliveries including
those which had not yet incorporated the image derived meridional drift,
lead similar zonal wind profiles. There are no significant differences
between the various zonal wind retrievals in the upper atmosphere. Near the
surface, where the winds are generally weak, a slightly different descent
speed or meridional drift profile could, however, lead to a significant
change in the retrieved zonal wind speed.
 
The state vectors of the receiving antennas and Titan were computed using
the software SPICE and the following kernels: vlba.bsp,
earth_000101_050808_050517.bpc, earthstns_itrf93_040916.bsp,
050214R_SCPSE_04336_05015.bsp, naif0007.tls, cpck19May2005.tpc SPICE and
the accompanying kernels are available at http://naif.jpl.nasa.gov/naif/
 
 
DOCUMENT Directory
==================
 
This directory contains the most important DWE documents and the DWE Health
Report, which describes the performance of the DWE USOs during the Huygens
mission.
 
Although the paper [FOLKNERETAL2006] is considered an important document
too, it was not included, because at the time of this writing, it was not
yet published.
 
More documentation is listed in the reference catalog in the CATALOG
directory.
 
 
CALIB Directory
===============
 
The CALIB directory contains a report that provides information on the DWE
performance during pre-launch and in-flight tests and describes the final
calibration of the frequency measurement.
 
 
CATALOG Directory
=================
 
This directory contains general information about the data set, such as
involved personnel, instrument description, references, etc.
 
 
INDEX Directory
===============
 
needed internally by archive.
 
 
Review
======
 
      The Huygens data sets were reviewed in two steps:
      (1) a review of the Experimenter-to-archive-ICD, in 2004.
      (2) a review of the data sets, in 2006.
      Procedures and details of this process can be obtained from
      the ESA archive team:
 
      Olivier Witasse or Joe Zender
      ESA ESTEC
      Keplerlaan 1
      2200 AG Noordwijk
      The Netherlands
      Olivier.Witasse@esa.int or Joe.Zender@esa.int
 
 The Experimenter-to-archive-ICD was reviewed by V. Dehant (Royal
 Observatory of Brussels) and by D. Strobel (John Hopkins University). This
 data set was reviewed by D. Strobel and by R. Lorenz (University of
 Arizona).
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
N/A
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

