<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.vl1-vl2-m-fts-4-sol-avg-ftpd-temp-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>VL1/VL2 MARS METEOROLOGY RESAMPLED SOL AVG FOOTPAD TEMP V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.viking::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vl1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vl2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:fts.vl1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:fts.vl2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vl1-vl2-m-fts-4-sol-avg-ftpd-temp-v1.0__dvo_atmos_vl1-vl2-m-fts-4-sol-avg-ftpd-temp-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Moore, H.J., R.E. Hutton, G.D. Clow, and C.R. Spitzer, Physical properties
                   of the surface materials at the Viking landings sites on Mars, USGS
                   Professional Paper 1389, 1987.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MOOREETAL1987</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Horowitz, R., and J.H. King, Tapes, documents, listings of data and
                   microfiche related to the atmospheric pressure data from the Viking Lander
                   1 and 2 Lander Meteorology Experiments, NSSDC data sets for Viking Lander
                   1: 75-075C-07I and 75-075C-07J, and for Viking Lander 2: 75-083C-07I, and
                   75-083C-07J, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NSSDC1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Seiff, A., The Viking Atmosphere Structure Experiment - Techniques,
                   Instruments, and Expected Accuracies, Space Science Instrumentation, 2,
                   381-423, 1976.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SEIFF1976</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tillman, J.E., Martian Meteorology and Dust Storms from Viking
                   Observations, Proceedings of the Case for Mars II Conference, Science and
                   Technology Series, American Astronautical Society, Vol. 62, 333-342, 1985.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TILLMAN1985</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>VL1/VL2-M-FTS-4-SOL-AVG-FTPD-TEMP-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>VL1/VL2 MARS METEOROLOGY RESAMPLED SOL AVG FOOTPAD TEMP V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1996-03-26</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1979-05-22</start_time>
        <stop_time>1982-11-13</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>WILLIAM R. GUEST</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>TBD</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains sol averages of the Martian near-surface
            temperatures obtained from the Viking Lander 1 and 2 thermocouple
            footpad temperature sensors.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>not applicable</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      This data set contains sol averages of the Martian near-surface
      temperatures obtained from the Viking Lander 1 and 2 thermocouple
      footpad temperature sensors.  The data set consists of the daily
      average footpad temperature values and relevant statistics
      presented on a sol by sol basis. The data set is composed of the
      following parameter fields (listed as the field name followed by a
      description).
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      SC_ID
        Spacecraft id: VL1 : Viking Lander 1 VL2 : Viking Lander 2
 
      SOL_LON
        Areocentric longitude of the Sun (Ls) corresponding to local
        midnight at the beginning of the sol
 
      VIKING_YEAR
        Viking mission year, starting at 1 when the Viking
        spacecraft reached Mars, and incremented at Ls = 0
        every martian year
 
      MARTIAN_DAY
        The martian solar day (sol), starting at day 0 when
        each Lander touched down.  Each martian day is 24 hr 39 minutes
        35.25 seconds in length.
 
      T_FTPD_MEAN
        Daily average footpad temperature (degrees Kelvin)
 
      T_FTPD_MIN
        Minimum daily footpad temperature (degrees Kelvin)
 
      T_FTPD_RANGE
        Maximum variation in footpad temperature during each day
        (degrees Kelvin)
 
      T_FTPD_SIGMA
        Standard deviation of the point-by-point footpad measurements
        from which the sol averaged value was determined (degrees Kelvin)
 
      MAX_TIME_GAP
        Length of maximum time gap between two
        measurements (hours)
 
      BEG_GAP_HOUR
        Local hour of maximum time gap start
 
      BEG_GAP_MIN
        Local minute of maximum time gap start
 
      BEG_GAP_SEC
        Local second of maximum time gap start
 
      END_GAP_HOUR
        Local hour at which maximum time gap ended
 
      END_GAP_MIN
        Local minute at which maximum time gap ended
 
      END_GAP_SEC
        Local second at which maximum time gap ended
 
      WARNING_FLAG
        Flags indicating number and length of time gaps,
        possible values are:
        .I - one or more time gaps of 3 hours or more,
        .C - a cross-midnight gap of 4 hours or more,
        IC - both .I and .C conditions,
        BB - no warning.
 
      Note: For the temperature and time parameters, negative numbers are
      used to represent no recorded values on those sols.
 
 
    Sensor Description
    ==================
      The footpad sensors, mounted on footpad 2 of each lander, are
      rugged thermocouples designed for measurements during
      atmospheric entry for engineering and the Entry Science
      Experiment [SEIFF1976].  They have served as a simple indicator
      of the surface, or near-surface, temperature during the mission
      [TILLMAN1985].  They were not designed to make good
      measurements of atmospheric temperature after landing, since
      their exposure, size, and location makes them susceptible to
      large conduction and radiation errors.  Their relatively large
      radiation and conduction errors, their exposure to winds
      disturbed by the footpad and lander, and changes in the shadows
      of the lander with season and location, make it difficult to
      correct these radiation errors.  At VL-1, the footpad sensor
      was buried by soil while for VL-2, it was free within the
      footpad.  Details of the burial and exposure are given in
      [MOOREETAL1987].
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The footpad temperature measurement is incorporated in the
      engineering data stream.  Measurements are taken along with all
      other data in the same lander data format and the formats were
      sampled to satisfy both engineering and science requirements.
      For example, each meteorology data frame was associated with a
      prior and subsequent engineering frame to provide an
      atmospheric pressure measurement for the meteorology experiment
      - the pressure sensor was sampled by the engineering data
      system, not the Viking Meteorology Instrument System.
      Engineering and meteorology sampling requirements produced data
      frames at intervals from much less than one second to
      approximately 40 minutes.
 
      The original point by point data (see PDS data set name VL1/VL2
      MARS METEOROLOGY CALIBRATED FOOTPAD TEMP V1.0; data set id
      VL1/VL2-M-FTS-3-FOOTPAD-TEMP-V1.0) were edited to remove
      communications generated errors using automated procedures to
      reject bad points.  These procedures checked against seasonally
      varying limit files and rejected points outside the limits.
      During the processing, these limits were updated for each lander
      and year. After the automated editing, the measurements were
      plotted, and remaining errors removed.  The editing is similar to
      that of the Viking Lander pressure record (see PDS data set name
      VL1/VL2 MARS METEOROLOGY DATA CALIBRATED DATA PRESSURE V1.0; data
      set id VL1/VL2-M-MET-3-P-V1.0, and description in [NSSDC1993]).
 
      The sol averages and ranges are calculated from this point-by-
      point data set.  The sol average is obtained by weighting each
      measurement according to the period that it represents.  The sol
      range is determined by subtracting the minimum from the maximum
      temperature on each sol.  Each sol is checked for the maximum
      period between samples and when this value exceeds approximately
      three hours, the raw data are manually edited.  The editing
      determines the validity of the data for each of the several
      functions which are separately flagged.  For example, the data may
      be adequate to form a daily average but not a daily range.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      This data set is sufficiently small that it is available online
      from the Planetary Atmospheres Node of the Planetary Data
      System (PDS), or from the National Space Science Data Center
      (NSSDC).
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      The footpad sensor was not designed to necessarily survive or
      provide low errors in the landed configuration footpad.  It is
      larger in diameter than the meteorology sensor and therefore
      has a slower response time and is more subject to conduction
      and radiation errors, as well as air heated or cooled by some
      lander components.  Since it is within the footpad and downwind
      of the lander for at least 120 degrees of wind direction, it is
      strongly influenced by the temperature of the lander leg, the
      footpad, and the lander.  At times the lander shades it from
      direct sunlight and its long wave radiation to space is
      constrained by the lander.  An example of the seasonal shading
      error can be seen in [TILLMAN1985] where the annual cycle of
      temperature is plotted as a function of time for several years.
      Due to the shading problems, there are two local peaks in the
      annual cycle instead of the expected single peak.
 
      The footpad sensor is buried under the soil on VL-1 but not
      VL-2.  [MOOREETAL1987] provide details of the exposure of the
      sensors.  [SEIFF1976] states that the &apos;overall expected
      accuracy&apos; in the descent phase is 1.25 degrees Kelvin.
      Comparing the design and exposure to the atmospheric sensor, it
      is expected that conduction and radiation errors of up to 10
      degrees or more at low wind speeds are present in data from the
      VL-2 sensor.  For VL-1, the base of the footpad is buried about
      .165 meters below the surface ([MOOREETAL1987], figures 16b,
      88a, 88b), and only the top of the sensor housing is exposed.
      It appears that the thermocouples are buried well below the
      surface.  Therefore, the temperature would be determined by the
      albedo, thermal conductivity of the soil and all of the
      associated lander physical parameters.
 
      Regardless of these problems, the VL-1 footpad sensor gives a
      clear indication of major events on short time scales such as
      great dust storms, as shown by [TILLMAN1985].
 
      The data set contains the following fields related to
      confidence level (listed as the field name followed by a
      description):
 
      MAX_TIME_GAP
        Length of maximum time gap between two
        measurements (hours)
 
      BEG_GAP_HOUR
        Local hour of maximum time gap start
 
      BEG_GAP_MIN
        Local minute of maximum time gap start
 
      BEG_GAP_SEC
        Local second of maximum time gap start
 
      END_GAP_HOUR
        Local hour at which maximum time gap ended
 
      END_GAP_MIN
        Local minute at which maximum time gap ended
 
      END_GAP_SEC
        Local second at which maximum time gap ended
 
      WARNING_FLAG
        Flags indicating number and length of time gaps
 
 
    Data Coverage
    =============
      Footpad temperature measurements were taken throughout the
      mission but were generated in edited and summarized format only
      after raw spacecraft mission data processing was implemented
      and formally begun by the Viking Computer Facility (VCF),
      Department of Atmospheric Sciences, University of Washington.
      These measurements from Viking Lander 1 were archived beginning
      at sol 1008 (May 22, 1979) and ending at sol 2245 (Nov.  13,
      1982), the Lander&apos;s last downlink.  For Viking Lander 2, data
      were archived beginning at VL2 sol 1000 and ending on sol 1050,
      which was the last high quality downlink.  (Subsequent to sol
      1050, there were unsuccessful attempts for about 100 sols to
      recover from a VL-2 power system failure).
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>75-075C-02B</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>75-083C-02B</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

