<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.clem1-l-rss-5-gravity-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CLEM1 LUNAR GRAVITY V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_space_program_science_experiment::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.clem1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.clem1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-rss-5-gravity-v1.0__browserc_clem1-l-rss-5-gravity-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-rss-5-gravity-v1.0__browserp_clem1-l-rss-5-gravity-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-rss-5-gravity-v1.0__dvo_geo_clem1-l-rss-5-gravity-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Davies, M.E., V.K. Abalakin, A. Brahic, M. Bursa, B.H. Chovitz, J.H. Lieske,
                   P.K. Seidelmann, A.T. Sinclair, and Y.S. Tjuflin, Report of the IAU/IAG/COSPAR
                   Working Group on Cartographic Coordinates and Rotational Elements of the
                   Planets and Satellites: 1991, Celestial Mechanics and Dynamical Astronomy, 53,
                   377-397, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DAVIESETAL1992B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Konopliv, A.S., W.L. Sjogren, R.N. Wimberly, R.A. Cook, and V. Alwar, A high
                   resolution lunar gravity field and predicted orbit behaviour, AIAA
                   Astrodynamics Specialist Conference, Victoria, B.C., Canada, Paper 93-622, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KONOPLIVETAL1993B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lemoine, F.G., D.E. Smith, D.D. Rowlands, M.T. Zuber, and G.A. Neumann,
                   Results from the Clementine lunar geodesy investigation, AAS/AIAA
                   Astrodynamics Conference, Halifax, Nova Scotia, Canada, Paper 95-313,
                   1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEMOINEETAL1995B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Zuber, M., D.E. Smith, F.G. Lemoine, and G. Neumann, The Shape and Internal
                   Structure of the Moon from the Clementine Mission, Science, Vol. 266, pp.
                   1839-1843, 1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ZUBERETAL1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CLEM1-L-RSS-5-GRAVITY-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CLEM1 LUNAR GRAVITY V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1996-01-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1994-02-19</start_time>
        <stop_time>1994-05-03</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>FRANK G. R. LEMOINE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Lemoine, F. G. R., CLEM1 LUNAR GRAVITY V1.0,
            CLEM1-L-RSS-5-GRAVITY-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 1996
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Clementine Lunar Gravity Archive contains gravity products
            derived from radio tracking data of the Clementine spacecraft
            while it orbited the Moon.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The gravitational signature of the Moon was determined from
            velocity perturbations of the Clementine spacecraft as measured
            from the Doppler shift of the S-band radio tracking signal.
            Clementine was tracked by NASA&apos;s Deep Space Network (DSN) at
            Goldstone, California, Canberra, Australia, Madrid, Spain, as
            well as by the Pomonkey, Maryland, tracking station operated by
            the Naval Research Laboratory. The tracking data were used to
            determine the Clementine orbit about the Moon, as well as the
            lunar gravity field [ZUBERETAL1994]. A detailed description of
            how the Clementine orbits were computed and an assessment of
            their quality can be found in [LEMOINEETAL1995B].
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The gravitational signature of the Moon was determined from
      velocity perturbations of the Clementine spacecraft as measured
      from the Doppler shift of the S-band radio tracking signal.
      Clementine was tracked by NASA&apos;s Deep Space Network (DSN) at
      Goldstone, California, Canberra, Australia, Madrid, Spain, as
      well as by the Pomonkey, Maryland, tracking station operated by
      the Naval Research Laboratory.  The tracking data were used to
      determine the Clementine orbit about the Moon, as well as the
      lunar gravity field [ZUBERETAL1994].  A detailed description of
      how the Clementine orbits were computed and an assessment of
      their quality can be found in [LEMOINEETAL1995B].
 
      The Clementine data were combined with S-band tracking
      observations from Lunar Orbiters 1, 2, 3, 4, and 5 and from the
      Apollo 15 and 16 subsatellites [KONOPLIVETAL1993B].  With the
      exception of the Lunar Orbiter 4 and Lunar Orbiter 5
      spacecraft, these spacecraft lacked the global coverage of
      Clementine (LO-4 and LO-5 were placed in near polar, elliptical
      orbits of the Moon), but most had lower periapsis altitudes and
      thus provided distributed regions of short-wavelength
      resolution in the vicinity of spacecraft periapses (generally
      +/- 40 degrees latitude).
 
      There are seven gravity products in this archive.  These
      include a 70-th degree and order spherical harmonic
      gravitational field model, designated Goddard Lunar Gravity
      Model 2 (GLGM-2), and digital gridded maps of the Free-air
      gravity anomalies (at 1 and 0.25 degree resolution), Free-air
      gravity errors, Bouguer gravity anomalies, Geoid anomalies,
      Geoid anomaly errors, and effective crustal thicknesses.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      There are 3 data types for the gravity products found on this
      volume: tabular, array, and image data.  The file containing
      the spherical harmonic coefficients of the Moon&apos;s gravity field
      (GLGM-2) is in tabular format, with each row in the table
      containing the degree index m, the order index n, the
      coefficients Cmn and Smn, and the uncertainties in Cmn and Smn.
 
      The gridded digital maps of Free-air gravity anomalies (at 1
      and 0.25 degree resolution), Free-air gravity errors, Bouguer
      anomalies, Geoid anomalies, Geoid anomaly errors, and crustal
      thicknesses are ASCII 2-D data arrays.  There is also a
      byte-scaled image of each of the gridded products.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      The gravitational signature of the Moon was determined from
      velocity perturbations of the Clementine spacecraft, Lunar
      Orbiters and Apollo 15 and 16 subsatellites as measured from
      the Doppler shift of the S-band radio tracking signal.  The
      Clementine Doppler data from the DSN stations were acquired
      with a count interval of 10 seconds.  Data from the Pomonkey
      station were also at a 10 second count interval.  Most of the
      historic Doppler data were at a count interval of 60 seconds.
 
      The Free-air gravity anomalies of the Moon (in milligals,
      mGals, where 1 mGal = 0.01 mm/s^2) are evaluated at the
      surface, and are determined from the GLGM-2 solution.  The
      Free-air gravity errors are also in mGals.  Bouguer anomalies,
      determined by subtracting the gravitational attraction of the
      surface topography from the free-air anomaly, are in mGals.
      Geoid anomalies and errors are in meters.  Crustal thicknesses,
      assuming a constant-density crust and mantle, are in
      kilometers.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The GLGM-2 gravity solution consists of 708,854 observations,
      of which 361,794 were contributed by Clementine.  The data were
      divided into 392 spans or independent arcs based on
      considerations of data coverage and timing of maneuvers.  The
      table below summarizes the number of observations and arcs from
      each spacecraft:
 
      Satellite Number Avg.  Arc Total Observations of Arcs Length
      (hours)
 
      Lunar Orbiter-1 48 21.76 44,503 Lunar Orbiter-2 62 16.38 68,732
      Lunar Orbiter-3 68 17.77 61,852 Lunar Orbiter-4 11 70.16 48,734
      Lunar Orbiter-5 51 33.74 47,690 Apollo-15 subsatellite 81 16.76
      44,096 Apollo-16 subsatellite 35 4.55 31,453 Clementine 36
      44.16 361,794
 
      Total 392 708,854
 
 
      For each arc certain parameters were determined: the spacecraft
      state (position and velocity), a solar radiation pressure
      coefficient, Doppler biases for each station over the arc to
      account for frequency biases, and the mismodeling of the
      effects of the troposphere and ionosphere on the Doppler
      signal.  The a priori force model that was used included the
      [KONOPLIVETAL1993B] gravity model, and included the third-body
      perturbations due to the Sun, the Earth, and all the planets,
      the solar radiation pressure perturbation, the Earth-induced
      and solar-induced solid lunar tides (assuming a k2 value of
      0.027, as derived by previous investigators), and appropriate
      relativistic effects.  The DE200 set of planetary and lunar
      ephemerides was used in the analyses.
 
      The data in GLGM-2 were weighted at 1 to 3 cm/s, with the
      exception of the Clementine data, which had a data weight of
      0.5 cm/s (because of their high quality).  Although each data
      arc was typically fit to the level of a few mm/s, the data were
      downweighted in this fashion in order to attenuate the power of
      the high degree terms, and account for any systematic
      mismodeling that might still be present in the data.  The
      solution was also derived using a power law rule (Kaula
      constraint of 15 x 10e-5/L^2), where L is the spherical
      harmonic degree.  Without this constraint, the high degree
      terms develop excessive power.
 
      In the process of deriving GLGM-2, extensive experiments were
      performed in order to select the a priori weights for the sets
      of data in the solution - and care was taken to downweight or
      delete data that produced spurious signals in the anomaly maps.
      (GLGM-2 is the 309th in the series of lunar gravity solutions
      that have been developed in the course of this work since just
      prior to the Clementine mission).  The gravity anomalies in
      this model were evaluated at the lunar surface.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      N/A
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      The coordinate system for the gravity data, and the
      coefficients in the GLGM-2 gravity field, is selenocentric,
      center of mass, longitude positive east.  The location of the
      pole and the prime meridian are defined as per the reference
      from [DAVIESETAL1992B], with corrections for two of the terms.
 
      alpha_0 = 270.000 + 0.003 T - 3.878 sin E1 - 0.120 sin E2 +
      0.070 sin E3 - 0.017 sin E4
 
      delta_0 = 66.541 + 0.013 T + 1.543 cos E1 + 0.024 cos E2 -
      0.028 cos E3 + 0.007 cos E4
 
      W = 38.317 + 13.1763582 d + 3.558 sin E1 + 0.121 sin E2 - 0.064
      sin E3 + 0.016 sin E4 + 0.025 sin E5
 
      E1 = 125.045 - 0.052992 d E2 = 250.090 - 0.105984 d E4 =
      176.625 + 13.340716 d
 
      The quantities E3 and E5 are listed incorrectly in the
      reference, and were corrected by [DAVIESETAL1993B, personal
      communication to the Clementine Science Team].  The correct
      values are:
 
      E3 = 260.008 + 13.012001 d E5 = 357.529 + 0.985600 d
 
      where T = interval in Julian centuries (36525 days) from the
      standard epoch.
 
      d = interval in days from the standard epoch.
 
      W = location of the prime meridian in degrees.
 
      alpha_0 and delta_0 are the standard equatorial coordinates, in
      degrees, with equinox J2000 at epoch J2000 (right ascension and
      declination).
 
      Standard Epoch is 2000 January 1.5 or Julian Date 2451545.0
      TBD.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      N/A
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The Clementine gravity dataset will be available electronically
      via the World-Wide Web and anonymous FTP transfer.  File types
      include ASCII and binary formats.  Formats will be based on
      standards established by the Planetary Data System (PDS).
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      The data noise on the historic Doppler data ranged from 0.3 to
      several mm/s, depending on the arc, and most of the data were
      at a count interval of 60 seconds.  The Clementine Doppler data
      from the DSN stations had a data noise of 0.25 mm/s with a
      count interval of 10 seconds.  Clementine was also tracked by a
      30 meter antenna of the Naval Research Lab in southern
      Maryland.  These data were also at 10 second count interval and
      had a data noise of 2.5 to 3.0 mm/s.
 
      Errors in the Free-air gravity anomalies from GLGM-2 ranged
      from 17-24 mGals over the equatorial nearside (+/- 30 degrees
      latitude), 32-36 mGals over the equatorial farside, and 40-45
      mGals over the high-latitude farside.
 
      The relative errors in Clementine topography are governed by
      the orbital accuracy, of order 10 m and the Lidar noise, of
      order 40 m, which translates to a 5 mGal error in the Bouguer
      anomaly.
 
      Errors in the Geoid range from 4-24 meters.
 
      Gridded digital maps showing the errors associated with the
      Free-air gravity and Geoid anomalies are included in the
      archive.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      The volume containing the Clementine gravity and topography
      datasets was reviewed by Clementine mission scientists and by
      PDS.
 
 
    Data Coverage/Quality
    =====================
      The Clementine data now provide the most powerful constraint on
      the low degree and order field, and strongly determine the low
      degree harmonics, as well as the sectoral terms of the lunar
      gravity field through degree 20.  The historical data from the
      Lunar Orbiters and the Apollo-15 subsatellite provided
      distributed regions of higher resolution coverage in the
      equatorial regions (+40 degrees N to -40 degrees S).  This is a
      consequence of the lower periapse altitude of these satellites:
      the Lunar Orbiters were placed in eccentric orbits with
      periapse altitudes as low as 30 km, but more typically between
      60 to 100 km.  The Apollo-15 subsatellite was located in a
      near-circular, retrograde orbit (inclination of 152 degrees)
      with a mean altitude of 100 km.  Clementine, with its eccentric
      near-five hour orbit, in contrast had a periapse altitude of
      415 km.
 
      Because of the Moon&apos;s synchronous rotation, spacecraft cannot
      be directly tracked from Earth over a large part of the lunar
      far side, so there is no tracking data from 120 to 240 degrees
      longitude in the +/- 45 degree latitude band.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      See Data Coverage/Quality above.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>94-004A-08A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

