<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.go-a-nims-3-pointspec-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>NIMS RADIANCE POINT SPECTRA OF IDA AND DACTYL V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.galileo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:nims.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.243_ida::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.asteroid::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.dactyl_ida_i::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-a-nims-3-pointspec-v1.0__browserp_go-a-nims-3-pointspec-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Carlson, R.W., P.R. Weissman, W.D. Smythe, J.C. Mahoney, and the NIMS Science
                   and Engineering Teams, Near-Infrared Mapping Spectrometer Experiment on
                   Galileo, Space Science Reviews 60: 457-502, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CARLSONETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Carlson, R.W., P.R. Weissman, M. Segura, L.W. Kamp, W. Smythe, and 9 others,
                   Infrared imaging spectroscopy of asteroid 243 Ida and discovery spectra of
                   satellite 1993 (243) 1, Bulletin of the American Astronomical Society 26, 1156,
                   1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CARLSONETAL1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GO-A-NIMS-3-POINTSPEC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>NIMS RADIANCE POINT SPECTRA OF IDA AND DACTYL V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2013-06-14</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1993-08-28T14:57:59Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1993-08-28T16:49:33Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JAMES GRANAHAN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Granahan, J.C., NIMS Radiance Point Spectra of Ida and Dactyl
            V1.0. GO-A-NIMS-3-POINTSPEC-V1.0. NASA Planetary Data System,
            2013.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Radiometrically corrected point spectra of asteroid 243 Ida and a
            spectrum of the asteroid satellite Dactyl (Ida I) acquired by
            Galileo NIMS on August 28, 1993.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data volume contains radiometrically corrected point spectra
            of asteroid 243 Ida and a spectrum of the asteroid satellite
            Dactyl (Ida I) as acquired by the Galileo spacecraft Near
            Infrared Mapping Spectrometer (NIMS) on August 28, 1993. They
            record the spectra collected as the Galileo spacecraft approached
            the 243 Ida system. These data are products of the calibration of
            the raw data number files idu002tn.qub, idu005tn.qub,
            idu006tn.qub, idu007tn.qub, idu019tn.qub, idu020tn.qub,
            idu022tn.qub, idu028tn.qub, idu032tn.qub, idu033tn.qub, and
            idu035tn.qub (DATA SET ID =&apos;GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0&apos;)
            with calibration factors acquired during the Jovian tour of the
            Galileo mission. These raw data .qub files are archived in the
            Imaging Node of the NASA Planetary Data System (PDS). The
            calibrated spectra consist of radiance and incidence/flux
            measurements for wavelengths between 0.7 - 5.2 micrometers.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    243 Ida radiance Near Infrared Mapping Spectrometer point spectra data
    description
 
    1    -    INTRODUCTION
 
    This data volume contains a radiometrically corrected point spectra of
    asteroid 243 Ida and a spectrum of the asteroid satellite Dactyl as
    acquired by the Galileo spacecraft Near Infrared Mapping Spectrometer
    (NIMS, Carlson et al., 1992) on August 28, 1993 (Carlson et al., 1994).
    They record the spectra collected as the Galileo spacecraft approached the
    243 Ida system. These data are products of the calibration of the raw data
    number files idu002tn.qub, idu005tn.qub, idu006tn.qub, idu007tn.qub,
    idu019tn.qub, idu020tn.qub, idu022tn.qub, idu028tn.qub, idu032tn.qub,
    idu033tn.qub, and idu035tn.qub (DATA SET ID =&apos;GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0&apos;) with
    calibration factors (DATA SET ID = &apos;GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0&apos;) acquired
    during the Jovian tour of the Galileo mission.  These raw data .qub files
    are archived in the Imaging Node of the NASA Planetary Data System (PDS).
    These calibrated spectra consist of radiance and incidence/flux
    measurements for wavelengths between 0.7 - 5.2 micrometers.  The data
    files are named by combining the target name, the Galileo spacecraft clock
    value at the start of the observation, and the data product type.  For
    instance &apos;ida2025514radiance.tab&apos; is a combination of the target name
    &apos;Ida&apos;,  the spacecraft clock time of &apos;2025514&apos;, and the &apos;radiance&apos; data
    type.  The .tab suffix indicates that the file is a PDS formatted text
    table file.  The &apos;reflectance&apos; data type refers to files that contain
    incidence/flux spectra.
 
    2    -     DATA OVERVIEW TABLE
 
    File                        Bands  Object  Observation Target
                                                Start(UT)  Distance(km)
    ida2025514radiance.tab        17   243 Ida  14:57:59   83244.2
    ida2025514reflectance.tab     17   243 Ida  14:57:59   83244.2
    ida2025537radiance.tab        17   243 Ida  15:21:13   66040.8
    ida2025537reflectance.tab     17   243 Ida  15:21:13   66040.8
    ida2025541radiance.tab        17   243 Ida  15:25:25   64069.1
    ida2025541reflectance.tab     17   243 Ida  15:25:25   64069.1
    ida2025552radiance.tab        17   243 Ida  15:37:07   55639.0
    ida2025552reflectance.tab     17   243 Ida  15:37:07   55639.0
    ida2025560radiance.tab        17   243 Ida  15:44:29   33021.8
    ida2025560reflectance.tab     17   243 Ida  15:44:29   33021.8
    ida2025564radiance.tab        17   243 Ida  15:48:39   47087.6
    ida2025564reflectance.tab     17   243 Ida  15:48:39   47087.6
    ida2025587radiance.tab        17   243 Ida  16:11:57   29819.8
    ida2025587reflectance.tab     17   243 Ida  16:11:57   29819.8
    ida2025605radiance.tab        379  243 Ida  16:29:54   14694.7
    ida2025605reflectance.tab     379  243 Ida  16:29:54   14694.7
    ida2025609radiance.tab        396  243 Ida  16:33:53   12689.3
    ida2025609reflectance.tab     396  243 Ida  16:33:53   12689.3
    ida2025612radiance.tab        51   243 Ida  16:37:45   10356.6
    ida2025612reflectance.tab     51   243 Ida  16:37:45   10356.6
    dactyl2025622radiance.tab     17   Dactyl   16:47:45   3957.0
    dactyl2025622reflectance.tab  17   Dactyl   16:47:45   3957.0
 
    3    -     GALILEO MISSION DESCRIPTION
 
    Galileo was a mission to Jupiter to perform long-term studies of the
    Jovian atmosphere and detailed studies of the Galilean satellites (Jet
    Propulsion Laboratory Interoffice Memorandum GLL-NAV-92-90, 1992).  It
    consisted of a two part spacecraft, an orbiter and an atmospheric probe.
    Both components were launched from the space shuttle Atlantis on October
    18, 1989. The orbiter contained remote sensing, particles, and wave
    sensors.  The remote sensing instruments included the Solid State Imager
    and the Near Infrared Mapping Spectrometer.  The atmospheric probe
    contained in-situ sensors to directly measure the atmosphere of Jupiter.
    The Galileo spacecraft encountered Venus (February 10, 1990), the Earth
    Moon system (December 8, 1990 and December 8, 1992), asteroid 951 Gaspra
    (October 29, 1991), asteroid 243 Ida (August 28, 1993) before entering the
    orbit of Jupiter on December 8, 1995.  This data set is from the asteroid
    243 Ida encounter. The Galileo mission investigated the Jovian system by
    deploying its atmospheric probe on July 13, 1995 and conducting
    observations until plunged into Jupiter on September 21, 2003.
 
    4    -     INSTRUMENT DESCRIPTION
 
    The Near Infrared Mapping Spectrometer (Carlson et al., 1992) instrument
    was an imaging spectrometer covering the wavelength region 0.7 to 5.2
    micrometers.  Its spectral resolution is 0.025 micron beyond 1 micron, and
    0.0125 microns below 1 micron, yielding 204 spectral elements in nominal
    mode.  The nominal pixel size is a square 0.5 x 0.5 milliradians.  The
    instrument acquires data in the order: (1) sampling of 17 detectors, (2)
    stepping of the scan mirror (20 elements in cross-cone), (3) stepping of
    the grating (nominally 12 steps per cycle).  The nominal 204 wavelength
    cycle requires 4 1/3 seconds.  The detectors (2 silicon, 15 indium
    antimonide) sample approximately uniformly across the spectrum.  The
    stepping of the grating provided NIMS with a variety of spectral data
    collection modes that ranged from 17 channels (no grating step movements)
    to 408 channels (24 grating step movements).
 
    5   -      243 IDA ASTEROID ENCOUNTER NIMS OBSERVATIONS
 
    The Galileo spacecraft performed a flyby encounter of the 243 Ida asteroid
    system with its closest approach occurring at 16:52:04 on August 28, 1993
    UTC.  The closest approach was at 243 Ida&apos;s dark
    side, 75 degrees south ecliptic latitude, at a 2400 kilometer range.
 
    NIMS conducted two types of science observations; the rotation
    observations and the &apos;close-in&apos; observations. The rotation portion covered
    approximate 390 degrees of 243 Ida rotation starting at -322 rims from
    closest approach. A rim is a unit of Galileo spacecraft clock time that is
    60 2/3 seconds in length.  NIMS acquired samples every 90 degrees (17 and
    408 channel modes), 30 degrees (102 channel mode), and 15 degrees (102
    channel mode) of rotation. The &apos;close-in&apos; portion covers from -28 rims
    prior to closest approach (the end of the rotation observations) to 1 rim
    after closest approach. At -28 rims and -22 rims, NIMS acquired two 204
    channel mode samples. At -11 rims before closest approach, NIMS observed
    243 Ida in the 102 channel mode to determine asteroid composition. From -5
    rims to 1 rim, collaborative NIMS and Galileo Solid State Imager (SSI)
    observations were taken; NIMS acquires data in a 17 channel mode at the
    highest spatial resolution possible for the  243 Ida Encounter. NIMS also
    rode along in the 17 channel mode on additional SSI observations from -1
    to +1 Rim to obtain the highest possible spatial resolution data on the
    asteroid.  Radiometric and photometric calibration observations were
    conducted by NIMS after the completion of the science observation
    sequence.
 
    The products in this data volume are a subset of the spatially unresolved
    NIMS observations of the 243 Ida system.  The Galileo mission at the time
    of the 243 Ida encounter did not have an operational high gain antenna to
    relay the data back to Earth.  The observations were recorded to a
    spacecraft tape recorder a played back to Earth.  A subset of the
    collected NIMS data was relayed back to Earth.  The data set was further
    reduced in number by calibrating only the data that had significant target
    signal.  The number of spectral channels was also reduced to those that
    could be calibrated. This reduction was primarily due to the erroneous
    scan platform motion that occurred during the 243 Ida encounter.  This
    motion offset asteroid 243 Ida in the NIMS aperture/slit during the sensor
    scan sequence.  This motion resulted in a varying intensity of the 243 Ida
    signal as the NIMS sensor collected data. In these instances, only the
    data from the first grating step were calibrated.
 
 
    6   -      DATA FILE FORMAT DESCRIPTION
 
    The data files for the 243 Ida radiance Near Infrared Mapping Spectrometer
    point spectra are ASCII (American Standard Code for Information
    Interchange) text files.  Each data file contains columns of floating
    point numeric values separated by spaces.  The radiance files consist of
    columns of wavelength values (micrometers), radiance
    (microwatts*centimeters**-2*steradians** -1*micrometers**-1), and
    instrument radiance precision (microwatts*centimeters**-2*steradians**
    -1*micrometers**-1).  The reflectance files consist of columns of
    wavelength values (micrometers), reflectance (a ratio of incidence/flux),
    and instrument reflectance precision (a ratio of incidence/flux precision
    values).  The calibration files consist of columns of wavelength values
    (micrometers), sensitivity
    (micrometers*steradians*centimeters**2*microwatts**-1), and dark values
    (data number). The solar files consist of columns of wavelength values
    (micrometers), and solar radiance (microwatts*centimeters**-2*steradians**
    -1*micrometers**-1).
 
    7   -    DATA PROCESSING HISTORY
 
    The radiance data in this data volume are derived from archived NIMS
    spectral images files available from the NASA PDS Imaging Node.  The 243
    Ida and Dactyl NIMS observations are archived in the Imaging Node as
    spectral image files of data number or instrument count values (DATA SET
    ID =&apos;GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0&apos;). These data number values were converted into
    radiance using the following equation: radiance value = (data number value
    - dark value)/sensitivity value. The dark value was determined through an
    average of background sky pixels for the observation.  The sensitivity
    value was obtained from recorded values used to process the NIMS
    observations of the Jupiter satellites Europa and Ganymede (DATA SET ID =
    &apos;GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0&apos;) that employed the same instrument collection
    modes and gains as the 243 Ida observations. The reflectance or
    incidence/flux values were calculated through a ratio of the radiance
    spectra over solar radiance spectrum. These reflectance values were scaled
    by a pixel fill factor determined by the coverage of a NIMS pixel by the
    aspect of the target as imaged by the Galileo Solid State Imager. The
    solar radiance spectra were created through an application of the inverse
    square law of radiance propagation to solar values archived in a NIMS Io
    observation (DATA SET ID = &apos;GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0&apos;).  The inverse square
    law was used to convert the solar radiance values at Io&apos;s distance to
    those that would be observed at asteroid 243 Ida. The point spectra in
    this data volume are the radiance or incidence/flux values of the single
    pixel in the processed spectral image that contained data from the
    spatially unresolved 243 Ida or Dactyl.  File specific processing
    information can be found in the following paragraphs of this section.
 
    The file ida2025514radiance.tab is derived from DN values from line 5
    sample 11 in PDS file IDU019TN.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0) and
    calibrated with values from the PDS file G2C002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID
    GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0).
 
    The file ida2025514calib.tab contains the calibration values from the PDS
    file G2C002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create
    ida2025514radiance.tab.
 
    The file ida2025514reflectance.tab is derived by a ratio of radiance
    values from ida2025514radiance.tab with solar radiance values derived from
    the PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0). A 28%
    pixel fill factor was used based on corresponding Galileo Solid State
    Imager imagery.
 
    The file ida2025514solar.tab contains the solar radiance derived from the
    PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create
    ida2025514reflectance.tab.  Sun and target distances used in the inverse
    square law calculations to model solar values at the target used the SPICE
    Tool Kit and the SPICE files s970311a.bsp, naif0008.tls, mips010314.tpc,
    and mk00062a.tsc.
 
    The file ida2025537radiance.tab is derived from DN values from line 14
    sample 11 in PDS file IDU020TN.QUB(DATA SET ID =GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0) and
    calibrated with values from the PDS file C3E001CI.QUB (DATA SET ID
    GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0).
 
    The file ida2025537calib.tab contains the calibration values from the PDS
    file C3E001CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create
    ida2025537radiance.tab.
 
    The file ida2025537reflectance.tab is derived by a ratio of radiance
    values from ida2025537radiance.tab with solar radiance values derived from
    the PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0). A 19%
    pixel fill factor was used based on corresponding Galileo Solid State
    Imager imagery.
 
    The file ida2025537solar.tab contains the solar radiance derived from the
    PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create
    ida2025537reflectance.tab. Sun and target distances used in the inverse
    square law calculations to model solar values at the target used the SPICE
    Tool Kit and the SPICE files s970311a.bsp, naif0008.tls, mips010314.tpc,
    and mk00062a.tsc.
 
    The file ida2025541radiance.tab is derived from DN values from line 4
    sample 11 in PDS file IDU035TN.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0) and
    calibrated with values from the PDS file C3E001CI.QUB (DATA SET ID
    GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0).
 
    The file ida2025541calib.tab contains the calibration values from the PDS
    file C3E001CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create
    ida2025541radiance.tab.
 
    The file ida2025541reflectance.tab is derived by a ratio of radiance
    values from ida2025541radiance.tab with solar radiance values derived from
    the PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0). A 50%
    pixel fill factor was used based on corresponding Galileo Solid State
    Imager imagery.
 
    The file ida2025541solar.tab contains the solar radiance derived from the
    PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create
    ida2025541reflectance.tab. Sun and target distances used in the inverse
    square law calculations to model solar values at the target used the SPICE
    Tool Kit and the SPICE files s970311a.bsp, naif0008.tls, mips010314.tpc,
    and mk00062a.tsc.
 
    The file ida2025552radiance.tab is derived from DN values from line 6
    sample 11 in PDS file IDU028TN.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0) and
    calibrated with values from the PDS file C3E001CI.QUB (DATA SET ID
    GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0).
 
    The file ida2025552calib.tab contains the calibration values from the PDS
    file C3E001CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create
    ida2025552radiance.tab.
 
    The file ida2025552reflectance.tab is derived by a ratio of radiance
    values from ida2025552radiance.tab with solar radiance values derived from
    the PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0). A 100%
    pixel fill factor was used based on corresponding Galileo Solid State
    Imager imagery.
 
    The file ida2025552solar.tab contains the solar radiance derived from the
    PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create
    ida2025552reflectance.tab.  Sun and target distances used in the inverse
    square law calculations to model solar values at the target used the SPICE
    Tool Kit and the SPICE files s970311a.bsp, naif0008.tls, mips010314.tpc,
    and mk00062a.tsc.
 
    The file ida2025560radiance.tab is derived from DN values from line 41
    sample 12 in PDS file IDU022TN.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0) and
    calibrated with values from the PDS file C3E001CI.QUB (DATA SET ID
    GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0).
 
    The file ida2025560calib.tab contains the calibration values from the PDS
    file C3E001CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create
    ida2025560radiance.tab.
 
    The file ida2025560reflectance.tab is derived by a ratio of radiance
    values from ida2025560radiance.tab with solar radiance values derived from
    the PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0). A 100%
    pixel fill factor was used based on corresponding Galileo Solid State
    Imager imagery.
 
    The file ida2025560solar.tab contains the solar radiance derived from the
    PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create
    ida2025560reflectance.tab.  Sun and target distances used in the inverse
    square law calculations to model solar values at the target used the SPICE
    Tool Kit and the SPICE files s970311a.bsp, naif0008.tls, mips010314.tpc,
    and mk00062a.tsc.
 
    The file ida2025564radiance.tab is derived from DN values from line 6
    sample 11 in PDS file IDU032TN.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0)
    calibrated with values from the PDS file C3E001CI.QUB (DATA SET ID
    GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0).
 
    The file ida2025564calib.tab contains the calibration values from the PDS
    file C3E001CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create
    ida2025564radiance.tab.
 
    The file ida2025564reflectance.tab is derived by a ratio of radiance
    values from ida2025564radiance.tab with solar radiance values derived from
    the PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0). A 25%
    pixel fill factor was used based on corresponding Galileo Solid State
    Imager imagery.
 
    The file ida2025564solar.tab contains the solar radiance derived from the
    PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create
    ida2025564reflectance.tab.  Sun and target distances used in the inverse
    square law calculations to model solar values at the target used the SPICE
    Tool Kit and the SPICE files s970311a.bsp, naif0008.tls, mips010314.tpc,
    and mk00062a.tsc.
 
    The file ida2025587radiance.tab is derived from DN values from line 8
    sample 11 in PDS file IDU033TN.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0) and
    calibrated with values from the PDS file C3E001CI.QUB (DATA SET ID
    GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0).
 
    The file ida2025587calib.tab contains the calibration values from the PDS
    file C3E001CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create
    ida2025587radiance.tab.
 
    The file ida2025587reflectance.tab is derived by a ratio of radiance
    values from ida2025587radiance.tab with solar radiance values derived from
    the PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0). A 50%
    pixel fill factor was used based on corresponding Galileo Solid State
    Imager imagery.
 
    The file ida2025587solar.tab contains the solar radiance derived from the
    PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create
    ida2025564reflectance.tab.  Sun and target distances used in the inverse
    square law calculations to model solar values at the target used the SPICE
    Tool Kit and the SPICE files s970311a.bsp, naif0008.tls, mips010314.tpc,
    and mk00062a.tsc.
 
    The file ida2025605radiance.tab is derived from DN values from line 4
    sample 13 in PDS file IDU006TN.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0) and
    calibrated with values from the PDS file G1E003CI.QUB, C3E001CI.QUB, and
    G7G008CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0).
 
    The file ida2025605calib.tab contains the calibration values from the PDS
    files G1E003CI.QUB, C3E001CI.QUB, and G7G008CI.QUB (DATA SET ID
    GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create ida2025605radiance.tab.
 
    The file ida2025605reflectance.tab is derived by a ratio of radiance
    values from ida2025605radiance.tab with solar radiance values derived from
    the PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0). A 100%
    pixel fill factor was used based on corresponding Galileo Solid State
    Imager imagery.
 
    The file ida2025605solar.tab contains the solar radiance derived from the
    PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create
    ida2025605reflectance.tab.  Sun and target distances used in the inverse
    square law calculations to model solar values at the target used the SPICE
    Tool Kit and the SPICE files s970311a.bsp, naif0008.tls, mips010314.tpc,
    and mk00062a.tsc.
 
    The file ida2025609radiance.tab is derived from DN values from line 11
    sample 13 in PDS file IDU005TN.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0) and
    calibrated with values from the PDS files G1E003CI.QUB, C3E001CI.QUB, and
    G7G008CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0).
 
    The file ida2025609calib.tab contains the calibration values from the PDS
    files G1E003CI.QUB, C3E001CI.QUB, and G7G008CI.QUB (DATA SET ID
    GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create ida2025609radiance.tab.
 
    The file ida2025609reflectance.tab is derived by a ratio of radiance
    values from ida2025609radiance.tab with solar radiance values derived from
    the PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0). A 100%
    pixel fill factor was used based on corresponding Galileo Solid State
    Imager imagery.
 
    The file ida2025609solar.tab contains the solar radiance derived from the
    PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create
    ida2025609reflectance.tab.  Sun and target distances used in the inverse
    square law calculations to model solar values at the target used the SPICE
    Tool Kit and the SPICE files s970311a.bsp, naif0008.tls, mips010314.tpc,
    and mk00062a.tsc.
 
    The file ida2025612radiance.tab is derived from DN values from line 4
    sample 16 in PDS file IDU007TN.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0) and
    calibrated with values from the PDS file G1E003CI.QUB, C3E001CI.QUB, and
    G7G008CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0).
 
    The file ida2025612calib.tab contains the calibration values from the PDS
    files G1E003CI.QUB, C3E001CI.QUB, and G7G008CI.QUB (DATA SET ID
    GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create ida2025609radiance.tab.
 
    The file ida2025612reflectance.tab is derived by a ratio of radiance
    values from ida2025612radiance.tab with solar radiance values derived from
    the PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0). A 100%
    pixel fill factor was used based on corresponding Galileo Solid State
    Imager imagery.
 
    The file ida2025612solar.tab contains the solar radiance derived from the
    PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create
    ida2025612reflectance.tab.  Sun and target distances used in the inverse
    square law calculations to model solar values at the target used the SPICE
    Tool Kit and the SPICE files s970311a.bsp, naif0008.tls, mips010314.tpc,
    and mk00062a.tsc.
 
    The file dactyl2025622radiance.tab is derived from DN values from line 5
    sample 13 in PDS file IDU002TN.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0) and
    calibrated with values from the PDS file C3E001CI.QUB (DATA SET ID
    GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0).  Position vectors are the values for 243 Ida.
    Distance and resolution values calculated from Galileo Solid State Imager
    imagery.
 
    The file dactyl2025622calib.tab contains the calibration values from the
    PDS file C3E001CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to create
    dactyl2025622radiance.tab.
 
    The file dactyl2025622reflectance.tab is derived by a ratio of radiance
    values from dactyl2025622radiance.tab with solar radiance values derived
    from the PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0). A
    14% pixel fill factor was used based on corresponding Galileo Solid State
    Imager imagery.
 
    The file dactyl2025622solar.tab contains the solar radiance derived from
    the PDS file C3I002CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to
    create dactyl2025622reflectance.tab.  Sun and target distances used in the
    inverse square law calculations to model solar values at the target used
    the SPICE Tool Kit and the SPICE files s970311a.bsp, naif0008.tls,
    mips010314.tpc, and mk00062a.tsc.
 
 
    8   -    POINT SPECTRA SUPPORT INFORMATION
 
    The point spectra support data information can be found in the table file
    science_index.tab.  This information includes the name of the data file,
    the name of the source file archived in the Imaging Node of the PDS, the
    instrument spacecraft mission name, the instrument name, the spacecraft
    mission phase name, the target of the observation, the instrument
    observation type/mode, the observation identifier, the observation start
    and stop time (Universal Time), the observation start and stop time in
    Julian date, the observation start and stop time as recorded by the
    spacecraft clock, the instrument to target center distance (kilometers),
    the target to Sun distance (kilometers),  the spacecraft to Sun position
    vector in the J2000 reference frame (kilometers), the target to Sun
    position vector in the J2000 reference frame (kilometers),  the target to
    Earth distance (kilometers),  the spacecraft to Earth position vector in
    the J2000 reference frame (kilometers),  the Earth to target position
    vector in the J2000 reference frame (kilometers), the horizontal pixel
    scale (kilometers), the vertical pixel scale (kilometers), the observation
    phase angle (degrees), the Earth to spacecraft state vector in the J2000
    reference frame (position in kilometers, velocity in kilometers/second),
    and the Earth to target state vector in the J2000 reference frame
    (position in kilometers, velocity in kilometers/second). These geometry
    values were calculated using the SPICE Tool kit and the following SPICE
    data files: s970311a.bsp, naif0008.tls, mips010314.tpc, and mk00062a.tsc.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The radiance data in this data volume are in cgs units
    (microwatts*centimeters**-2*steradians**-1*micrometers**-1).
 
    The reflectance data in this volume was created through a ratio of
    observed radiance values with modeled solar radiance values.  It does not
    contain any photometric correction for observation geometry.  The
    reflectance data products also include target thermal emission
signatures.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

