<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ody-m-rss-1-raw-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>2001 MARS ODYSSEY RADIO SCIENCE RAW DATA SET - V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.2001_mars_odyssey::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.ody::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.ody::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:sun.sun::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-rss-1-raw-v1.0__browserp_ody-m-rss-1-raw-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-rss-1-raw-v1.0__browser_ody-m-rss-1-raw-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-rss-1-raw-v1.0__dvo_geo_ody-m-rss-1-raw-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mannucci, A.J., B.D. Wilson, D.N. Yuan, C.H. Ho, U.J. Lindqwister, and T.F.
                   Runge, A Global Mapping Technique for GPS-Derived Ionospheric Total Electron
                   Content Measurements, Radio Science, 33, 565-582, 1998.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MANNUCCIETAL1998</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tyler, G.L., G. Balmino, D.P. Hinson, W.L. Sjogren, D.E. Smith, R.A. Simpson,
                   S.W. Asmar, P. Priest, and J.D. Twicken, Radio science observations with Mars
                   Global Surveyor: Orbit insertion through one Mars year in mapping orbit,
                   Journal of Geophysical Research, 106, 23327-23348, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TYLERETAL2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>ODY-M-RSS-1-RAW-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>2001 MARS ODYSSEY RADIO SCIENCE RAW DATA SET - V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2002-02-28</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2002-01-01</start_time>
        <stop_time>2004-12-31</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>RICHARD A. SIMPSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            2004-02-24 RS:simpson Add ARCHIVE_STATUS and ;Simpson, R.A., 2001
            Mars Odyssey Radio Science Raw Data Set - Map V1.0,
            ODY-M-RSS-1-RAW-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw radio science data and ancillary files from the 2001 Mars
            Odyssey mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            2004-02-27 RS:simpson added2004-03-01 RS:simpson revisedThis data
            set contains archival raw, partially processed, and
            ancillary/supporting radio science data acquired during the 2001
            Mars Odyssey (ODY) mission. The radio observations were carried
            out using the ODY spacecraft and Earth-based receiving stations
            of the NASA Deep Space Network (DSN). The observations were
            designed to test the spacecraft radio system, the DSN ground
            system, and ODY operations procedures and to be used in
            reconstructing the spacecraft orbit, generating high-resolution
            gravity field models of Mars, and determining the nature of the
            near-Sun solar plasma. Of most interest are likely to be the
            Orbit Data Files in the ODF directory and the ionospheric and
            tropospheric media calibration files in the ION and TRO
            directories, respectively. The first ODF in the data set begins
            on 2002-01-06, which was actually in the late stages of the
            Aerobraking Phase and just before periapsis was lowered for about
            2 weeks to about 200 km; the Mapping altitude was about 400 km.
            Data were delivered to PDS in approximately chronological order
            at the rate of 1-3 CD-WO volumes per month, of which about 0.01
            GB/month were ODF&apos;s. By volume, the largest data type was
            either the Archival Tracking Data File (TDF; until early 2003) or
            the Tracking and Navigation File (TNF; beginning early 2003),
            both of which served as parents of the ODF.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The 2001 Mars Odyssey (ODY) Radio Science (RS) Raw Data Archive
      (RDA) is a time-ordered collection of raw and partially
      processed data collected during the 2001 Mars Odyssey mission
      to Mars.  There were no formally recognized radio science
      investigations within the mission.  For information on
      investigations conducted using Mars Global Surveyor (with
      similar capabilities) see [TYLERETAL2001].
 
      This data set was collected beginning in 2002, as the
      spacecraft was nearing its circular orbit, and during its
      Mapping phase which followed.
 
      Two types of measurements were conducted; these are known as
      closed-loop and open-loop recordings.  The closed-loop system
      used a phase-lock loop in the ground receiver to track the
      downlink signal, reporting both amplitude and frequency at
      rates typically of 1-10 times per second.  In the open-loop
      system, the signal was simply converted to a baseband frequency
      range; the entire passband was sampled and recorded for later
      processing.  Closed-loop data are efficient for characterizing
      slowly changing signals and are the input to operational
      navigation and orbit-determination processes.  Open-loop data
      (because of their much higher rate and volume) are collected
      only when the signal is expected to be very dynamic -- such as
      during a spacecraft maneuver or an occultation.  Open-loop
      data were limited to data from the high-gain antenna (HGA)
      deployment and solar conjunction because there was no science
      open-loop requirement within the mission.  Solar conjunction
      data were collected by the JPL Radio Science Systems Group on
      a &apos;best efforts&apos; basis during August 2002.
 
      The data set includes three primary data types.  Archival
      Tracking Data Files (ATDFs or TDFs) are the most primitive (and
      most voluminous) product of the closed-loop system.  Orbit Data
      Files (ODFs) are edited versions of ATDFs, specifically
      targeted to spacecraft navigators and scientists interested in
      gravity fields.  Radio Science Receiver records (RSRs) are the
      primary data type from the open-loop system.
 
      Typical users of these data might analyze range and Doppler
      measurements in ATDFs or ODFs to reconstruct the spacecraft
      trajectory.  Relevant questions would include the measurement
      uncertainties in range and Doppler at different DSN antennas;
      these could set constraints on any model of Mars&apos; gravity
      field developed later, for example.  Analysis of RSRs could
      help determine pointing of the spacecraft high-gain antenna
      (HGA) during and after its deployment.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      The ATDF is the primary output from the ODY closed-loop system.
      ATDFs have 150 fields, though not all had been assigned during
      the ODY era.   Each ATDF in the data set is accompanied by a
      full PDS label which defines both the content and the format
      of the file at the bit level.  ATDF data fields include:
           Range
           High- or low-rate Doppler
           High or low-rate downlink phase
           Differential Range vs Integrated Doppler (DRVID)
           Allan deviation
           Smoothed noise
           Uplink phase
      Other information included in ATDF data records is date and
      time; spacecraft ID; ground station and its configuration;
      status flags and values reported by various ground systems;
      calibration values, noise estimates, and tolerances (station
      delay, transmitter power, etc.); and signal strength.
 
      The ODF is an edited version of the ATDF; it is a smaller file,
      issued more frequently than the ATDF.  It contains the most
      important information (range and Doppler) needed by spacecraft
      navigators and investigators interested in determining
      gravitational fields of bodies such as Mars.  Each ODF is
      accompanied by a full PDS label which describes both the
      content and format of the associated file.  ODF data fields
      include:
           Narrowband spacecraft VLBI, Doppler mode (cycles)
           Narrowband spacecraft VLBI, phase mode (cycles)
           Narrowband quasar VLBI, Doppler mode (cycles)
           Narrowband quasar VLBI, phase mode (cycles)
           Wideband spacecraft VLBI (nanoseconds)
           Wideband quasar VLBI (nanoseconds)
           One-way Doppler (Hertz)
           Two-way Doppler (Hertz)
           Three-way Doppler (Hertz)
           One-way total count phase (cycles)
           Two-way total count phase (cycles)
           Three-way total count phase (cycles)
           PRA planetary operational discrete spectrum range (range
                units)
           SRA planetary operational discrete spectrum range (range
                units)
           RE(GSTDN) range (nanoseconds)
           Azimuth angle (degrees)
           Elevation angle (degrees)
           Hour angle (degrees)
           Declination angle (degrees)
 
      Radio Science Receiver records (RSRs) contain samples of open
      loop receiver output.  Each block of data samples is accompanied
      by a 260-byte header which captures important acquisition
      parameters.  Each RSR is accompanied by a full PDS label which
      describes both the content and format of the file at the bit
      level.  Header information includes:
           Date and time of the first data sample
           Sample rate and channel assignment
           Phase/frequency of the numerically controlled oscillator
           Gain of the channel
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      ATDFs are screened for &apos;bad&apos; data points, which are removed
      before the file is released by the JPL Radio Metric Data
      Conditioning Team (RMDCT).
 
      ODFs are abstracted from subsets of ATDF data.
 
      The open-loop data delivered to Stanford were in the RSR (Radio
      Science Receiver) format.
 
      A full PDS label accompanies each TDF, ODF, and RSR file and
      gives a bit level description of the content and format.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      Data are stored on CD-WO volumes approximately chronologically.
      Files of some types were delayed in delivery to Stanford and
      may be out of strict chronological order on the CDs.  Users
      should consult listings in the INDEX/CUMINDEX.TAB file to
      ascertain full coverage of each data type.
 
      TDFs were created approximately every 1-2 days during the ODY
      mission.  They are stored in the TDF directory on CD volumes.
      File names are of the form   ydddeeeC.TDF  where  y  is the
      one-digit year of the first data,  ddd  is the three-digit
      day-of-year of the first data,  eee  is the three-digit day-
      of-year of the last data, and  C  is a single letter (beginning
      with &apos;A&apos;) denoting the sequence in which files with the same
      ydddeee  were handled.  Generally  ydddeeeB.TDF  is a revised
      version of  ydddeeeA.TDF.  The PDS label has file name
      ydddeeeC.LBL.  The typical TDF contains about 40 Mbytes.
 
      ODFs were typically issued daily during the ODY mission; during
      periods of high spacecraft activity (such as around maneuvers)
      ODFs were released more often.  ODFs are stored in
      the ODF directory.  File names are of the form   ydddeeeC.ODF
      where the file name components are the same as for the TDF
      (previous paragraph).  In most cases  ydddeeeB.ODF was NOT
      simply a revised version of  ydddeeeA.ODF;  there were many
      requests for special ODF processing -- to obtain higher time
      resolution over short intervals, for example.  The PDS label
      has file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical ODF file sizes are small
      multiples of 8064 bytes (e.g., less than 100 kB).
 
      Radio Science Receiver records (RSRs) were produced whenever
      the RSR was set to &apos;record&apos; mode.  These files are stored in the
      RSR directory.  In most cases, the entire RSR run was collected
      into a single ODR file.  But in other cases, it was more
      convenient to subdivide the RSR data; queries were issued for
      shorter time spans, and separate files were produced.  File
      names are of the form  ydddhhmm.RSR  where  y  is the one-digit
      year of the first data,  ddd  is the day-of-year of the first
      data,  hh  is the hour on which the first sample was taken, and
      mm  was the minute on which the first sample was taken.  In
      cases where two files had the same  ydddhhmm  (for example, two
      DSN stations began recording at the same time, or a second query
      was submitted for data which appeared suspicious after the
      first query was processed), the less significant digit in  mm
      of the second file was converted to a letter (&apos;0&apos; became &apos;A&apos;,
      &apos;1&apos; became &apos;B&apos;, ..., &apos;9&apos; became &apos;J&apos;).  In cases were three files
      had the same  ydddhhmm, the less significant  mm  digit was
      converted to &apos;K&apos;, &apos;M&apos;, etc.  The PDS label has file name
      ydddhhmm.LBL.
 
      At 2000 complex samples per second (16 bits I, 16 bits Q), a
      7-minute RSR session would yield an 8260 byte record each
      second or about 3.5 MB total.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      An extensive set of ancillary files is needed for proper
      analysis and interpretation of the radio data (file types
      TDF, ODF, and ODR).  These are organized in parallel
      directories and stored approximately chronologically.  When
      a file type is not represented on a CD-WO volume, the
      corresponding directory has been omitted.  With the exception
      of files stored in the CALIB directory, ancillary files
      appear on only one CD-WO volume.  Users should refer to
      the INDEX/CUMINDEX.TAB listing to locate ancillary files.
 
      Files in the CALIB Directory
      ----------------------------
        Files in the CALIB directory are those likely to have wide
        applicability in working with the raw data.  They help
        unpack and allow use of the raw data, rather than being
        &apos;instrument&apos; calibration data per se.  They include
        clock conversion files, files of planetary constants,
        HGA mounting data files, and leapsecond files.  Each file
        is accompanied by a PDS minimal label.
 
        Clock Conversion files were produced by the JPL/PDS
        Navigation Ancillary Information Facility (NAIF) for use
        with NAIF-developed and ODY-provided software.  These are
        ASCII files of variable length records.  Each record is
        delimited by an ASCII carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13)
        line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10), which may need to be
        converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt; before the file is used
        on the local machine.  File names have the form  TSCnnnnn.SCK
        where  nnnnn  is a sequence number beginning with  00001
        and the file with the highest number is the most recent.
        The value of  nnnnn  is set by NAIF.
 
        Planetary Constants files were produced by the JPL/PDS
        Navigation Ancillary Information Facility (NAIF) for use
        with NAIF-developed and ODY-provided software.  These are
        ASCII files of variable length records.  Each record is
        delimited by an ASCII carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13)
        line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10), which may need to be
        converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt; before the file is used
        on the local machine.  File names have the form  PCKydddC.TPC
        where  y  is the one-digit year of the file creation date,
        ddd  is the day-of-year of the file creation date, and  C
        is a character denoting sequence when more than one file
        with the same  yddd  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos;
        and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers
        of similar coverage files.
 
        Leapsecond files were produced by the JPL/PDS
        Navigation Ancillary Information Facility (NAIF) for use
        with NAIF-developed and ODY-provided software.  These are
        ASCII files of variable length records.  Each record is
        delimited by an ASCII carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13)
        line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10), which may need to be
        converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt; before the file is used
        on the local machine.  File names have the form  LSKydddC.TLS
        where  y  is the one-digit year of the file creation date,
        ddd  is the day-of-year of the file creation date, and  C
        is a character denoting sequence when more than one file
        with the same  yddd  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos;
        and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers
        of similar coverage files.
 
        Antenna Reconstruction Files are typically used in conjunction
        with Antenna Gimbal Kernel (AGK) files to determine the
        pointing of an antenna or the position of its phase center
        with respect to the spacecraft center of mass.  There are
        three types of Antenna Reconstruction Files: the Antenna SPK
        (ASP) File, the Hinge CK (HCK) File, and the Text Frame Kernel
        (TFK) File.  An ASP file contains the locations of low-gain
        antennas and boom lengths for the high-gain antenna (HGA).
        The HCK file contains hinge angles for the (deployed) HGA.
        The TFK file contains information on coordinate frame
        definitions for translating between the spacecraft frame and
        the frame of the high-gain antenna.  File names are of the
        forms HGAnnnnn.ASP, HINGEnnn.HCK, and HGAnnnnn.TFK, where the
        &apos;n&apos; string gives a sequence number.  ASP and HCK files are
        ASCII files in NAIF transfer format; TFK files are ASCII
        files.  In all cases, each record is delimited by the ASCII
        carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10)
        pair.  On some systems it may be necessary to convert the
        &lt;CR&gt;&lt;LF&gt; pair to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt; before using the file on
        the local machine.  Each Antenna Reconstruction File is
        accompanied by a PDS minimal label with the same file name
        except for an extension of .LBL.
 
      Antenna Gimbal Kernel Files (AGK Directory)
      -------------------------------------------
        Antenna Gimbal Kernel files were produced by NAIF.  Each AGK
        file contains information on the state of the HGA azimuth
        and elevation gimbals as a function of time.  These are ASCII
        files in NAIF transfer format.  Each record is delimited by
        an ASCII carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed (LF&gt; (ASCII
        10) pair, which may need to be converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or
        &lt;LF&gt; before the file is used on the local machine.  File
        names have the form  ydddeeeZ.AGK  where  &apos;y&apos; is the least
        significant digit of the year in which data in the file begin,
        &apos;ddd&apos; is the day-of-year when data  begin, &apos;eee&apos; is the
        day-of-year when data end, and &apos;Z&apos; is a  single upper case
        letter indicating order of files when there is more than one
        with the same &apos;ydddeee&apos; in the data set.  Z  is &apos;A&apos; for the
        first file, &apos;B&apos; for the second, etc.  Each AGK file is
        accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        ydddeeeZ.LBL.  Typical file sizes are 1 MByte.
 
      Angular Momentum Desaturation Files (AMD Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Angular Momentum Desaturation files were produced by the ODY
        Spacecraft Team (SCT).  Each AMD file documents a set of AMD
        events on the spacecraft.  These are ASCII files of variable
        length records.  Each record is delimited by an ASCII
        carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII
        10), which may need to be converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt;
        before the file is used on the local machine.  File names
        have the form  ydddeeeC.AMD  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee
        is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each AMD file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are less than 1500
        bytes.
 
      Browse Files (BRO Directory)
      ----------------------------
        Browse files are composite PostScript files summarizing
        quick-look processing of RSR data.  Each file has a name of
        the form  ydddhhmm.PSn  where  ydddhhmm  is identical to
        the character string in the source RSR file and  n  is the
        receiver channel represented in the data.  Each BRO file is
        accompanied by a detached PDS label with name ydddhhmm.LBL.
        Only one channel  n  is expected from each RSR.  Each
        PostScript file is sized to fit on a single 8-1/2x11 inch
        page.  Each landscape format page includes four panels
        showing a histogram of raw data (12-bit) samples (upper
        left), one-minute average power spectra derived from the
        raw samples (upper right), one-second averages of raw sample
        power versus time (lower left), and an extract of the first
        few lines of the source RSR PDS label (lower right).  BRO
        files may be helpful in quickly scanning data to determine
        which files are suitable for closer study.
 
      Earth Orientation Parameter Files (EOP Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Earth Orientation Parameter files were produced by the Time
        and Earth Motion Precision Observation (TEMPO) Group at JPL.
        They documented and predicted Earth rotation (rate and axis).
        These are ASCII files of variable length records.  Each
        record is delimited by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).
        File names have the form  ydddzeee.EOP  where  y  is
        the one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is
        the day-of-year of the first data in the file,  z  is the
        one-digit year of the last data, and  eee  is the day-of-year
        of the last data in the file.  EOP files were typically
        released on Tuesdays and Fridays.  There are both &apos;long&apos;
        and &apos;short&apos; versions.  The long file covered past motion
        since about 1962 and a prediction for about three months into
        the future; these files have typical sizes of 860 kB.  The
        short file covered the most recent 9-12 months of past motion
        and a prediction for 1-3 months into the future; these
        files are typically 30 kB.  Each EOP file is accompanied
        by a PDS minimal label with file name  ydddzeee.LBL.
 
      Ionosphere Calibration Files (ION Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Ionosphere Calibration files were produced by the Tracking
        System Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL.  They
        documented and predicted Earth ionospheric conditions.
        These are ASCII files of variable length records.  Each
        record is delimited by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).
        File names have the form  ydddeeeC.ION  where  y  is
        the one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is
        the day-of-year of the first data in the file,  eee  is the
        day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file with the
        same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses
        to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage
        files.  ION files were usually released at one week
        intervals to cover a single month;  ydddeeeA.ION  would be
        the file released during the first week,  ydddeeeB.ION  would
        be the file released during the second week, etc.  Each ION
        file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are less than 50 kB.
 
        In mid-2003 the method of producing Ionosphere Calibration
        files was improved.  Global Ionosphere Map (GIM) software
        created daily Global Ionospheric Maps from global GPS data.
        Each day, a final map was created for the UT day three days
        previously and a preliminary map was created for the UT day
        immediately before.  Also created were predict maps a couple
        times a week by averaging recent &apos;normal&apos; days. Then the
        software evaluated the maps at the spacecraft line-of-sight
        and fitted the results to a normalized polynomial versus
        time over each spacecraft pass.  This was done for all
        three modes: final, preliminary, and predict.  Then the
        software selected the best available calibration for each
        pass (in priority order final &gt; preliminary &gt; predict).
        Then the operator ran a plotting program to view all of the
        calibrations and overrode the default selections where
        desired.  The mapping technique is described by
        [MANNUCCIETAL1998].
 
      Light Time Files (LIT Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Light Time files were produced by the ODY Navigation Team
        (NAV).  They gave radio propagation time from the spacecraft
        to Earth vs time.  These are ASCII files of fixed
        length records.  Each record is delimited by an ASCII
        carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII
        10), which may need to be converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt;
        before the file is used on the local machine.  File names
        have the form  ydddeeeC.LIT  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee
        is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each LIT file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are less than 1 MB.
 
      Maneuver Implementation/Reconstruction Files (MIF Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Maneuver Implementation/Reconstruction files were produced by
        the ODY Spacecraft Team (SCT); they documented spacecraft
        maneuver events.  These are ASCII files of variable length
        records.  Each record is delimited by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt;
        (ASCII 10).  File names have the form  ydddeeeC.MIF  where  y
        is the one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is
        the day-of-year of the first data in the file,  eee  is the
        day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file with the
        same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses
        to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage
        files.  Each MIF file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label
        with file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are 2327
        bytes.
 
      Maneuver Performance Data Files (MPD Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Maneuver Performance Data files were produced by the ODY
        Spacecraft Team (SCT).  They contain estimates of spacecraft
        mass and center of mass; moments of inertia; thruster
        locations, directions, and magnitudes; and propellant flow
        rate.  These are ASCII files of variable length records.
        Each record is delimited by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt;
        (ASCII 10).  File names have the form  ydddeeeC.MPD  where
        y  is the one-digit year of the first data in the file,
        ddd  is the day-of-year of the first data in the file,  eee
        is the day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C  is
        a character denoting sequence when more than one file with
        the same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and
        progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of
        similar coverage files.  Each MPD file is accompanied by a
        PDS minimal label with file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical
        file sizes are 4 kB.
 
      Maneuver Profile Files (MPF Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Maneuver Profile Files were produced by the ODY Navigation
        Team (NAV).  They are generic descriptions of orbit
        adjustments used by ODY during aerobraking.  These are ASCII
        files of variable length records.  Each record is delimited
        by a carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed &lt;LF&gt;
        (ASCII 10) pair.  File names have the form  XnnnDDCC.MPF
        where  X  is a character,  nnn  is a 3-digit number,  DD
        indicates the adjustment direction (&apos;UP&apos; or &apos;DN&apos;), and
        CC  indicates the sequence if there is more than one file
        with the same  XnnnDD.  CC starts from &apos;AA&apos;.  Each  MPF
        is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        XnnnDDCC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are less than 700 bytes.
 
      Orbit Propagation and Time Generation Files (OPT Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Orbit Propagation and Time Generation files were produced by
        the ODY Navigation Team (NAV).  They contain estimates of
        event timing (e.g., equator crossings) that depend on
        precise knowledge of the spacecraft orbit.  These are ASCII
        files of variable length records.  Each record is delimited
        by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).  File names
        have the form  ydddeeeC.OPT  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee
        is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each OPT file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are less than 100 kB.
 
      Solar Array Kernel Files (SAK Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Solar Array Kernel files were produced by the ODY Spacecraft
        Team (SCT).  They give the attitude of the solar array
        panel as a function of time.  These are ASCII files of
        variable length records in a special NAIF &apos;transfer&apos; format.
        Each record is delimited by a carriage-return (ASCII 13)
        line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10) pair, which may need to be
        removed before the file is used on the local machine.
        After delimiter conversion (if needed) the file would
        ordinarily be passed through the NAIF utility SPACIT  or
        TOBIN  to convert it to the local binary format.  File names
        have the form  ydddeeeC.TCK  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file, eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee
        is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each TCK file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with
        file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are less than
        5 MB.
 
      Small Forces File (SFF Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Small Forces Files were created from the ODY spacecraft
        engineering telemetry stream.  These are ASCII files of
        variable length records.  Each record is delimited by a
        carriage-return (ASCII 13) line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10) pair.
        File names have the form  ydddeeeC.SFF  where  y  is the
        one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the
        day-of-year of the first data in the file,  eee  is the
        day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file with
        the same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and
        progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of
        similar coverage files.  Each SFF file is accompanied by
        a PDS minimal label with file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.
        Typical file sizes are less than 0.1 MB.  File content
        and structure is defined by SFF_SIS.TXT in the DOCUMENT
        directory.
 
        Well into the mission (July 2005) SFF files from the
        aerobraking period were obtained and added to the archive.
        As a result, files covering 2002-01-16 and earlier are
        PDS TABLE objects with full PDS labels, while the files
        collected for later dates have the properties described
        in the paragraph above.  The file content, delimiters,
        and file naming convention are the same for the
        aerobraking data; SFF_SIS.TXT remains relevant.  Only the
        format is different.
 
      Sequence of Events Files (SOE Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Sequence of Events Files were produced by the ODY Mission
        Control Team.  These are ASCII files of variable length
        records.  Each record is delimited by a carriage-return
        (ASCII 13) line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10) pair, which may need
        to be removed before the file is used on the local machine.
        File names have the form  ydddeeeC.SOE  where  y  is the
        one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the
        day-of-year of the first data in the file,  eee  is the
        day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file with
        the same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and
        progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of
        similar coverage files.  Each SOE file is accompanied by
        a PDS minimal label with file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.
        Typical file sizes are less than 1 MB.
 
      Spacecraft/Planetary Ephemeris (SPK) Files (SPK Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Spacecraft/Planetary Ephemeris Files (also known as SP
        kernels or SPK files) were produced by the ODY Navigation Team
        (NAV).  These files give spacecraft and planetary ephemerides.
        These are ASCII files of variable length records in
        a special NAIF &apos;transfer&apos; format.  Each record is delimited
        by a carriage-return (ASCII 13) line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10)
        pair, which may need to be removed before the file is used on
        the local machine.  After delimiter conversion (if needed)
        the file would ordinarily be passed through the NAIF utility
        SPACIT  or  TOBIN  to convert it to the local binary format.
        File names have the form  ydddeeeC.SPK  where  y  is the
        one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the
        day-of-year of the first data in the file,  eee  is the
        day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file
        with the same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and
        progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of
        similar coverage files.  Each SPK file is accompanied by a
        PDS minimal label with file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file
        sizes are less than 5 MB.
 
      Spacecraft Attitude (CK) Files (TCK Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Spacecraft Attitude Files (also known as C kernels or CK
        files) were produced by the ODY Spacecraft Team (SCT).
        These are ASCII files of variable length records in
        a special NAIF &apos;transfer&apos; format.  Each record is delimited
        by a carriage-return (ASCII 13) line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10)
        pair, which may need to be removed before the file is used on
        the local machine.  After delimiter conversion (if needed)
        the file would ordinarily be passed through the NAIF utility
        SPACIT  or  TOBIN  to convert it to the local binary format.
        File names have the form  ydddeeeC.TCK  where  y  is the
        one-digit year of the first data in the
        file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of the first data in the file,
        eee  is the day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C
        is a character denoting sequence when more than one file
        with the same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and
        progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of
        similar coverage files.  Each TCK file is accompanied by a
        PDS minimal label with file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file
        sizes are less than 5 MB.
 
      Troposphere Calibration Files (TRO Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Troposphere Calibration files were produced by the
        Tracking System Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL.
        They documented and predicted Earth tropospheric conditions.
        These are ASCII files of variable length records.  Each
        record is delimited by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).
        File names have the form  ydddeeeC.TRO  where  y  is
        the one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is
        the day-of-year of the first data in the file,  eee  is the
        day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file with the
        same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses
        to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage
        files.  TRO files were typically released at the beginning of
        a month and covered the previous month.  Each TRO file is
        accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are 100 kB.
 
        Starting in early 2001, TSAC began basing TRO files on
        measurements using the Global Positioning Satellite (GPS)
        system.  These files can be distinguished by an
        ORIGINAL_PRODUCT_ID beginning with &apos;ATC&apos; rather than the
        earlier &apos;TROPCAL&apos;.  Detailed file structure was slightly
        different, but the same Software Interface Specification
        (SIS) was used.
 
      DSN Weather Files (WEA Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        DSN Weather files were produced by the Tracking System
        Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL.  Files give weather
        calibration information for DSN complexes. These are ASCII
        files of variable length records.  Each record is delimited
        by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).  File names have
        the form  ydddeeeD.WEA  where  y  is the one-digit year of
        the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of the
        first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the last
        data in the file, and  D  is a single digit denoting the
        DSN complex at which the data were acquired (&apos;1&apos; for
        Goldstone, &apos;4&apos; for Canberra, or &apos;6&apos; for Madrid).  WEA files
        were typically released weekly and contain all weather data
        for the complex since 1 January.  Each WEA file is
        accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        ydddeeeC.LBL.  The files grow at the rate of approximately
        90 kB per month.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      SPK, TCK, and SAK files can be converted to a wide range
      of coordinate frames by the NAIF reader routines.
 
      Other data types are not dependent on definition of a
      coordinate system.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      Software for parsing, reducing, and analyzing data such as
      these has been developed at Stanford University and elsewhere.
      Because such software must usually operate at the bit-level and
      is written for a narrow range of platforms, it is not suitable
      for general distribution.  No software is included with this
      archival data set.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The archival data set is written on CD-WO media using the
      Yamaha/GEAR authoring system.   The CD-WO volumes conform to
      ISO 9660 standards.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this archival data set have been collected to support
      radio science investigations, including derivation of the
      gravity field of Mars.  These are similar to data collected
      using other spacecraft and are believed to be generally of
      good quality.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      Because there was no formal radio science component to the
      2001 Mars Odyssey mission, the review of these data will be
      conducted by the early users of the data set who have
      acquired files from the Planetary Data System.  Their
      comments, criticisms, and suggestions will be evaluated
      to determine whether corrections are needed in future volumes
      or whether early volumes should be modified and reissued.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Data are essentially continuous beginning in early 2002.  The
      coverage on each archival volume was keyed to the dates of the
      included ODF&apos;s.  During low-volume periods approximately a
      month of data was included on each volume (e.g., ODRS_0008
      contains data primarily from June 2002).
 
      Solar superior conjunction occurred on 2002-08-12 and
      again on about 2004-09-15.  RSR data were collected on a
      &apos;best efforts&apos; basis during August 2002 for future studies of
      the solar corona.  The spacecraft radio system was in two-way
      mode and the signal was sampled at 1000 samples/s for the 90
      minutes of each orbit when the spacecraft was not occulted.
      There was usually one 70-m DSN pass per day.
 
      Mars opposition occurred during late summer 2003 and fall 2005.
 
      Well into the mission (July 2005) radio tracking and small
      forces data (types ODF, TDF, and SFF) were obtained for the
      aerobraking phase of the mission (late 2001 and early 2002).
      These data were folded into the regular archiving stream and
      appear on volumes in the range ODRS_0094 to ODRS_0100.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The limitations in this data set follow from the quality of
      the execution, which is described above under Data Coverage
      and Quality.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

