<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-loi-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESS MDIS MAP PROJ LOW-INCIDENCE ANGLE BASEMAP RDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mdis-nac.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-loi-v1.0__browserp_mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-loi-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-loi-v1.0__browser_geo_mercury_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-loi-v1.0__browser_mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-loi-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-loi-v1.0__dvo_imaging_mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-loi-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Becker, K.J., M.S. Robinson, T.L. Becker, L.A. Weller, K.L. Edmonson, G.A.
                   Neumann, M.E. Perry, S.C. Solomon, First digital elevation model of Mercury,
                   47th Lunar and Planetary Science Conference, abstract #2949, 2016.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BECKERETAL2016</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Domingue, D.L., B.W. Denevi, S.L. Murchie, and C.D. Hash, Application of
                   multiple photometric models to disk-resolved measurements of Mercury&apos;s surface:
                   insights into Mercury&apos;s regolith characteristics, Icarus, 268, 172-203, 2016
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DOMINGUEETAL2016</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hawkins, S.E., III, J. Boldt, E.H. Darlington, R. Espiritu, R.E. Gold, B.
                   Gotwols, M. Grey, C. Hash, J. Hayes, S. Jaskulek, C. Kardian, M. Keller, E.
                   Malaret, S.L. Murchie, P. Murphy, K. Peacock, L. Prockter, A. Reiter, M.S.
                   Robinson, E. Schaefer, R. Shelton, R. Sterner, H. Taylor, T. Watters, and B.
                   Williams, The Mercury Dual Imaging System on the MESSENGER spacecraft, Space
                   Science Reviews, 131, 247-338, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAWKINSETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hawkins, S.E., III, S.L. Murchie, K.J. Becker, C.M. Selby, F.S. Turner, M.W.
                   Noble, N.L. Chabot, T.H. Choo, E.H. Darlington, B.W. Denevi, D.L. Domingue,
                   C.M. Ernst, G.M. Holsclaw, N.R. Laslo, W.E. McClintock, L.M. Prockter, M.S.
                   Robinson, S.C. Solomon, and R.E. Sterner, II, In-flight performance of
                   MESSENGER&apos;s Mercury Dual Imaging System, Proceedings of the SPIE, Volume 7441,
                   pp. 74410Z-74410Z-12, 2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAWKINSETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-H-MDIS-5-RDR-LOI-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESS MDIS MAP PROJ LOW-INCIDENCE ANGLE BASEMAP RDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-05-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-08-19T18:01:23Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-04-30T11:07:43Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>CHRISTOPHER HASH</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            C. Hash, MESS MDIS MAP PROJ LOW-INCIDENCE ANGLE BASEMAP RDR V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 2016
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Low solar incidence angle basemap reduced data records for the
            MDIS camera system on MESSENGER.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== The Mercury Dual Imaging System (MDIS) consists
            of two cameras, a Wide Angle Camera (WAC) and a Narrow Angle
            Camera (NAC), mounted on a common pivot platform. This dataset
            includes Map Projected Low- Incidence Angle Basemap RDRs (LOIs)
            which comprise a global map of I/F measured by the NAC or WAC
            filter 7 (both centered near 750 nm) during the Extended Mission
            at low solar incidence angles to accentuate albedo and albedo
            variations, photometrically normalized to a solar incidence angle
            (i) = 30 degrees, emission angle (e) = 0 degrees, and phase angle
            (g) = 30 degrees, at a spatial sampling of 256 pixels per degree.
            The LOI data set is a companion to the Basemap Data Record (BDR)
            data set, High Incidence Angle Illuminated from the East (HIE)
            data set, and High Incidence Angle Illuminated from the West
            (HIW) data set, all of which are also composed of WAC filter 7
            and NAC images, except acquired at higher solar incidence angles
            centered at 68 to 78 degrees to highlight topography. The map is
            divided into 54 &apos;tiles&apos;, each representing the NW, NE,
            SW, or SE quadrant of one of the 13 non-polar or one of the 2
            polar quadrangles or &apos;Mercury charts&apos; already defined
            by the USGS. Each tile also contains 5 backplanes: observation
            ID; BDR metric, a metric used to determine the stacking order of
            component images, modified for the higher incidence angle
            centered near 78 degrees; solar incidence angle; emission angle;
            and phase angle.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      A major imaging campaign for MDIS in MESSENGER&apos;s primary mission
      was acquisition of a global data set at low emission angles for
      cartographic purposes, and moderate to high incidence angles that
      highlight topography. Those images were mosaicked into Basemap
      Reduced Data Records (BDRs). The LOI data set also consists of a
      global map of I/F measured by the NAC or WAC filter 7 (both
      centered near 750 nm), but it is complementary because of
      illumination at lower solar incidence angles that highlights
      albedo variations instead of topography. It is also complementary
      to the global 8-color map contained in the Multispectral Reduced
      Data Records (MDR) data set. The MDR data were acquired at nearly
      the same photometric geometry as this LOI data set, but the
      LOI data are at four times higher spatial resolution.
 
      Map tiles are named based on the quadrant of the Mercury chart they
      span:
 
      MDIS_ppp_rrrPPD_Hxxddv.IMG
 
      where:
 
        ppp = product type = LOI
        rrr = resolution in pixels/degree (PPD)
        Hxx = Mercury chart designation
        dd = quadrant within Mercury chart (NW, NE, SW, or SE), or a
           polar chart (NP, SP)e limits
        v = version number
 
 
      The following is an example file name with a description of the
      individual components:
 
      MDIS_LOI_256PPD_H03NE0.IMG
 
      For this image:
        Product type = LOI (LOI)
        Resolution = 256 pixels/degree (256PPD)
        Mercury chart = Shakespeare (H03)
        Quadrant = Northeast (NE)
        Version = 0
 
      The LOI directory, present in the LOI archive volume, contains
      MDIS Map Projected Low Incidence Angle Basemap Reduced Data
      Records (LOIs). The LOIs are organized into subdirectories based
      on the Mercury Chart containing LOIs.  Latitude and longitude
      limits of Mercury Charts, as named at the end of mission delivery,
      are:
 
      Quadrangle         Subdirectory   Lat. (degrees)  Long. (deg. east)
      H-1 Borealis       H01            65 to 90        0 to 360
      H-2 Victoria       H02            22.5 to 65      270 to 360
      H-3 Shakespeare    H03            22.5 to 65      180 to 270
      H-4 Raditladi      H04            22.5 to 65      90 to 180
      H-5 Hokusai        H05            22.5 to 65      0 to 90
      H-6 Kuiper         H06            -22.5 to 22.5   288 to 360
      H-7 Beethoven      H07            -22.5 to 22.5   216 to 288
      H-8 Tolstoj        H08            -22.5 to 22.5   144 to 216
      H-9 Eminescu       H09            -22.5 to 22.5   72 to 144
      H-10 Derain        H10            -22.5 to 22.5   0 to 72
      H-11 Discovery     H11            -65 to -22.5    270 to 360
      H-12 Michelangelo  H12            -65 to -22.5    180 to 270
      H-13 Neruda        H13            -65 to -22.5    90 to 180
      H-14 Debussey      H14            -65 to -22.5    0 to 90
      H-15 Bach          H15            -90 to -65      0 to 360
 
      An LOI:
      - Consists of map-projected photometrically normalized I/F CDRs
        mosaicked into a basemap map tile;
      - Contains image data in I/F corrected photometrically to i=30
        degrees, e=0 at a resolution of 256 pixels per degree (~166
        m/pixel at the equator);
      - Represents one latitude-longitude bin in a global map;
      - Is composed of images acquired with by the NAC or by the WAC in
        filter 7, both centered near 750 nm;
      - Contains images acquired as part of the low-incidence angle
        basemap campaign; and
      - Contains 5 backplanes:
        (a) observation id, (b) MDR metric, modified for the difference
        in pixel scale, (c) solar incidence angle, (d) emission angle,
        and (e) phase angle.
 
 
    Versions
    ========
 
      Version numbers of LOIs increment on reprocessing or addition of
      new data.  Polar tiles are in polar stereographic projections, other
      tiles in equirectangular projection.
 
      Version 1 is released at PDS release 15 at end of mission,
      is compiled using NAC or WAC 750-nm images from any campaign that
      best fit the intended illumination geometry, i.e., low emission angle
      and minimized incidence angle. It is controlled and projected
      onto a global digital elevation model. It uses a Kasseleinin-Shkuratov
      photometric model, whose parameters are the same for any given
      wavelength band across all MESSENGER end-of-mission map data
      products. I/F is taken from version 5 CDRs, and information for
      backplanes is taken from version 1 DDRs, both generated in end of
      mission deivery 15.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      MDIS observing variable pertaining to the LOIs are as follows.
 
      Pixel Binning: Some LOI images are unbinned and 1024x1024 pixels.
      Some images are 2x2 pixel binned in the focal plane hardware
      (also known as &apos;on-chip&apos; binning), resulting in 512 x 512
      images. The WAC was used to acquire LOI images from lower
      altitudes, and the NAC was used at higher altitudes. Within the
      altitude range for either camera, on-chip binning was used
      within the lower portion of the range, to control data volume
      and to manage data flow on the spacecraft. No further binning
      by the spacecraft main processor (MP) was used.
 
      12-8 bit compression: Images are read off the detector in 12-bit
      format. 12 bit images may converted to 8 bit images using one of
      eight lookup tables (LUTs). All images collected as part of
      the LOI basemap have been converted to 8 bits.
 
      FAST/DPCM compression: All images are compressed losslessly using
      FAST/DCPM compression as they are read out of the DPU, to conserve
      recorder space. Once the data are written to the recorder, they can
      be uncompressed and recompressed more aggressively in the MP.
 
      Wavelet compression: Images may be integer wavelet transform-
      compressed in the MP, typically at 3:1 for color data and 4:1 for
      monochrome data, but any value from 1 to 32 can be used. The initial
      configuration in Mercury orbit was to perform 12 to 8 bit conversion
      using LUT0 for the WAC and LUT2 for the NAC, with a wavelet
      compression ratio of 8:1 for monochrome imaging and 4:1 for color
      imaging. Initial images exhibited unexpectedly visible compression
      artifacts. Beginning 19 April 2011, LUT0 and LUT2 were replaced
      with LUT1 which better preserves image dynamic range, and
      compression ratios were decreased to 4:1 or less for monochrome
      data and 3:1 or less for color data where possible. Lossless
      compression was used when downlink allowed.
 
      Exposure Control: The exposure time of MDIS images can be set
      manually by command, or automatically by the software. In manual
      mode, exposure times from 1-989, 1001-1989, ..., to 9001-9989 ms
      are available. In autoexposure mode the exposure time of the next
      image is computed by the DPU software, and cannot exceed 989 ms
      in duration. If the time of the next image occurs before the
      calculation can be completed, and pixel binning or filter
      position change, then the algorithm compensates for predicted
      changes in scene brightness and filter transmission using an
      onboard data structure. All images in LOIs were acquired using
      automatic exposure.
 
      Pointing: The MDIS imagers are mounted on a pivot platform, which
      is itself mounted to the MESSENGER spacecraft deck. The pivot
      platform is controlled by a stepper motor, which is controlled by
      the Data Processing Unit (DPU). The pivot platform can move in
      either direction. The total range of motion is 240 degrees, limited
      by mechanical &apos;hard&apos; stops, and is further constrained by &apos;soft&apos;
      stops applied by the software. The nominal pointing position for
      MDIS is defined as 0 degrees, aligned with the spacecraft +Z axis
      and the boresight for several other instruments. The range of the
      soft stops is set to 40 degrees in the spacecraft -Y direction
      (toward the MESSENGER sunshade) and +50 degrees in the +Y direction
      (away from the sunshade). The pivot position can be commanded in
      intervals of 0.01 degrees within this range. During acquisition of
      the LOI basemap, the pivot was used to point the WAC or NAC
      to low emission angles on the surface, at times when the solar
      incidence angle was at as low an incidence angle as possible.
 
      Filter selection: The WAC imager contains a 12 position filter
      wheel to provide spectral imaging over the spectral range of the
      CCD detector. WAC filter 7 (750 BP 5) was chosen to complement the
      NAC because its bandpass within that of the NAC lessens any
      discontinuities that might result from regional variations in
      spectral slope.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      A sequence of processing creates an LOI from CDRs and DDRs. A Derived
      Data Record (DDR) consists of multiband images whose line and sample
      dimensions and coordinates correspond one-for-one with those of a
      CDR. It has 5 bands of data used to help create an LOI, including for
      every image pixel: (a) latitude, (b) longitude, (c) incidence angle,
      (d) emission angle, and (e) phase angle. The DDRs are an intermediate
      product used to create LOIs and other map products, are defined as a
      distinct data product in the MDIS CDR/RDR Software Interface
      Specification, and are delivered to the PDS beginning with
      delivery 11.
 
      The sequence of processing is as follows:
 
    (a) Experiment Data Records (EDRs) are assembled from raw data.
    (b) Radiance images are created from the EDRs and calibration files.
    (c) Radiance is converted to I/F CDRs by dividing by (pi * solar flux
        at 1 AU / heliocentricdistance_in_AU^2).
    (d) I/F is photometrically corrected to i = 30 degrees, e = 0 degrees.
    (e) Gimbal positions are extracted from the spacecraft housekeeping
        and formatted as a gimbal C kernel.
    (f) Using the gimbal C kernel and other SPICE kernels, DDRs are
        created. The surface intercept on a sphere of Mercury&apos;s radius
        is calculated for each spatial pixel. The angles of this pixel
        relative to the equatorial plane and reference longitude constitute
        the latitude and longitude of the pixel. For that latitude and
        longitude, solar incidence, emission, and phase angles are
        determined.
    (g) I/F corrected to i = 30 degrees, e = 0 degrees is map projected
        into LOIs using the latitude and longitude information
        in the DDRs. The same procedure is used on DDRs to assemble the
        backplanes with derived information. They are appended to the
        image band in the following order:
          OBSERVATION_ID
          MDR metric, modified for the difference in pixel scale
          Solar Incidence Angle
          Emission Angle
          Phase Angle
        where OBSERVATION_ID is taken from the CDR label, the
        ordinal number of the image among all MDIS images taken
        post-launch, and the photometric angles are taken from the DDR.
 
      For version 1 LOIs, any image taken as part of the low
      incidence angle campaign is a candidate to include, as are images
      from any campaign with suitable illumination, within the following
      criteria:
 
      - Controlled images are primarily used, but non-controlled images are
        used as needed to minimize gaps in coverage
      - Incidence angle at the center of the images is &lt; 90 degrees
      - In polar tiles (H01, H15) phase angle at the center of the images
        is &lt; 95 degrees
      - In non-polar tiles images scale is &gt; 100 m/pixel
      - In polar tiles (H01, H15) images scale is &gt; 50 m/pixel
 
      A stacking order (&apos;which image is on top&apos;) is shared by LOIs and
      early verions of 3-Color Map Projected Multispectral RDRs (MD3s)
      and 8-Color Map Projected Multispectral RDRs (MDRs). The objective
      is to have &apos;on top&apos; images with high spatial resolution, low
      emission angle, and low solar incidence angle. Image sorting and
      stacking is as follows. An MDR metric represents both spatial
      resolution and image geometry is evaluated at the camera boresight;
      lowest values represent the &apos;best&apos; image. The &apos;worst&apos; complete, map-
      projected image with the highest value for the metric is laid into
      the LOI first; then the complete image with the second-highest value
      is laid in second, overwriting the first image where the coverage
      coincides, and so on until the complete &apos;best&apos; image with the lowest
      value for the metric is on top. At all latitudes and solar incidence
      angles, the MDR metric modified for LOIs is:
 
      PIXEL_SCALE / (cos i * cos e)
 
      where i is solar incidence angle, e is emission angle, and the value
      of PIXEL_SCALE is limited not to be below approximately 166 meters,
      so that unfavorably illuminated images with high spatial resolutions
      not captured at the resolution of an LOI do not overwrite more
      favorably illuminated images.
 
      The photometric correction applied to low-incidence images is a
      Kasseleinen-Shkuratov function described by [DOMINGUEETAL2016].
      The form of the function is given as:
 
      I/F = AN*exp[-(g*mu)]{c_sub_l[2cos i/(cos i + cos e)]+[1-c_sub_l]cos i}
 
      where AN is normal albedo at a given wavelength, and mu and c_sub_l
      are wavelength-dependent variables.
 
      The parameters for the photometric correction were
      derived by modeling data acquired from multiple regions between
      24 degrees and 46 degrees south latitude and 330 degrees and 353
      degrees east longitude. These regions sample incidence angle (i),
      emission angle(e), and phase angle (g) coverage commensurate
      with global mapping campaigns. In addition whole-disk
      Mercury images taken at a large number of geometries during
      the Mercury flybys expand the phase angle range.
      The photometric measurements were modeled using a least squares
      grid search routine over the available parameter space. The model
      parameter values were individually plotted as a function of wavelength
      over the MDIS filter central wavelength values. A polynomial trend was
      fit to each parameter as a function of wavelength. The polynomial
      trend value at each filter central wavelength was then used as the
      model parameter values for determining the photometric correction.
      The parameter values applicable to LOIs are given in the
      table below. Photometric behavior of Mercury in NAC images is assumed
      to be equivalent to that in the WAC G filter.
 
      WAC
      filter, wavelength,      AN,       mu,    c_sub_l
      G,             749,  0.1111,   0.5628,     0.6424
 
 
    Data
    ====
      There is one data type associated with this volume, LOIs consisting
      of mosaicked, photometrically corrected WAC filter 7 (G filter)
      CDRs and NAC CDRs, appended with 5 backplanes describing the
      component CDRs and their photometric geometries as recorded in DDRs.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
 
      There is one type of ancillary data provided with this
      dataset:
 
      1. There may be a BROWSE directory containing browse images in
      PNG and/or GeoTIFF format. See BROWINFO.TXT in that directory
      for more details.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
 
      The cartographic coordinate system used for the MDIS data products
      conforms to the J2000 celestial reference frame for star imaging,
      and the IAU planetocentric system with East longitudes being
      positive for planetary surfaces. The value for Mercury radius is
      2439.4 km.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
 
      The MDIS archive is organized and stored in the directory
      structure described in the Mercury Dual Imaging System (MDIS)
      Calibrated Data Record (CDR) and Reduced Data Record (RDR)
      Software Interface Specification (SIS). The contents of the
      archive, along with fiduciary checksums, are compressed into
      a single &apos;zip archive&apos; file for transmittal to the PDS Imaging
      node.  The zip archive preserves the directory structure
      internally so that when it is decompressed the original
      directory structure is recreated at the PDS Imaging node.
      The zip archive is transmitted to the PDS Imaging node via
      FTP to the URL specified by the node for receiving it.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      Known issues of concern are described below.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was examined by a peer review panel
      prior to its acceptance by the Planetary Data System (PDS). The
      peer review was conducted in accordance with PDS procedures.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
 
      Only a subset of raw EDR data are calibrated to CDRs and then
      incorporated into LOI products. Briefly, the following criteria
      are met:
 
      (a) The data represent a scene and not the instrument test
      pattern, as indicated by data quality index (DQI) byte 0.
 
      (b) The exposure time is greater than zero (zero exposures
      occur in some images due to software features), as indicated
      by DQI byte 1.
 
      (c) Less than 20 percent of the image is saturated (empirically
      this is a threshold dividing wholly corrupted images from
      everything else).
 
      (d) The target of the image is MERCURY.
 
      (e) The image was taken as part of the low incidence angle
      basemap campaign during MESSENGER&apos;s extended mission, or
      as part of another campaign with photometric geometry closer
      to that desired.
 
      LOIs are based on version 4 CDRs which correct a number of earlier
      calibration artifacts. Some issues still remain.
      The OBSERBATION_ID for a part of a LOI is a pointer back to the
      WAC filter 7 or NAC image used for that part of the LOI. Those
      images may be subject to some or all of the following issues.
 
      (1) COMPRESSION ARTIFACTS. Images may be integer wavelet transform-
      compressed in the MP, typically at 3:1 for color data and 4:1 for
      monochrome data, but any value from 1 to 32 can be used. The initial
      configuration in Mercury orbit was to perform 12 to 8 bit conversion
      using LUT0 for the WAC and LUT2 for the NAC, with a wavelet
      compression ratio of 8:1 for monochrome imaging and 4:1 for color
      imaging. Initial images exhibited unexpectedly visible compression
      artifacts. Beginning 19 April 2011, LUT0 and LUT2 were replaced
      with LUT1 which better preserves image dynamic range, and
      compression ratios were decreased to 4:1 or less for monochrome
      data and 3:1 or less for color data where possible. Lossless
      compression was used when downlink allowed. Images that are
      part of LOI products typically were compressed 4:1 or losslessly.
 
      (2) RADIOMETRIC ACCURACY. The radiometric calibration of the
      WAC was updated several times over the mission to iteratively
      reduce residuals from 3 sources of error: (a) time-variable
      responsivity of the detector, (b) residuals in the flat-field
      correction, and (c) residuals in the correction to
      responsivity for detector temperature. For multispectral
      products, the residuals from time-variable responsivity
      initially led to distinct seams; correction of this artifact
      is treated in more detail below.
 
      In version 5 CDRs an improved temperature correction was
      derived empirically, by fitting as a function of CCD
      temperature, the median values of images acquired throughout
      Mercury orbit at a wide range of temperatures but a narrow range
      of photometric geometries. The flat field was updated
      empirically using the median of thousands of photometrically
      corrected images of relatively bland field-filling images
      of Mercury.
 
      (3) SCATTERED LIGHT. In the NAC, scattered light from out-of-field
      sources is an issue. The geometry contributing most of the scatter
      is 1-2 fields-of-view sunward of the NAC boresight. For a very
      large, evenly illuminated source that overfills the field-of-view
      by a factor of several, ray-trace studies supported by testing
      during Venus flyby 2 suggest that 2-7% of the radiance measured in
      the field-of-view will have come from out-of-field sources. The
      spatial pattern of the scatter is variable, due to diffuse
      reflections off the internal instrument housing.
 
      The WAC is subject to scattered light
      originating from within the field-of-view or just outside it. One
      source is multiple reflections off of 13 optical surfaces (2
      sides of each of 4 lenses, the spectral filter, and the CCD cover
      glass, as well as the CCD surface itself). The scatter becomes
      worse at longer wavelengths. Just off the limb of a large
      extended source near 1 field-of-view in size, like Venus or
      Mercury, measured radiance increases with wavelength from 2% to 7%
      of the value measured on the extended source. The value decreases
      with distance off the target more quickly at longer than at
      shorter wavelengths, but remains at 1% hundreds of pixels from
      the source. Conversely, light must be scattering from bright
      parts of an image to dark parts of an image. Averaged over
      sources tens of pixels in area, and away from abrupt brightness
      contrasts, scattered light affects shapes of spectra measured
      from WAC data at least at the 1-2% level, worse near brightness
      boundaries or for small, bright crater ejecta. The expected effect
      is enhanced brightness at &gt;650 nm in dark areas, and decreased
      brightness at &gt;650 nm in small bright areas.
 
      In the end-of-mission delivery 15, a forward model of the
      expected WAC scatter from a given scene was derived using
      optical design software modeling CCD structure and hardware,
      with magnitudes of scatter calibrated against flight measurements.
      The ray trace analysis reveals an in-scene component from light
      diffracted by the CCD and reflected by the CCD cover glass, and
      an out-of-scene component from light reflected off metallic
      surfaces alongside the CCD and back off the cover glass.
      These analyses suggest that scattered light is present in
      monochrome map products but in general is not an issue in
      morphologic interpretations. However caution is urged in using
      quantitative photometric analysis in high-contrast or shadowed
      terrain in these products.
 
      (4) TIME-VARIABLE WAC RESPONSIVITY. During Mercury orbit it was
      recognized that filter-dependent changes in WAC responsivity on
      the order of +/- 15% occurred over timescales as short as several
      days. Because those variations were not consistent from filter to
      filter, they led to spurious spectral features, which were
      particularly conspicuous near 750 nm. The cause(s) of these
      variations in responsivity are not known, but they could include
      transient radiation effects on the detector or electronics, aging
      of filters, periodic deposition and burn-off of contaminants on
      filters, or incorrect recording of exposure time.
 
      For version 5 WAC CDRs in delivery 15 at end of mission, an
      empirical correction covers the full duration of the orbital
      phase. Overlaps between color image sets in color mapping campaigns
      were used to derive a multiplicative correction factor for each
      filter and for each Earth day (2-3 orbits). Version 1 LOIs use
      CDRs with this updated correction. An analysis of overlap among
      individual images shows that residual differences (which include
      errors from calibration, scattered light, and possible incomplete
      correction of photometric variation) average &lt;2% for the majority
      of the planet.
 
      (5) MAP PROJECTION ERRORS. LOIs are constructed from images
      controlled using c-smithed kernels and a global digital
      elevation model (DEM), both derived using a least-squares
      bundle adjustment of common features, measured as tie point
      coordinates in overlapping NAC and WAC-G filter images of Mercury
      at favorable solar incidence and emission angles.
      Empirically, misregistration errors between images
      are generally at the pixel scale of the map (0.2 km) in
      most locations. Derivation of smithed kernels and the DEM for
      end of mission data products is described by [BECKERETAL2016].
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      None
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

