<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.uly-j-sce-1-tdf-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ULY JUP SCE RAW ARCHIVAL TRACKING DATA FILES V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.ulysses::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.uly::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:sce.uly::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.uly-j-sce-1-tdf-v1.0__browserp_uly-j-sce-1-tdf-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Bird, M.K., S.W. Asmar, P. Edenhofer, O. Funke, M. Paetzold, and H. Volland,
                   The structure of Jupiter&apos;s Io plasma torus inferred from Ulysses radio
                   occultation observations, Planet. Space Sci. 41, 999-1010, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BIRDETAL1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   TRK-2-25: DSN Tracking System Interfaces Archival Tracking Data File
                   Interface, DSN System Requirments Detailed Interface Design, JPL Document
                   820-13; Rev. A, Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, January 1, 1986.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TRK-2-25</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>ULY-J-SCE-1-TDF-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ULY JUP SCE RAW ARCHIVAL TRACKING DATA FILES V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2001-08-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1992-02-04T20:28:18.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1992-02-09T15:44:00.000Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>MICHAEL K. BIRD</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Bird, M.K., ULY JUP SCE RAW ARCHIVAL TRACKING DATA FILES V1.0,
            ULY-J-SCE-1-TDF-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2001
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Ulysses SCE raw ATDFs of the Io Plasma Torus obtained during the
            Ulysses Jupiter flyby: 1992-02-04 20:28 to 1992-02-09 15:44.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains raw radio tracking data from the Ulysses
            (ULY) Solar Corona Experiment (SCE) obtained during the ULY
            Jupiter flyby. The data target the Io Plasma Torus (IPT) and
            cover the period 1992-02-04 20:28 to 1992-02-09 15:44.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
      This data set contains raw radio tracking data from the Ulysses
      (ULY) Solar Corona Experiment (SCE) obtained during the ULY
      Jupiter flyby. The data target the Io Plasma Torus (IPT) and
      cover the period 1992-02-04 20:28 to 1992-02-09 15:44.
 
      The data set includes 10 NASA Deep Space Network (DSN) Archival
      Tracking Data Files (ATDF or TDF), and documentation. The data
      are obtained from the Radio Science Support group at JPL. There
      are basically two types of data: ranging and Doppler (Frequency),
      recorded as a function of UT Ground Received Time. These ranging
      and Doppler data are obtained from the standard DSN tracking
      receivers. Doppler data are often used to infer spacecraft radial
      motion relative to the tracking antenna.
 
      The radio downlinks from Ulysses were monitored during the
      passage of the spacecraft through the IPT shortly after closest
      approach to Jupiter. The electron content of the Io torus was
      derived from the dispersive phase shift of the S-band (2.3 GHz)
      signal with respect to the X-band (8.4 GHz) signal. Corrections
      were applied for non-Jovian contributions to the change in
      electron content arising from the interplanetary medium and the
      terrestrial ionosphere. Ulysses&apos; North-to-South encounter
      trajectory was well suited for investigating the global structure
      of the Jovian plasma environment near Io&apos;s orbit, especially its
      latitudinal extent and azimuthal variations. (IPT investigation
      description adapted from [BIRDETAL1993]. For more information
      please refer to the complete paper.)
 
 
      Parameters
      ==========
      Each ATDF data record contains 117 parameters, stored in records
      of 288 bytes. A physical record (8064 bytes) consists of 28
      logical records. Among these parameters are signal levels (&apos;AGC&apos; =
      automatic gain control in dBm), antenna pointing angles, frequency
      (often referred to simply as &apos;Doppler&apos;), range, and residuals.
 
      Data values are reported at rates no higher than 10 per second.
      For the Ulysses Jupiter encounter the received frequencies at
      S-Band and X-band were recorded at a sample time of one per
      second.
 
      The ATDF is described in section TRK-2-25 of the JPL Document
      820-13 [TRK-2-25]. An ASCII copy of this document (TRK_2_25.TXT)
      is included in the DOCUMENT/SCE directory of this volume.
 
 
      Processing
      ==========
      ATDFs are files of radiometric data produced by the Network
      Operations Control Center (NOCC) Navigation Subsystem (NAV). They
      are derived from Intermediate Data Records by NAV and contain all
      radiometric measurements received from the DSN station.
 
 
      Data
      ====
      ATDFs contain precise radio range and Doppler measurements made
      between DSN ground stations and a spacecraft. During the Ulysses
      Jupiter encounter, coded waveforms were transmitted from the
      Earth, relayed by the on-board Ulysses telecommunications system,
      and received back on Earth. Cross correlation between the
      transmitted and received waveforms yielded a measurement of the
      round trip distance, which could then be related to the
      Earth-Venus distance during the flyby. Doppler shift from the same
      measurements could be interpreted as relative velocity along the
      propagation path.
 
      An ATDF has a file name of the form &apos;ydddeeeX.TDF&apos; where &apos;y&apos; is
      the least significant digit of the year and &apos;ddd&apos; is the
      day-of-year for the first ATDF record. The &apos;eee&apos; gives day-of-year
      for the last data record in the ATDF. &apos;X&apos; indicates file sequence
      when there are multiple files per start/stop day-of-year (&apos;A&apos; for
      the first file, &apos;B&apos; for the second, etc.).
 
      Each ATDF is accompanied by a full PDS detached label with name
      ydddeeeX.LBL which completely describes the contents of the ATDF.
      The format and contents are also described in TRK_2_25.TXT in the
      DOCUMENT/SCE directory this volume. Both the ATDF and its label
      are stored in the TDF directory of an archival volume.
 
 
      Ancillary Data
      ==============
 
        Observing Geometry
        ------------------
        A NAIF (PDS Navigation and Ancillary Information) &apos;transfer&apos;
        format SPK file is provided for the period 1992-01-05 to
        1995-10-31. This file contains the positions of Ulysses, Jupiter
        Earth, the Sun, and Jupiter&apos;s four Galilean satellites (Io,
        Europa, Ganymede, and Callisto) in data modules that can be read
        with software from the NAIF Toolkit. This &apos;transfer&apos; format SPK
        file (ULY92106.XSP) is located in the GEOMETRY directory. It is
        accompanied by a detached PDS label (ULY92106.LBL) which
        describes some of the SPK file&apos;s characteristics.
 
        Before using &apos;transfer&apos; NAIF files, the user should convert the
        ASCII carriage-return line-feed delimiters on each record to the
        default delimiter for text files on the local system, then use
        the NAIF utility SPACIT to convert the archival file to local
        binary.
 
        An overview of the SPICE data system can be found in SPICE.TXT
        located in the DOCUMENT directory of this volume.
 
        For additional information on acquiring, installing, and using
        SPICE data or software please contact the PDS NAIF node:
 
          Address:  Jet Propulsion Laboratory
                    Mail Stop 301-125L
                    Pasadena, California 91109-8099
 
          Phone:    (818) 354-3869
 
          E-mail:   Charles.Acton@jpl.nasa.gov
                      or
                    pds_operator@naif.jpl.nasa.gov
 
        Documentation
        -------------
        Included in the DOCUMENT directory is an ASCII version
        (TRK_2_25.TXT) a document [TRK-2-25] describing the format of
        the ATDF data files contained on this volume.
 
 
      Coordinate System
      =================
      Most data types are not dependent on definition of a coordinate
      system; for those that are, the user should consult the SIS for
      information.
 
 
      Software
      ========
      Software for parsing, reducing, and analyzing these data has been
      developed at the University of Bonn (Germany), the Jet Propulsion
      Laboratory, and other institutions. Because parsing must be done
      at the bit level, adaptation of the software to other platforms is
      not always easy. No software has been prepared for general
      distribution, and none is included with this archive. Users should
      refer to the PDS labels and Software Interface Specifications
      (/DOCUMENT/TRK_2_25.TXT) for detailed information on file formats
      before writing their own software.
 
 
      Media/Format
      ============
      This archival data set is written on DVD-R media on a Pioneer
      DVR-A03 recorder (a DVD-R for General, 650 nm wavelength). The
      DVD-R volume conforms to ISO 9660 standards.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      Overview
      ========
      There are no known limitations to use of these data, subject to
      signal-to-noise considerations which would be typical for systems
      of this type.
 
 
      Review
      ======
      Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data set,
      the archive was distributed to both PDS and non-PDS personnel,
      including the PDS Radio Science advisor, for preliminary review.
 
 
      Data Coverage and Quality
      =========================
      The data cover the Jupiter encounter period from 1992-02-04 to
      1992-02-09. Data coverage is as follows:
 
      File          bytes     start time        stop time
      ------------  --------  ----------------  ----------------
      2035036A.TDF  31522176  1992-02-04 20:28  1992-02-05 17:00
      2036037A.TDF  30119040  1992-02-05 15:45  1992-02-06 05:05
      2037037A.TDF  30119040  1992-02-06 03:35  1992-02-06 14:08
      2037038A.TDF  33755904  1992-02-06 12:53  1992-02-07 03:44
      2038038A.TDF  32578560  1992-02-07 02:30  1992-02-07 16:15
      2038039A.TDF  30989952  1992-02-07 15:00  1992-02-08 04:30
      2039039A.TDF  26038656  1992-02-08 03:15  1992-02-08 12:00
      2039040A.TDF  33763968  1992-02-08 11:45  1992-02-09 00:00
      2039040B.TDF  33626880  1992-02-08 22:45  1992-02-09 10:15
      2040040A.TDF  32812416  1992-02-09 09:00  1992-02-09 15:44
 
      In addition to the normal signal-to-noise constraints, the
      following known data quality issues apply to this data set:
 
        S-band coverage commences at 1992-02-05 19:44 (DOY 36) and
        terminates 1992-02-09 19:16 (DOY 40).
 
      Limitations
      ===========
      None.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

