<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-e-v-h-spice-6-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER SPICE KERNELS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-spice-6-v1.0__browserp_mess-e-v-h-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-spice-6-v1.0__browser_mess-e-v-h-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-spice-6-v1.0__browser_wgc_mess-e-v-h-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.naif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-E/V/H-SPICE-6-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESSENGER SPICE KERNELS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-05-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-08-03T07:13:35Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-04-30T19:26:02Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>MIKE REID</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Turner, Scott, MESSENGER SPICE KERNELS V1.0,
            MESS-E/V/H-SPICE-6-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2007.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Navigation and ancillary data in the form of SPICE System kernel
            files for the MESSENGER mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set includes the complete set of MESSENGER SPICE data
            files (&apos;kernel files&apos;), which can be accessed using
            SPICE software. The SPICE data contains geometric and other
            ancillary information needed to recover the full value of science
            instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft
            and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments,
            spacecraft orientation, spacecraft sequences of events, and data
            needed for relevant time conversions.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
 
      This data set includes the complete set of MESSENGER SPICE data
      files (``kernel files&apos;), which can be accessed using SPICE
      software. The SPICE data contains geometric and other ancillary
      information needed to recover the full value of science
      instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft
      and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments,
      spacecraft orientation, and data needed for relevant time
      conversions.
 
      This data set is contained on a single virtual volume,
      MESSSP_1000, including data from all mission phases and covering
      from launch, 2004-08-03T00:00:00, through the end time of the
      latest reconstructed spacecraft orientation CK file supplied in
      the data set. Until the end of the spacecraft life span this data
      set is accumulating with new data added approximately six months. Data
      are associated with the mission phases given below. These are defined
      in the MESSENGER DMAP. These may be updated periodically.
 
                            Start time          End time
      Phase Name            Date (DOY)          Date (DOY)
      -------------------   -----------------  -----------------
      Launch                03 Aug 2004 (216)  12 Sep 2004 (256)
      Earth Cruise          13 Sep 2004 (257)  18 Jul 2005 (199)
      Earth Flyby           19 Jul 2005 (200)  16 Aug 2005 (228)
      Venus 1 Cruise        17 Aug 2005 (229)  09 Oct 2006 (282)
      Venus 1 Flyby         10 Oct 2006 (283)  07 Nov 2006 (311)
      Venus 2 Cruise        08 Nov 2006 (312)  22 May 2007 (142)
      Venus 2 Flyby         23 May 2007 (143)  20 Jun 2007 (171)
      Mercury 1 Cruise      21 Jun 2007 (172)  30 Dec 2007 (364)
      Mercury 1 Flyby       31 Dec 2007 (365)  28 Jan 2008 (028)
      Mercury 2 Cruise      29 Jan 2008 (029)  21 Sep 2008 (265)
      Mercury 2 Flyby       22 Sep 2008 (266)  20 Oct 2008 (294)
      Mercury 3 Cruise      21 Oct 2008 (295)  15 Sep 2009 (258)
      Mercury 3 Flyby       16 Sep 2009 (259)  14 Oct 2009 (287)
      Mercury 4 Cruise      15 Oct 2009 (288)  03 Mar 2011 (062)
      Mercury Orbit         04 Mar 2011 (063)  17 Mar 2012 (077)
      Mercury Orbit Year 2  18 Mar 2012 (078)  17 Mar 2013 (076)
      Mercury Orbit Year 3  18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)
      Mercury Orbit Year 4  18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)
      Mercury Orbit Year 5  18 Mar 2015 (077)  30 Apr 2015 (120)
 
 
      Data Types (SPICE kernel types)
      ===============================
 
      SPK kernels contain ephemerides for spacecraft, planets,
      satellites, comets and asteroids as well as for moving or fixed
      spacecraft and instrument structures. They provide position and
      velocity, given in a Cartesian reference frame. SPK files are
      located under the ``data/spk&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      PCK kernels contain certain physical, dynamical and cartographic
      constants for target bodies, such as size and shape
      specifications, and orientation of the spin axis and prime
      meridian. PCK files are located under the ``data/pck&apos; directory
      of this data set.
 
      IK kernels (Instrument description kernels) give descriptive and
      operational data peculiar to a particular scientific instrument,
      such as internal timing relative to the spacecraft clock and
      field-of-view model parameters. IK files are located under the
      ``data/ik&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      CK kernels describe pointing, containing a transformation
      traditionally called the C-matrix which is used to determine
      time-tagged pointing (orientation) angles for a spacecraft
      structure upon which science instruments are mounted. CK files
      are located under the ``data/ck&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      EK (Events) kernels are derived from the integrated sequence of
      events used to produce actual spacecraft commands. EK files are
      not used by the MESSENGER program and are not included in this
      data set.
 
      LSK (Leap seconds) kernels contain the leap seconds and the values
      of other constants required to perform a transformation between
      Universal Time Coordinated (UTC) and Ephemeris time (ET). LSK
      files are located under the ``data/lsk&apos; directory of this data
      set.
 
      SCLK (Spacecraft Clock) kernels contain on-board clock
      calibration data required to perform a mapping between Ephemeris
      time (ET) and spacecraft on-board time (SCLK.) SCLK files are
      located under the ``data/sclk&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      FK (Frame Definitions) kernels contain information required to
      define reference frames, sources of frame orientation data and
      inter-connections between these frames and other frames
      supported within the SPICE system. This includes mounting
      alignment information for each instrument. FK files are located
      under the ``data/fk&apos; directory of this data set.
 
 
      Kernel File Details
      ===================
 
      A brief overview of the different types of MESSENGER kernels
      included in this data set is provided in the
      CONFIDENCE_LEVEL_NOTE section of this file while details
      specific to individual files are found in the ``*info.txt&apos;
      files in the corresponding data directory. The most detailed
      description of the data in each file is provided in metadata
      included inside the file -- in the description area of text
      kernels or in the comment area of binary kernels.
 
 
      Software
      ========
 
      The SPICE Toolkit contains software modules needed to read SPICE
      kernel files. SPICELIB software is highly documented via
      internal headers. Additional documentation is available in
      separate ASCII text files called Required Reading files. For
      example, the S- and P- Kernel (SPK) Required Reading File, named
      SPK.REQ, describes use of the SPK kernel file readers and
      contains sample programs.
 
      The latest SPICE Toolkit for a variety of computer platforms
      such as PC, Mac, SUN, etc. is available at the NAIF Node of PDS
      electronically (via anonymous FTP and WWW servers). Refer to
      information in ``software/softinfo.txt&apos; for details regarding
      obtaining this software. Each version of the Toolkit is also
      archived at the NASA National Space Science Data Center.
 
 
      Loading Kernel Files into a SPICE-based Application
      ===================================================
 
      The easiest way to make data from a collection of SPICE kernels
      available to a SPICE-based application is to list these kernels
      in a meta-kernel and load it into the program using the high
      level SPICE data loader routine FURNSH. This data set provides
      such meta-kernel(s) under the ``extras/mk&apos; directory. For more
      information about the MESSENGER meta-kernel(s), see the file
      ``extras/mk/mkinfo.txt&apos;.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      This data set contains SPICE kernel files created during mission
      operations. Some general information about this collection follows
      here, but the prospective user is also referred to extensive
      descriptions about each file that are stored inside each kernel
      file. These metadata provide detailed information regarding the
      information source from which the data were derived, the type of
      processing applied to the source data, applicability of the data,
      etc. Metadata are located in the ``comment area&apos; for binary
      kernel types (SPK, CK, ESQ), accessible using either the COMMNT
      or SPACIT utility program found in the NAIF Toolkit. Metadata are
      located after ``\begintext&apos; markers within the text kernel types
      (PCK, IK, FK, LSK, SCLK, MK), accessible by using any available
      text file display tool such as a word processor, text editor, or
      the unix ``more&apos; or ``cat&apos; commands.
 
      Where there are questions about data accuracy or ``confidence&apos;
      not addressed herein the reader is invited to contact the NAIF
      node of the Planetary Data System for possible further
      information.
 
 
      SPK Files
      =========
 
      Three kinds of SPK files are provided in this archive: a planetary
      ephemerides SPK, merged spacecraft reference trajectory SPKs, and a
      final SPK that contains both merged spacecraft reference trajectory and
      planetary ephemerides (msgr_040803_150430_150430_od431sc_2.bsp).
      Each of these kinds is briefly described below; more information
      is available in the file ``data/spk/spkinfo.txt&apos;.
 
      Planetary SPK
      -------------
 
      The DE405 planetary ephemeris SPK file included in this data set
      contains ephemeris data for the Solar System planet barycenters,
      Sun, Mercury, Venus, Earth, Moon, and Mars. This version of
      ephemerides was officially used by the project during mission
      operations. The internal comments included this SPK file provide
      detailed accuracy information. A custom version of this file containing
      data from both DE405 and DE423, spk/msgr_de405_de423s.bsp, is included
      in this archive and used prior to the final release. It is deprecated in
      the final release since the data it contains are merged into the final
      spacecraft trajectory SPK.
 
      Merged Spacecraft Reference Trajectory SPKs
      -------------------------------------------
 
      These SPKs are the latest official full-mission merged reference
      trajectory SPK files that contain only the spacecraft ephemeris.
      They were created by merging a series of reconstructions and
      short-term predictions onto the modeled whole-tour SPK. These
      files include extensive internal comments providing detailed
      information about reconstructed and predicted portions of the
      data.
 
      Note: The final version of the full-mission merged trajectory SPK,
      msgr_040803_150430_150430_od431sc_2.bsp, also contains the required
      planetary ephemeris. As noted above, the DE405 planetary ephemeris and
      the custom planetary ephemeris, msgr_de405_de423s.bsp, should not be
      loaded when this SPK is loaded. See the final MKs for details.
 
      CK Files
      ========
 
      Three kinds of C-kernel files are provided in this archive: the
      spacecraft bus and solar panel orientation CKs, the MDIS attitude
      history CKs, and the MDIS Pivot Platform CKs. Each of these kinds
      is briefly described below; more information is available in the
      file ``data/ck/ckinfo.txt&apos;.
 
      All of these CK files were produced from engineering telemetry
      down linked from the spacecraft. As is often the case with
      spacecraft engineering telemetry-based measurements, considerable
      uncertainty exists as to the accuracy of such measurements, and,
      data quality (accuracy and completeness) can vary significantly.
 
      Spacecraft Bus and Solar Panel Orientation CK Files
      ---------------------------------------------------
 
      These CK files providing the orientation of the spacecraft bus
      (``the spacecraft&apos;) can be used to support interpretation of
      data obtained by all science experiments. These CK Files also
      contain the orientation of the +X to -X solar panels relative to
      the spacecraft bus. They were generated by mission operations at
      variable sampling resolutions depending on downlink availability
      and spacecraft configuration (can be up to 1 Hz). The engineering
      telemetry that supplied the attitude history included a quality
      flag which was used during construction of the files to eliminate
      readings that do not meet science requirements.
 
      The spacecraft guidance and control telemetry from Oct 20, 2006
      was interrupted when the spacecraft was demoted to earth
      acquisition mode. Due to the anomaly, data were missing. The CK
      file covering this day was ``patched&apos; with simulated data to
      provide coverage for the missing period.
 
      MDIS Attitude History CK Files
      ------------------------------
 
      These CKs provide orientation of the spacecraft bus based on the
      1-Hz spacecraft attitude data bracketing MDIS observations only.
      They represent the same information as the spacecraft bus
      orientation CKs, but at a different sampling frequency. These CK
      files store 16 bit ``compressed&apos; quaternions, unlike the
      spacecraft CK files, which use full 32 bit quaternions. The
      angular rate data included in the MDIS attitude history file did
      not come from Guidance and Control telemetry. Instead, this
      information was derived from the attitude information.
 
      Note that if the normal spacecraft bus orientation telemetry
      supports a 1-Hz rate, this data is not necessary and may not be
      down linked. Therefore the MDIS attitude history file may not
      cover all MDIS observations - just those for which sufficient
      coverage may not exist in the spacecraft bus CK&apos;s.
 
      MDIS Pivot Platform (Gimbal) CK Files
      -------------------------------------
 
      These CKs provide pointing of the MDIS instrument over time. The
      MDIS stepper motor setting telemetry was used to calculate the
      pointing for each image taken. This information was included in
      the image header and was used to construct these CK files. Every
      set of MDIS exposures has related orientation information
      provided in these CKs.
 
      Caution on Using CK Files
      -------------------------
 
      While not a data accuracy issue, the CK user is nevertheless
      cautioned to understand and properly use the data found and
      tolerance arguments that are inputs to the CK reader provided in
      the SPICE Toolkit. Descriptions about how to read CK files are
      found in the CK reader routine headers (top of the source code
      files) and in the ``CK Required Reading&apos; document; these are
      contained in each SPICE Toolkit package.
 
 
      PCK Files
      =========
 
      PCK files provide size, shape and orientation data for ``target&apos;
      bodies such as Earth, Venus and Mercury. A description of these
      data items and reference to their source is provided inside the
      PCK file, which is a simple text file that can be viewed using
      any word processor, text editor or text display utility.
 
      Two types of PCK file are provided in this data set: a type of PCK file
      containing the official IAU/IAG/COSPAR values as of 10/21/2011 and a
      type containing a MESSENGER specific file for the MESSENGER updates to
      Mercury parameters. This second type of PCK file was adopted by the
      MESSENGER Principle Investigator based on the recommendation of the
      MESSENGER science team concerning the best and most current data. It
      contains both the generic PCK provided by NAIF and the MESSENGER
      specific parameters.
 
      More information about the PCK files included in this data set is
      available in the file ``data/pck/pckinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      FK Files
      ========
 
      Frames kernel files provide specifications for how one reference
      frame is defined relative to another frame. This data set
      includes two kinds of FK files: FKs providing the complete set of
      frame definitions for the spacecraft, its structures such as
      solar array, and all of its science instruments and FKs defining
      a number of dynamic frames used in science data reduction. Meta
      information provided in the comments included in these files
      consists of the frame specifications, description of the frame
      relationships, source of and accuracy of the information, etc.
 
      More information about the MESSENGER FK files is available in the
      file ``data/fk/fkinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      IK Files
      ========
 
      Instrument kernel files provide specifications for the mounting
      alignment and--where applicable--field-of-view size, shape and
      orientation for the named instrument. Metadata describing these
      estimates are provided in each IK file included in this archive.
      Parameter values were determined from pre-launch measurements and
      in-flight measurements.
 
      This data set includes IK files for the EPPS, GRNS, MAG, MASCS,
      MDIS, MLA, and XRS instruments. They represent the best available
      information at the present time and meet science requirements.
 
      More information about the MESSENGER IK files is available in the
      file ``data/ik/ikinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      SCLK Files
      ==========
 
      Spacecraft Clock kernel files provide a tabulation of data needed
      for converting time measurements between ephemeris time (ET) and
      spacecraft clock time (SCLK). A SPICE SCLK file is made from a
      similar file--SCLK/SCET file, or SCLKvSCET file--produced by
      another mission entity. Each newly made SCLK file fully replaces
      the previous SCLK file.
 
      The time correlation accuracy of the SCLK files provided in this data
      set meet the science requirements for all phases of the mission.
 
      Note that the SCLK kernels provided in this data set have been
      determined to be in a relativistic solar system barycentric frame
      of reference. This has been verified through confirmation that
      the ephemerides used to compute the SCLK kernel correlations are
      in a solar barycentric frame. It is critically important that the
      users of these kernels for time applications be aware of this and
      that they properly interpret the time correlations in the SCLK
      kernels. The file ``sea_2007_010.pdf&apos; in the ``document&apos;
      directory should be consulted for information on how to do this.
      In addition, the file ``sea_2003_024.pdf&apos; in the ``document&apos;
      directory gives further information on the format and design of
      these kernels.
 
      More information about the SCLK files is available in the
      file ``data/sclk/sclkinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      LSK Files
      =========
 
      Leap seconds kernel files provide a tabulation of ``leap
      seconds&apos; and some other terms used in converting time
      measurements between ephemeris time (ET) and Universal Time
      (UTC). ``Spacecraft Event Time&apos; (SCET) is the commonly used name
      for UTC events measured at the spacecraft.
 
      Metadata describing how the LSK data are obtained or computed is
      contained inside the LSK text file. The time conversion provided
      by SPICE LSK files is accurate to approximately 0.000030 seconds.
 
      More information about the LSK files is available in the file
      ``data/lsk/lskinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      EK Files
      ========
 
      Events kernel (EK) files are not used by the MESSENGER mission;
      therefore, no EKs are included in this data set.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>PSCM-00029</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

