<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.co-e-j-s-sw-mimi-2-lemms-uncalib-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CASSINI E/J/S/SW MIMI LEMMS SENSOR UNCALIBRATED DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mimi.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.saturn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:plasma_stream.solar_wind::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.co-e-j-s-sw-mimi-2-lemms-uncalib-v1.0__browserp_co-e-j-s-sw-mimi-2-lemms-uncalib-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Krimigis, S.M., D.G. Mitchell, D.C. Hamilton, S. Livi, J. Dandouras, S.
                   Jaskulek, T.P. Armstrong, J.D. Boldt, A.F. Cheng, G. Gloeckler, J.R. Hayes,
                   K.C. Hsieh, W.-H. Ip, E.P. Keath, E. Kirsch, N. Krupp, L.J. Lanzerotti, R.
                   Lundgren, B.H. Mauk, R.W. McEntire, E.C. Roelof, C.E. Schlemm, B.E. Tossman, B.
                   Wilken, and D.J. Williams, Magnetosphere Imaging Instrument (MIMI) on the
                   Cassini Mission to Saturn/Titan, Space Sci Rev. 114, 233-329, 2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KRIMIGISETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kusterer, M.B., L.M. Burke, Level 1A File Layouts, Cassini/MIMI Data Analysis
                   Center Level 1A File Layouts, The Johns Hopkins University Applied Physics
                   Laboratory Document, Revision 18, December 2003.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KUSTERER-BURKE2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Manweiler, J.W., W.A. Rasmuss, and S. Joy, MIMI Standard Data Products and
                   Archive Volume Software Interface Specification, v2.1, JPL Document D-31634,
                   Cassini document IO-AR-006, 2005.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MANWEILERETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CO-E/J/S/SW-MIMI-2-LEMMS-UNCALIB-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CASSINI E/J/S/SW MIMI LEMMS SENSOR UNCALIBRATED DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-04-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1999-01-03T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-06-30T23:59:59Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>Jerry W. Manweiler</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Manweiler, J.W., W. Rasmuss, and S. Joy,
            CO-E/J/S/SW-MIMI-2-LEMMS-UNCALIB-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2005.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains all of the data collected by the LEMMS
            sensor of the MIMI instrument aboard the Cassini spacecraft for
            the entire Cassini mission. LEMMS stands for Low Energy
            Magnetospheric Measurements. See MANWEILERETAL2005
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Cassini Magnetospheric Imaging Instrument(MIMI) Low Energy
            Magnetospheric Measurement System (LEMMS) uncalibrated data set
            includes all data collected from the MIMI Data Processing Unit
            during the mission. The original data has been decommutated and
            decoded by software at the Applied Physics Laboratory (APL) and
            has been then further ordered and filtered by software at
            Fundamental Technologies, LLC. The data is provided in an
            uncalibrated form in conjunction with a PDS MIMI calibration
            volume COMIMI_0000 which provides specific algorithms for the
            derivation of calibrated data. This data set includes
            uncalibrated values for each energy channel for the LEMMS sensor
            for all times during the mission including the Earth flyby, the
            Jupiter flyby, interplanetary cruise, and the entire Saturn tour.
            Data are presented in a set of tables which are of variable
            length and use a comma to separate various fields. This data set
            is intended to be the most comprehensive and complete data set
            included in the Cassini MIMI LEMMS archive. A browse data set is
            included with Key Parameter data that is calibrated using the
            algorithms provided in the Calibration volume. In addition, a
            series of images are provided with the KP browse data that
            displays the KP data which can lead the user to the particular
            times of interest. This data set should be among the first used
            by a user of any of the MIMI LEMMS archive as it will lead one to
            information required to search for more detailed or highly
            specialized features in the original data.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The Cassini Magnetospheric Imaging Instrument(MIMI) Low Energy
    Magnetospheric Measurement System (LEMMS) uncalibrated data set
    includes all data collected from the MIMI Data Processing Unit during
    the entire Cassini mission [MANWEILERETAL2005]. The original data has
    been decommutated and decoded by software at the Applied Physics
    Laboratory (APL) and has been then further ordered and filtered by
    software at Fundamental Technologies, LLC. The data is provided in an
    uncalibrated form in conjunction with a PDS MIMI calibration volume
    COMIMI_0000 which provides specific algorithms for the derivation of
    calibrated data. This data set includes uncalibrated values for each
    energy channel for the LEMMS sensor for all times during the mission
    including the Earth flyby, the Jupiter flyby, interplanetary cruise,
    and the entire Saturn tour.  Data are presented in a set of tables
    which are of variable length and use a comma to separate various
    fields.  This data set is intended to be the most comprehensive and
    complete data set included in the Cassini MIMI LEMMS archive.  A
    browse data set is included with Key Parameter data that is calibrated
    using the algorithms provided in the Calibration volume. In addition,
    a series of images are provided with the KP browse data that displays
    the KP data which can lead the user to the particular times of
    interest.  This data set should be among the first used by a user of
    any of the MIMI LEMMS archive as it will lead one to information
    required to search for more detailed or highly specialized features in
    the original data.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    This data set comprises low energy charge particle count rate
    measurements for each energy channel of the LEMMS detector in a
    regular and high time rate mode.  In addition this data set includes
    LEMMS PULSE HEIGHT ANALYSIS measurement data for a statistically
    select sample of the particle measurements. The standard product ID&apos;s
    are:
 
    LEMMS Accumulation Rate Data - low energy charge particle count rate
                                   measurements
    LEMMS Fine Rate Accumulation Data - low energy charge particle count
                                        rate measurements for a select
                                        list of channels at a high time
                                        resolution.
    LEMMS Pulse Height Analysis Data - Statistically sampled set of
                                       discrete particle measurements.
 
    The data is organized in time by the spin of the spacecraft.  When the
    spacecraft is in staring mode then the MIMI DPU automatically creates
    a virtual spin that divides the time collection periods into 16
    sectors, 16 subsectors, and 16 microsectors and maintains a simple
    organizational structure for characterizing the collection of the time
    into time segments.  When the spacecraft is spinning at a minimally
    defined spin rate (adopted by the MIMI DPU) then the MIMI data is
    automatically segregated into 16 sectors, 16 subsectors, and 16
    microsectors.  When the spacecraft is spinning and the LEMMS
    instrument is rotating the LEMMS rotation period is synchronized to
    the spacecraft spin period so that there are 16 sectors in a spin, 16
    subsectors in a sector and 16 microsectors in a subsector.  The CHEMS
    and INCA instrument collection times are then also keyed to these
    values.
 
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    Data in this data set were processed by the use of a number of
    software programs which assemble segmented mini-packets in the raw
    telemetry packets into complete sets, de-compress the data that were
    compressed by one of a number of compression algorithms by the MIMI
    flight software onboard and organize the channel data into
    appropriate time segments.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The MIMI LEMMS uncalibrated data set includes three ASCII CSV tables
    (each associated with a Standard Product ID) of count rate data as a
    function of time collected from the MIMI LEMMS Detectors and collated
    into channel sets. Each table contains variable length records for
    which the fields are comma delimited.
 
    LEMMS Accumulation Rate Data
    ----------------------------
 
      Fields include:
        a purpose identifier where science data records are identified
        with purpose = sci
        starting and ending ephemeris times
        Spin, sector, subsector (and for LEMMS Fine Rate (FRT) data
        microsector)
        SCLOCK and spin period that are used to derive the starting
        ephemeris time
           Notes regarding the SCLOCK value:
           1.  Only the SCLOCK major segment value is provided - MIMI
               currently does not have access to the fine SCLOCK value
               hence SCLOCK resolution is limited to +- 1/2 SCLOCK count
           2.  The SCLOCK is only available from telemetry at the
               beginning of each spin. All other published SCLOCKS are
               derived from the spin starting SCLOCK, the spin numbers
               (for the current and next available spins), and the spin
               period.
           3.  SCLOCK values are assumed to drive the value of the
               ephemeris times and not vice-versa. All effort is made to
               validate the published ephemeris times but since updates to
               the Cassini SCLOCK kernel in SPICE can occur the values of
               ephemeris time are only as accurate as the currently
               published Cassini SCLOCK SPICE kernel.
        Spacecraft staring mode where staring = 0 when spinning and 1
        otherwise
 
        LEMMS Channel count rate data organized as:
          Low Energy Telescope channels
            A0-A8 - These channels are sensitive to protons and heavier
                    ions. The A0-A4 channels are somewhat sensitive to
                    electrons.
            B0-B3 - These channels are sensitive to protons and He.
            BE    - This channel is sensitive to 1 - 2.6 MeV energetic
                    electrons.
            C0-c7 - These channels are associated with magnetically
                    sweeped particles and are sensitive to electrons
            AS, BS, ES, FS are the singles rates measured by the A, B, E
                    and F detectors.
            E2/F2S is the ratio of the E2 to F2 singles rates
 
          High Energy Telescope channels
            E0-E7 - These channels are sensitive to electrons and somewhat
                    sensitive to X-rays
            G1    - This channel is sensitive to X-rays only
            P1-P9 - These channels are mainly sensitive to protons.
                    P1-P2 are sensitive to all species of charged
                    particles and X-rays
                    P7-P9 are also sensitive to He
            H1-H5 - These channels are sensitive to He and heavier species
                    H5 is also sensitive to 20-25 MeV protons
            Z1-Z3 - These channels are sensitive to species heavier than
                    He
            D1-D3, D41 are the singles rates for each of the D detectors
                    in the LEMMS system
 
        Priority Channels
          In various portions of the mission, a subset of main channels
          are identified to provide high time resolution data (for each
          two microsectors).  The totals of the sums for each of these
          priority channels are included in the list of channels for
          diagnostic use.  The number and specific selection of priority
          channels varies over the life of the mission.
 
        LEMMS Center look angle in Degrees, which provides the angle
        between the pointing of the low energy telescope of the LEMMS
        instrument with respect to the -Z axis.
        The LEMMS instrument rotates around the -Y axis.
 
    LEMMS Fine Rate Accumulation Data
    ---------------------------------
 
      Fields include:
        a purpose identifier where science data records are identified
        with purpose = sci
        starting and ending ephemeris times
        Spin, sector, subsector (and for LEMMS Fine Rate (FRT) data
        microsector)
        SCLOCK and spin period that are used to derive the starting
        ephemeris time
           Notes regarding the SCLOCK value:
           1.  Only the SCLOCK major segment value is provided - MIMI
               currently does not have access to the fine SCLOCK value
               hence SCLOCK resolution is limited to +- 1/2 SCLOCK count
           2.  The SCLOCK is only available from telemetry at the
               beginning of each spin. All other published SCLOCKS are
               derived from the spin starting SCLOCK, the spin numbers
               (for the current and next available spins), and the spin
               period.
           3.  SCLOCK values are assumed to drive the value of the
               ephemeris times and not vice-versa. All effort is made to
               validate the published ephemeris times but since updates to
               the Cassini SCLOCK kernel in SPICE can occur the values of
               ephemeris time are only as accurate as the currently
               published Cassini SCLOCK SPICE kernel.
        Spacecraft staring mode where staring = 0 when spinning and 1
        otherwise
 
        LEMMS Channel count rate data organized based upon the current set
        of priority channels The set of priority channels changes from
        time to time during the mission.  The specific channels for any
        particular data file are identified by the headers of that data
        file.
 
        LEMMS Center look angle in Degrees, which provides the angle
        between the pointing of the low energy telescope of the LEMMS
        instrument with respect to the -Z axis.  The LEMMS instrument
        rotates around the -Y axis.
 
 
    LEMMS Pulse Height Analysis Data
    --------------------------------
 
      Fields include:
        a purpose identifier where science data records are identified
        with purpose = sci
        starting and ending ephemeris times
        Spin, sector, subsector
        SCLOCK and spin period that are used to derive the starting
        ephemeris time
           Notes regarding the SCLOCK value:
           1.  Only the SCLOCK major segment value is provided - MIMI
               currently does not have access to the fine SCLOCK value
               hence SCLOCK resolution is limited to +- 1/2 SCLOCK count
           2.  The SCLOCK is only available from telemetry at the
               beginning of each spin. All other published SCLOCKS are
               derived from the spin starting SCLOCK, the spin numbers
               (for the current and next available spins), and the spin
               period.
           3.  SCLOCK values are assumed to drive the value of the
               ephemeris times and not vice-versa. All effort is made to
               validate the published ephemeris times but since updates to
               the Cassini SCLOCK kernel in SPICE can occur the values of
               ephemeris time are only as accurate as the currently
               published Cassini SCLOCK SPICE kernel.
        Spacecraft staring mode where staring = 0 when spinning and 1
        otherwise
 
      LEMMS Detector Channel count rate data is an array of counts for
      each of the three low energy telescope solid state detectors.  Each
      field contains the counts observed within each of the 64 energy bins
      for each of the detectors (A, E1, and F1) accumulated over the
      specific time interval. The Detector energy bins are
      quasi-logarithmically spaced. See the MIMI_CALIBRATION calibration
      file for spacing deltas and min and max energies.
 
      LEMMS Center look angle in Degrees, which provides the angle between
      the pointing of the low energy telescope of the LEMMS instrument
      with respect to the -Z axis.  The LEMMS instrument rotates around
      the -Y axis.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    Included with the LEMMS data set volumes are ancillary data files
    representing the MIMI Key Parameter (KP) data.  The MIMI KP data is a
    calibrated subset of the important channels for each of the MIMI
    detectors.  The subset of channels have been identified to most
    reasonably show characteristic energetic particle events during the
    mission.  The KP data is calculated at an arbitrarily defined 60
    second cadence which is different than the approximate collection
    times for the instruments as identified below for standard operations:
    (It must be realized that the collection times vary based upon the
    telemetry rate but nothing more than a factor of 2, 4, or 8.)
 
        Instrument      Product Type     Approx Collection Time (s)
        ------------------------------------------------------------
        LEMMS           Accumulation     5 (each subsector)
        LEMMS           Fine Rate        0.6 (each microsector)
        LEMMS           PHA              5 (each subsector)
        CHEMS           Accumulation     4
        CHEMS           Science          5 (each subsector)
        CHEMS           PHA              80 (each sector)
        INCA            Accumulation     7.5
        INCA            IMAGES           180 (2 sectors)
        INCA            PHA              22
 
     Data points for each record of the KP data are first Median Quartile
     Filtered then averaged (except in the case where the median is zero)
     for each sector.  The sectored data is then interpolated into the 60
     second data cadence of the KP data file.  The KP data is then
     converted into a flux in units of 1/(cm^2*sr*sec*KeV) or for the case
     of CHEMS 1/(cm^2*sr*sec*keV/e)
 
     Browse plots for each of the KP data files are produced.  There are 7
     different browse plots available.
 
     Inst    Wild Card File Name                  Plotted KP data
     ---------------------------------------------------------------------
     LEMMS   LEMMS_KP_ELEC_(yyyydoy)_(ver#).JPG   KP LEMMS Electron flux
     LEMMS   LEMMS_KP_ION_(yyyydoy)_(ver#).JPG    KP LEMMS Ion flux
     CHEMS   CHEMS_KP_HEP_(yyyydoy)_(ver#).JPG    KP CHEMS Helium Plus
                                                  flux per charge
     CHEMS   CHEMS_KP_HEPP_(yyyydoy)_(ver#).JPG   KP CHEMS Helium Plus
                                                  Plus flux per charge
     CHEMS   CHEMS_KP_HP_(yyyydoy)_(ver#).JPG     KP CHEMS Hydrogen Plus
                                                  flux per charge
     CHEMS   CHEMS_KP_OP_(yyyydoy)_(ver#).JPG     KP CHEMS Oxygen Plus
                                                  per charge
     INCA    INCA_KP_(yyyydoy)_(ver#).JPG         Hydrogen TOF flux
 
     Usage Note
     ----------
       The KP browse data and associated browse plots are to be used as an
       initial characterization of the particle environment and are NOT to
       be used for publications.  The data is not at publication quality
       and is provided as is.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    The data in this data set are measurements of count rates based upon
    the orientation of the LEMMS instrument (LEMMS Center look direction).
    Particle flux effects are then determined by transforming from a
    spacecraft centered coordinate system, properly rotated to account for
    the appropriate LEMMS telescope and look direction, into whatever
    external coordinate (reference system) is most appropriate.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    There is no sample software provided as of the writing of this catalog
    file although the calibration volume does provide algorithms for
    conversion of count rates into flux.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    These data are supplied to the Planetary Data System via electronic
    means and are then broken into segments based upon the media currently
    prescribed by PDS.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    This data set contains all calibrated data for the LEMMS Detector as
    part of the Cassini MIMI instrument for the interval described above.
    Every effort has been made to ensure that all data returned to APL
    from the spacecraft is included and that the calibrated browse data
    products are accurate.
 
    The LEMMS C0 channel (and less so for the C1 channel) has occasional
    exceptionally high rates (spectral indexes exceeding 6) that are due
    either to direct solar exposure and/or to specular reflection from
    various parts of the spacecraft.  This was first identified during the
    Earth - Jupiter Cruise phase of the mission. Priority channels were
    reorganized during this time but with the unexpected result that the
    C1 channel was being corrupted without the ability to identify the
    source of the corruption at a high time resolution which the priority
    channels provide.  Just prior to SOI the priority channels were again
    re-established to include the C0 channel for the specific purpose of
    enabling the data user to develop algorithms to eliminate those data
    values that include this contamination.
 
    The low energy A (A0 - A4) channels are subject to contamination by
    electrons.
 
    As of January 2005, the LEMMS detector no longer has the ability to
    rotate.  Various attempts to correct this anomaly have been tried with
    the result of moving the fixed position to other nearby pointing
    directions but these attempts have failed in their ability to restart
    full motion of the detector.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    The MIMI LEMMS data will be reviewed internally by the Cassini MIMI
    team prior to release to the PDS. The data set will also be peer
    reviewed by the PDS.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    All data in the stated interval are included, to the best of our
    knowledge and attempts to determine completeness.  In general, the
    instrument was operated only briefly during early tour for the
    following intervals:
 
    1.  Antenna deployment   1997-10-25T00:00 - 1997-10-26T05:30
    2.  Venus 1 flyby        1998-04-26T12:54 - 1998-05-08T19:21
    3.  Instrument Checkout  1998-12-30T09:10 - 1999-01-19T05:40
    4.  Venus 2 flyby        1999-06-24T09:08 - 1999-06-24T21:20
    5.  Earth flyby          1999-08-13T17:39 - 1999-09-14T22:20
 
    Only data for interval 5 is provided to PDS due to technical issues in
    processing.
 
    Beginning in February of 2000 the instrument was operated more-or-less
    continuously with small daily runs of approximately 8 hours.
    Intermittent data collection occurred during 2002 and 2003 with
    multiple day gaps in the data
 
    Large Data Gaps:
    1.  Cruise               2000-066 - 2000-155
    2.  Cruise               2000-210 - 2000-246
    3.  Cruise               2000-311 - 2000-320
    4.  Cruise               2000-322 - 2000-333
    5.  Post Jupiter Cruise  2003-018 - 2003-104
    6.  Post SOI             2004-187 - 2004-193 - Spacecraft safing
                                                   shut off
    7.  Saturn               2012-293 - 2012-303 - propellant gauging test
 
    Those days for which the instrument did not collect data either due to
    the instrument being off or due to communication issues, the data set
    will not contain any files.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    As noted above the A0 and C0 channels (and somewhat less so the C1, A1
    and additional C and A channels) have occasional significant
    corruption of the count rate due to direct solar pointing and/or due
    to specular reflection of UV from various parts of the spacecraft.
    There has as yet been no systematic algorithm developed to capture
    when these events occur either by the spectral power of the data or
    else by the pointing excepting in the situation when the LEMMS
    instrument itself is directly pointed into the Sun.  This last
    situation can be easily identified by using the SPICE routines.
 
    The KP browse data and associated browse plots are to be used as an
    initial characterization of the particle environment and are NOT to be
    used for publications.  The data is not at publication quality and is
    provided as is.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>IN_PEER_REVIEW</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

