<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.go-j-nims-2-edr-v2.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GALILEO NIMS EXPERIMENT DATA RECORDS: JUPITER OPERATIONS</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.galileo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:nims.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:ring.j_rings::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.callisto::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.europa::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.ganymede::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.io::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-j-nims-2-edr-v2.0__browserp_go-j-nims-2-edr-v2.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-j-nims-2-edr-v2.0__browserp_go-j-nims-2-edr-v2.1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-j-nims-2-edr-v2.0__dvo_imaging_go-j-nims-2-edr-v2.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Carlson, R.W., P.R. Weissman, W.D. Smythe, J.C. Mahoney, and the NIMS Science
                   and Engineering Teams, Near-Infrared Mapping Spectrometer Experiment on
                   Galileo, Space Science Reviews 60: 457-502, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CARLSONETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kamp, L., &apos; 10. Kamp, L., &apos;Project Galileo Software Interface Specification:
                   Near- Infrared Mapping Spectrometer Experiment Data Record (NIMS EDR) for Phase
                   2&apos;, D-3048, GLL Project 232-08, SFOC0038-02-00-03, SFOC1-MPS-GLL-NIMSEDR,
                   Revision A, June 17, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KAMP1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Zamani, P., Project Galileo Software Interface Specification: NIMS Experiment
                   Data Record, 625-610: SIS 232-08 (JPL D-296), July 30, 1991.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ZAMANI1991</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GO-J-NIMS-2-EDR-V2.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GALILEO NIMS EXPERIMENT DATA RECORDS: JUPITER OPERATIONS</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1998-05-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1996-05-24T17:08Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2002-03-19T01:15Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>Dr. Robert W. Carlson</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            NIMS Experiment Data Record (EDR)
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            NIMS Experiment Data Record (EDR) files contain raw data from the
            Galileo Orbiter Near-Infrared Mapping Spectrometer
            (CARLSONETAL1992). This raw data requires considerable processing
            before it is readily amenable to science analysis. The EDRs
            comprise the base dataset from which spectral image cubes will be
            created by continually evolving software using successively more
            accurate calibration and geometry data.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    NIMS Experiment Data Record (EDR) files contain raw data from the
    Galileo Orbiter Near-Infrared Mapping Spectrometer
    (CARLSONETAL1992).  This raw data requires considerable processing
    before it is readily amenable to science analysis.  The EDRs
    comprise the base dataset from which spectral image cubes will be
    created by continually evolving software using successively more
    accurate calibration and geometry data.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The files consist principally of 10-bit sensor values from the 17
    NIMS detectors ordered by time of acquisition.  During cruise, these
    were interleaved with NIMS background and housekeeping values, and,
    less frequently, various instrument temperatures, AACS (scan
    platform and rotor pointing) data and engineering measurements.
    For Jupiter observations, only the sensor values are in the EDR.
    Those engineering and AACS values which are still being returned
    are collected in separate datasets.
 
    Sensor values are measured simultaneously in all detectors; a set of
    17 values is acquired at each of 20 cross-track positions (via a
    secondary scanning mirror) in a period of 1/3 second.  A grating may
    step between mirror scans; as many as 24 steps may result in 20
    spectra of as many as 408 wavelengths each.  A second spatial
    dimension is added by spacecraft and scan platform motion.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The EDRs are generated by the Multimission Image Processing System
    (MIPS) at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) from data sources
    derived ultimately from decommutated Galileo telemetry.  During
    cruise, they were divided into files containing up to 100 RIMs
    (60 2/3 second intervals) of data.  During Jupiter operations,
    a separate EDR is generated for each NIMS observation.  Each file
    contains the best data available from the several ground stations
    receiving Galileo telemetry.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    During cruise, the data were organized into 1024-byte records, one
    for each minor frame (2/3 second) of spacecraft clock time.  In that
    time, the NIMS instrument has collected sensor values for all 17
    detectors over two scans (20 positions down and 20 positions up) of
    the secondary mirror.
 
    Due to the failure to deploy the Galileo high gain antenna,
    procedures were developed for editing NIMS data from Jupiter
    observations in wavelength and/or mirror position, and for lossless
    compression of the data before playback.  (The data are, however,
    decompressed before the EDR is written.)  Thus for Jupiter (phase 2)
    operations, the EDR format was revised:  one record is written for
    each *half* minor frame of spacecraft clock time, except that no
    record is written for a half minor frame during which no data is
    selected.  A valid-data mask in the binary header indicates which
    records in a RIM are actually present.
 
    A detailed description of the structure of the EDR may be found in
    the Galileo Software Interface Specification (ZAMANI1991 for cruise,
    KAMP1996 for Jupiter operations).  The same information is available
    in both human and machine-readable form in the Planetary Data System
    (PDS) structure files on the NIMS EDR CD-ROM volumes.
 
    As received from MIPS, each file has a Vicar label preceding a
    PDS/ISIS label.  The Vicar labels have been removed from the EDRs
    on  the CD-ROMs but they are present in detached form.  The
    PDS/ISIS-labelled EDRs themselves may be readily displayed and
    further processed by software in the ISIS system, and by PDS
    utilities.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    A Postscript-format Guide to the planned observations, including
    footprint plots on the target, instrument parameters, etc. is
    included with the EDRs on the CD-ROM, as are tables of parameters
    for each EDR file and each observation, a digitized map of the
    Galileo booms in cone-clock space and tables of NIMS internal
    geometry and timing.  Separate files of NIMS engineering values
    (mostly temperatures) are also included.  Tables of (noise) spikes
    in time order have been developed for Europa, Ganymede and Callisto
    observations and are also included on the CD-ROM.
 
    Calibration and dark value files, and SPICE files (spacecraft
    positions, planetary positions and constants, processed pointing
    geometry, spacecraft clock versus universal time, etc.) will be
    included in later volumes of the CD-ROM set, or in a separate
    CD-ROM.  Presently, calibration and dark value files required for
    cube generation may be obtained from the NIMS team, and SPICE files
    may be obtained from the Galileo Science Data Team.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    Simple software is available from the NIMS team for displaying the
    raw data in various ways, but use of this software requires
    considerable familiarity with the operation of the NIMS instrument.
    Most science analysis requires generation of spectral image cubes
    using ancillary geometric data, and decalibration of the raw data
    numbers.  This may be done with one of several sets of cube
    generation programs available in the ISIS and Vicar systems.
    (Data cubes generated in this way will be made available in a
    separate series of CD-ROMs.)  Programs for displaying validity and
    status information and for re-attaching the Vicar label to the EDR
    are also available.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    The NIMS EDRs are archived on CD-ROM for delivery to the Planetary
    Data System (PDS).  Formats are based on standards for such products
    established by PDS.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    NIMS EDRs contain essentially raw data as received from Galileo
    telemetry.  These are generally processed into spectral image cubes
    for science analysis.  A fuller discussion of confidence levels will
    be more appropriate for the spectral image cube dataset.
 
 
    Review
    ------
      The NIMS EDRs are reviewed prior to archiving by the NIMS team.
      Data received is compared with data expected, and replays of
      missing data requested.  The status and validity information on
      the EDRs themselves is examined.  Spectral image cubes of NIMS
      target data are generated and reviewed for spatial data coverage
      and consistency against observational plans.  Often, spikes
      (usually due to radiation noise) are identified and tabulated.
      Format and documentation of the CD-ROM archive volumes are
      reviewed by PDS.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    -------------------------
      The EDRs contain flags which indicate the validity of individual
      subsets of NIMS sensor data.  Special values (DNs 0-4) identify
      various kinds of data editing or loss.
 
 
    Limitations
    -----------
      The raw data numbers on the NIMS EDRs are of limited use.  Proper
      science analysis requires the computation of radiances according
      to the best understanding of the instrument calibration, and
      proper projection of the data onto the target in the form of
      spectral image cubes.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

