<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dif-e-hrii-2-epoxi-earth-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>EPOXI EARTH OBS - HRII RAW SPECTRA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.epoxi::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:hrii.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dif-e-hrii-2-epoxi-earth-v1.0__browserp_dif-e-hrii-2-epoxi-earth-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Cowan, N.B., E. Agol, V.S. Meadows, T.A. Livengood, D. Deming, C.M. Lisse, M.F.
                   A&apos;Hearn, D.D. Wellnitz, S. Seager, and D. Charbonneau, Alien Maps of an
                   Ocean-Bearing World, ApJ, 700, 915-923, 2009, doi:10.1088/0004-637X/700/2/915.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.COWANETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hampton, D.L., J.W. Baer, M.A. Huisjen, C.C. Varner, A. Delamere, D.D.
                   Wellnitz, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, and K.P. Klaasen, An Overview of the Instrument Suite
                   for the Deep Impact Mission, Space Science Reviews, 117, 43-93, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3390-8.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAMPTONETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., M.F. A&apos;Hearn, M. Baca, A. Delamere, M. Desnoyer, T. Farnham, O.
                   Groussin, D. Hampton, S. Ipatov, J. Li, C. Lisse, N. Mastrodemos, S.
                   McLaughlin, J. Sunshine, P. Thomas, and D. Wellnitz, Deep Impact Instrument
                   Calibration, Rev. Sci. Instrum., 79, 091301, 2008, doi:10.1063/1.2972112.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Livengood, T.A., L.D. Deming, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, D. Charbonneau, T. Hewagama, C.M.
                   Lisse, L.A. McFadden, V.S. Meadows, T.D. Robinson, S. Seager, and D.D Wellnitz,
                   Properties of an Earth-Like Planet Orbiting a Sun-Like Star: Earth Observed by
                   the EPOXI Mission Astrobiology, 11(9), 907-930, 2011, doi:10.1089/ast.2011.0614.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LIVENGOODETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DIF-E-HRII-2-EPOXI-EARTH-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>EPOXI EARTH OBS - HRII RAW SPECTRA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2009-12-31</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2008-03-18T18:21:12.114Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2008-06-05T17:19:30.768Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STEPHANIE MCLAUGHLIN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            McLaughlin, S.A., B. Carcich, D. Deming, K.P. Klaasen, and D.D.
            Wellnitz, EPOXI EARTH OBS - HRII RAW SPECTRA V1.0,
            DIF-E-HRII-2-EPOXI-EARTH-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2009.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw, 1.05- to 4.8-micron spectra of Earth acquired by the Deep
            Impact High Resolution Infrared Spectrometer during three,
            24-hour-long observing periods on 18-19 March, 28-29 May, and 4-5
            June 2008 for the EPOXI mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set set contains version 1.0 of raw, 1.05- to
            4.8-micron spectra of Earth acquired by the High Resolution
            Infrared Spectrometer (HRII) during the EPOCh phase of the EPOXI
            mission. Three sets of observations were acquired on 18-19 March,
            28-29 May, and 4-5 June 2008 to characterize Earth as an analog
            for extrasolar planets. Each observing period lasted
            approximately 24 hours, and spectra were acquired twice per hour.
            During the observing period in May, the Moon transited across
            Earth as seen from the spacecraft. Additional Earth observations
            are planned for the mission, and these data will be added to a
            future version of this data set.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set contains version 1.0 of raw, 1.05- to 4.8-micron spectra
    of Earth acquired by the High Resolution Infrared Spectrometer (HRII)
    during the EPOCh phase of the EPOXI mission.  Three sets of
    observations were acquired on 18-19 March, 28-29 May, and 4-5 June
    2008 to characterize Earth as an analog for extrasolar planets.  Each
    observing period lasted approximately 24 hours, and spectra were
    acquired twice per hour.  During the observing period in May, the Moon
    transited across Earth as seen from the spacecraft.
 
    At every half hour of each observing period, the spacecraft slewed
    across the Earth while the IR spectrometer recorded data; these
    scans were performed three times within several minutes, alternating
    direction from south-to-north and north-to-south.  Each scan
    consisted of eight 128x256 binned subframes.  Each half-hour set
    alternated between slower scans with longer frame exposure times
    and faster scans with shorter frame durations.
 
    Additional Earth observations are being planned for the mission
    because two observing periods that were scheduled from late March
    through early May 2008 were canceled due to a telecommunications
    anomaly on board the spacecraft.  These data will be added to a
    future version of this data set.
 
 
    Required Reading
    ---------------
      The following documents are essential for the understanding and
      interpretation of this data set.  Please note the most recent
      version of these documents, including other formats such as ASCII
      text, can be found in the Deep Impact and EPOXI documentation data set,
      DI-C-HRII-HRIV-MRI-ITS-6-DOC-SET-V2.0.
 
      EPOXI_SIS.PDF
        - The Archive Volume and Data Product Software Interface
          Specifications document (SIS) describes the the data set, the
          science data products, and defines keywords in the PDS labels.
 
      CALIBRATION_PAPER_DRAFT.PDF
        - The Deep Impact instrument calibration paper by Klaasen, et al.
          (2008) [KLAASENETAL2006] describes how the instruments were
          calibrated for Deep Impact and similarly for EPOXI and explains
          the calibration process used for both missions.  The published
          version should be available online in the Review of Scientific
          Instruments by the American Institute of Physics.  The EPOXI
          archive provides only an incomplete draft.
 
      INSTRUMENTS_HAMPTON.PDF
        - The Deep Impact instruments paper by Hampton, et al. (2005)
          [HAMPTONETAL2005] provides very detailed descriptions of the
          instruments.
 
      EPOCH_EARTH_OBS.PDF
        - This document describes of the EPOCh Earth observations
          although most of the information is captured in this data set
          catalog file you are reading.
 
      EPOCH_EARTH_SEQ_2008.PDF
       - This document provides pointing and sequencing information
         for the EPOCh Earth observations in 2008, including descriptions
         of the HRII scans of Earth (scan direction, rate, etc.).
 
      EPOCH_OVERVIEW.PDF
        - This presentation provides an overview of the EPOCh phase of
          the EPOXI mission.
 
      HRII_2_EPOXI_EARTH.TAB
        - This ASCII table provides image parameters such as the mid-obs
          Julian date, exposure time, mission activity type, and
          description or purpose for each observation (i.e., data product)
          in this data set.  This file is very useful for determining which
          data files to work with.
 
      Publications of the scientific results from the Earth observations
      in this data set include Cowan, et al. (2009) [COWANETAL2009] and
      Livengood, et al. (2009) [LIVENGOODETAL2009].
 
 
    Related Data Sets
    -----------------
      The following PDS data sets are related to this one and may be useful
      for research:
 
      DIF-E-HRII-3/4-EPOXI-EARTH-V1.0
        - Calibrated HRII Earth observations
 
      DIF-CAL-HRII-2-EPOXI-CALIBRATIONS-V1.0
        - Raw HRII dark frames that bracket each set of Earth observations
          in this data set
 
      DIF-E-HRIV-2-EPOXI-EARTH-V1.0
      DIF-E-HRIV-3/4-EPOXI-EARTH-V1.0
        - Raw and calibrated HRIV visible CCD Earth observations at
          350, 450, 550, 650, 750, 850, and 950 nm, covering the same
          three observing periods as this data set
 
      DIF-E-MRI-2-EPOXI-EARTH-V1.0
      DIF-E-MRI-3/4-EPOXI-EARTH-V1.0
        - Raw and calibrated MRI visible CCD context images of Earth at
          750 nm, covering only the March 2008 observing period.
 
      DI-C-HRII-HRIV-MRI-ITS-6-DOC-SET-V2.0
        - Deep Impact and EPOXI documentation set
 
      DIF-C/E/X-SPICE-6-V1.0
        - EPOXI SPICE kernels
 
      DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV/MRI-6-EPOXI-TEMPS-V1.0
        - HRII, HRIV, and MRI instrument thermal telemetry data for EPOXI
          which may be useful for determining how temperature fluctuations
          affect the science instruments, in particular the IR spectrometer
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The raw two-dimensional (wavelength and spatial/along-slit) FITS
    spectral images and PDS labels in this data set were generated by the
    Deep Impact/EPOXI data pipeline, maintained by the project&apos;s Science
    Data Center (SDC) at Cornell University.  The FITS data were assembled
    from raw telemetry packets sent down by the flyby spacecraft.
    Information from the embedded spacecraft header (the first 100 bytes of
    quadrant A image data) was extracted and stored in the primary FITS
    header.  Geometric parameters were computed using the best available
    SPICE kernels and the results were also stored in the FITS header.  If
    telemetry packets were missing, the corresponding pixels were flagged
    as missing in the quality map included as a FITS image extension.  The
    quadrant nomenclature and the image quality map are described in the
    Deep Impact instrument calibration document and the EPOXI SIS document
    included in this data set.  The SDC did not apply any type of
    correction or decompression algorithm to the raw data.
 
 
  Data
  ====
 
    FITS Images and PDS Labels
    --------------------------
      Each raw spectral image is stored as FITS.  The primary data unit
      contains the two-dimensional spectral image, with the fastest
      varying axis corresponding to increasing wavelengths from about
      1.05 to 4.8 microns and the slowest varying axis corresponding to
      the spatial or along-slit dimension.  The primary array is
      followed by one image extension that contains a two-dimensional
      pixel-by-pixel quality map.  This extension uses one byte of eight
      bit flags to indicate the quality of each pixel in the primary
      image.  The data label provides a short description of each bit.
      For more information about the FITS primary image and its
      extension or for examples of how to access and use the quality
      flags, refer to the EPOXI SIS document or the Deep Impact
      instrument calibration document.
 
      Each FITS file is accompanied by a detached PDS data label.  The
      EPOXI SIS document provides definitions for the keywords found in a
      data label.
 
 
    File Naming Convention
    ----------------------
      The naming convention for the raw data labels and FITS files is
      HIyymmddhh_eeeeeee_nnn.LBL or FIT where &apos;HI&apos; identifies the HRII
      instrument, yymmddhh provides the UTC year, month, day, and hour at
      the mid-point of the observation, eeeeeee is the exposure ID
      (OBSERVATION_ID in data labels), and nnn provides the image number
      (IMAGE_NUMBER in the data labels) within the exposure ID.
 
      Up to 999 individual images can be commanded for one exposure ID.
      Spectral scans often had 32 or more frames for one specific exposure.
      Therefore, nnn in the file name provides the sequentially increasing
      frame number within an exposure ID and corresponds to IMAGE_NUMBER in
      the data labels.  For example, if 32 frames were commanded for a scan
      with an exposure ID of 1000001, the first FITS file name would be
      HI08060416_1000001_001.FIT and the last would be
      HI08060416_1000001_032.FIT.
 
 
    Image Compression
    -----------------
      Although raw data numbers for HRII frames could be compressed on
      board the flyby spacecraft by use of a lookup table then downlinked,
      processed, and archived in the same format, Earth spectra acquired
      during the time period covered by this data set were never
      compressed.  Therefore the COMPRESSED_IMAGE_VALUE keyword in the
      data labels is always set to &apos;UNCOMPRESSED&apos;.  For more information
      about this topic, see the image compression section of the Deep
      Impact instrument calibration documents.
 
 
    Image Orientation
    -----------------
      A true-sky &apos;as seen by the observer&apos; view is achieved by displaying
      the image using the standard FITS convention:  the fastest-varying
      axis (samples or wavelength) increasing to the right in the display
      window and the slowest-varying axis (lines or spatial/along-slit)
      increasing to the top.  This convention is identified in the data
      labels:  the SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION keyword is set to RIGHT and
      LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION to UP.
 
      The direction to celestial north, ecliptic north, and the Sun is
      provided in data labels by CELESTIAL_NORTH_CLOCK_ANGLE,
      ECLIPTIC_NORTH_CLOCK_ANGLE, and SUN_DIRECTION_CLOCK_ANGLE keywords
      and are measured clockwise from the top of the image when is
      displayed in the correct orientation as defined by
      SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION and LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION.  Please note
      the aspect of the North celestial pole in an image can be computed
      by adding 90 degrees to the boresight declination given by
      DECLINATION in the data labels.
 
      For a comparison of the orientation FITS image data from the three
      science instruments, see the quadrant nomenclature section of the
      Deep Impact instrument calibration document.  Also the EPOXI SIS
      has a brief discussion of this topic.
 
 
    Spectral Scans
    --------------
      Each IR scan across the Earth consists of multiple frames within
      one exposure ID (OBSERVATION_ID in the data labels).  To work with
      these spectral scans, it is recommended that all frames for one
      exposure ID be stacked into a three-dimensional cube.  Then, a
      spatial-spatial map can be produced for a specific wavelength by
      selecting the appropriate spectral column from the image cube.
      Spectral wavelengths are provided by the second FITS extension,
      the spectral registration (wavelength) map.
 
 
    IR Slit Location
    ----------------
      For a comparison of the relative locations of the IR slit with
      respect to the fields of view of the Medium Resolution Instrument
      Visible CCD (MRI) and the High Resolution Instrument Visible CCD
      (HRIV), see the relative boresight alignments section of the
      Deep Impact instrument calibration document.
 
 
    Timing for Spectra
    ------------------
      It is important to note that the readout order of the IR detector
      affects the timing of the spectra.  When a HRII spectral image is
      displayed using the true-sky convention, the wavelength increases
      horizontally to the right and the spatial or along-slit direction
      is vertical.  In this orientation, the IR detector was read out
      from the left and right edges and toward the center and starting
      with the first row at the bottom and ending with the last row at
      the top of the display.  Since the detector is reset and read out
      on a pixel-by-pixel basis, the read out order affects the time at
      which each pixel is exposed, although each pixel has the same
      exposure duration.  Additionally, the end of the spectrometer slit
      that always points roughly towards the sun is the first line to be
      readout and the last line to be read out is furthest from the sun,
      assuming the spacecraft is in its usual orientation with the solar
      pointing roughly toward the sun.  For more information about the
      timing of the spectra, see the IR focal plane and quadrant
      nomenclature sections of the Deep Impact instrument calibration
      document.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
    Data Units
    ----------
      Raw spectral image data have units of raw data numbers.
 
 
    Imaging Modes
    -------------
      One HRII image mode was used for all Earth spectra:
 
                    X-Size  Y-Size  Bin
        Mode Name   (pix)   (pix)  Type  Comments
        ---- ------ ------  -----  ----- ---------------------------------
          2  BINSF1   512     126   2x2  Binned sub-frame
 
      In the table above, X-Size is the spectral dimension and Y-Size is
      the spatial dimension.  For a thorough description of the imaging
      modes, please see the Deep Impact instruments document or the Deep
      Impact instrument calibration document.  Also the EPOXI SIS has a
      brief discussion of this topic.
 
 
    Time- and Geometry-Related Keywords
    -----------------------------------
      All time-related keywords in the data labels, except
      EARTH_OBSERVER_MID_TIME, are based on the clock on board the flyby
      spacecraft.  EARTH_OBSERVER_MID_TIME provides the UTC when an
      Earth-based observer should have been able to see an event recorded
      by the instrument.
 
      For Earth observations, sub-spacecraft and sub-solar longitude and
      latitude coordinates (planetocentric, body-fixed rotating) are
      provided, when available, in the data labels by
      SUB_SPACECRAFT_LONGITUDE, SUB_SPACECRAFT_LATITUDE,
      SUB_SOLAR_LONGITUDE, and SUB_SOLAR_LATITUDE.
 
      The SDC pipeline was not able to automatically determine the proper
      geometric information for the target of choice in some cases.  When
      these parameters could not be computed, the corresponding keywords
      in the data labels are set to a value of unknown, &apos;UNK&apos;.  Also if
      GEOMETRY_QUALITY_FLAG is set to &apos;BAD&apos; or GEOMETRY_TYPE is set to
      &apos;PREDICTED&apos; in the PDS labels, then this indicates the geometry
      values may not be accurate and should be used with caution.  The
      value &apos;N/A&apos; is used for some geometry-related keywords in the data
      labels because these parameters are not applicable for certain
      calibration targets.
 
      Observational geometry parameters provided in the data labels were
      computed at the epoch specified by the mid-obs UTC, IMAGE_MID_TIME,
      in the data labels.  The exceptions are the target-to-sun values
      that were calculated for the time when the light arrived at the
      target and the earth-observer-to-target values that were calculated
      for the time when the light left the target.
 
      The flyby spacecraft clock SPICE kernels (SCLK) used to convert to
      UTC and to calculate geometry-related parameters for this data set
      have a known accuracy of no better than 0.5 seconds.  However as
      this data set was being produced, the mission operations team
      figured out how to correct raw clock correlation data for the
      flyby spacecraft to allow timing fits that are accurate to at
      least the sub-second level.  The project plans to generate a
      complete, corrected set of correlations since launch.  This will
      ultimately result in a future version of a SCLK kernel that will
      retroactively change correlation for **all** Deep Impact and EPOXI
      data.  When this kernel is available, it will be added to the
      SPICE data sets for the two missions and posted on the NAIF/SPICE
      web site at http://naif.jpl.nasa.gov/naif/.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    The geometric parameters included in the data labels and FITS headers
    were computed using the best available SPICE kernels at the time the
    data products were generated.  NAIF used these kernels to produce the
    EPOXI SPICE data set, DIF-C/E/X-SPICE-6-V1.0.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    Earth Mean Equator and Vernal Equinox of J2000 (EME J2000) is the
    inertial reference system used to specify observational geometry
    parameters in the data labels, unless specified otherwise (e.g,
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LONGITUDE).
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The observations in this data set are in standard FITS format with PDS
    labels, and can be viewed by a number of PDS-provided and commercial
    programs.  For this reason no special software is provided with this
    data set.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The data files in this data set were reviewed internally by the EPOXI
    project.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    This data set is archived at the PDS Small Bodies Node (SBN) and the
    Multi-Mission Archive at STScI (MAST).  It passed a peer review held
    by SBN on 23 July 2009; MAST personnel participated.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    There are no unexpected gaps in this data set.  All Earth observations
    received on the ground were processed and included in this data set.
 
    Horizontal striping through some images indicates missing data.  The
    image quality map extension identifies where pixels are missing.  If
    the second most-significant bit of a pixel in the image quality map is
    turned on, then data for the corresponding image pixel is missing.  For
    more information, refer to EPOXI SIS document.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
 
    Predicted observational geometry
    --------------------------------
      Some data products for the Earth observation on 28-29 May
      (2008/149-150) have geometry values based on predicted (estimated)
      pointing C-kernels found in the EPOXI SPICE archive.  Memory
      limitations on board the spacecraft caused some attitude information
      to be overwritten, and thus reconstructed (final and accurate)
      pointing data for part of this observing period were not generated
      nor available to the data pipeline .  However the EPOCh team
      provided a file of geometry from JPL Horizons that they used for
      analysis of the May Earth data.  See EPOCH_EARTH_GEOM_2008MAY.ASC
      located in the DOCUMENT/ directory of this data set.
 
 
    HRI Telescope Focus
    -------------------
      Images of stars acquired early during the Deep Impact mission in 2005
      indicated the HRI telescope was out of focus.  However, this focus
      problem does not significantly affect the HRII instrument.  For more
      details, please see the instrument calibration paper by Klaasen,
      et al. (2008) [KLAASENETAL2006].
 
 
    Displaying Images
    -----------------
      Flight software writes an image header over the first 100 bytes of
      quadrant A.  These image header pixels were included in the raw FITS
      images.  Since the values in these pixels vary dramatically, it is
      recommended that the values of the MINIMUM and MAXIMUM keywords in
      the data label (or the MINPVAL and MAXPVAL in the FITS header) be
      used to scale an image for display because these values exclude the
      header bytes as well as the reference rows and columns located around
      the edge of the spectral image.  For more information, see the
      quadrant nomenclature section of the Deep Impact instrument
      calibration document or the EPOXI SIS document.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

