<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dawn-a-vir-3-rdr-vis-ceres-spectra-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DAWN VIR CAL (RDR) CERES VISIBLE SPECTRA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:vir.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.1_ceres::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dawn-a-vir-3-rdr-vis-ceres-spectra-v1.0__browserp_dawn-a-vir-3-rdr-vis-ceres-spectra-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Ammannito, E., G. Filacchione, A. Coradini, F. Capaccioni, G. Piccioni, M.C. de
                   Sanctis, M. Dami, and A. Barbis, On-ground characterization of
                   Rosetta/VIRTIS-M. I. Spectral and geometrical calibrations, Rev. Sci. Instrum.,
                   Vol. 77, Iss. 9, p. 093109, doi:10.1063/1.2349308, 2006.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.AMMANNITOETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   De Sanctis, M. C., A. Coradini, E. Ammannito, G. Filacchione, M.T. Capria, S.
                   Fonte, G. Magni, A. Barbis, A. Bini, M. Dami, I. Ficai-Veltroni, and G. Preti,
                   VIR Team, The VIR Spectrometer, Space Sci Rev, doi:10.1007/s11214-010-9668-5,
                   2010.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DESANCTISETAL2010</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   De Sanctis, M.C., J.P. Combe, E. Ammannito, E. Palomba, A. Longobardo, T.B.
                   McCord, S. Marchi, F. Capaccioni, M.T. Capria, D.W. Mittlefehldt, C.M. Pieters,
                   J. Sunshine, F. Tosi, F. Zambon, F. Carraro, S. Fonte, A. Frigeri, G. Magni,
                   C.A. Raymond, C.T. Russell, D. Turrini, Detection of Widespread Hydrated
                   Materials on Vesta by the VIR Imaging Spectrometer on board the Dawn Mission,
                   Astrophys. J. Lett. 758 L36, doi:10.1088/2041-8205/721/2/L172, 2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DESANCTISETAL2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Filacchione, G., E. Ammannito, A. Coradini, F. Capaccioni, G. Piccioni, M.C. de
                   Sanctis, M. Dami, and A. Barbis, On-ground characterization of
                   Rosetta/VIRTIS-M. II. Spatial and radiometric calibrations, Rev. Sci. Instrum.,
                   Vol. 77, Iss. 10, p. 103106, doi:10.1063/1.2360786, 2006.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FILACCHIONEETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Melchiorri, R., G. Piccioni, A. Mazzoni, VIRTIS-M flight lamps, Rev. of Sci.
                   Instr., 74(8), 3796-3801, 2003.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MELCHIORRIETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DAWN-A-VIR-3-RDR-VIS-CERES-SPECTRA-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DAWN VIR CAL (RDR) CERES VISIBLE SPECTRA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2015-09-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2015-01-13T19:36:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-09-29T04:56:42Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>MARIA CRISTINA DE SANCTIS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            De Sanctis, M.C., M.T. Capria, M. Giardino, E. Ammannito, S.
            Fonte, DAWN VIR CAL (RDR) CERES VISIBLE SPECTRA V1.0,
            DAWN-A-VIR-3-RDR-VIS-CERES-SPECTRA-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2015.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Calibrated data from the VIR instrument visible channel on the
            DAWN spacecraft during the Ceres Encounter mission phases.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains the spectral radiance (W/(m**2*sr*micron))
            data from the Dawn VIR instrument visible channel for all Ceres
            encounter mission phases. The data cover the time period between
            2014-12-26 and 2016-06-01.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Required Reading
  ================
    The format of all VIR data are described in detail by the SIS document
    located in the /DOCUMENT directory. VIR team strongly recommends
    reading this documentation before using the data. In addition, there
    is a calibration procedure document that defines the data processing
    steps and the proper usage of the calibration files that are part of
    this data set.
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
       This data set contains the spectral radiance (W/(m**2*sr*micron))
       data from the Dawn VIR instrument visible channel for all Ceres
       encounter mission phases. The data cover the time period between
       2014-12-26 and 2016-06-30.
 
 
  VIR Ceres Observations
  ======================
    The following table contains a listing of VIR observations at Ceres.
 
    ------------------------------------------------------------------------
    Dawn Science Observations
    ------------------------------------------------------------------------
    Start    Mission Activity     Activity
    Date     Phase   Name         Description
    ========================================================================
    14-12-26 CSA    APPROACH     Ceres Science Approach Phase
    ------------------------------------------------------------------------
    15-01-13 CSA    OPNAV_001    Ride-along cubes to FC OpNav images
    15-01-25 CSA    OPNAV_002    Ride-along cubes to FC OpNav images
    15-02-04 CSA    OPNAV_003    Ride-along cubes to FC OpNav images
    15-02-12 CSA    RC1          Ride-along cubes to FC rotational
                                 characterization movie #1
    15-02-19 CSA    RC2          Ride-along cubes to FC rotational
                                 characterization movie #2
    15-02-25 CSA    OPNAV_004    Ride-along cubes to FC OpNav images
    15-03-01 CSA    OPNAV_005    Ride-along cubes to FC OpNav images
    15-04-10 CSA    OPNAV_006    Ride-along cubes to FC OpNav images
    15-04-15 CSA    OPNAV_007    Ride-along cubes to FC OpNav images
 
    ========================================================================
    15-04-24 CSR    RC3          Ceres Science Rotational Characterization 3
    ------------------------------------------------------------------------
    15-04-25 CSR    RC3          RC3 Equatorial Limb 001 (South) high phase
    15-04-30 CSR    RC3          RC3 Equatorial Limb 002 (North) high phase
    15-05-04 CSR    RC3n         RC3 North lit side
    15-05-05 CSR    RC3e         RC3 Equator lit side
    15-05-07 CSR    RC3s         RC3 South lit side
 
    ------------------------------------------------------------------------
    15-05-09 CTS    TRANSFER_    Ceres Transfer to Survey Phase
                    TO_Survey
    ------------------------------------------------------------------------
    15-05-16 CTS    OPNAV_008    Ride-along cubes to FC OpNav images
    15-05-22 CTS    OPNAV_009    Ride-along cubes to FC OpNav images
 
    ------------------------------------------------------------------------
    15-06-05 CSS    SURVEY       Ceres Science Survey Phase (range ~4850 km)
    ------------------------------------------------------------------------
    15-06-05 CSS    CYCLE1       Survey Cycle (orbit) 1
    15-06-08 CSS    CYCLE2       Survey Cycle (orbit) 2
    15-06-11 CSS    CYCLE3       Survey Cycle (orbit) 3
    15-06-14 CSS    CYCLE4       Data lost to instrument reset, all data lost
    15-06-17 CSS    CYCLE5       Survey Cycle (orbit) 5 VIS-Only
    15-06-21 CSS    CYCLE6       Survey Cycle (orbit) 6
    15-06-24 CSS    CYCLE7       Survey Cycle (orbit) 7 VIS-Only
    15-06-27 CSS    CYCLE8       Data lost to instrument reset, all data lost
 
    ------------------------------------------------------------------------
    15-07-01 CTH    TRANSFER_    Ceres Transfer to HAMO Phase
                    TO_HAMO
    ------------------------------------------------------------------------
                                 No science observation in this phase
 
    ------------------------------------------------------------------------
    15-08-18 CSH    HAMO         Ceres Science HAMO Phase (avg rng ~1950 km)
    ------------------------------------------------------------------------
    15-08-18 CSH    CYCLE1       12 orbits of pushbroom nadir imaging
    15-08-29 CSH    CYCLE2       12 orbits of pushbroom off-nadir imaging
    15-09-09 CSH    CYCLE3       12 orbits of pushbroom off-nadir IR-only
    15-09-20 CSH    CYCLE4       12 orbits of pushbroom off-nadir imaging
    15-10-01 CSH    CYCLE5       12 orbits of pushbroom near nadir IR-only
    15-10-12 CSH    CYCLE6       12 orbits of pushbroom off-nadir imaging
 
    ------------------------------------------------------------------------
    15-10-23 CTL    TRANSFER_    Ceres Transfer to LAMO Phase
                    TO_LAMO
    ------------------------------------------------------------------------
                                 No science observation in this phase
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The data in this data set are calibrated, CODMAC Level 3 data. The
    data processing includes spectral, geometric, flat-field, and
    radiometric calibration.  The details of how these calibrations were
    performed are described in the VIR_CALIBRATION document contained
    the DOCUMENT/CALIBRATION directory of this archive. This document
    describes how the calibration parameters were derived an gives a
    procedure for generating the calibrated data set from the raw EDR
    data set DAWN-A-VIR-2-EDR-VIS-CERES-SPECTRA-V1.0. Files containing
    the calibration parameters and referenced in the calibration
    procedure are located in the CALIB directory of this archive.
 
    After operations at the asteroid Vesta, the VIR team identified some
    artifacts in the instrument responsivity in the 2.5-3.5 micron region,
    which is where several absorption bands of OH and H2O occur. Those
    artifacts were systematic, and therefore they did not prevent the
    detection of relative spectral variations associated with OH and H2O.
    Actually, the only paper published [DESANCTISETAL2012] in which are
    discussed spectra in this range used a different calibration method
    described in the paper itself. This method used a simple correction of
    the response function based on an empirical calibration correction that
    is appropriate to recover the signal in that specific range. However,
    the absolute absorption band depth of OH and H2O could not be
    calculated. To compute a new instrument responsivity the team used the
    internal lamp of the spectrometer. This lamp, made of a tungsten
    filament, is characterized by a black body-like emission at about 2400K
    ([MELCHIORRIETAL2003]). Since the spectrum of the infrared radiation
    emitted by the tungsten filaments is featureless, a polystyrene filter
    was inserted for a wavelength calibration of the IR channel. The idea
    was to use the black body radiation of this lamp to retrieve a relative
    Instrument Responsivity in the 2.5-3.5 micron region. First the signal
    from the internal calibration lamp was calibrated with the on-ground
    responsivity, and the equivalent temperature of the radiation fitting a
    Planck curve was determined. The next step was to compute the Planck
    function at the equivalent temperature.
 
    The new Instrument Responsivity is the result of the ratio between the
    raw signal of the lamp and the Planck function. This ratio must be
    multiplied by a factor to take into account the integration time used to
    acquire the signal, the transmittance of the polystyrene filter, and the
    viewing geometry. The new instrument responsivity function minimizes
    most calibration residuals that were showing as artifact peaks between
    2.5 and 2.9 microns in the previous calibration. It now allows the use
    of VIR spectra to identify absorption bands of OH and H2O, without
    requiring additional empirical corrections. As calibration is always an
    ongoing process, the instrument team is looking forward to enable the
    interpretation of absolute absorption band depths, which is a required
    step for the calculation of surface material abundances.
 
    It is VIR team practice to consider the entire collection of
    calibration files as a single unit so the version number of every file
    was incremented to V2 even though only the IR responsivity file was
    updated.
 
  Data
  ====
    The data are in PDS format. A detailed description of the data format
    is given in the VIR SIS document located in the DOCUMENT directory of
    this data set.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    No ancillary data included in this data set.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
      The geometry items SC_SUN_POSITION_VECTOR,
      SC_TARGET_POSITION_VECTOR and SC_TARGET_VELOCITY_VECTOR
      provided in the label of the data product are relative to the
      Earth Mean Equator frame of J2000.
 
      SUB_SPACECRAFT_LATITUDE, SUB_SPACECRAFT_LONGITUDE are
      given in the PLANETOCENTRIC coordinate system. These parameters
      are corrected for planetary and stellar aberrations.
      Distances are given in km, angles in degrees.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    Data confidence is nominal, meaning that all data have been
    validated by the VIR team and found as expected. Any exceptions
    are noted by the DATA_QUALITY field in the label files.
 
    Following the loss of the 2nd reaction wheel during Vesta departure,
    Dawn had to rely on the RCS thrusters, rather than reaction wheels,
    to maintain pointing. While the Dawn system does not employ true
    dead-banding, the net result of the thruster firings is to introduce
    pointing offsets of up to +/- 0.64 degrees in +X and +Y, and rates of
    up to 0.01 degrees/second (or ~ 0.7 VIR pixels/second). The
    combination of long VIR integration times with large pointing and
    pointing rate errors complicates interpreting the data acquired as
    normal spectral cubes. When Dawn is near to Ceres, the timing of
    the thruster firings is moderately predicable with the most common
    attitude near one of the deadband limits. When Dawn is far from its
    selected target the thruster firing is more random and the impact of
    not being pointed at Ceres nadir is amplified. This is especially
    apparent in the VIR cubes since each frame of the cube effectively
    has its own pointing. During Approach and RC3, Ceres is highly
    distored in the raw data cubes and care must taken to properly
    correct the geometry when calibrating and interpretting these data.
 
  Review
  ======
    These are the same data files that were utilized by the Dawn Science
    Team. Any errors or deficiencies reported by the Science Team were
    corrected by the VIR team. Note, however, that the geometry information
    provided in the PDS labels was updated to reflect the IAU coordinate
    system updated to Dawn derived pole right ascension and declination
    values. A full PDS peer review was conducted of all products in this
    data set.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    Data coverage is good unless otherwise noted by the DATA_QUALITY
    keyword.
 
    VIR spectra are affected by residual systematic errors due to imperfect
    radiometric and spectral calibration that influence the quality of
    imaging spectrometer data.
 
    The data are affected by systematic deviations from spectrum of the
    target due to imperfect radiometric standards, by spectral
    miscalibration, and by systematic errors resulting from uncertainties in
    the solar reference spectrum. The spectral images can show &apos;stripes&apos; due
    to the slight deviation that exists between the input/output transfer
    function of each sample of the detector.  These stripes are particularly
    evident when the signal is very low. Visible channels with a wavelength
    &gt; 0.95 microns cannot be used for scientific analysis, because of the
    straylight effect which currently has no correction. By excluding these
    wavelengths from the spectrum, the offset between the visible and the
    infrared channels in the range where they meet disappear. In some
    sporadic cases where this offset can still be observed, the instrument
    team recommends scaling the IR channel to the VIS channel, having the
    latter a good agreement with the Framing Camera dataset.
 
    The instrument team is working to resolve some of the issues described
    here. The team plans to release, in the near future, a new level of
    derived data products that will partially solve the problems above
    reported. Regarding the misalignment of the VIR spectra with respect of
    the ground based spectra, the instrument team has released a correction
    factor that is designed to be applied to the VIR &apos;denoise&apos; (L-1C) dataset
    to obtain the agreement with the ground based spectra. The &apos;denoise&apos;
    data set is planned for future release.
 
    Dropouts that may be observed in some images are due to instrument
    saturation. The spectral range in which these dropouts occur varies
    depending upon exposure duration, target topography, and incidence
    angle.
 
    The spacecraft safed as it entered the RC3 mission phase. As a result,
    the cubes in the first rotation of the RC3 Equatorial Limb 001 (South)
    high phase observations were lost.
 
    The VIR instrument reset in Survey cycles 4 and 8 before any science
    data were discharged to spacecraft memory so these data were completely
    lost. Prior to and during the first few orbits of the Survey mission
    phase, the VIR cryocooler began showing signs of aging. As a result,
    Survey cycles 5 and 7 were acquired in VIS-only mode with the cryocooler
    turned off to preserve it for use during the HAMO mission phase.
 
    During the HAMO mission phase, the cryocooler set point was raised from
    75 deg Kelvin to 80 deg Kelvin to reduce the strain on the cooler. There
    is a slight decrease in the signal to noise ratio as a result of running
    the cooler at a warmer temperature. Cycles 3 and 5 of HAMO were acquired
    in IR-only mode in order to increase the number of IR frames that could
    be acquired. Orbit 6 of HAMO cycle 1 was also an IR-only orbit. After
    HAMO sequences were initially built and delivered to the Dawn project,
    the team decided to reduce the repetition time between frames in each
    cube. This reduced the size of the gaps between frames within cubes but
    increased the gaps between cubes.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    No limitations on these data
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

