<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mer1-mer2-m-imu-4-edl-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MER1/MER2 MARS IMU ENTRY DESCENT AND LANDING DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_exploration_rover::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mer1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mer2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:imu.mer1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:imu.mer2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer1-mer2-m-imu-4-edl-v1.0__browserp_mer1-mer2-m-imu-4-edl-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Crisp, J.A., M. Adler, J.R. Matijevic, S.W. Squyres, R.E. Arvidson, and D.M.
                   Kass, Mars Exploration Rover mission, J. Geophys. Res., 108(E12), 8061,
                   doi:10.1029/2002JE002038, 2003.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CRISPETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MER1/MER2-M-IMU-4-EDL-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MER1/MER2 MARS IMU ENTRY DESCENT AND LANDING DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2004-08-24</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-01-04T04:04:52.022Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2004-01-25T05:04:44.582Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID M. KASS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            D.M. Kass, J.T. Schofield, J. Crisp, E.S. Bailey, E.J. Konefat,
            W.J. Lee, E.C. Litty, R.M. Manning, A.M. San Martin, J.R. Willis,
            R.F. Beebe, J.R. Murphy and L.F. Huber,
            MER1/MER2-M-IMU-4-EDL-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Mars Exploration Rover 1 and 2 Inertial Measurement Unit Entry,
            Descent and Landing Data Records, Version 1.0
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>not applicable</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    TRANSFORMED data files consist of time ordered records of Inertial
    Measurement Unit (IMU) quaternion elements and accelerations for
    the Backshell IMU; and quaternion elements and integrated change in
    velocity for the Rover IMU measured during the Entry, Descent, and
    Landing phases of the MER1 (Opportunity) and MER2 (Spirit) landers.
    For these files, the quantities have been (via onboard spacecraft
    processing) spatially transformed to the center of mass of the
    entry vehicle prior to backshell:lander separation, and following
    separation to the backshell&apos;s center of mass (for the Backshell
    IMU) and the center of mass of the rover (for the Rover IMU).
 
    HIGHRATE data files consist of time ordered records of Inertial
    Measurement Unit (IMU) three-axis rotation rates and velocity
    changes for the Backshell IMU; and three-axis rotation rates and
    velocity changes for the Rover IMU measured during an approximately
    five minute subset of the approximately 30 minute Entry, Descent,
    and Landing phases of the MER1 (Opportunity) and MER2 (Spirit)
    missions.  These HIGHRATE rotation rates and velocity changes have
    not been spatially transformed.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The TRANSFORMED data files contain the following measurements:
    Spacecraft Clock Time: Units = seconds Rover IMU Quaternion
    Element 1: Units = N/A Rover IMU Quaternion Element 2: Units =
    N/A Rover IMU Quaternion Element 3: Units = N/A Rover IMU
    Quaternion Element 4: Units = N/A Backshell IMU Quaternion
    Element 1: Units = N/A Backshell IMU Quaternion Element 2: Units
    = N/A Backshell IMU Quaternion Element 3: Units = N/A Backehsll
    IMU Quaternion Element 4: Units = N/A Rover IMU Velocity Change
    X-Direction: Units = m/s Rover IMU Velocity Change Y-Direction:
    Units = m/s Rover IMU Velocity Change Z-Direction: Units = m/s
    Backshell IMU Acceleration X-Direction: Units = m/s**2 Backshell
    IMU Acceleration Y-Direction: Units = m/s**2 Backshell IMU
    Acceleration Z-Direction: Units = m/s**2
 
    The HIGHRATE data files contain the following measurements:
    Spacecraft Clock Time: Units = seconds Rover IMU X-Direction
    Rotation Rate: Units = radians/s Rover IMU Y-Direction Rotation
    Rate: Units = radians/s Rover IMU Z-Direction Rotation Rate:
    Units = radians/s Rover IMU X-Direction Velocity Change: Units =
    m/s Rover IMU Y-Direction Velocity Change: Units = m/s Rover IMU
    Z-Direction Velocity Change: Units = m/s Backshell IMU
    X-Direction Rotation Rate: Units = radians/s Backshell IMU
    Y-Direction Rotation Rate: Units = radians/s Backshell IMU
    Z-Direction Rotation Rate: Units = radians/s Backshell IMU
    X-Direction Velocity Change: Units = m/s Backshell IMU
    Y-Direction Velocity Change: Units = m/s Backshell IMU
    Z-Direction Velocity Change: Units = m/s
 
 
  Data
  ====
    Each of the two Mars Exploration Rover (MER) spacecraft had two
    Inertial Measurement Units (IMU) on board.  All four IMU were
    quality controlled Litton LN-200S units
    (http://www.ngnavsys.com/SiteMap/).  The four units were selected
    from a larger population for improved stability.  The IMU were on
    the spacecraft as engineering sensors, primarily to assist in
    Entry, Descent and Landing (EDL), but also to assist in surface
    mobility.  Thus the data were processed and collected for
    engineering uses and have a number of unusual features.
 
    The two IMU on each spacecraft were located in significantly
    different positions.  One was inside the rover (the rover IMU:
    RIMU) and thus inside the lander and one was attached to the
    backshell (backshell IMU: BIMU).  Note that neither IMU was
    particularly close to the entry capsule center of mass or spin
    axis.  The data from the RIMU were collected throughout EDL
    (although there are gaps where they were not trasmitted back to
    Earth, see below).  Just before bridle cut (right after the retro
    rockets begin firing and just before the bouncing begins), the
    BIMU is turned off since bridle cut &apos;discards&apos; the backshell (and
    BIMU).  See [CRISPETAL2003] for details on the spacecraft design
    and EDL timeline.
 
    The very high rate data produced directly by the LN-200S units
    were summed in firmware and sampled at 8 Hz.  In some cases the 8
    Hz data were then stored directly and eventually played back.
    This is the HIGHRATE dataset.  These data only cover a relatively
    short portion of the entire EDL process (since they were not of
    prime engineering interest).  These data have been processed to
    physical units.  This is due to the digital output of the IMU
    itself being essentially in physical units.  The DN values from
    the IMU were converted to physical values on the spacecraft in
    the process of summing to the 8 Hz sampling.  The ground
    depacketization then directly ended up with the physical units.
 
    The TRANSFORMED datasets contain data that were used by the
    on-board algorithms in realtime during the EDL process.  The
    on-board software converted the IMU output into physical units
    and then transformed them for use by the flight software.  All of
    the transformations were based on the nominal (not measured)
    properties of the spacecraft (and various components).  The
    accelerations were transformed to the center of mass (CM) and
    into the spacecraft coordinate system, changing the effective
    axes of the data.  Before the deployment of the lander, this is
    the CM of the entry capsule.  Afterwards, the BIMU measurements
    were transformed to the CM of the backshell and the rover IMU
    measurements to the CM of the lander.  Secondly, the RIMU data in
    each axis were accumulated in a register to give accumulated
    delta-V since the start of the entry.  The gyroscope data were
    used to compute a quaternion for the orientation of the
    spacecraft component relative to J2000.  Like the acceleration
    data, this was done for the entire capsule before lander
    deployment for both IMU; and then for the backshell with the BIMU
    data, and lander for the RIMU data.  The quaternions calculated
    onboard the spacecraft were positive normalized.  Thus, the
    fourth element is redundant and was not transmitted back to
    Earth.  During depacketization, the fourth element was
    recalculated: e4 = sqrt(1 - e1*e1 + e2*e2 + e3*e3) where e1..e4
    are the four elements of the quaternion.  This calculation
    produced &apos;complete&apos; quaternions so they are easier to use.  This
    calculation was performed for all the quaternions and results in
    the fourth element being set to unity when there are no data
    (since the other three elements are then zero).
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The processing was done on the spacecraft for every one of the 8
    Hz samples.  But, due to limitations on the spacecraft memory,
    only some of the samples were stored and these samples were not
    co-added before being stored.  The frequency of the saved data
    depended on the phase of the entry process (these range from 0.05
    Hz to 4 Hz, see the actual datasets for the various sampling
    rates).  In addition to being stored on board, some of the
    TRANSFORMED data were sent to MGS (Mars Global Surveyor) during
    the EDL process over the UHF link.  This also continued for a
    short period after landing.  Some of the data sent directly to
    MGS were also stored on board and some were not stored (also,
    some of the stored data were not sent over the UHF link).  Due to
    the motions of the lander, the UHF link to MGS was somewhat
    intermittent and parts of the data sent were lost (there is also
    a regular data loss due to the realtime nature of the data
    transmission).  This is the cause of the various gaps, holes and
    irregular spacing of the samples.  The data returned during EDL
    and the stored data sent back later are complementary in many
    cases (in particular, for MER2 the two streams are both at 4 Hz
    but on alternating 8 Hz timesteps, resulting in an effective 8 Hz
    record--minus the lost data over the UHF link).  Data from the
    two paths have been merged together in the archived datasets.
    This was done during the telemetry processing, before being
    delivered for calibration.  The data from the two sources are
    identical when they overlap (since they are essentially the same
    data played back twice by different communication paths), and so
    this was only a removal of duplicate records (and sorting by
    time, but the order of the returned packets was not chronological
    in any case).
 
    One other correction was made to the data during telemetry
    processing.  Timesteps without any IMU data were removed (these
    were usually caused by events that caused a momentary loss of the
    UHF link).  There were some timesteps for which only a subset of
    the IMU data (usually the quaternion element values) were
    transmitted.  In these instances, the file record includes the
    transmitted values, but the non-transmitted values for these
    records have been set to a value of zero.  Note that zero is a
    legal value for an IMU measurement.  These instances of
    incomplete IMU data transmission are identified by the occurrence
    of all six accelerometer values (three RIMU and three BIMU)
    having the value of zero, or all six rotation rate values in the
    HIGHRATE files, or eight quaternion element values in the
    TRANSFORMED files, having the value of zero.
 
    The accumulated delta-V values for the RIMU were reset to 0 by
    the flight software while those data were used during EDL (the
    cause is known and the timing of the resets is known due to the
    spacecraft events they are associated with).  This is the cause
    of the sudden jump in the RIMU data where they go to zero in all
    three axes and then start accumulating once again.
 
    The data presented are those transmitted from the spacecraft.
    Since processing was done onboard the spacecraft (since these
    data were used in real-time by the onboard software to provide
    control and critical event triggering during EDL), the &apos;raw&apos; DN
    values were not stored on the spacecraft.  Rather, the values
    used by the on-board software (acceleration, accumulated velocity
    changes, rotation rates) are the values that were transmitted and
    are available for this archive.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
   The complete 8 Hz data collected and utilized during EDL are not
   available within this archive. Data transmission dropouts between
   each rover and MGS have resulted in several short gaps within the
   data.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

