<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.sdu-c-dynsci-2-wild2-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>STARDUST WILD 2 ENCOUNTER DYNAMIC SCIENCE EXPERIMENT DATA</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.stardust::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.sdu::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:dynsci.sdu::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.81p-wild_2_1978_a2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.sdu-c-dynsci-2-wild2-v1.0__browserp_sdu-c-dynsci-2-wild2-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>SDU-C-DYNSCI-2-WILD2-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>STARDUST WILD 2 ENCOUNTER DYNAMIC SCIENCE EXPERIMENT DATA</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2004-09-30</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-01-02T17:58:57.305Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2004-01-02T20:58:55.142Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STARDUST DATA MANAGEMENT AND ARCHIVE TEAM</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Semenov, B.V., A.R. Cheuvront, K.V. Gilliland, and C.H. Acton,
            STARDUST WILD 2 ENCOUNTER DYNAMIC SCIENCE EXPERIMENT DATA,
            SDU-C-DYNSCI-2-WILD2-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Spacecraft attitude and thruster firing data that comprise the
            Dynamic Science Experiment conducted during the Stardust
            encounter with comet Wild 2.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains data from the Dynamic Science Experiment
            conducted during the Stardust encounter with comet Wild 2 on
            January 2, 2004. The data in this archive are organized into two
            tables in standard PDS format. The first of these tables provides
            high rate attitude control system (ACS) data spanning 40 minutes
            around closest approach while the second table provides attitude
            control thruster firing information (aka ``small
            forces&apos;&apos;) spanning 3 hours around closest approach.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview:
    =================
      This archive contains data from the Dynamic Science Experiment
      conducted during the Stardust spacecraft encounter with comet
      Wild 2 on January 2, 2004. The data in this archive are organized
      into two tables in standard PDS format. The first of these tables
      provides high rate attitude control system (ACS) data spanning 40
      minutes around closest approach while the second table provides
      attitude control thruster firing information (aka ``small
      forces&apos;&apos;) spanning 3 hours around closest approach. This data
      provides a significant measure of the spacecraft&apos;s performance
      and the attitude control system&apos;s reaction to particle impacts.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      The primary parameters contained in the attitude data table are
      quaternions providing spacecraft orientation relative to the EME
      2000 inertial reference frame (also known as the J2000 frame),
      spacecraft angular rates given in the spacecraft-fixed reference
      frame, and attitude and angular rate errors. The primary
      parameters contained in the small forces data table are thruster
      firing period begin and end times, accumulated delta-V values and
      numbers and duration of firings for each of the thrusters.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The source data for both tables were generated on-board the
      spacecraft and were sent down within packets in the spacecraft
      telemetry stream.
 
      On the ground the attitude parameters were extracted into a text
      file containing data in tabular format using standard JPL
      Advanced Multimission Operations System (AMMOS) tools for
      channelized telemetry access. This text file was then slightly
      modified -- commas delimiting columns were inserted, UTC time
      tags were re-formatted to be in ISO format, and string column
      values were quoted -- to fully comply with PDS requirements.
 
      The small forces parameters were similarly extracted from
      telemetry and then saved in a Small Forces File (SFF) using the
      MAKSFF process developed and run by NAIF. For inclusion into this
      archive the SFF file, which was a variable length line ASCII text
      file containing a table with a fixed number of columns, was
      augmented with two more columns (begin and end time as UTC) and
      re-formatted similarly to the attitude data to comply with PDS
      requirements.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      Both data files in this archive are plain ASCII text files, each
      containing a single PDS-style table with fixed-width,
      comma-delimited columns. Each file contains a few-line text
      header preceding the data. In the attitude data file the header
      lines list telemetry channel IDs, names, channel data types, and
      formats. The small forces data file header lines provide the
      original SFF file header. Each of the two data files is
      accompanied by a detached PDS label, described in detail in the
      ONLABELS.TXT document included in the archive. The format of the
      table columns is defined by an external table format file,
      pointed to by the label.
 
      Attitude Data
      -------------
        The channelized attitude telemetry produced by the ACS was
        collected at different rates during encounter. The data before
        and after closest approach was recorded at 2-second intervals.
        For the closest approach, which occurred at 2 January 2004
        19:21:32 UTC, from 19:09:29 through 19:36:28 UTC most of
        attitude data was recorded at 0.1-second intervals. One
        exception is the body rate error data, which was still recorded
        at 2-second intervals and, therefore, appears to be ``stuck&apos;&apos;
        at one value while all other parameters are changing.
 
        The ACS_MODE channel included in the attitude data file
        describes whether the ACS was controlling attitude according to
        the ground-commanded reference attitude (ENCOUNTER ABSOLUTE
        pointing mode, or ENC_ABS), or to the flight software-updated
        trajectory (ENCOUNTER RELATIVE pointing mode, or ENC_REL).
        Before and after the roll slews, the ACS_MODE was ENC_ABS. When
        the roll was commanded, the mode changed to ENC_REL. After
        closest approach, the return roll was commanded and the mode
        changed to ENC_ABS. For about 30 seconds after these command
        mode changes, the rate and attitude data reflects the slews. At
        all other times it reflects the attitude close to the fixed
        attitude that the controller was trying to maintain.
 
        Body rates provided in the attitude file are filtered Inertial
        Measurement Unit (IMU) data, and attitude errors are computed
        from the estimated spacecraft quaternion compared to the
        reference quaternion. Since the controller was maintaining a
        fixed attitude (except during the slews) the body rate is the
        same magnitude but with opposite sign of the rate error. The
        measurement noise of about 0.00002 rad/sec is clearly seen in
        the rate data during the whole period covered by the file.
 
      Small Forces Data
      -----------------
        The flight software included an idealized thruster model, and
        was configured to produce data summarizing a 1-second interval
        of thruster activity and the resulting change in spacecraft
        velocity. Although the control system ran at 10Hz, the 1-second
        small forces data collection interval was chosen as a
        compromise between providing every pulse detail with the risk
        of overwriting the data, and not providing enough resolution
        for analysis.
 
        The small forces data included the time the packet was
        recorded, the number of commanded thruster pulses for each
        thruster, the total on-time for each thruster in milliseconds,
        and the computed delta-V in the inertial EME-2000 reference
        frame. This data was collected only when necessary; that is, if
        no thruster commands occurred over an interval, no small forces
        data were generated. The average spacecraft attitude quaternion
        for the interval was also included in the packet.
 
        A set of thruster calibration activities undertaken by the
        navigation and spacecraft teams over the course of the mission
        showed that the timing of the deltaV values computed by the
        spacecraft was very accurate while the deltaV magnitude was
        within +/- 30 percent of the values estimated from ground
        tracking data.
 
      Using Attitude and Small Forces Data Together
      ---------------------------------------------
        Individual thruster firing records from the small forces file
        may be correlated to the attitude data by looking for a fast
        change in the spacecraft rate immediately following the firing
        and slower change in the spacecraft orientation for the period
        from this truster firing to the next one. Firing of a
        particular thruster or a set of thrusters usually results in
        change in a particular rate component. Therefore identifying
        the thruster(s) that fired in addition to the time of firing is
        essential. Also, the frequency at which the thrusters were
        firing at different times during the encounter along with the
        information about which of the thrusters were firing may
        indicate how much ``effort&apos;&apos; the ACS was spending to compensate
        for the effect of the surrounding dust environment while trying
        to maintain the commanded attitude.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      Since neither of the two data files provided in this data set was
      supplemented with additional geometry data prior to archiving,
      the following SPICE kernels archived in the Stardust SPICE data
      set, SDU-C-SPICE-6-V1.0, may be used for computing any derived
      geometry parameters that might be needed to analyze the data:
 
        Kernel Type   File Name
        ------------  ------------------------
        LSK           naif0007.tls
        SCLK          sdu_sclkscet_00105.tsc
        FK            sdu_v17.tf
        SPKs          sdu_l_2003_w2.bsp
                      sdu_w2_opnav.bsp
        ------------  ------------------------
 
      The spacecraft orientation data -- both quaternions and angular
      rates -- provided in the attitude and small forces data files
      were used in making, and are available in, the following SPICE CK
      files provided in the Stardust SPICE data set, SDU-C-SPICE-6-V1.0:
 
        Kernel Type   File Name
        ------------  ------------------------
        CKs           sdu_sc_rec_2003_w2_v2.bc
                      sdu_sc_rec_w2_opnav.bc
        ------------  ------------------------
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      The two reference frames, with respect to which the data included
      in this archive are provided, are:
 
        - Earth Mean Equator and Equinox vector of 2000 JAN
          01 12:00 (EME J2000), and
 
        - Stardust spacecraft reference frame shown in this diagram:
 
                                                   || Dust Collector
                         Main                      ||     Array
          Solar Array   Shield                     ||
            Shield        .-.         o HGA        ||
            .-.       +Z ^| |   ._____|_____.      o
            | |==========|====o==\=========/==o===============
            `-&apos;          || |-------------------. .        Solar
                         || |                   |/|        Array
                         || | .-----.  CIDA     | |
                 &lt;-------o| | |      &apos;          | |  Return
               +X      +Y | | .   __/           | | Capsule
                          | |  `. `.            |\|
                          | |--- `. `.---- -----&apos; o---------
                          | |      `. `.           \_______/
                          `-&apos;        `.&apos;`.
                                        .&apos;
 
 
      The orientation quaternions stored in both tables provide
      orientation of the Stardust spacecraft reference frame relative
      to the EME J2000 reference frame. These quaternions are of the
      popular engineering style:  Q = {r1*sin(phi/2), r2*sin(phi/2),
      r3*sin(phi/2), cos(phi/2)}, where R = (r1, r2, r3) is a unit
      vector specifying the rotation axis defined in the base frame.
      (This is not the formation style used within the SPICE system.) A
      rotation matrix formed from such a quaternion, when left
      multiplied by some vector given in the base frame, will rotate
      that vector into the target frame: rt = RM*rb. For help in
      understanding quaternion syntax and use refer to the discussion
      on quaternions provided in the PDS Standards Reference, also
      available from the NAIF node document database as ``A Brief
      Discussion of Quaternions as Used in Space Remote Sensing.&apos;&apos;
 
      The delta V components provided in the small forces data file are
      given with respect to the EME J2000 reference frame.
 
      The angular rates and attitude and rate errors provided in the
      attitude data file are given with respect to the Stardust
      spacecraft reference frame.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      The data in this data set are in standard PDS format and,
      therefore, can be displayed by a number of PDS-provided tools or
      loaded into commercial programs that support comma-delimited
      formats. For this reason no special processing software is
      included in this data set.
 
 
    Contact Information
    ===================
      For any questions regarding the data in this archive, contact:
 
        Dr. John D. Anderson, Stardust Radio Science and Dynamic
        Science Experiment Lead
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      Overall flawless Stardust spacecraft ACS performance during the
      Wild 2 encounter, internal consistency of the data, and
      independent confirmation of correctness of the attitude and and
      small forces data by processing of the tracking and images over
      the course of the mission give a high level of confidence in
      accuracy of this data.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This data was reviewed by the Dynamic Science Experiment team
      members as part of the post-encounter data analysis activities.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      This set includes all high rate ACS data produced by the
      spacecraft during the closest approach period of the Wild 2
      encounter. No known gaps exist in the coverage provided by the
      data products.
 
      Only complete packets, the integrity of which was verified by the
      standard JPL AMMOS telemetry tools using embedded checksums, were
      used to generate the data products provided in this data set.
      Consistency of the data was verified by cross-checking between
      the attitude and small forces data products and between the
      actual data products and the nominal encounter attitude profile.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      None.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

