<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.near-a-5-collected-models-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>NEAR COLLECTED TARGET MODELS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.near_earth_asteroid_rendezvous::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.near::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:msi.near::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.eros::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.mathilde::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.near-a-5-collected-models-v1.0__browserp_near-a-5-collected-models-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Davies, M.J., V.K. Abalakin, M. Bursa, J.H. Lieske, B. Morando, D.
                   Morrison, P.K. Seidelmann, A.T. Sinclair, B. Yallop, and Y.S. Tjuflin,
                   Report of the IAU/IAG/COSPAR Working Group on Cartographic Coordinates and
                   Rotational Elements of the Planets and Satellites: 1994, Celestial
                   Mechanics and Dynamical Astronomy, 63, 127-148, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DAVIESETAL1996A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kaula, W.M., Theory of Satellite Geodesy, Blaisdell, Waltham, MA, 1966.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KAULA1966</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Konopliv, A.S., J.K. Miller, W.M. Owen, D.K. Yeomans, J.D. Giorgini, R.
                   Garmier, J.-P. Barriot, &apos;A Global Solution for the Gravity Field, Rotation,
                   Landmarks, and Ephemeris of Eros,&apos; 16th International Symposium on Space
                   Dynamics, Pasadena, CA, USA, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KONOPLIVETAL2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Miller, J.K., A.S. Konopliv, P.G. Antreasian, J.J. Bordi, S. Chesley, C.E.
                   Helfrich, W.M. Owen, D.J. Scheeres, T.C. Wang, B.G. Williams, and D.K. Yeomans,
                   Determination of Shape, Gravity, and Rotational State of Asteroid 433 Eros,
                   Icarus, in press, 2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MILLERETAL2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Neumann, G.A., F.G. Lemoine, D.D. Rowlands, D.E. Smith, and M.T. Zuber,
                   Crossover Analysis of Mars Orbiter Laser Altimeter Data, J. Geophys. Res., Vol.
                   106, pp. 23753-23768, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NEUMANNETAL2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Thomas, P.C., J. Veverka, J.F. Bell, B.E. Clark, B. Carcich, J. Joseph, M.
                   Robinson, L.A. McFadden, M.C. Malin, C.R. Chapman, W. Merline, and S.
                   Murchie, Mathilde: Size Shape and Gravity, Icarus, 140, 17-27, 1999.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.THOMASETAL1999</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Thomas, P.C., J. Joseph, B. Carcich, J. Veverka, B.E. Clark, J.F. Bell III, M.
                   Robinson, S. Murchie, L. Prockter, A. Cheng, N. Izenberg, M. Malin, C. Chapman,
                   L.A. McFadden, R. Kirk, M. Gaffey, and P.G. Lucey, Eros: Shape, Topography, and
                   Slope Processes, Icarus, Vol. 155, pp. 18-37, 2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.THOMASETAL2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>NEAR-A-5-COLLECTED-MODELS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>NEAR COLLECTED TARGET MODELS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2002-04-19</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1997-06-25T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2002-02-12T19:42:43Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>SMALL BODIES NODE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Raugh, A., NEAR COLLECTED TARGET MODELS V1.0,
            NEAR-A-5-COLLECTED-MODELS-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2002.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Collected shape and gravity models and related data for the NEAR
            targets 433 Eros and 253 Mathilde.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Collected shape and gravity models and related data for the NEAR
            targets 433 Eros and 253 Mathilde.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
      Several instrument teams from the Near Earth Asteroid Rendezvous
      (NEAR) mission derived models of the main mission target, 433
      Eros. In addition, the Multi-Spectral Imager team also derived
      a shape model of the secondary target 253 Mathilde. These models
      and their associated data and descriptions have been collected
      into this data set for ease of distribution.
 
      The models are divided into groups based on the source of the
      files:
 
        MSI - Produced by the MSI team
        ---
        - Numerical shape model and mosaic shape map of 253 Mathilde
        - Plate models of 433 Eros in 6 resolutions
        - A plate model of Eros in the Thomas RGST format
 
        NAV - Produced by the Navigation team from NLR data
        ---
        - Spherical harmonic coefficients for shape and gravity of Eros
        - Triangular plate model of Eros from NLR measurements
 
        NLR - Produced by the NLR team
        ---
        - Global numerical shape model of Eros
        - Shape map of Eros
        - NLR coverage map
        - Spherical harmonic shape model of Eros
 
        RSS - Produced by the Radio Science Subsystem, using combined
        ---   NLR and radar tracking data
        - Gravity map of Eros
        - Maps of the Bouguer anomaly of Eros in 3 increasing orders
        - Two spherical harmonic models of Eros with covariance matrices
        - Landmark files for Eros
 
 
      Modification History
      ====================
      These data were culled from the version 1.0 NEAR archive. The
      data set descriptions from that delivery were converted to
      document files to accompany this data set. Data labels were
      updated:
 
       1. Information and references that became available in the
          months following the original archive delivery have been
          added. In some cases reference publication years have been
          changed.
       2. Extrema have been found and added to data product labels
          where they seemed useful.
       3. DATA_SET_ID, PRODUCT_ID, PRODUCT_NAME and related fields
          have been changed to reflect the new data set being created.
 
      In many cases file names have been changed to something shorter
      and more mnemonic.
 
      The original spherical harmonic model files all contained
      degenerate tables listing parameters relevant to the model.
      These lines have been removed from the data file and the
      parameters included in the description at the top of the
      labels.
 
      The following additional changes were made to specific data file
      labels included in this collection:
 
       MSI Shape Models - Eros
       -----------------------
       o The FILE_RECORDS value, which was incorrect in all but two
         cases, was corrected.
 
       MSI Shape Models - Mathilde
       ---------------------------
       o Existing files were extracted from the Thomas optical shape
         models already in the SBN archives.
 
       NLR Shape and Gravity models
       ----------------------------
       o The NLR125AR.IMG file was converted to two FITS files:
 
          1. A signed 2-byte integer version; and
          2. An IEEE-real floating-point version.
 
         In both cases the scaling factor and offset from the original
         label was applied to the data. For the integer file, the result
         was rounded to the nearest integer. Minimal FITS headers were
         created in both cases, and the PDS labels modified accordingly.
         [Name in this data set: NLR/SHAPEMAP*.FIT]
 
       o The structure included in the NLRT180A.LBL file seemed to bear
         only a slight resemblance to the actual structure of the data
         (wrong record size, wrong number of columns, wrong field sizes,
         etc.).  The following changes were made to the data (and
         reflected in the label):
 
         + All records were trimmed to a fixed length (48 bytes).
         + Embedded blanks were removed from the first record to fit it
           into the 48-byte length.
         + Blank coefficient fields were filled with the equivalent
           representation of zero.
         + All &apos;D&apos; exponentiation operators in the data file were
           changed to &apos;E&apos;.
         [NLR/SHCOEFF.TAB]
 
       o The JGE15A01 (ASCII and binary) files were reformatted to
         follow the style used in the NLR spherical harmonic files.
         Specifically:
 
         + The SHA coefficients file was reformatted to remove trailing
           zeros and field delimiters. The constants in the header line
           were moved into the label.
         + The SHB (binary) covariance file was converted to ASCII,
           output using the same record format and sorted into the same
           order as the other covariance file.
         [RSS/N15ACOEFF.TAB and RSS/N15ACOVAR.TAB]
 
 
       Navigation Team Shape and Gravity Models
       ----------------------------------------
       (Produced by the navigation team from NLR data)
 
       o The files containing the spherical harmonic coefficients for
         the gravity and shape models were converted from the internal
         format submitted to flat tables more conducive to PDS handling.
         No data were changed, added or omitted.
 
       o The plate model originally included as part of the shape model
         file (with the spherical harmonic solution) was pulled out into
         a separate file.
 
       o The triangular plate shape model was reformatted slightly to
         match the format used in other radar shape models already
         archived at the SBN.  The principal change consisted of adding
         flags in the first column of each record to indicate which
         records defined vertices and which facets.
 
 
       Radio Science Team Shape and Gravity Models
       -------------------------------------------
       o The Bouguer gravity maps were converted to FITS files and the
         labels modified accordingly.
 
       o The gravity map file was also converted to a FITS file.
 
       o The landmarks file was reformatted to collect the position and
         uncertainty vector for each landmark into a single record. The
         label was re-written accordingly.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      Confidence Level Overview
      =========================
      Consult the documentation for caveats concerning individual
      models.
 
      Review
      ======
      This collection will undergo external review in May 2002.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>GD-11F</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

