<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mro-m-hirise-5-dtm-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MRO MARS HIGH RESOLUTION IMAGING SCIENCE EXPERIMENT DTM V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:hirise.mro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-hirise-5-dtm-v1.0__browserp_mro-m-hirise-5-dtm-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-hirise-5-dtm-v1.0__browser_geo_mars_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-hirise-5-dtm-v1.0__dvo_imaging_mro-m-hirise-5-dtm-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Eliason, E., Software Interface Specification for HiRISE Reduced Data Record
                   Products, Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter, JPL Document Number D-32006,
                   MRO-M-HIRISE-3-RDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2006.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ELIASON2006A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Eliason, E., HiRISE EDR &amp; RDR Archive Volumes Software Interface Specification,
                   JPL Document Number D-32005, NASA Planetary Data System, 2006.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ELIASON2006B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Ultrahigh resolution topographic mapping of Mars with MRO HiRISE stereo images:
                   Meter-scale slopes of candidate Phoenix landing sites, J. Geophys. Res. 2008.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KIRKETAL2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MRO-M-HIRISE-5-DTM-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MRO MARS HIGH RESOLUTION IMAGING SCIENCE EXPERIMENT DTM V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2009-12-08</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2009-12-09T15:16:33.333Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>ALFRED MCEWEN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            McEwen, A., Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter High Resolution Imaging
            Science Experiment, Digital Terrain Model,
            MRO-M-HIRISE-5-DTM-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2009.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Derived, Digital Terrain Model, geometrically-mapped elevation
            and orthoimages for HiRISE (High Resolution Imaging Science
            Experiment).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset includes derived Digital Terrain Models and their
            corresponding orthoimages from the HiRISE instrument on MRO.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The High Resolution Imaging Science Experiment (HiRISE) is one of
    the remote sensing instruments on the Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter
    (MRO) spacecraft that acquires orbital observations of the Martian
    surface during a two earth-year primary mapping phase.  MRO,
    successfully launched in August 2005, arrived at Mars in March
    2006.  Following orbit insertion the spacecraft went into an
    aerobraking period to achieve a 250 x 315 kilometer near-polar
    orbit suitable for the Primary Science Phase (PSP) mapping that
    started in November 2006. Since the start of PSP HiRISE has been
    continuously operating acquiring 10-20 observations per day.
 
    The HiRISE team is responsible for maintaining an updated dataset
    of the best version of its science data until meaningful
    changes in data calibration no longer occur and to release data in
    an appropriate manner for public access including their final
    deposition to NASA&apos;s Planetary Data System (PDS). In carrying out
    these responsibilities, the HiRISE team creates two types of
    standard data products:  1) Experiment Data Record (EDR) products
    and 2) Reduced Data Record (RDR) Products. An additional, derived product
    is produced from HiRISE stereo image pairs: 3) Digital Terrain Model (DTM)
    Products. This document describes the DTM standard products.
 
    The Digital Terrain Model (DTM) product is an image file that represent
    elevations for an area imaged in stereo by HiRISE. The source images are
    orthorectified using the DTM to produce orthoimages. Both the DTM and the
    orthoimages are resampled to a standard map projection They are formatted
    and organized according to the standards of the PDS. The DTM is stored as
    a standard PDS IMAGE object with an attached label. The orthoimages are
    stored in the JPEG2000 format accepted by the PDS. The JPEG2000 images are
    accompanied by a PDS detached label providing supporting information about
    the observation.
 
    The HiRISE DTM products comply with the PDS standards for file formats and
    labels, specifically using the PDS image object definition. The DTM image
    object uses &apos;IMG&apos; as its filename extension. The PDS label is embedded
    within the DTM image object. The DTM orthoimage files, formatted according
    to the JPEG2000 standard, use &apos;JP2&apos; as their filename extension. They are
    accompanied by PDS labels; files that have the same name as the image data
    file but use &apos;LBL&apos; for their filename extension. The label files provides
    image data characterization and science metadata information about the
    observation. Additionally, the ancillary data files that accompany the DTM
    products and the archive volume structure are in conformance with PDS
    standards.
 
    DTM orthoimage data are stored in the JPEG2000 ISO/IEC Part 1 standard
    format (http://www.jpeg.org/jpeg2000/), which was accepted by the
    PDS standard in October 2005. The JPEG2000 standard offers
    benefits distinctly advantageous for storage and access to very
    large images. With HiRISE RDR products reaching sizes exceeding
    30,000 x 70,000 pixels the use of JPEG2000 was recognized as a
    suitable solution for the storage and distribution of these data
    products. Advantages include excellent compression performance,
    multiple resolution levels from a single image data set,
    progressive decompression quality layers, lossless and lossy
    compression (HiRISE RDR products use lossless compression per the
    PDS Standard), pixel datum precision up to 38 bits, multiple image
    components (or bands), and selective image area access. These
    features are achieved by the use of a sophisticated image coding
    system based on discrete wavelet transforms (DWT) combined with
    other coding techniques to generate a JPEG2000 codestream that can
    be rendered to image pixel rasters using
    inverse transform algorithms.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The processing involved in a HiRISE DTM and associated orthoimages
    is partially automated, but still involves a great deal of manual
    input. For this reason, it cannot be pipelined as the other
    HiRISE products are. HiRISE DTMs are being produced at several
    institutions including HiROC, USGS Flagstaff, NASA Ames and JPL,
    using the prodedures described here.
 
    The image data that are the starting points for DTM production are the
    radiometrically and geometrically calibrated individual RED CCDs. They
    have gone through the normal HiRISE image processing pipeline up to the
    HiStitch pipeline, as described in RDR_DS.CAT. Generally, the color CCDs
    are not used for DTM production. The RED CCDs are reprojected into ideal
    camera space using the ISIS3 (http://isis.astrogeology.usgs.gov/) program
    noproj. After noproj the individual CCDs are mosaicked together and then
    converted to 8-bit raw format. The 8-bit raw images are then imported into
    the commercial software package Socet Set (copyright) by BAE, Inc. to
    create the DTM. SPICE information for the RED5 CCD is gathered to provide
    pointing information for the image to be imported into Socet Set
    (copyright).  The stereo pair is then triangulated and controlled to MOLA
    elevation values, when possible. MOLA tracks are used as the reference
    points for elevation and horizontal alignment. At equatorial latitudes,
    sometimes the MOLA tracks do not completely span the HiRISE image
    footprint. In polar regions, although the MOLA tracks are more densely
    spaced, seasonal changes in snow/frost coverage create variability on the
    scale of a few meters. In both of these cases the producer uses their best
    judgement to tie the HiRISE DTM to the MOLA tracks. Terrain extraction is
    performed in Socet Set (copyright) using their proprietary algorithms.
    After the terrain model is produced, it is examined for obvious blunders
    and artifacts. These are edited to the extent required by the project, but
    within reasonable time constraints.
 
    Socet Set (copyright) is used to create the orthoimages for each image in
    the stereo pair. Orthoimages are produced at two resolutions. The first is
    the full resolution of the original imagery (e.g. 0.25 m for bin1 images).
    The second is produced at the same GSD as the DTM. A typical HiRISE DTM
    produced from two bin1 images can have a GSD (or post spacing) of 1m.
    During the project pre-processing, the stretch parameters to convert from
    the native 16-bit to 8-bit format are preserved. These parameters are
    documented in the label as SCALE and OFFSET should the end user wish to
    restore the full dynamic range of the original image to the derived
    orthoimage.
 
    The DTM and orthoimages are exported from Socet Set (copyright) to the
    ISIS3 cube format in order to populate the labels with correct scaling and
    mapping values for subsequent PDS format conversion and label generation.
    These products are map projected using the same mapping definitions as the
    standard HiRISE RDR products.
 
    Additionally DTM and orthoimage product browse, annotated browse,
    and thumbnail jpeg images are created for HiRISE and PDS Imaging
    Node web-based distribution services.
 
  Data
  ====
    Radiometrically and geometrically corrected RED band products are
    the input source to DTM processing. Two HiRISE images are used,
    comprising a stereo pair. Stereo imaging is accomplished by rolling
    the spacecraft off-nadir. The first stereo image acquired typically is
    a small off-nadir roll. The second stereo image is usually the larger
    off-nadir roll. Elevations are derived from a priori knowledge of
    the observation geometry and the degree of cross-track parallax
    between the two stereo images. Stereo image targeting includes
    consideration of shadow length and direction, incidence and phase
    angle. The ideal stereo pair for DTM creation is acquired under
    similar lighting conditions and with a stereo convergence angle
    of 15 to 25 degrees.
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    Generation of the DTM products relies on the MRO-project deliveries
    for the Spacecraft Ephemeris (SPK kernels) and MRO spacecraft pointing
    files (CK kernels)
 
  Coordinate System &amp; Cartographic Standards
  ==========================================
    The HiRISE DTM products are compatible with the cartographic standards
    and mapping conventions used by the HiRISE RDR and MRO CRISM map products.
    When spatially registering map products produced by the two instrument
    teams only a translation and scale change are required.  The
    coordinate system used is planetocentric latitude and east positive
    longitude direction. The planetocentric latitude is the angle from the
    equator to a point on the surface of an oblate planet. The longitude
    increases from west to east (left to right).
    The planetary constants used in the camera model to produce the HiRISE
    RDR products are obtained from the NAIF SPICE planetary constants
    kernel pck0008.tpc.  The Mars constants of particular importance are
    the right ascension and declination of the pole, the prime meridian,
    rotation rate, and radii.  The constants used are:
    BODY499_POLE_RA          = (  317.68143   -0.1061      0.  )
    BODY499_POLE_DEC         = (   52.88650   -0.0609      0.  )
    BODY499_PM               = (  176.630    350.89198226  0.  )
    BODY499_RADII            = ( 3396.19    3396.19     3376.20 )
 
    Additionally, the SPICE kernel de405.bsp was used for the ephemeris
    data for Mars.
 
    Two map projections are used in the HiRISE DTM products:
    Equirectangular and Polar Stereographic.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
 
    Known problems are TBD.
 
  Review
  =====
    This archival data set has been examined by a peer review panel
    prior to its acceptance by the Planetary Data System (PDS). The
    peer review has been carried out in accordance with PDS
    procedures.
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    DTM products are derived products from HiRISE stereo observations
    that are radiometrically corrected. The observational coverage on
    the martian surface is dependent on the instrument operating modes
    of the observation and on the amount of overlap between of the stereo
    pair. The largest coverage at 300 kilometer spacecraft altitude is
    about 6 km crosstrack and 37 kilometers downtrack.
 
    During the Primary and Extended Science Phases of MRO operations,
    HiRISE is expected to acquire well over 1000 stereo pairs. Due to the
    lengthy and complicated process required to produce DTMs, not all of
    the stereo pairs will be used to create DTMs. DTMs to be produced
    are prioritized by scientific usefulness, optimal image quality and
    appropriate photometric parameters.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

