<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.clem1-l-lidar-5-topo-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CLEM1 LUNAR TOPOGRAPHY V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_space_program_science_experiment::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.clem1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:lidar.clem1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-lidar-5-topo-v1.0__browserc_clem1-l-lidar-5-topo-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-lidar-5-topo-v1.0__browserp_clem1-l-lidar-5-topo-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-lidar-5-topo-v1.0__dvo_geo_clem1-l-lidar-5-topo-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Dickey, J., J.E. Faller, X.X. Newhall, R.L. Ricklefs, J.G. Ries, P.J.
                   Shellus, C. Veillet, A.L. Whipple, J.R. Wiant, J.G. Williams, and C.F.
                   Yoder, Lunar Laser Ranging: A Continuing Legacy of the Apollo Program,
                   Science, 265, 482-490, 1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DICKEYETAL1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lemoine, F. G., D. E. Smith, M. T. Zuber, G.A. Neumann, and D.D. Rowlands,
                   A 70th degree and order lunar gravity model from Clementine and historical
                   data, submitted to Journal of Geophysical Research, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEMOINEETAL1995A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Smith, D. E., M. T. Zuber, G. A. Neumann and F. G. Lemoine, The topography
                   of the Moon from the Clementine LIDAR, submitted to Journal of Geophysical
                   Research, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SMITHETAL1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Williams, J. G., X.X. Newhall, E.M. Standish, Users of Ephemerides of the
                   Earth-Moon System, JPL Internal Memorandum, December 18, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.WILLIAMSETAL1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Zuber, M., D.E. Smith, F.G. Lemoine, and G. Neumann, The Shape and Internal
                   Structure of the Moon from the Clementine Mission, Science, Vol. 266, pp.
                   1839-1843, 1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ZUBERETAL1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CLEM1-L-LIDAR-5-TOPO-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CLEM1 LUNAR TOPOGRAPHY V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1996-01-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1994-02-19</start_time>
        <stop_time>1994-05-03</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>MARIA T. ZUBER</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Zuber, M. T., CLEM1 LUNAR TOPOGRAPHY V1.0,
            CLEM1-L-LIDAR-5-TOPO-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 1996
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Clementine Lunar Topography Archive contains topography data
            acquired by a laser ranging instrument (LIDAR) onboard the
            Clementine spacecraft while it orbited the Moon.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Clementine spacecraft included a Light Imaging Detection and
            Ranging (LIDAR) instrument. The LIDAR instrument measured the
            slant range from the spacecraft to the lunar surface. This data
            set contains topography data derived from the LIDAR measurements.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Clementine spacecraft included a Light Imaging Detection
      and Ranging (LIDAR) instrument.  The LIDAR instrument measured
      the slant range from the spacecraft to the lunar surface.
 
      The instrument acquired high resolution profiles of lunar
      topography.  The profiles were then gridded and used to produce
      digital maps at 1 and 0.25 degree resolution.  A 70th-degree
      and order spherical harmonic expansion of the data yielded the
      topographic model designated Goddard Lunar Topography Model 2B
      (GLTM-2B).  This topographic model represents the first
      reliable global characterization of surface heights for the
      Moon.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      There are 3 data types for the topography products found in
      this volume: tabular, array, and image data.  The data file
      containing the orbital altimetry profiles is in tabular format,
      with each row containing altimetry data and information for a
      given point in an orbit.
 
      The file containing the spherical harmonic coefficients of the
      Moon&apos;s topography (GLTM-2B) is also in tabular format, with
      each row in the table containing the degree index m, the order
      index n, and the coefficients Cmn and Smn.
 
      The gridded digital maps of topography (at 1 and 0.25 degree
      resolution) are ASCII 2-D data arrays.  There is also a byte-
      scaled image of each of the gridded products.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      The LIDAR instrument measured the slant range from the
      spacecraft to the lunar surface at spacecraft altitudes of 640
      km or less.  Range value was determined by the number of clock
      cycles between the laser start pulse and the received signal.
      The spacecraft orbited within ranging distance (orbital
      altitudes &lt;640 km) for approximately one-half hour per 5-hour
      orbit during the 2-month lunar mapping mission, and typically
      ranged at a rate of 1 shot per 1.6 seconds.  The elevations, in
      meters, were referenced to a spheroid with flattening of
      1/3234.93.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      Range was determined by the number of clock cycles between the
      laser start pulse and returned signal, using a calibration
      factor of 39.972 m per cycle.  Determining the range involved
      interpolating the spacecraft orbital trajectory to the time of
      the laser measurement, applying time-tag corrections to the
      original lidar data as supplied by the Naval Research
      Laboratory, including a 2 msec delay to the laser fire time.
      Corrections were then made for the one-way light time to the
      surface, and the measured range from the spacecraft to the
      surface was then transformed to a lunar radius in a
      center-of-mass reference frame.  Lunar radii are thus expressed
      in selenocentric surface coordinates.  The spacecraft
      quaternions were then used to correct the ranges for off-nadir
      pointing of the spacecraft.
 
      During the course of the mission the LIDAR typically ranged at
      a rate of 1 shot per 1.6 seconds and triggered on about 123,000
      shots, corresponding to 19% of the transmitted laser pulses.
      Typical along-track shot spacings were on the order of 20 km,
      but this varied considerably.  Ranging at 8 Hz was performed on
      pass 323 and successfully downloaded.  Much of the time, the
      first trigger in the range window was a true echo, but often,
      particularly over rough terrain, there were multiple triggers
      that did not correlate with lunar features.  In order to
      produce a digital topographic model of the Moon, it was
      necessary to develop a filter [SMITHETAL1995] which, when
      applied to the data, returned at most a single valid range
      value for each bounce point.  Since the detailed topography is
      largely unknown, the filter was based on a priori knowledge of
      the surface properties.  After filtering, a few dozen ranges,
      corresponding to known impact features, were manually included,
      and several suspect ranges excluded.
 
      While the altimetry along-track is fairly dense, the east-west
      coverage is limited by the 2.8 degree spacing of the
      groundtracks, repeating every 132 orbits.  The filtered data
      were averaged and assembled into a 0.25x0.25 degree grid in the
      latitude range from -79 to +82 degrees by minimum-curvature
      interpolation.  The elevations were referenced to a spheroid
      with flattening of 1/3234.93, which corresponds to the
      flattening term, C20 obtained for the lunar gravity field
      [LEMOINEETAL1995A].  This is the observed dynamical flattening
      of the planet.  The LIDAR did not return ranging information at
      the poles, nor was data coverage complete at lower latitudes.
      Therefore before performing a spherical harmonic expansion of
      the lunar radii it was necessary to &apos;fill in&apos; the polar regions
      (~3% of the planet&apos;s surface area) by minimum-curvature
      interpolation across the poles.  A spherical harmonic model of
      topography, complete to degree and order 70, was then produced
      by numerically integrating the Fourier transform of the gridded
      data at each latitude times the normalized associated Legendre
      polynomial, with respect to the cossine of the latitude.  This
      model is designated Goddard Lunar Topography Model 2B (GLTM-2B)
      [SMITHETAL1995].
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      N/A
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      The coordinate system for the topography data, and the
      coefficients in the GLTM-2B topography field, is selenocentric,
      center of mass, longitude positive east.  The location of the
      pole and the prime meridian are defined as per the reference
      from [WILLIAMSETAL1993; DICKEYETAL1994], who used the latest
      Lunar Laser Ranging (LLR) data to define the lunar orientation.
      The locations of the pole and the prime meridian are defined
      using a series of chebychev polynomials, which are available
      upon request from NASA Goddard Space Flight Center (contact
      Frank G.  Lemoine at 301-286-2460 or
      flemoine@olympus.gsfc.nasa.gov) or the PDS Geoscience Node
      (contact Jim Alexopoulos at 314-935-5365 or
      jim@wuzzy.wustl.edu).
 
 
    Software
    ========
      N/A
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The Clementine topography dataset will be available
      electronically via the World-Wide Web and anonymous FTP
      transfer.  File types include ASCII and binary formats.
      Formats will be based on standards established by the Planetary
      Data System (PDS).
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      Orbits were characterized by a formal uncertainty in radial
      position of about 10 meters and have an accuracy with respect
      to the lunar center of mass of approximately 100 m
      [LEMOINEETAL1995A], which is comparable to the single-shot
      ranging precision of the lidar (40 m).
 
 
    Review
    ======
      The volume containing the Clementine gravity and topography
      datasets was reviewed by Clementine mission scientists and by
      PDS.
 
 
    Data Coverage/Quality
    =====================
      Laser ranging was performed on revolutions 8 to 163 in the
      southern hemisphere during the first month, and revolutions 165
      to 332 in the north during the second month of the mapping
      phase of the mission.  During the first month, with spacecraft
      periselene at latitude -30 degrees, topographic profiles were
      obtained in the approximate latitude range -79 to +20 degrees.
      In the second month of mapping, with spacecraft periselene at
      latitude +30 degrees, profiles were obtained in the approximate
      latitude range -20 to +82 degrees.  This resulted in
      near-globally distributed profiles of elevation around the Moon
      [ZUBERETAL1994].
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      See Data Coverage/Quality above.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>94-004A-04A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

