<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.co-s-uvis-2-spec-v1.2</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CASSINI ORBITER SATURN UVIS EDITED SPECTRA 1.2</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:uvis.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.dark_sky::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.saturn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:ring.s_rings::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.albiorix::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.atlas::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.bestia::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.calypso::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.dione::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.enceladus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.epimetheus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.helene::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.hyperion::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.iapetus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.ijiraq::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.janus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.mimas::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.paaliaq::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.pan::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.pandora::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.phoebe::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.prometheus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.rhea::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.siarnaq::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.skoll::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.tarvos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.telesto::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.tethys::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.titan::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.ymir::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:star.star::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:sun.sun::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.co-s-uvis-2-spec-v1.2__browserp_co-s-uvis-2-spec-v1.2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Esposito, L.W., J.E. Colwell, K. Larsen, W.E. McClintock, A.I.F. Stewart, J.
                   Tew Hallett, D.E. Shemansky, J.M. Ajello, C.J. Hansen, A.R. Hendrix, R.A. West,
                   H.U. Keller, A. Korth, W.R. Pryor, R. Reulke, and Y.L. Yung, Ultra-Violet
                   Imaging Spectroscopy shows an active Saturn system, Science, 307, 1251-1255,
                   2005, LASP reprint 1000.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ESPOSITOETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CO-S-UVIS-2-SPEC-V1.2</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CASSINI ORBITER SATURN UVIS EDITED SPECTRA 1.2</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1999-01-07</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>LARRY ESPOSITO</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Esposito, L. (et al.), Cassini Ultraviolet Imaging Spectrograph
            Cassini Tour Data, NASA Planetary Data System,
            CO-S-UVIS-2-SPEC-V1.2, 2005.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            A set of spectra.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Spectroscopy of Jupiter, Saturnian rings, atmospheres and
            satellites for determining chemical abundance, compositional
            albedo, aerosol profiling, ring reflected spectra and diffraction
            patterns.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      The UVIS Spectrum Dataset
      ==========================
          The UVIS instrument is part of the remote sensing payload of
       the Cassini orbiter spacecraft.  UVIS has two  spectrographic
       channels that provide images and spectra covering the ranges
       from 56 to 118 nm and 110 to 190 nm.  A third optical path
       with a solar  blind CsI photocathode is used for a high
       signal-to-noise ratio stellar  occultation by rings and
       atmospheres.  A separate hydrogen deuterium  absorption cell
       measures the relative abundance of deuterium and hydrogen
       from their lyman-alpha emission.  These channels are referred
       to as EUV,  FUV, HSP, and HDAC in this document.  The UVIS
       science objectives include  investigation of the chemistry,
       aerosols, clouds, and energy balance of the Titan and Saturn
       atmospheres; neutrals in the Saturn magnetosphere; the
       deuterium-to-hydrogen ratio for Titan and Saturn; icy
       satellite surface  properties; and the structure and
       evolution of Saturns rings.   basic instrument design adapts
       proven design concepts using a  grating spectrometer followed
       by a multi-element detector.  We chose to  use imaging, pulse-
       counting microchannel plate detectors because of more  than a
       decade of experience using this kind of detector equipped
       with a  CODACON readout anode.  The CODACON (Coded Anode
       Array Converter) acts as a photon locator.  The photon counts
       are accumulated in an external memory to build a picture that
       is periodically read out for transfer to the spacecraft memory
       and eventually, transmission to the ground.   The two dimensional
       format for the CODACON detectors allows simultaneous  spectral
       and one-dimensional spatial coverage.  The detector format is
       1024 x 64 (spectral by spatial).
          The Cassini HDAC consists of a channel electron Multiplier
       photodetector  equipped with 3 absorption cell filters:  a
       hydrogen cell, a deuterium cell  and an oxygen cell.  The
       oxygen cell is not utilized in flight.  The  hydrogen and
       deuterium cells function as adjustable absorption filters.
       In  each cell a hot tungsten filament disassociates the
       hydrogen and deuterium  molecules into atoms, producing an
       atomic density determined by each of 16  different filament
       temperatures.  These atoms resonantly absorb the  hydrogen
       and deuterium Lyman-alpha lines passing through the cells.
       Cycling the filaments on and off and comparing the
       differences in signal  gives a direct measurement of the
       relative hydrogen and deuterium signals.   Each cell has two
       filaments controlled by separate filament current
       regulators.  Only one filament at a time per cell is used
       during flight.   A Pulse Amplifier Discriminator detects
       photoelectrons from the CEM and  sends pulses to the UVIS
       instrument logic.   S contains a high speed photometer with
       an integration time as short  as 2.0 ms to observe stars
       occulted by the rings of Saturn.  The photon  counts
       collected from the photocathode are passed as a time ordered
       sequence to the instrument, then to spacecraft memory for
       transfer to the  ground.    The data in a UVIS observation
       are a copy of what was in the UVIS memory  buffer. That is,
       the observation consists of unprocessed experiment data
       stored in binary format. An observation belongs to one of
       four different  types of data product: a spectrum, a time
       series of spatial-spectral  images, a time series of detector
       counts, or an image at one wavelength.   Each observation has
       a unique identifier that associates it with a time  range and
       with the configuration of the instrument during that time.
       Each data product will contain one observation and will be
       completely  defined by a PDS label.  The objects will be
       correct in the sense that  they will conform to PDS formatting
       requirements and will be consistent  with data archived by the
       UVIS team.  They will be complete in that they  will represent
       all data taken by the UVIS instrument.  In addition, CODMAC
       level 3 data products will be derivable from the archived data
       and an  associated set of calibration data.
           The EUV and FUV channels can be read out to produce
       spectra.  Each  spectrum is generated by accumulating
       detector counts over a fixed time  interval.  The time
       interval is defined in the instrument configuration
       associated with the observation.  A spectrum consists of a
       sequence of  counts, each count being associated with a
       detector column (or columns). In the simplest case, a
       spectrum is a sequence of 1024 integers where  each integer
       is the number of counts taken during a fixed time interval
       by the detector at a particular wavelength and summed over
       the spatial  dimension of the detector.  In more complex
       cases, each integer in the  spectrum corresponds to a set of
       columns and is derived by summing over  both the spatial and
       spectral dimensions.  For example, if the binning defined on
       the spectral dimension is two, a spectrum will consist of
       512 integers, where each integer is derived by first summing
       1024  columns in the spatial dimension, then summing
       contiguous pairs of  detector lines in the spectral
       dimension.  A still more complex case  involves spectra
       derived from a set of sub regions of the detector.    In this
       case, the detector is divided into a set of active rectangular
       sub regions (windows).  Each window can be binned in the manner
       described above.  A data product (also referred to as an
       observation) is a sequence of spectra taken from a window
       during the same instrument  configuration.
          All instrument configuration information including
       window, bin, and integration time specifications will be
       contained in the PDS object label.
          For a more extensive description of the UVIS instrument
       see the file ROOT/DOCUMENT/UVIS.TXT on this archive
       volume.
 
      Parameters
      ==========
      The observation type for each observation is found in OBSERVATION_TYPE
      column of INDEX.TAB.  The specific purpose of each observation
      may be found in the object DESCRIPTION field contained in the label.
 
      Processing
      ==========
      The observation data products are generated by the Laboratory for
      Atmospheric and Space Physics at the University of Colorado using
      the Data Archiving and Processing System (DAPS) software.  This
      software receives telemetry packet SFDUs from the Telemetry Data
      System, extracts science and engineering data, archives the data
      in a database management system and produces PDS data and label
      object files located on a CD-ROM or DVD physical storage medium.
 
      All time information is generated from the spacecraft clock using
      the Cassini SCLKSET files.  The DAPS system uses NAIF software and
      project generated SPICE Kernels to generate pointing information.  All
      of these values are contained in the PDS object label.
 
      Data
      ====
            The EUV and FUV spectra will be archived as a 1024x1xN
       PDS Qube, that  is, N spectra, each containing 1024 integers
       representing detector counts. When windowing or binning is
       defined data will be located in the upper left hand corner of
       the window from which the data was derived and the Qube will
       be padded with null values.  For example, if a detector
       window is defined with its upper left corner at (10, 10) and
       its lower right corner at (20, 20) and its binning is defined
       to be (2, 10) then the data for the Nth spectrum will be found
       at (10, 1, N) through (15, 1, N) in the Qube. All the numbers
       outside this range will be a null value.
 
         ***************************
      0  *ddddddddddddddddddddddddd*
         ***************************
         0                       1024
 
      Fig. 2.2.2.1 A single windowed sample with (1x64) binning where
      d is data.
 
         ***************************
      0  *nddddnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnn*
         ***************************
      0    10 15                 1024
 
      Fig. 2.2.2.2 A window with an upper left hand corner at (10, 10),
      and a lower right hand corner at (20,20) and 2x10 binning,  where
      d is data, n is null.
 
      Calibration data are used to transform detector counts into
      geophysical units. The EUV, FUV channels have an associated
      calibration process.  FUV and EUV  data are converted to Rayleighs.
      The UVIS team supplies calibration data files.  The calibration
      process is described below and in the PDS label file associated with
      the calibration. data file.
 
      Calibration data consist of an MxN matrix and a scalar value.  Each
      matrix  and scalar should be used to scale the individual integrations
      of a raw  data product.  The result is a calibrated data product which
      is isomorphic  to the original containing data in units of
      kilorayleighs.   In addition, each calibration data product contains a
      mapping of detector lines to  wavelengths which is stored in the BAND
      BIN_CENTER keyword value.
 
      Calibration data are archived as a PDS Qubes with the dimensions
      1024x64x1  or 1024x1x1.  All instrument configuration data for the
      observation is  contained in the associated PDS label; in addition the
      label contains  instructions for using the calibration data and a
      detector column to  wavelength mapping and the scalar multiplier
      which is stored in the  CORE_MULTIPLIER value).
 
      In addition to this mechanism, non-standard calibration routines
      developed by UVIS team members may be provided.  These routines may
      require  user input and control.  These procedures are not supported
      nor are their  validity guaranteed, however to the extent that they
      are intended for  general use by the UVIS team, we will submit
      algorithms and associated data  and documentation.
 
      Ancillary Data
      ==============
      The UVIS team supplies calibration data files and the algorithms used
      to generate the FUV and EUV calibration data.  The calibration
      algorithms are archived as text files in the SOFTWARE/CALIB directory
      of the PDS data volume. The file names contain channel and version
      information.  These algorithms  generate calibration data which is
      located in the CALIB/VERSION_n/...  directories.  The algorithms are
      provided as a description of the process by which calibration data is
      generated.  They are not used to calibrate raw data.
 
      Coordinate System
      =================
      In the UVIS data products, all time values that are represented as
      strings  are in UTC time.  All time values are derived from the
      spacecraft clock  using the SCLKSCET translation table supplied by
      the  Cassini project.  All pointing data are expressed in the J2000
      coordinate system.
 
      Software
      ========
      LASP provides software for reading PDS data products.  This software
      is  located in the ROOT/SOFTWARE/READERS directory.  The software
      requires Java 1.4 compatible class libraries and RSI/IDL version 6.
      Instructions for running the  routines are located in the file
      READERS_README.TXT, located in the same directory.
 
      These readers are provided as a convenience for users to access the
      data. Users may choose another approach if desired.  The readers
      enable users to load PDS objects into an RSI/IDL process where they
      are represented as 3  dimensional arrays of integers corresponding to
      the PDS Qube object in which they are stored.  PDS label data are
      stored in an IDL structure variable.
 
      DISC FORMAT
      =================================================================
      This disc has been formatted so that a variety of computer systems
      (e.g. IBM PC, Macintosh, Sun, VAX) may access the data.  Specifically,
      the disc is formatted according to the UDF-Bridge DVD format
      standard which provides ISO 9660 level 2 standard compatibility.
      For further information, refer to the ISO 9660 Standard Document:
      RF# ISO 9660-1988, 15 April 1988.
 
      Specific to the ISO 9660 level 2 standard, filenames on this CD
      conform to the 27.3 file naming convention i.e.,
      1.  The file name portion may be up to 29 characters long; or
      2.  The extension may be up to 29 characters long,
      3.  In no case, however, may the total file name length, including
      the . exceed 31 characters.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      Confidence Level Overview
      =========================
      The UVIS data objects are organized into separate observations.
      Each observation contains data taken from one configuration of
      the instrument.  There may be more than one observation generated
      from one instrument configuration.  This may occur because science
      data generated by the UVIS instrument is dropped when corrupted
      data is detected or transmission failures occur.  The UVIS ground
      system detects this and divides the data into two observations, one
      terminated prior to the data drop the next beginning immediately
      afterword.  The start time and duration of an observation correspond
      to the end times of the first and last records in the observation.
      Incomplete observations are filled with zeroes.  Over 95% of data
      taken by the instrument is contained in the UVIS archive.
 
      Only one hardware feature affects UVIS data.  A light leak in the
      instrument casing causes an increase in the background counts in
      the lower half of the EUV channel wavelength range.  This effect is
      detectable by visual inspection of a graph of the data.  No tools
      for detection or correction of these background counts exists.
 
      One anomaly in the flight software caused data errors to appear
      when multiple windows which do not cover the entire EUV or FUV
      detector are defined.  In an observation, the data errors appear
      as randomly located spikes in detector count values, and one
      completely incorrect spatial line located at a random spatial
      index.  These errors are detectable by visual inspection of a
      plot of the data.  The anomaly was fixed by a revison to the
      software and effects data between launch and 2001-071 09:00:00 UTC
 
      Review
      ======
      This volume has completed a peer review by the PDS. The peer review
      panel consisted of Lyle Huber, Mitch Gordon, Steven Adams, Ron Joyner
      and Mark Vincent representing PDS, David Judd and Wayne Pryor from the,
      UVIS team Diane Connor from the Cassini Project and Kurt Retherford
      and John Clarke as outside users.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

