<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dif-cal-hrii-hriv-mri-2-ground-tv4-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DEEP IMPACT PREFLIGHT THERMAL-VACUUM 4 HRII/HRIV/MRI DATA</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_impact::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:hrii.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:hriv.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mri.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dif-cal-hrii-hriv-mri-2-ground-tv4-v1.0__browserp_dif-cal-hrii-hriv-mri-2-ground-tv4-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   A&apos;Hearn, M.F., M.J.S. Belton, A. Delamere, and W.H. Blume, Deep Impact: A
                   Large-Scale Active Experiment on a Cometary Nucleus, Space Science Reviews,
                   117, 1-21, 2005, doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3387-3.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.AHEARNETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hampton, D.L., J.W. Baer, M.A. Huisjen, C.C. Varner, A. Delamere, D.D.
                   Wellnitz, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, and K.P. Klaasen, An Overview of the Instrument Suite
                   for the Deep Impact Mission, Space Science Reviews, 117, 43-93, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3390-8.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAMPTONETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., B. Carcich, G. Carcich, E.J. Grayzeck, and S. McLaughlin, Deep
                   Impact: The Anticipated Flight Data, Space Science Reviews, 117, 335-372, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3385-5.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV/MRI-2-GROUND-TV4-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DEEP IMPACT PREFLIGHT THERMAL-VACUUM 4 HRII/HRIV/MRI DATA</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2004-10-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2003-02-23T19:04:48Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2003-03-12T14:12:25Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STEPHANIE MCLAUGHLIN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Hampton, D.L., D.D. Wellnitz, and S.A. McLaughlin, DEEP IMPACT
            PREFLIGHT THERMAL-VACUUM 4 HRII/HRIV/MRI DATA,
            DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV/MRI-2-GROUND-TV4-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Image and temperature dataacquired during the preflight
            thermal-vacuum test (TV4) ofthe Deep Impact High Resolution
            Instrument&apos;s Infrared Spectrometer(HRII) and Visible CCD
            (HRIV) and Medium Resolution Instrument&apos;sVisible CCD (MRI)
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains image and temperature data acquired during
            the preflight thermal-vacuum test (TV4) of the High Resolution
            Instrument&apos;s Infrared Spectrometer (HRII) and Visible CCD
            (HRIV) and the Medium Resolution Instrument&apos;s Visible CCD
            (MRI) for the Deep Impact Mission.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  This data set description was provided by Stephanie McLaughlin and
  Dennis Wellnitz, University of Maryland, who participated in
  the ground calibration tests of the Deep Impact instruments.
 
 
Data Set Overview
=================
 
  This data set contains image and temperature data acquired during the
  preflight thermal-vacuum test (TV4) of High Resolution Instrument&apos;s
  Infrared Spectrometer (HRII) and Visible CCD (HRIV) and the Medium
  Resolution Instrument&apos;s Visible CCD (MRI) for Deep Impact.  The
  experiments performed during TV4 were designed by the Ball Aerospace
  team with input from the Deep Impact science team.  TV4 was conducted
  by Don Hampton of Ball Aerospace.  Several science team members were
  present at all times to assist with the experiments and perform
  real-time analysis of the data.
 
  The main objective of TV4 was to obtain calibration data for all three
  instruments on the Flyby spacecraft at the 140K temperature range for
  the HRI optics, warmer than TV2 where the lowest nominal temperature
  was 130K.  The warmer operating temperature of the IR focal plane
  array (FPA) caused bad pixels to bloom in the HRII instrument.
 
  Also, during TV4, several calibration experiments were performed
  for the HRII instrument, which had a light-reduction filter
  inserted into the middle of the spectrometer&apos;s slit after TV2 when
  it was determined that the HRII instrument would overexpose the
  nucleus of the comet during encounter:
 
    - Perform tests at the nominal operating temperatures of 130K
      for the HRI optics and 106K for the IR FPA.
    - Determine best focus at the operating temperatures.
    - Obtain flat fields from various blackbody sources to measure
      the response of the FPA at different wavelengths.
    - Determine the non-linearity of the FPA.
    - Activate the internal calibration lamp.
    - Check for stray light.
    - Check for spectral motion caused by motion of the HRIV filter
      wheel.
    - Check adjustments made to the FPA spectral and spatial
      registrations based on TV1 results.
    - Check the spatial and spectral dispersion of the FPA.
 
  Also, during TV4, several calibration experiments were performed
  for the HRIV and MRI instruments:
 
    - Check focus.
    - Check co-alignment and co-focus with the HRII instrument.
    - Check registration of the parallel overclock columns and
      the serial overclock rows.
    - Test the photo-response of the CCD by using several calibrated
      blackbody sources and obtain flats.
    - Measure dark current as the CCD cools.
    - Measure bias.
 
  To meet these objectives, the entire instrument platform for the
  Flyby spacecraft was placed inside the Rambo thermal-vacuum
  chamber.  A test bench was setup outside the chamber to direct
  light from an external source through the main window of the
  chamber.  The chamber was also equipped with a side window made
  of Zinc-Selenide to simulate the window of the Ball 8 chamber
  that was used during TV2.
 
  TV4 activities are summarized in the following chart.
 
              Avg Temperatures(K)
  Date/(DOY)  FPA    Prism    CCD  Tests
  ----------  -------------------- ---------------------------------
  2003-02-23   304    305     306  Warm functional tests of all 3
  (054)                            instruments
 
  2003-02-24   304    305     306  Warm functional tests of all 3
  (055)                            instruments
 
  2003-02-25   304    305     306  Warm functional tests of all 3
  (056)                            instruments
                                   HRIV: Warm focus
 
  2003-02-26  ~282   ~281    ~291  Begin cooldown; Functional tests
  (057)                            HRIV: Focus, Dark current
                                   MRI: Dark current
 
  2003-02-27  ~242   ~240    ~253  Continue cooldown
  (058)                            HRII: Test IR delay procedure
                                   HRIV: Dark current
                                   MRI:  Dark current, Linearity,
                                         Flats, Focus,
 
  2003-02-28  ~150   ~166    ~185  Continue cooldown
  (059)                            HRIV: Dark current
                                   MRI:  Dark current
 
  2003-03-01  ~109   ~142    ~165  Continue cooldown
  (060)                            HRII: Test light-reduction filter,
                                         Dark current, Flats, Argon source
                                   HRIV: Bias, Darks
                                   MRI:  Bias, Darks, Latent image,
                                         Internal stimulator, Focus
 
  2003-03-02  ~106   ~140    ~170  Cold
  (061)                            HRII: Light-reduction filter tests
                                   HRIV: Flats, Ambient light, Bias
                                   MRI:  Flats, Ambient light, Bias
 
  2003-03-03  ~106   ~140    ~173  HRIV: Co-boresight with MRI, Focus
  (062)
                                   MRI:  Focus, Flats, Alignment
 
  2003-03-04  ~106   ~140    ~170  MRI:  Focus, Flats, Alignment
  (063)
 
  2003-03-05  ~106   ~140    ~172  HRII: Ambient light
  (064)                            HRIV: Focus, Latent image, Flats
                                         Shutter block test, Bias
                                   MRI:  Imaging
 
  2003-03-06  ~105   ~139    ~168  HRII: Calibration lamp, Argon and
  (065)                                  Krypton sources, Co-focus
                                         with HRIV, Light-reduction filter
                                         tests, Flats, Ambient light, Darks
                                   HRIV: Internal stimulator, Bias, Flats
                                   MRI:  Flats
 
  2003-03-07  ~106   ~139    ~172  Encounter sequence for all 3
  (066)                            instruments
                                   HRII: IR delay tests, Flats,
                                         CO, CH4, and N2 gas cells, Darks,
                                         Linearity, Boresight with respect
                                         to HRIV
                                   HRIV: HRII boresight
 
  2003-03-08  ~104   ~139    ~168  No data taken
  (067)
 
  2003-03-09  ~104   ~139    ~168  Encounter sequence for all 3
  (068)                            instruments
 
  2003-03-10  ~106   ~144    ~180  Encounter sequence for all 3
  (069)                            instruments
                                   HRII: Image test targets
                                   MRI:  Image test targets
 
  2003-03-11  ~134   ~160    ~185  HRIV: Warm imaging
  (070)                            MRI:  Focus
 
  2003-03-12  ~241   ~244    ~254  MRI:  Warm imaging
  (071)
 
 
  For more information about the mission, the HRI and MRI instruments,
  and the anticipated flight data, see A&apos;Hearn, et al. (2005)
  [AHEARNETAL2005], Hampton, et al. (2005) [HAMPTONETAL2005], and
  Klaasen, et al. (2005) [KLAASENETAL2005].
 
 
Parameters
==========
 
  HRII
  -----
 
    The HRII spectral image data are in units of raw data numbers.
    For TV4, all seven of the HRII&apos;s image modes were tested:
 
    Image  MinExp  X-Size  Y-Size  #Images
    Mode#  (sec)   (pix)   (pix)    Output  Binning  Comments
    -----  ------  ------  ------  -------  -------  ----------------------
      1     2.862    512     256       1      2x2
      2     1.432    512     126       1      2x2
      3     0.717    512      64       1      2x2
      4     2.861   1024     512       1      1x1
      5     2.865    512     256       1      2x2
      6     1.432   1024     512       2      1x1    Reset then data frame
      7     2.864   1024     512       1      1x1    Memory check mode
 
    In this table, MinExp is the frame-to-frame minimum exposure times,
    X-Size is spectral dimension and Y-Size is spatial dimension of the
    FPA.  For all image modes except 6, the reset frame is automatically
    subtracted, on-chip, from the data frame and the result is output.
    For more information about the image modes, see Hampton, et. al (2005)
    [HAMPTONETAL2005].
 
  HRIV/MRI
  --------
 
    The HRIV and MRI image data are in units of raw data numbers.
    The following image modes were defined and tested during TV4:
 
     Image  MinExp  X-Size  Y-Size
      Mode#   (ms)   (pix)   (pix)   Binning  Comments
      -----  ------  ------  ------  -------  -------------------------
        1      3.5    1024    1024     1x1    Shuttered
        2      3.5     512     512     1x1    Shuttered
        3      3.5     256     256     1x1    Shuttered
        4    217.8     256     256     1x1    Not shuttered
        5      3.5     128     128     1x1    Shuttered
        6     98.4     128     128     1x1    Not shuttered
        7     47.4      64      64     1x1    Not shuttered
        8     47.4      64      64     1x1    Not shuttered,no overscan
        9      3.5    1024    1024     1x1    Shuttered; diagnostic
 
    In this table, MinExp is the minimum exposure time and the term
    shuttered means the light blocker in the HRIV or MRI instrument
    is always used (opened and closed).  For all modes, additional
    exposure time can be commanded.  For unshuttered modes, a delay time
    (duration to wait before the start of the CCD readout) can also be
    commanded.  For more information about the image modes, see
    Hampton, et. al (2005) [HAMPTONETAL2005].
 
    Please note that the results from TV2 indicated the need for
    additional image modes with shorter minimum exposure times.
    Four new image modes were defined and implemented for all of the
    Deep Impact CCDs after TV2.
 
 
Data
====
 
  Images
  ------
 
    The data are in the form of FITS files with attached FITS headers
    and detached PDS labels.  One data files contains one HRII, HRIV
    or MRI image.  The fastest-varying axis is considered the X axis and
    the slowest-varying, the Y axis.  TV4 data filenames have this format:
    Iyymmdd_hhmmss_sss_x.FIT where the &apos;yymmdd_hhmmss_sss&apos; string the date,
    time and subseconds stamp provided by the ground-support computer
    when it stored the original data file.  The clock on the ground-support
    computer was set to local Mountain time.  The &apos;x&apos; string is valued with
    &apos;A&apos; for HRIV or MRI data, and &apos;B&apos; for HRII data.  After TV2,
    the ground-support computer was modified to store the reset and data
    frames for HRII image mode 6 into two separate data files with unique
    time stamps; the reset frame was store first, then the data frame.
 
    For TV4, the ground-support computer stored data files in a native
    image format, called &apos;IMG&apos;.  The raw data numbers were 14-bit and
    and left justified.  A 100-byte image header was pre-pended to each
    data array.  The &apos;IMG&apos; data were converted to FITS at the Deep Impact
    Science Data Center (SDC) at Cornell University, using algorithms
    developed by Ball Aerospace for testing of the instruments and to
    allow real-time analysis of data during thermal-vacuum tests.
    During the conversion, raw data numbers were right justified to
    give the actual, true data numbers.  Data in the 100-byte image
    header are captured in the FITS header.
 
    After TV2, the Field Programmable Gate Arrays (FPGA) for each of
    the CCDs was adjusted so that the columns of serial overclocks
    and several rows of parallel overclocks would be correctly
    located around the edges of the CCD array.
 
    During TV4, the amplifier gains for the IR FPA were not correct.
    This caused the right side of the array (columns 513-1014) to have
    a bias about 2000 DN (data number) greater than the left side fo the
    array (columns 1-512).  Amplifier gains were corrected after TV4.
 
    It is important to note that the higher IR FPA temperature during
    TV4 (106K) caused bad pixels to bloom noticeably when compared to
    data from TV2, when IR FPA temperatures range was about 86-90K.
 
  Instrument Temperatures
  -----------------------
 
    The instrument temperatures found in the PDS labels were extracted
    from the temperature keywords in the FITS headers.  During TV4,
    ground-support equipment correctly recorded temperatures in the
    image headers.  As a check, temperatures of various components of the
    HRII/HRIV and MRI instruments were also recorded every 5 minutes by
    two thermister monitors (computers).  Temperature data, in fixed-width
    ASCII table format, are available in the data directory.  There is
    one table of HRII/HRIV temperatures and one table of MRI. Time
    stamps in the temperature file are are based on local Mountain time
    and are within several minutes of the time stamps in the FITS
    filenames. Temperatures found in the tables or the PDS labels can be
    used for analysis
 
    It is important to note that the IR FPA temperatures recorded by the
    thermister monitor were adjusted by -3.26K before being stored in the
    temperature table.  After thermal-vacuum 4 (TV4), Ball Aerospace
    personnel analyzed all IR FPA temperatures and determined the
    temperatures recorded by the monitor needed to be adjusted by -3.26K
    because the cable connected to this temperature point included about
    18 inches of manganin wire which resulted in higher temperature
    measurements due to its higher electrical resistance.
 
         .
Ancillary Data
==============
 
  The DOCUMENT directory provides the HRII/HRIV and MRI image
  logs recorded during TV4.  The logs contain an entry for each image
  acquired during TV4 and include image parameters such as mode and
  experiment type.  The logs include a brief description of each type
  of experiment performed during TV4 and a summary of the experiments
  performed on each test date.
 
  The DOCUMENT directory also provides daily reports written by the
  test leaders and distributed to the test team and the science
  team.  The reports describe in detail the test activities as well
  problems and successes encountered during TV4.
 
  The DOCUMENT directory includes the local PDS data dictionary used
  to produce the labels as well as sample IDL code used to read
  and extract temperatures from the TV4 HRII/HRIV temperature table.
 
 
Media/Format
============
 
  This data set is released as a logical data volume.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    1) The time stamp in the FITS filename can vary by several
       tens of seconds of the actual time the image was acquired.
 
    2) The project elected store and archive MRI FITS images from
       flight with the sky orientation during the approach to Tempel 1:
       East is to the left and North is up.  However, MRI FITS images
       from TV4 were stored in the engineering orientation with
       East to the right and North up.  When comparing MRI FITS images
       from TV4 to those acquired during flight, a left-to-right flip
       about the y axis is required for the TV4 data.
 
    3) The images in this archive were used extensively by the science
       team and Ball Aerospace engineers to verify the instruments were
       operating within requirements and to calibrate the instruments.
       These data were reviewed internally by the Deep Impact project
       before release to the planetary community.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

