<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.phx-m-met-3-l-rdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>PHOENIX MARS MET LIDAR ATMOSPHERIC PROFILES RDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.phoenix::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.phx::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:lidar.phx::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.phx-m-met-3-l-rdr-v1.0__browserp_phx-m-met-3-l-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.phx-m-met-3-l-rdr-v1.0__browser_geo_phx-m-met-3-l-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.phx-m-met-3-l-rdr-v1.0__dvo_atm_phx-m-met-3-l-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Whiteway, J, M. Daly, A. Carswell, C. Dickinson, T. Duck, L. Komguem, and C.
                   Cook, Lidar on the Phoenix Mars Mission, J. Geophys. Res., volume 113, E00A08,
                   doi:10.1029/2007JE003002
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.WHITEWAY2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>PHX-M-MET-3-L-RDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>PHOENIX MARS MET LIDAR ATMOSPHERIC PROFILES RDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2008-12-23</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2008-05-28T20:35:58.613Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2008-06-24T12:24:49.144Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>CAMERON S. DICKINSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Dickinson, C. D., PHX ATMOSPHERIC LIDAR PROFILES V1.0, NASA
            Planetary Data System, 2008.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            PHX LIDAR raw laser scattering profiles
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The PHX Atmospheric Lidar Profiles product contains raw (volts
            and counts) laser scattering atmospheric profiles for photon
            counting data at 532nm, and analog data at both 532 and 1064nm
            wavelengths. The range data is provided as a time series of
            profiles between 5 and 90 min in total duration, with each
            profile representing an accumulation or average over 1.28-20.24
            sec. Supplemental data of estimated laser power (given as a
            voltage) and inter-profile analog background skylight estimates
            are also provided.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Modification History
  ====================
    Version 1 data volumes include volumes LS003 through LS029, released
    Dec 2008.  These volumes contain Lidar data collected May 2008
    through June 2008, specifically Sols 3-29.
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The Phoenix Mars Lander arrived at 68.2184N, 234.2487E on May 25, 2008.
 
    The  PHX Atmospheric Lidar Profiles product contains  raw laser
    scattering atmospheric profiles (i.e profiles in counts or volts,
    but not corrected for all instrumental effects).  Each operation
    of the lidar instrument is provided as a separate product, and often
    more than one operation was conducted per sol.
 
    The RDR Data are organized into Photon Counting (532nm), Analog (532 &amp;
    1064nm) and Supplemental (Laser Power, Lidar Background Skylight and
    sensorhead temperatures).
 
    The lidar instrument is highly configurable, leading to a myriad of
    possible data volume outcomes.  Briefly, a single (vertical) profile
    of atmospheric scattering is given for a single point in time, and
    listed as values at various ranges (distance) from the lander (with
    the difference between successive ranges defining the sampling
    range interval).  Successive profiles, marked with a separate time,
    determine the temporal sampling interval (period duration), and the
    total duration is defined as the product of total number of profiles
    and sampling interval (temporal integration duration).  The range
    sampling interval for analog and photon counting channels can be
    configured separately,
 
    Supplemental data contains the average, min and max laser voltages
    (provided as an estimate of laser power); inter_pulse analog
    background values; and sensor-head temperature estimates, as an
    indicator of co-alignment between laser transmitter and receiver.
    [WHITEWAY2008]
 
    The Data is organized by a unique identifier (Token) is keeping with
    the other Phoenix instruments.  The token for the Lidar was set each
    instance of operation, and is provided as a 4 byte hex value.
 
    Every record is stored with both the spacecraft time, and UTC start
    time, and each data record can thus be retrieved from each table
    using time as a common key.
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    Each RDR file contains time as fractions of a seconds since
    START_TIME.  The range that scattering occurs at is given from the
    lander deck (approximately vertical) in meters.
 
    The number of profiles and integration duration are also provided for
    reference.
 
    During surface operations, the range resolution was nominally set to
    20m and 50m, respectively, for the analog and photon counting data;
    The sampling period was between 1.28 - 20.48 sec, with the vast
    majority of lidar operations employing 20.24 sec resolution; each
    operation of the lidar was between 5 and 90 min in total duration,
    with the average operation lasting 20 min.
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The RDR products have had the following changes as compared to the EDRs:
 
    1.  The data has been changed and reordered where required to be
        consistent with the SIS.
 
    2.  The Frame Count is converted to the duration of each
        measurement in Earth seconds.
 
    3.  Digital Numbers have been converted to Volts given:
 
        Volts = (DN / NLSIP / RSD) * -8.929312609 + 0.7314
        (NLSIP = Number of Laser Shots per Integration Period
        NSD = Range Sampling Distance (e.g. 50m) / 2.5)
 
    Finally, the data were converted to PDS format, converting the
    tab-delimited fields to fixed-width fields, and exchanging the
    multiple packet headers for a single session header by the MET GDS.
 
    Address:     Cameron Dickinson
                 Dept. of Earth and Space Science Engineering
                 York University
                 4700 Keele St
                 Toronto, ON M3J 1P3
 
    Phone:       (416) 736-2100 X 23870
    Email:       cameron.dickinson@gmail.com
 
    For science related questions about the data, please contact the
    MET Instrument Science Team Lead:
 
    Address:     James Whiteway
                 Dept. of Earth and Space Science Engineering
                 York University
                 4700 Keele St
                 Toronto, ON M3J 1P3
 
    Phone:       (416) 736-2100 X 22310
    Email:       whiteway@yorku.ca
 
 
  Data
  ====
    All of the data in this data set are contained in ASCII tabular files
    with detached PDS labels.  Data is stored in a separate directory
    relating to the sol in which the recording of data commenced (i.e.
    data acquired from 003 10:00 local to 004 10:15 will be in the sol
    3 directory)
 
    Individual filenames are constructed as follows:
 
                             MS002RLP_00896227243_10CCM0.LBL
 
        1: The first character will always be an &apos;M&apos;, representing MET
           data.
        2: The second character will be an &apos;S&apos;, signifying surface
           data (versus &apos;C&apos; for Cruise)
      3-5: The next three characters provide the sol number of the data
           file.
      6-8: The next three characters describe the type of MET data,
           ELP - EDR Lidar Photon Counting *532 nm)
           ELA - EDR Lidar Analog (532 &amp; 1064 nm)
           ELS - EDR Lidar Supplemental Data
           RLP - RDR Lidar Photon Counting *532 nm)
           RLA - RDR Lidar Analog (532 &amp; 1064 nm)
           RLS - RDR Lidar Supplemental Data
        9: Blank
    10-20: SCLK - Spacecraft clock
       21: Blank
    22-25: Operations Token
       26: Producer (M for MET Team)
       27: Version
       28: Period
    29-31: Extension, LBL or TAB
 
    The tabular files are formatted so that they may be read directly into
    many database management systems (DBMS) or spreadsheet programs on
    various computers.  Each of the files contains two tables.  The first
    is the header table, and is only a single record in length.  The
    second table contains all of the data records for a session and varies
    in length.
 
    All fields in the tables are stored in columns of fixed width and are
    right justified.  The records are of fixed length; since the header
    records are shorter than the data records, they have been padded with
    blank spaces at the end of the record.  The last two bytes of each
    record contain the ASCII carriage return and line feed characters.
    This allows the tables to be treated as fixed length record files on
    computers that support this file type and as normal text files on
    other computers.
 
    The PDS labels are object-oriented. The object to which the labels
    refer (the tables) is denoted by a statement of the form:
 
        ^object = location
 
    in which the carat character (&apos;^&apos;, also called a pointer in this
    context) indicates that the object starts at the given location.  For
    an object located outside the label file (as in this case), the
    location denotes the name of the file containing the object, along
    with the starting record.  For example:
 
        ^TABLE = &apos;MS013RLP_00126907202_15C6M1.TAB&apos;
 
    indicates that the TABLE object is in the same directory as the
    detached label file. (Records are counted starting at 1, not 0.)
 
    The detached label files are stream format files, with a carriage
    return (ASCII 13) and a line feed character (ASCII 10) at the end of
    each record.  This allows the files to be read by the MacOS, DOS,
    UNIX, and VMS operating systems.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The EDR/RDR tables can be displayed on UNIX, Macintosh,
    and PC platforms as simple ASCII files, or using the PDS developed
    program, NASAView.  This software is freely available from the PDS
    Central Node and may be obtained from their web site at
    http://pds.nasa.gov/.  For more information or help in obtaining
    the software, contact the PDS operator at the following address:
 
    Address:     Planetary Data System, PDS Operator
                 Jet Propulsion Laboratory
                 4800 Oak Grove Drive
                 Pasadena, CA 91109
 
    Phone:       (818) 354-4321
    Email:       pds_operator@jpl.nasa.gov
    WWW URL:     http://pds.nasa.gov/
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Review
  ======
    The contents of this data have been peer reviewed by the following
    people:
 
    Lyle Huber        - PDS Atmospheres Node, New Mexico State University
    Jim Murphy        - PDS Atmospheres Node, New Mexico State University
    Cameron Dickinson - MET/Lidar Data Manager, York University
    Jim Whiteway      - MET/LIDAR Instrument Co-Investigator, York University
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

