<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.pvo-v-ouvs-5-imidr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>PVO V OUVS INBOUND MONOCHROME IMAGE DATA RECORD V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.pioneer_venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.pvo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:ouvs.pvo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.pvo-v-ouvs-5-imidr-v1.0__browserp_pvo-v-ouvs-5-imidr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Alexander, M.J., &apos;A Mechanism for the Venus Thermospheric Superrotation&apos;,
                   Geophys. Res. Lett., 19, 2207-2210, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ALEXANDER_1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Alexander, M.J., A.I. Stewart, S.C. Solomon, and S.W. Bougher, &apos;Local-Time
                   Asymmetries in the Venus Thermosphere&apos;, J. Geophys. Res., 98, 10849 -
                   10871, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ALEXANDER_ETAL_1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Bougher, S.W., J.C. Gerard, A.I. Stewart, and C.G. Fesen, &apos;Nitric Oxide
                   Airglow: Model Calculations Based on the Venus Thermospheric General
                   Circulation Model&apos;, J. Geophys. Res., 95, 6271-6284, 1990.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BOUGHER_ETAL_1990</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Esposito, L.W., M. Copley, R. Eckert, L. Gates, A.I Stewart, and H.
                   Worden, &apos;Sulfur Dioxide at the Venus Cloud Tops 1978-1986&apos;, J. Geophys.
                   Res., 93, 5267-5276, 1988.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ESPOSITO_ETAL_1988</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Phillips, J.L., A.I. Stewart, and J.G. Luhmann, &apos;The Venus Ultraviolet
                   Aurora: Observations at 130.4 nm&apos;, Geophys. Res. Lett., 13, 1047-1050.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PHILLIPS_ETAL_1986B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Stewart, A.I, &apos;Design and Operation of the Pioneer Venus Orbiter
                   Ultraviolet Spectrometer&apos;, IEEE Transactions on Geoscience and Remote
                   Sensing, GE-18, 65-70, 1980.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.STEWART_1980</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Stewart, A.I., D.E. Anderson, L.W. Esposito, and C.A. Barth, &apos;Ultraviolet
                   Spectroscopy of Venus: Initial Results from the Pioneer Venus Orbiter&apos;,
                   Science, 203, 777-779, 1979.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.STEWART_ETAL_1979</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Stewart, A.I., J.C. Gerard, D.W. Rusch, and S.W. Bougher, &apos;Morphology of
                   the Venus Ultraviolet Night Airglow&apos;, J. Geophys. Res., 85, 7681-7870,
                   1980.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.STEWART_ETAL_1980</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>PVO-V-OUVS-5-IMIDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>PVO V OUVS INBOUND MONOCHROME IMAGE DATA RECORD V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1995-09-27</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1978-12-05T12:03:07Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1992-07-24T00:53:02Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>A. Ian F. Stewart</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>not applicable</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Inbound Monochrome Image Data Record (IMIDR) is a set of
            rectified monochromatic images of Venus acquired by the Pioneer
            Venus Orbiter Ultraviolet Spectrometer (PVOUVS).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>not applicable</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    DATA SET OVERVIEW
    =================
 
      The Inbound Monochrome Image Data Record (IMIDR) is a set of
      rectified monochromatic images of Venus acquired by the Pioneer
      Venus Orbiter Ultraviolet Spectrometer (PVOUVS).  Each image is
      accompanied by a pseudo-image of several geometric parameters
      such as latitude and illumination angle, so that the parameters
      associated with a given pixel in the image can be found in the
      corresponding pixels in the pseudo-images.  The image size is
      128 x 128 pixels.  The pixel size is usually 125 x 125 km, but
      for some images larger pixel sizes are used.  If a given pixel
      is sampled more than once during the acquisition of an image,
      the appropriate signals and geometric variables are averaged;
      if a pixel is not sampled, the image and pseudo-images contain
      zeroes.
 
      The IMIDR provides a mission-long set of images at several
      far-UV and near-UV wavelengths associated with day and night
      airglow emissions and with reflected sunlight.  All Venus
      phases are sampled, as are all levels of solar activity during
      1978-1992.
 
      Descriptions of the scientific utility and past research uses of
      this data set can be found in the following references:
      STEWART_ETAL_1979, STEWART_ETAL_1980, PHILLIPS_ETAL_1986B,
      ESPOSITO_ETAL_1988, BOUGHER_ETAL_1990, ALEXANDER_1992, and
      ALEXANDER_ETAL_1993.
 
 
    PARAMETERS
    ==========
 
      The PVOUVS recorded the field-of-view-averaged brightness as
      the spacecraft rotated on its spin axis and moved along its
      orbit.  The brightness is reported in the images as counts / 4
      msec.  The length of the slit is typically several image
      pixels, and smearing in the north-south direction is present
      (it is noticeable at the southern limb).  The width of the slit
      is usually less than one pixel.
 
      The geometric variables associated with each image pixel depend
      on the sun-Venus-spacecraft geometry and on the spacecraft spin
      axis orientation.
 
 
    PROCESSING
    ==========
 
      The PVOUVS science data stream was screened for obvious noise
      spikes.  The instrument configuration was at times uncertain
      due to problems with uplink record-keeping and with on-board
      command execution.  When the uncertainties could not be
      resolved using the OUVS command plans and the downlinked
      science and instrument status data, the science data were
      discarded.
 
      The rectification is performed as follows.  The OUVS
      line-of-sight is offset from the spacecraft spin axis s by an
      angle a.  Each sample is characterized by the spacecraft
      position vector P and the line-of-sight unit vector l.  An
      image plane is defined whose normal z lies in the P,s plane and
      makes an angle 180-a with s.  Two unit vectors y and x are
      defined in the image plane: y lies in the P,s plane and points
      in the northern hemisphere, and x makes up a right-handed set
      with y and z.  The X and Y coordinates of the sample in the
      image plane are proportional to l.x and l.y, and its distance
      from the image origin is the length of the perpendicular from
      the planet center to the line-of-sight.  Note that the unit
      vector y is fixed throughout the image acquisition, but x and z
      rotate slowly about y as the spacecraft moves along its
      inclined orbit.
 
      Errors in the reported spin axis orientation s and spin rate w
      and in the data timing produced distorted rectifications.  w
      could be corrected using an OUVS internal spin rate monitor.
      Where necessary and possible, adjustments were made to s and to
      the data timing to produce an undistorted rectification.
 
 
    DATA
    ====
 
      The IMIDR consists of a set of structures, one per image, that
      contain an image and eight supporting pseudo-images, as follows :
 
      II.IMG  - the PVOUVS signal, expressed as counts per 4 msec
      II.BIN  - the equivalent number of 4-msec samples in each pixel
      II.RP   - the perpendicular distance from planet center to
                line-of-sight (km)
      II.SLAT - the colatitude measured from Venus&apos; north orbit pole (deg)
      II.SLON - the hour angle measured retrograde from Venus&apos; antisolar
      	        meridian (deg)
      II.LZA  - the local zenith angle between the Venus-centered
      	        spacecraft position vector and the line-of-sight (deg)
      II.SZA  - the illumination angle (deg)
      II.EMA  - the emission angle (deg)
      II.SCA  - the scattering angle (deg)
 
      Geometric parameters are evaluated at the intersection of the
      line-of-sight with a Venus-centered sphere of radius 6200 km
      (ie, altitude 150 km), or, if the line-of-sight does not
      intersect this sphere, at the point of closest approach to the
      planet&apos;s center.
 
 
    ANCILLARY DATA
    ==============
 
      SEDR tapes supplied by the Pioneer Project were used for all
      ancillary data concerning Venus&apos; orbit around the Sun, PVO&apos;s
      orbit around Venus, and PVO&apos;s orientation, spin rate, and spin
      phase.  All timing information came from the EDR tapes supplied
      by the Pioneer Project.  Information about the instrument
      configuration came from the EDR tapes.  Where possible, the
      data from these various sources and the science data from the
      instrument were cross-checked for consistency, and decisions
      about validity were made.  Instrument calibration information
      was obtained from pre-flight laboratory calibrations [STEWART_1980]
      and from several in-flight calibration operations using
      the stars Spica and Hadar.
 
 
    COORDINATE SYSTEM
    =================
 
      The coordinate system used for the images is described in the
      Processing section above.  The SLAT and SLON pseudo-images use
      a system of Venus colatitude measured from Venus&apos; orbital north
      pole and hour angle measured retrograde from the plane
      containing Venus&apos; orbit pole and the Sun-Venus vector.
 
 
    SOFTWARE
    ========
 
      No software is provided with this dataset.
 
 
    MEDIA/FORMAT
    ============
 
      The PV OUVS IMIDR will be available on compact disc write-once
      (CD-WO) media and on-line through the Planetary Atmospheres
      Node Home Page (http://atmos.nmsu.edu/).  Organization and formats
      will be according to PDS and ISO 9660 level 1 standards.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    CONFIDENCE LEVEL OVERVIEW
    =========================
 
      The major confidence issues associated with the IMIDR have to
      do with the instrument calibration and configuration,
      specifically the grating position (ie wavelength) at which the
      image was acquired.  The uncertainty in sensitivity is
      estimated to be +-30%.  The instrument grating position is
      secure when the telemetry format included the grating position
      monitor; when it did not, it is judged that a combination of
      the command planning and an assessment of image appearance
      yielded a high confidence level.
 
 
    DATA COVERAGE AND QUALITY
    =========================
 
      Command planning for OUVS for most of the PVO mission called
      for 4 monochromatic images per week on the dayside and 7 per
      week on the nightside, for a total of about 4000.  The actual
      number is substantially less, for one or more of these reasons:
        - Venus superior conjunctions
        - loss of telemetry due to spacecraft or DSN problems
        - intermittent failure of the OUVS grating control unit
        - inability to replace EDR/SEDR data lost on the ground
      The image set, despite these outages, cover the
      entire mission and provide adequate sampling in Venus phase,
      and solar activity (both solar rotation and solar cycle).
 
      There are many cases where only partial images were obtained.
      Most of these are included in IMIDR because of their
      contributions to studies of long-term variations.
 
      Image quality is affected by the following factors:
 
      - Instrument dark counts.  Normally the dark count rate was
      dominated by cosmic ray events in the detectors, and was about
      1/sec in both channels.  If the front face of the sunshade was
      sunlit, an extra 1.5 counts/sec appeared in the F-channel.  On
      a small number of orbits, dark counts due to the aftereffects
      of solar flares either contributed noticeably to or dominated
      the dark count rates.
 
      - Signal level.  In all of the airglow images the effects of
      counting statistics are evident. Images in reflected sunlight
      are generally free of this effect.
 
      - Instrument telemetry rate.  The OUVS readout frequency
      depended on the number of words assigned to OUVS in the
      telemetry format and on the downlink telemetry rate.  The
      frequency with which OUVS swaths across the planet were
      downlinked typically varied from about 25 to about 300 per
      hour, depending mostly on the Venus-Earth range.
 
      - Instrument integration period.  Images were acquired with
      integration periods of 8, 16, or 32 msec.  The image
      rectification algorithm assigned all the counts in a sample to
      the image pixel appropriate to the center of the sampling
      period.  Integration periods of 16 and especially 32 msec led
      to an undersampling of the grid of image pixels and a loss of
      spatial resolution in the east-west dimension.
 
      - Instrument slit length.  The length of the OUVS field of view
      (.024 rad) led to noticeable image smearing in the north-south
      dimension, more obvious at the southern limb which was viewed
      from ranges of 20000-50000 km.
 
 
    LIMITATIONS
    ===========
      The IMIDR is not a complete record of the appearance of Venus
      at all UV wavelengths.  Only selected wavelengths were studied,
      and many gaps in the data set exist.
 
 
    ERRATA
    ======
      The algorithm used to generate the IMIDR products described herein
      contained an error.  The error rejected valid data words but
      introduced no bias.  The OUVS instrument generated 256-word data
      blocks.  The algorithm assigned each word to the appropriate pixel in
      the rectified image, and accumulated the total counts and the number
      of words assigned to each pixel.  The final rectified image was then
      the ratio of the array containing accumulated counts to the array
      containing the number of assigned words, ie the average counts.  When
      more than one word within a given data block was assigned to a
      particular pixel, however, the algorithm discarded all but the last
      such word.  Thus, the average counts were obtained from a smaller set
      of words than were actually available.  No systematic errors in the
      IMIDR products result from this problem, except that the values in
      the .BIN array reflect the unintended rejection of valid data words.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

