<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lro-l-lend-4-5-rdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LRO LUNAR EXPLORATION NEUTRON DETECTOR 4/5 RDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:lend.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-lend-4-5-rdr-v1.0__browserp_lro-l-lend-4-5-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-lend-4-5-rdr-v1.0__dvo_geo_lro-l-lend-4-5-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-lend-4-5-rdr-v1.0__pds.geo.lro.orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mitrofanov, I.G., et al., Experiment LEND of the NASA Lunar Reconnaissance
                   Orbiter for high resolution mapping of neutron emission of the Moon,
                   Astrobiology, 8(4):793-804, 2008.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MITROFANOVETAL2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Planetary Data System Standards Reference, Jet Propulsion Laboratory Document
                   D-7669, Part 2, 20 March 2006.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PDSSR2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LRO-L-LEND-4/5-RDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LRO LUNAR EXPLORATION NEUTRON DETECTOR 4/5 RDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2010-03-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2010-03-15</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>WILLIAM BOYNTON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Boynton, W.V., 2009 Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter Lunar
            Exploration Neutron Detector RDR Data
            V1.0,LRO-L-LEND-4/5-RDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2009.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Calibrated or converted housekeeping and scientific data
            collected from the Lunar Exploration Neutron Detector aboard the
            Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Calibrated or converted housekeeping and scientific data
            collected from the Lunar Exploration Neutron Detector aboard the
            Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
       The Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter (LRO) Lunar Exploration
       Neutron Detector (LEND) that will act as large orbital neutron
       telescope for mapping the Moon&apos;s neutron albedo. LEND consists
       of eight 3He sensors for detecting thermal and epithermal
       neutrons, four of which are collimated to improve spatial
       resolution. LEND also contains the Sensor for High Energy
       Neutrons (SHEN), which is a stilbene scintillator that produces
       a flash of light each time a high energy neutron in the energy
       range 0.3 - 15.0 MeV collides with a hydrogen nucleus and
       creates a recoil proton. A full description of the LRO LEND
       instrument can be found in [MITROFANOVETAL2008].
 
       The LRO LUNAR EXPLORATION NEUTRON DETECTOR 4/5 RDR data set is
       a time series collection of rectified science data (RSCI),
       converted housekeeping data (CHK), derived science data (DLD),
       extended derived science data (DLX) and averaged science data
       (ALD).
 
       LEND collects a new spectrum (frame) approximately every
       second. Approximately 86400 spectra are expected to be received
       every day. The collection interval can be changed in the middle
       of a time series file, which can be determined by noting the
       difference between record timestamps. The data (both science
       and housekeeping) are downloaded from the spacecraft. Data are
       output to a spooler that passes them to the University of
       Arizona (UA) database ingest process. The ingest process inputs
       raw data into the UA database. Data are retrieved from the UA
       database to build the LEND RDR data products.
 
       The LEND RDR data set is intended to provide both intermediate
       (RSCI, CHK) and advanced (DLD, DLX, ALD) data products for the
       LEND instrument. This data should be useful to those scientists
       who are experienced in neutron spectroscopy.
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      The LEND RDR data set is composed of five data types,
      rectified science data (RSCI), converted housekeeping data
      (CHK), derived science data (DLD), extended derived science data
      (DLX) and averaged science data (ALD). The RSCI data type is the
      LEND science data with timing and spatial information added. The
      CHK data is the housekeeping data converted from digital number
      (as sent down from the spacecraft) to physical units. The DLD data
      type is a time series of science data for each of the nine LEND
      sensors that has been corrected for changes in detector efficiency
      and changes in the Cosmic Ray flux.  In addition, records
      corrupted by Solar Particle Events and known instrument
      anomalies have been removed. The DLX data type is an extension of
      the DLD data type, containing supplemental values useful for
      interpretation of DLD data. The ALD data type takes the
      DLD data and averages it over a spatial and temporal grid
      as defined below.
 
    Processing
    ==========
      A full description of the LEND data processing can be found in
      the RDR SIS located in the document folder that accompanies
      this release. The following paragraphs are a summary of how the
      data are processed from data receipt through averaging.
 
      LEND data are downloaded from the LRO spacecraft. The data are
      received by a process called LEND_tl that translates LEND
      packets from any source to any destination and examines
      instrument health via messages. The data are checked for packet
      type, header information, messages, or errors, and are output to
      a spooler and to a data display IDL program called LEND Displays
      Data sent to the spooler are passed to the UA database ingestion
      process, which inputs raw data into the UA database. Data sent
      to the LEND Displays program is recorded at IKI and held in a
      data repository.
 
      All data packets received by the LEND Displays program are
      processed for timing and spatial information. Once time data
      are extracted from the data packet, UTC time is calculated from
      the spacecraft time (time at the middle of the collection
      interval) by a SPICE function. The UTC time is then inserted
      into the database. The spatial portion of the data packet is
      calculated using other SPICE routines. The returned values are
      all the spatial elements of an observation, including latitude
      and longitude at the mid-point of the observation. The RSCI
      data are output once timing and spatial elements are calculated
      for each collection interval in a given day.
 
      The LEND housekeeping data is also ingested into the LEND
      relational database. Upon ingestion, database triggers are used
      to convert digital numbers in the housekeeping data into
      physical units. The CHK data is the converted housekeeping data
      and also includes the UTC time at the mid-point of the
      collection interval.
 
      The LEND instrument collects 11 neutron signals from nine
      independent detectors, whose response functions are sensitive
      to different energy regions. Raw neutron counts are reported in
      the LEND RCSI data set as a 16-channel spectrum for each of the
      eight 3He detectors (SETN, CSETN1, CSETN2, CSETN3, CSETN4, STN1,
      STN2, and STN3) and as 3 spectra for the stilbene detector
      (SHEN_Low, SHEN_gamma and SHEN_High). In the DLD data set,
      neutron counts for the 3He detectors are reported as the sum
      of counts in channels 9-16, corrected for detector efficiency
      and Cosmic Ray flux. The counts for the omnidirectional
      detectors (SETN, STN1, STN2, and STN3) have also been
      normalized to a 50km altitude.
 
      The stilbene scintillator records two
      neutron signals and a gamma signal. The neutron counts are
      reported as the sum of counts in channels 9 and above for each of
      the signals.
 
      As of Release 25, March 15, 2016, the complete DLD data set was
      redelivered, reflecting updated normalization procedures for
      generating the DLD data set. The LEND DLD data set is generated from
      the rectified science (RSCI) data set, following normalization to
      correct for various effects.  The data are normalized to correct for
      changes in count rate over time due to solar cycle cosmic-ray
      variations and any possible change in detector efficiency.  The data
      are also corrected for differences in efficiency between each of the
      detectors. The normalization values are determined by separately
      averaging the counts in each of the detectors measured early in the
      mission over the polar regions (poleward of 60 degrees).
 
      The background term reported for each collection interval is
      the galactic cosmic-ray flux induced
      background as measured in each detector during the cruise
      phase of the mission when the spacecraft was far from both the
      Earth and the Moon. The observed background count for the
      detector of interest must be multiplied by (1-omega(t)/4pi) where
      omega(t) is the solid angle subtended by Moon for the current
      position in the spacecraft orbit. The resulting term is the
      background counts in the particular collection interval for the
      detector of interest.
 
      Background subtracted count values for each of the eleven
      neutron signals (SETN, CSETN1, CSETN2, CSETN3, CSETN4, STN1,
      STN2, STN3, SHEN_Low, SHEN_gamma, and SHEN_High)
      are temporally and spatially binned to create the ALD data.
      This data is used to compare seasonal and geographic changes
      in the neutron flux. The temporal binning is synodic periods
      and the spatial binning is half degree cells above and below 80, -80
      degrees and one degree cells elsewhere. Membership
      in a temporal bin is determined by calculating the fraction of
      the collection interval time spent in each temporal cell.
      Membership in a spatial bin is determined by calculating the
      fraction of the collection interval length in a given spatial
      cell along the orbital trajectory projection on the Lunar
      surface. The temporally and spatially binned counts for
      each of the eleven signals are calculated by: 1) multiplying
      the background subtracted counts by the collection interval
      fraction and summing the result for each collection interval
      within the temporal interval 2) multiplying the duration
      (in seconds) of each collection interval by the collection
      interval faction and summing the result for each collection
      interval within the temporal interval 3) dividing the
      summed counts by the summed time to yield a counting rate in
      units of counts per second. The summed time is the EXPOSURE.
 
      The averaged counting rates are then normalized by the average
      counting rate from the region of the Moon defined as
      above. The normalization values for each signal are the
      *_NORMALIZATION fields given in the ALD data set. The
      normalization calculation yields the *_RATE fields, which can
      be used to create signal specific neutron maps. Because the
      rates are ratios of counting rates, they are unitless. Error
      fields, *_ERR, are also present for each of the signals. The
      errors are simply based on the counting statistics for the raw
      LEND counts.
 
      The conversion of normalized counting rates to neutron fluxes
      requires knowledge of the efficiency of each of the neutron
      detectors. Efficiency functions, derived from model
      calculations and direct calibrations, describe the directional
      and energy dependent response of each of the nine LEND
      detectors to bombardment by neutrons. A series of Monte-Carlo
      simulations will be run to calculate the efficiency of each
      LEND detector. The simulations will account for the composition
      and geometry of the LEND instrument. In parallel, a series of
      experimental calibration measurements will be carried out to
      understand the quality of the Monte-Carlo simulations. Two
      types of experiments will be performed. The first experiment
      measures the LEND response to monoenergetic neutron sources
      with known spectra and the second measures the LEND response
      to energetic neutron fluxes. The combined results of the
      numerical simulations and the experiments yield detector
      specific efficiency functions.
 
      As a further analysis of the data, calculations will be made
      with MCNPX for various models of the Moon. The neutron flux at
      the spacecraft predicted by these calculations will be fitted
      with a power law, AE^-alpha. The power law spectrum is then
      multiplied by the nine efficiency functions to obtain computed
      counting rates in the LEND detectors. These computed counting
      rates are compared to the real counting rates in via a Pearson
      minimizing procedure. The values, A and alpha, for the model
      that best satisfy the minimization criterion, are inserted into
       the ALD as the NEUTRON_NORM and ALPHA fields.
 
      The NEUTRON_NORM and ALPHA values are used to estimate
      the neutron flux (n/(cm^2-s)) at the LRO orbit in different
      ranges of epithermal and fast neutrons (EPITHERMAL_FLUX1
      100 eV - 10 KeV, EPITHERMAL_FLUX2 10 KeV - 1 MeV, FAST_FLUX1
      1 MeV - 2.5MeV, and FAST_FLUX_2 2.5 MeV - 10 MeV) for each
      map grid by taking the integral of the
      neutron spectrum as described by A and alpha over the energy
      interval. See the RDR SIS located in the Documents directory
      that accompanies this release for further details.
 
    Data
    ====
 
     CHK
     ---
      The converted housekeeping data is simply composed of the
      digital number to physical unit converted housekeeping data plus
      associated timing and spatial data. The data is recorded in a
      time-series, and is grouped by day.
 
     RSCI
     ----
     The rectified science data is simply the LEND science data with
     additional timing and spatial data added in. The RSCI is similar
     to the EDR SCI data except that it includes all spacecraft
     positional information and UTC time conversions. Data is
     recorded as a time-series
 
     DLD
     ---
      Derived LEND data are composed of corrected detector counts,
      background counts, and the associated timing and
      spatial information.  The eleven background count fields are
      derived from count data collected during the
      cruise phase of the mission. The eleven detector
      count fields are the corrected  counts at the
      detector of interest over one collection interval. Timing and
      spatial data provided with the counts include spacecraft clock
      values and spacecraft geometry data. The times and spatial
      fields are all recorded at the center of the collection interval.
 
     DLX
     ---
      Extended derived LEND data provide supplemental data for DLD
      data, including detector count uncertainties, a calculated sum
      of corrected counts in the 4 CSETN detectors, and the associated
      timing information. The times are all recorded at the center of
      the collection interval.
 
     ALD
     ----
      Averaged LEND Data products are composed of averaged
      normalized counting rates and the
      associated timing, spatial and engineering information. The
      ALDs consists of the cumulative background subtracted and
      normalized counts of neutrons at the nine LEND detectors
      averaged over the 0.5 latitude longitude and a synodic period.
      Please refer to the RDR SIS located in the documents directory
      that accompanies this release for a full description of how LEND
      spectra are processed to yield averaged normalized counting
      rates and orbital neutron fluxes. The timing and spatial data
      provided with each ALD record include the time and spatial range
      over which the average was generated.
 
     ALF
     ----
      Averaged LEND Fluxa products are composed of orbital neutron fluxes
      and the associated timing, spatial and engineering information. The
      ALFs consists of the cumulative background subtracted and
      normalized counts of neutrons at the nine LEND detectors
      averaged over the 0.5 latitude longitude and a synodic period.
      Please refer to the RDR SIS located in the documents directory
      that accompanies this release for a full description of how LEND
      spectra are processed to yield averaged normalized counting
      rates and orbital neutron fluxes. The timing and spatial data
      provided with each ALD record include the time and spatial range
      over which the average was generated.
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
     Ancillary data needed to understand the LEND data processing
     can be found in the RDR SIS document located in the document
     folder that accompanies this release.
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
     Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter (LRO) reduced data record (RDR)
     data use lunar planetocentric/body-fixed coordinates with
     east-positive longitude from 0 to 360 degrees.  A mean
     Earth/polar axis (ME) reference system (also called the mean
     Earth/rotation system) is used, with the z axis being the mean
     rotational pole and with the prime meridian (zero degrees
     longitude) defined by the mean Earth direction.
 
     The ME reference system is used for all LRO archival data. This
     LRO standard is documented in &apos;A Standardized Lunar Coordinate
     System for the Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter, LRO Project White
     Paper, 451-SCI-000958, Version 3, January 30, 2008&apos;.  Using
     coordinates in the ME system is consistent with recommendations
     from the International Astronomical Union (IAU)/International
     Association of Geodesy (IAG) Working Group on Cartographic
     Coordinates and Rotational Elements.
 
     A Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) planetary and lunar ephemeris
     and corresponding Euler angle set are used to define an ME frame
     to which the LRO data are registered.  The LRO Data Working
     Group (LDWG) determines which ephemeris and Euler angle set
     should be used.  Alternatively, LRO data can be registered to an
     existing or new reference frame in the ME system, via ties to
     surface points known in the frame (examples include Lunar Laser
     Ranging (LLR) retroreflectors, points in images and Digital
     Elevation Models).
 
     When a JPL planetary and lunar ephemeris is used, the JPL
     Navigation and Ancillary Information Facility (NAIF) provides
     the necessary lunar ephemeris file (SPK) and binary lunar
     orientation file (PCK) in a Principal Axes (PA) reference frame
     for use with the SPICE Toolkit. NAIF also provides the frames
     kernel (FK) used for accessing the PA orientation in the PCK and
     for transforming from the PA frame to the ME frame.
 
     Alternatively, the JPL lunar ephemeris information is available
     in an ASCII format not requiring the use of the SPICE Toolkit.
     This information is available from a JPL website:
     http://ssd.jpl.nasa.gov.
 
    Software
    ========
     No LEND specific software is provided with this data set.
 
     PDS-labeled images and tables can be viewed with the program
     NASAView, developed by the PDS and available for a variety of
     computer platforms from the PDS web site
     http://pds.nasa.gov/tools/software_download.cfm. There is no
     charge for NASAView.
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The LEND RDR will be delivered using DVD media. Formats will be
      based on standards for such products established by the
      Planetary Data System (PDS) [PDSSR2006].
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      The data presented in the LEND RDR is processed for engineering
      units and combined with converted timing. Accuracy of the data
      presented here is dependent on appropriate use of SPICE and
      pre-flight calibration data for engineering unit conversions.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      The LEND RDR was reviewed internally by the LEND team prior to
      release to the PDS. PDS also performed an external peer
      review of the LEND RDR.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Data reported are derived from the minimally processed data
      received from the orbiter during nominal LEND operations. All
      data received is reformatted into one of the EDR data types.
      RDR data is produced from the EDR data set, which by
      definition is of good quality.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    The RDR data set is limited by any errors in the EDR data set.
 
  Data Compression
  ===============
    No data compression is used.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

