<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ear-a-3-rdr-apd-polarimetry-v8.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ASTEROID POLARIMETRIC DATABASE V8.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.support_archives::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.publit::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:compil.publit::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.asteroid::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-a-3-rdr-apd-polarimetry-v8.0__browserp_ear-a-3-rdr-apd-polarimetry-v8.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lupishko, D.F., and R.A. Mohamed, A New Calibration of the Polarimetric Albedo
                   Scale of Asteroids, Icarus 119, 209-213, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LUPISHKO-MOHAMED1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>EAR-A-3-RDR-APD-POLARIMETRY-V8.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ASTEROID POLARIMETRIC DATABASE V8.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2014-05-16</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1958-10-22</start_time>
        <stop_time>2014-02-10</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>CAROL NEESE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Lupishko, D., Ed., Asteroid Polarimetric Database V8.0.
            EAR-A-3-RDR-APD-POLARIMETRY-V8.0. NASA Planetary Data System,
            2014.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Compilation of published and unpublished polarimetry results for
            asteroids through Feb. 10, 2014.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Asteroid Polarimetric Database (APD) is a collection of
            asteroid polarimetry results compiled by D.F. Lupishko of Karazin
            Kharkiv National University, Ukraine. It is intended to include
            most asteroid polarimetry available through Feb. 10, 2014.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
  The Asteroid Polarimetric Database (APD) is compiled by D.F. Lupishko of
  Karazin Kharkiv National University, Ukraine.  This database tabulates the
  original data comprising degree of polarization as a function of phase angle
  of the asteroid, and additional parameters where available.  The data
  included are published asteroid polarimetry for which observation dates are
  available, and unpublished asteroid polarimetry data which are provided to
  Lupishko along with the dates of observation.  The last column of the APD
  file is a reference code consisting of the publication year and name of the
  first author.  The full citations for the papers may be found in the
  accompanying reference list file, apdrefs.asc, in the document directory.
  For convenience, the list of references has also been included in the data
  directory with a data label.  For unpublished data, the code Unpubl. along
  with the name of the observer is used.  This version of the APD is current
  through Feb. 10, 2014.
 
  Modification History
  ====================
  This data set was first reviewed and ingested in 1996, and was updated in
  1997 with additional polarimetric data published since then, as well as an
  added table of derived polarimetric parameters including polarization curves
  and polarimetric albedos of selected asteroids.  In 1999, 2000, and 2006,
  2008, and 2012 the data set was updated again with additional polarimetric
  observations published since the previous version.
 
  The 2012 version (V7.0) adds 214 new observations of 45 asteroids.  The
  additions include the 2004 Torino observations of Itokawa, which had been
  archived in a separate data set, EAR-A-I0066-3-ITOKAWAPOL-V1.0.  Thus this
  version supersedes the Itokawa polarimetry data set.
 
  In 2012, the polarimetric curves table, apdcurv.tab, was moved from the data
  directory to the document directory because it has not been updated since
  1999 and since then several more recent analyses have been published.
 
  In 2014, the data set was updated to version V8.0 with the addition of 332
  new entries of polarimetric results from five additional papers.  The new
  papers included are
 
    1. Gil-Hutton, R. and Canada-Assandri, M. (2012) Astron. Astrophys, 539,
  A115. DOI: 10.1051/0004-6361/201117237
    2. Canada-Assandri M., Gil-Hutton R., Benavidez P. 2012. Astron.
  Astrophys, v. 542, A11.
    3. Gil-Hutton R., Canada-Assandri M. 2011. Astronomy &amp; Astrophys, v. 529,
  A86.
    4. Masiero J. 2010.  Icarus, v. 207, No. 2, p. 795-799.
    5. Velichko F.P., Magnusson P. 2012. Astronomicheskii Tsirkulyar, a1575,
  p.1-2.
 
  Parameters
  ==========
  The parameters tabulated in &apos;apd.tab&apos; are filter, phase angle, degree of
  polarization, polarization position angle, position angle of the scattering
  plane, and both degree of polarization and position angle in the proper
  coordinate system measured from the perpendicular to the scattering plane.
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
 
  Parameters of the polarimetric curve for individual asteroids, as well as
  polarimetric albedos, are compiled in the file &apos;apdcurv.tab&apos;, originally in
  the data directory.  This file reproduces the data in Table 2 of Lupishko
  and Mohamed (1996) [LUPISHKO&amp;MOHAMED1996], and was updated in 1999 with
  slightly revised values for four asteroids.  Since it is now outdated, it
  has now been moved to the document directory.
 
  The entries in &apos;apd.tab&apos; include a reference to the published paper in which
  the data appeared, and to the observatory and telescope where the
  observations were made.  The full references of the papers cited may be
  found in the file &apos;apdrefs.asc&apos; in the document directory, and in the file
  apdrefs.tab in the data directory.  A general compilation of asteroid
  polarimetry papers is also included in the file &apos;polrefs.asc&apos; in the
  document directory.  The telescopes and observatories are listed in the
  document &apos;polobs.asc&apos;.
 
  A pdf document providing plots of polarization as a function of phase angle
  for typical asteroids of G, B, C, M, S, V, and E types, as well as a table
  of average albedos and polarization phase dependences for the main asteroid
  types, is included in the document directory.
 
  References
  ==========
 
  Lupishko, D.F., and R.A. Mohamed, A New Calibration of the Polarimetric
  Albedo Scale of Asteroids, Icarus 119, 209-213, 1996.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
  This is a compilation of asteroid polarimetry results from the published
  literature.  The user is referred to the individual publications for
  information on the confidence level of any given observation.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

