<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.co-x-uvis-2-wav-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CASSINI ORBITER N/A UVIS IMAGE AT ONE WAVELENGTH</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:uvis.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.co-x-uvis-2-wav-v1.0__browserp_co-x-uvis-2-wav-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.co-x-uvis-2-wav-v1.0__browser_co-x-uvis-2-wav-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Esposito, L.W., J.E. Colwell, K. Larsen, W.E. McClintock, A.I.F. Stewart, J.
                   Tew Hallett, D.E. Shemansky, J.M. Ajello, C.J. Hansen, A.R. Hendrix, R.A. West,
                   H.U. Keller, A. Korth, W.R. Pryor, R. Reulke, and Y.L. Yung, Ultra-Violet
                   Imaging Spectroscopy shows an active Saturn system, Science, 307, 1251-1255,
                   2005, LASP reprint 1000.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ESPOSITOETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CO-X-UVIS-2-WAV-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CASSINI ORBITER N/A UVIS IMAGE AT ONE WAVELENGTH</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1999-01-07T00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>LARRY ESPOSITO</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Esposito, L. (et al.), Cassini Ultraviolet Imaging Spectrograph
            Jupiter Flyby Data, NASA Planetary Data System,
            CO-X-UVIS-2-WAV-V1.0, 2005.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            A set of images at one wavelength.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Imaging of the Saturn system at a wavelength in the far or
            extreme ultraviolet.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
     The UVIS Image at One Wavelength Dataset
     ========================================
          The UVIS instrument is part of the remote sensing payload of
       the Cassini orbiter spacecraft.  UVIS has two spectrographic
       channels that provide images and spectra covering the ranges
       from 56 to 118 nm and 110 to 190 nm.  A third optical path
       with a solar blind CsI photocathode is used for a high signal-
       to-noise ratio stellar occultation by rings and atmospheres.
       A separate hydrogen deuterium absorption cell measures the
       relative abundance of deuterium and hydrogen from their lyman-
       alpha emission.  These channels are referred to as EUV, FUV,
       HSP, and HDAC in this document.  The UVIS science objectives
       include investigation of the chemistry, aerosols, clouds, and
       energy balance of the Titan and Saturn atmospheres; neutrals
       in the Saturn magnetosphere; the deuterium-to-hydrogen ratio
       for Titan and Saturn; icy satellite surface properties; and
       the structure and evolution of Saturns rings.
  	       The basic instrument design adapts proven design concepts using
       a grating spectrometer followed by a multi-element detector.
       We chose to use imaging, pulse-counting microchannel plate
       detectors because of more than a decade of experience using
       this kind of detector equipped with a CODACON readout anode.
       The CODACON (Coded Anode Array Converter) acts as a photon
       locator.  The photon counts are accumulated in an external
       memory to build a picture that is periodically read out for
       transfer to the spacecraft memory and eventually, transmission
       to the ground.  The two dimensional format for the CODACON
       detectors allows simultaneous spectral and one-dimensional
       spatial coverage.  The detector format is 1024 x 64 (spectral
       by spatial).
          The Cassini HDAC consists of a channel electron Multiplier
       photodetector equipped with 3 absorption cell filters:  a
       hydrogen cell, a deuterium cell and an oxygen cell.  The
       oxygen cell is not utilized in flight.  The hydrogen and
       deuterium cells function as adjustable absorption filters.
       In each cell a hot tungsten filament disassociates the
       hydrogen and deuterium molecules into atoms, producing an
       atomic density determined by each of 16 different filament
       temperatures.  These atoms resonantly absorb the hydrogen and
       deuterium Lyman-alpha lines passing through the cells.
       Cycling the filaments on and off and comparing the
       differences in signal gives a direct measurement of the
       relative hydrogen and deuterium signals.  Each cell has two
       filaments controlled by separate filament current
       regulators.  Only one filament at a time per cell is used
       during flight.  A Pulse Amplifier Discriminator detects
       photoelectrons from the CEM and sends pulses to the UVIS
       instrument logic.    contains a high speed photometer with an
       integration time as short as 2.0 ms to observe stars occulted
       by the rings of Saturn.  The photon counts collected from the
       photocathode are passed as a time ordered sequence to the
       instrument, then to spacecraft memory for transfer to the ground.
          The data in a UVIS observation are a copy of what was in
       the UVIS memory buffer. That is, the observation consists of
       unprocessed experiment data stored in binary format. An
       observation belongs to one of four different types of data
       product: a spectrum, a time series of spatial-spectral
       images, a time series of detector counts, or an image at one
       wavelength.  Each observation has a unique identifier that
       associates it with a time range and with the configuration of
       the instrument during that time.  Each data product will
       contain one observation and will be completely defined by a
       PDS label.  The objects will be correct in the sense that
       they will conform to PDS formatting requirements and will be
       consistent with data archived by the UVIS team.  They will be
       complete in that they will represent all data taken by the
       UVIS instrument.  In addition, CODMAC level 3 data products
       will be derivable from the archived data and an associated
       set of calibration data.
          The UVIS instrument can generate
       an image data product from the FUV or EUV detectors.  These
       images consist of a sequence of lines.  A line is a sequence
       of 1 to 64 integers representing detector counts in the
       spatial dimension.  Each line in the image will contain data
       taken from the same detector column. Each line will contain
       data taken during a fixed time interval.  The lines in the
       sequence will be time ordered.  A data product (also referred
       to as an observation) consists of a set of data taken during
       a single instrument configuration.  The image at one
       wavelength product will be archived as a 1024x64x1 PDS Qube.
       When windowing or binning is defined the data will be located
       in a sub-region of the Qube as described in the SPECDS.CAT and
       CUBEDS.CAT. documents.  All instrument configuration data for
       an observation including window, bin, and integration time
       specifications will be contained in the associated PDS label.
          For a detailed description of the UVIS instrument see the file
       ROOT/DOCUMENT/UVIS.TXT on this archive volume.
 
      Parameters
      ==========
          The following observation types are found on this volume.
 
      UFPSCAN: Interplanetary hydrogen survey.  The purpose of this
      observation type is to search for and measure Lyman Alpha
      emissions while scanning the interplantary medium.
 
      The observation type for each observation is found in OBSERVATION_TYPE
      column of INDEX.TAB.  The specific purpose of each observation
      may be found in the object DESCRIPTION field contained in the label.
 
      Processing
      ==========
      The observation data products are generated by the Laboratory for
      Atmospheric and Space Physics at the University of Colorado using
      the Data Archiving and Processing System (DAPS) software.  This
      software receives telemetry packet SFDUs from the Telemetry Data
      System, extracts science and engineering data, archives the data
      in a database management system and produces PDS data and label
      object files located on a CD-ROM or DVD physical storage medium.
 
      All time information is generated from the spacecraft clock using
      the Cassini SCLKSET files.  The DAPS system uses NAIF software and
      project generated SPICE Kernels to generate pointing information.  All
      of these values are contained in the PDS object label.
 
      Data
      ====
      A UVIS spatial spectral cube is a time ordered sequence of
      1024 x 64 matrices in which each element of the matrix is the number
      of counts taken at an individual detector pixel during a fixed time
      interval.  The time interval is set in the instrument configuration
      associated with the observation.
 
      UVIS is capable of windowing and binning the EUV and FUV detectors.
      In these more complex cases, each integer in the cube corresponds
      to a rectangular subregion of detector cells and is derived by summing
      over the spatial and spectral dimensions.  For example, if the binning
      defined on the spectral and spatial dimensions is two, the cube consists
      of 32x512 integers, where each integer is derived by summing the
      counts from disjoint 2x2 subregions of the detector.  The PDS Qube
      object is a sequence of 1024x64 samples, in which all data are located
      in a 32x512 sub-region in the upper left hand corner, located at (0,0).
      All other locations in the PDS Qube contain null values.  A still more
      complex case involves cubes derived from a set of sub regions of the
      detector called windows.  In this case, the detector is divided into a
      set of active rectangular sub regions (windows).  Each window can also
      be binned in the manner just described.  The data stored in the PDS
      Qube are located in the upper left hand corner of the window.  For
      example, if a detector window is defined with its upper left corner
      at (10,10) and its lower right corner at (20, 20) and its binning is
      defined to be (2,2) then the data for the Nth sample is found in the
      rectangle with a upper left corner equal to (10, 10, N) and a lower
      right hand corner equal to (15, 15, N) in the 1024x64 sample of the
      PDS Qube.
      A data product (also referred to as an observation) is a cube
      generated  during a particular instrument configuration, including
      pointing and  instrument set up.  All instrument configuration
      information including window, bin and integration time specifications
      are contained in the PDS object label.
      The following diagrams illustrate these configurations as contained in
      a sample of a PDS Qube.
 
      0   ***************************
          *ddddddddddddddddddddddddd*
          *ddddddddddddddddddddddddd*
          *ddddddddddddddddddddddddd*
          *ddddddddddddddddddddddddd*
          *ddddddddddddddddddddddddd*
      64  ***************************
      0                       1024
 
      Fig. 2.2.2.1 An unbinned, single windowed sample where d is data.
 
 
      0  ***************************
         *ddddddddddddnnnnnnnnnnnnn*
         *ddddddddddddnnnnnnnnnnnnn*
      32 *ddddddddddddnnnnnnnnnnnnn*
         *nnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnn*
         *nnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnn*
      64 ***************************
      0          512         1024
 
      Fig. 2.2.2.2 An unbinned window with an upper left hand corner at 0, 0,
      and a lower right hand corner at 512, 32.  Where d is data, n is null.
 
      0  ***************************
         *dddddnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnn*
         *nnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnn*
      32 *nnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnn*
         *nnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnn*
         *nnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnn*
      64 ***************************
      0   256    512         1024
 
      Fig. 2.2.2.3: A window binned by 32 in the spatial dimension and 2 in the
      spectral dimension with an upper left hand corner at 0, 0, and a lower
      right hand corner at 512, 32.  Where d is data and n is null.
 
      0  ***************************
         *dddddnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnn*
         *nnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnnn*
      32 *nnnnnnnnnnndddddddddddddd*
         *nnnnnnnnnnndddddddddddddd*
         *nnnnnnnnnnndddddddddddddd*
      63 ***************************
      0   256    512         1023
 
      Fig. 2.2.2.4: Two windows where the first is binned by 32 in the
      spatial dimension and 2 in the spectral dimension and where the first
      has an upper left hand corner at 0, 0, and a lower right hand corner
      at 512, 32.  The  second is unbinned with an upper left hand corner at
      512, 32 and a lower right corner at 1023, 63.  Where d is data and n
      is null.
 
      Calibration data are used to transform detector counts into
      geophysical units. The EUV, FUV channels have an associated
      calibration process.  FUV and EUV  data are converted to Rayleighs.
      The UVIS team supplies calibration data files.  The calibration
      process is described below and in the PDS label file associated with
      the calibration. data file.
 
      Calibration data consist of an MxN matrix and a scalar value.  Each
      matrix  and scalar should be used to scale the individual integrations
      of a raw  data product.  The result is a calibrated data product which
      is isomorphic  to the original containing data in units of
      kilorayleighs.   In addition, each calibration data product contains a
      mapping of detector lines to  wavelengths which is stored in the BAND
      BIN_CENTER keyword value.
 
      Calibration data are archived as a PDS Qubes with the dimensions
      1024x64x1  or 1024x1x1.  All instrument configuration data for the
      observation is  contained in the associated PDS label; in addition the
      label contains  instructions for using the calibration data and a
      detector column to  wavelength mapping and the scalar multiplier
      which is stored in the  CORE_MULTIPLIER value).
 
      In addition to this mechanism, non-standard calibration routines
      developed by UVIS team members may be provided.  These routines may
      require  user input and control.  These procedures are not supported
      nor are their  validity guaranteed, however to the extent that they
      are intended for  general use by the UVIS team, we will submit
      algorithms and associated data  and documentation.
 
      Ancillary Data
      ==============
      The UVIS team supplies calibration data files and the algorithms used
      to generate the FUV and EUV calibration data.  The calibration
      algorithms are archived as text files in the SOFTWARE/CALIB directory
      of the PDS data volume. The file names contain channel and version
      information.  These algorithms  generate calibration data which is
      located in the CALIB/VERSION_n/...  directories.  The algorithms are
      provided as a description of the process by which calibration data is
      generated.  They are not used to calibrate raw data.
 
      Coordinate System
      =================
      In the UVIS data products, all time values that are represented as
      strings  are in UTC time.  All time values are derived from the
      spacecraft clock  using the SCLKSCET translation table supplied by
      the  Cassini project.  All pointing data are expressed in the J2000
      coordinate system.
 
      Software
      ========
      LASP provides software for reading PDS data products.  This software
      is  located in the ROOT/SOFTWARE/READERS directory.  The software
      requires Java 1.4 compatible class libraries and RSI/IDL version 6.
      Instructions for running the  routines are located in the file
      READERS_README.TXT, located in the same directory.
 
      These readers are provided as a convenience for users to access the
      data. Users may choose another approach if desired.  The readers
      enable users to load PDS objects into an RSI/IDL process where they
      are represented as 3  dimensional arrays of integers corresponding to
      the PDS Qube object in which they are stored.  PDS label data are
      stored in an IDL structure variable.
 
      DISC FORMAT
      =================================================================
      This disc has been formatted so that a variety of computer systems
      (e.g. IBM PC, Macintosh, Sun, VAX) may access the data.  Specifically,
      the disc is formatted according to the UDF-Bridge DVD format
      standard which provides ISO 9660 level 2 standard compatibility.
      For further information, refer to the ISO 9660 Standard Document:
      RF# ISO 9660-1988, 15 April 1988.
 
      Specific to the ISO 9660 level 2 standard, filenames on this CD
      conform to the 27.3 file naming convention i.e.,
      1.  The file name portion may be up to 29 characters long; or
      2.  The extension may be up to 29 characters long,
      3.  In no case, however, may the total file name length, including
      the . exceed 31 characters.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      Confidence Level Overview
      =========================
      The UVIS data objects are organized into separate observations.
      Each observation contains data taken from one configuration of
      the instrument.  There may be more than one observation generated
      from one instrument configuration.  This may occur because science
      data generated by the UVIS instrument is dropped when corrupted
      data is detected or transmission failures occur.  The UVIS ground
      system detects this and divides the data into two observations, one
      terminated prior to the data drop the next beginning immediately
      afterword.  The start time and duration of an observation correspond
      to the actual times of the first and last records in the observation.
      Incomplete observations are filled with zeroes.  Over 95% of data
      taken by the instrument is contained in the UVIS archive.
 
      Only one hardware feature affects UVIS data.  A light leak in the
      instrument casing causes an increase in the background counts in
      the lower half of the EUV channel wavelength range.  This effect is
      detectable by visual inspection of a graph of the data.  No tools
      for detection or correction of these background counts exists.
 
      One anomaly in the flight software caused data errors to appear
      when multiple windows which do not cover the entire EUV or FUV
      detector are defined.  In an observation, the data errors appear
      as randomly located spikes in detector count values, and one
      completely incorrect spatial line located at a random spatial
      index.  These errors are detectable by visual inspection of a
      plot of the data.  The anomaly was fixed by a revison to the
      software and effects data between launch and 2001-071 09:00:00 UTC
 
      Review
      ======
      This volume has completed a peer review by the PDS. The peer review
      panel consisted of Lyle Huber, Mitch Gordon, Steven Adams, Ron Joyner
      and Mark Vincent representing PDS, David Judd and Wayne Pryor from the,
      UVIS team Diane Connor from the Cassini Project and Kurt Retherford
      and John Clarke as outside users.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

