<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mer2-m-mtes-4-btr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MER2 MARS MINIATURE THERMAL EMISSION SPECTROMETER BTR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_exploration_rover::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mer2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mini-tes.mer2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer2-m-mtes-4-btr-v1.0__browser_geo_mer2-m-mtes-4-btr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer2-m-mtes-4-btr-v1.0__dvo_geo_mer2-m-mtes-4-btr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer2-m-mtes-4-btr-v1.0__pds.geo.mer.analysts_notebook::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CHRISTENSEN2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mars Exploration Rover Mission, Mini Thermal Emission Spectrometer
                   Software Interface Specification, 2003
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MTESSIS2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MER2-M-MTES-4-BTR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MER2 MARS MINIATURE THERMAL EMISSION SPECTROMETER BTR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2004-08-03</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-01-06T03:47:45.803Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>Phil Christensen</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Christensen, Phil, MER 2 Mars Mini-TES BTR V1.0, NASA Planetary
            Data System, MER2-M-MTES-4-BTR-V1.0, 2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains Mini-Thermal Emission Spectrometer
            (Mini-TES) Science Brightness Temperature Reduced Data Records
            (BTRs) acquired by Spirit (MER 2) during the Mars Exploration
            Rover Mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This archive contains Mars Exploration Rover Miniature Thermal
            Emission Spectrometer (Mini-TES) Brightness Temperature Reduced
            Data Record (BTR) products and ancillary files. The Mini-TES BTR
            products archived on this volume are the original products used
            during mission operations by the Mars Exploration Rover project.
            Supporting documentation and label files conform to the Planetary
            Data System (PDS) Standards, Version 3.6, Jet Propulsion
            Laboratory (JPL) document number D-7669.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set contains data that will help determine the mineralogy
    of Martian rocks and soils, determine the thermophysical properties
    of soil patches, and determine the temperature profile, dust
    opacity, water-ice opacity, and water vapor abundance in the lower
    boundary layer of the Martian atmosphere. The Mini-TES calibrated
    radiance is the primary data product for the MER mission. These data
    will be converted to effective emissivity and surface temperature by
    fitting a Planck blackbody function to the calibrated spectrum. The
    emissivity spectra will be converted to mineral abundance using a
    linear deconvolution model and a matrix of mineral spectra from the
    ASU Mineral Library and other sources. The derived surface
    temperature will be used to produce thermal inertia images via a
    thermal model, using data from multiple times of day where possible
    Attempts will be made to coordinate these diurnal observations with
    the times of TES or THEMIS direct overflights, providing
    simultaneous temperature observations that can be extended to
    broader regions surrounding the rovers.
 
    The Mini-TES will also view upward at angles up to 30 degrees above
    the horizon to provide high-resolution temperature profiles of the
    Martian boundary layer. This upward-viewing mode will yield high-
    resolution temperature profiles through the bottom few km of the
    atmosphere using temperatures retrieved from the wings of the 15-mm
    CO2 band. This lowest region of the atmosphere has been difficult to
    measure on Mars because of the nature of the weighting functions as
    seen from orbit, and because of the difficulty of determining
    surface contributions to radiance.
 
    Atmospheric water abundance will be obtained by vertical and
    horizontal viewing of rotational H2O lines. Separate measurements of
    water near the ground will be obtained by viewing distant surface
    obstacles. The broad water-ice feature centered near 800 cm^-1 will
    allow monitoring of ground ice hazes. Together, these measurements
    will illuminate the behavior of water in lower atmosphere and of
    water transport between the atmosphere and surface. Atmospheric dust
    abundance will be obtained using the redundant temperature
    information in both sides of the 15 mm CO2 band, together with
    differential absorption across the dust band in that region.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The Mini-TES data products comply with NASA processing level
    standards.  All Mini-TES products are spectral image QUBEs derived
    from the previous level product.
 
    RDRs, BTRs, and EMRs will be produced in succession by the Mini-TES
    Team and placed into the OSS for distribution. If a data product
    needs to be regenerated for any reason, the original version will be
    overwritten with the new version. The new version may have a version
    number revision in the file name and will contain updates to keyword
    values and History objects within the header.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    Each Mini-TES data product consists of a single file of header
    objects attached to a spectral cube. There are 4 fundamental parts
    of a data product:
 
    1) an attached PDS label in ASCII format, composed of keyword-value
       pairs
 
    2) a History object, describing the processing history that the data
       product has gone through; this ASCII object is a set of ODL
       statements, similar to the PDS keyword-value pairs
 
    3) a table of binary, fixed-length records (available in EDRs only);
       table records are the internal calibration spectra and their
       associated telemetry values
 
    4) a spectral cube, containing either interferogram data or radiance
       spectra and organized by azimuth and elevation with housekeeping
       and telemetry values attached as suffix backplanes
 
    The size of a data product will vary from sequence to sequence
    depending upon the size of the image commanded and the processing
    level completed. The average expected size of the data in an EDR
    from a 2-hour panoramic scan will be approximately 1.7MB.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    ASU has provided data processing software, called &apos;calibrate_qube&apos;,
    which converts EDR data into calibrated RDR data and the successive
    higher level data products: BTR and EDR.  If necessary,
    interferogram data are converted via FFT into raw radiance spectra.
    Raw radiometric data is calibrated using available calibration
    target observations, both internal and external, and the known
    Mini-TES instrument response function as described in &apos;The Mini-TES
    Data Processing Guide&apos;.  The calibration software is executed on the
    ASU hyper-spectral analysis system called Davinci.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    The data set will initially be delivered and kept online. Upon
    Mission completion, the Mini-TES BTRs will be delivered to PDS
    on DVD.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
NULL
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

