<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-e-v-h-mascs-4-virs-ddr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER E/V/H MASCS 4 VIRS DERIVED DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mascs.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-4-virs-ddr-v1.0__browserp_mess-e-v-h-mascs-4-virs-ddr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-4-virs-ddr-v1.0__browser_geo_mercury_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-4-virs-ddr-v1.0__browser_mess-e-v-h-mascs-4-virs-ddr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-4-virs-ddr-v1.0__dvo_geo_mess-e-v-h-mascs-4-virs-ddr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   McClintock, W.E., and M.R. Lankton, The Mercury Atmospheric and Surface
                   Composition Spectrometer for the MESSENGER mission, Space Science Reviews, 131,
                   481-521, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MCCLINTOCK-LANK2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-E/V/H-MASCS-4-VIRS-DDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESSENGER E/V/H MASCS 4 VIRS DERIVED DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-05-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2008-014T19:12:55Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-120T09:47:27Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>NOAM IZENBERG</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Izenberg, N., MESSENGER E/V/H MASCS 4 VIRS DERIVED DATA V1.0,
            MESS-E/V/H-MASCS-4-VIRS-DDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2013.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The MESSENGER MASCS VIRS derived observations consist of science
            and instrument data collected by the VIRS detector during flyby
            and orbital operations of Mercury.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== This data set consists of the MESSENGER MASCS
            VIRS derived observations, also known as DDRs. The MASCS VIRS
            experiment is a fixed concave grating spectrograph with a beam
            splitter that simultaneously disperses the spectrum onto two
            photodiode arrays. There are two VIRS DDR data products, one for
            each array, which result in coverage of the wavelength ranges of
            the visible (VIS) and near infrared (NIR).
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
   Data Set Overview
   =================
     This data set consists of the MESSENGER MASCS VIRS derived data
     records (DDRs). Each VIRS observation results in data from two
     spectral regions. The spectra cover the wavelength ranges of the
     visible (VIS) (300-1050 nm) and near infrared (NIR)
     (850-1450 nm), with a resolution of 5 nm. There is a data overlap
     with UVVS in the VIS wavelength range. There are three standard
     VIRS EDR data products: VIS data, NIR data, and Housekeeping
     data. The housekeeping EDR contains instrument parameters that
     may be useful in analyzing the VIRS data. Housekeeping data are
     incorporated into the two standard CDR data products (one each
     for VIS and NIR). DDR products (one each for VIS and NIR) are
     generated from on-planet (flyby and orbit) CDRs.
 
   Instrument Overview
   ===================
     The MASCS instrument consists of a small Cassegrain telescope
     that simultaneously feeds the UVVS and VIRS experiments. The
     MASCS VIRS experiment is a fixed concave grating spectrograph
     with a beam splitter that simultaneously disperses the spectrum
     onto two solid-state array detectors: a 512-element silicon
     photodiode array, with a sensitivity to visible wavelengths
     (300-1050 nm), and a 256-element indium-gallium-arsenide
     photodiode array, to measure near infrared wavelengths
     (850-1450 nm). The VIRS detector will help to measure the surface
     reflectance and search for ferrous bearing minerals, Fe-Ti
     bearing phases, and ferrous iron on the surface of Mercury. See
     the INST.CAT file for more information and [MCCLINTOCK&amp;LANK2007]
     for full details.
 
   Parameters
   ==========
     The principal parameters when observing with the MASCS VIRS are
     as follows:
 
     * Integration Time: The amount of time that the array detectors
     will integrate photon counts. Unit is 50 milliseconds.
 
     * Integration Count: The amount of integrations that will be
     taken.
 
     * Period: The interval time after which another integration will
     be started. Integrations are started at the top of every period.
     Time between integrations is the period time minus the
     integration time. Unit is 0.05 second.
 
     * Dark Frequency: The frequency at which dark counts will be
     collected during a VIRS observation. For an entered number n,
     dark counts will be collected every nth integration.
 
     * NIR Gain: Sets the gain of the NIR array detector, to either
     low, high, or N/A when the VIS detector is enabled.
 
     * NIR Lamp On: The NIR flat field lamp is powered on or off.
 
     * VIS Lamp On: The VIS flat field lamp is powered on or off.
 
     * Binning: The number of pixels that were binned together in the
     data.
 
     * Start Pixel: Start pixel of data captured by the detector
     array. For VIS, the value can be from 0-511. For NIR, the value
     can be from 0-255.
 
     * End Pixel: End pixel captured by the detector array. The end
     pixel value must be greater than the start pixel value.
 
   Derived Product Overview
   ========================
     This data set consists of MASCS VIRS Derived Data Records (DDRs)
     (calculated from the EDRs and CDRs as described in the SIS). The
     DDRs are the processed data records of derived surface
     reflectance used for scientific analysis. The science DDRs
     contain Mercury surface reflectance measured by the VIRS
     detectors. DDRs also contain photometrically corrected versions
     of the reflectance data. The VIRS instrument shutter can be
     closed for on-board dark observations, or the instrument can be
     pointed to empty space for space-darks.
 
     The processing steps from the CDR to the DDR level include:
 
     1. Eliminate all CDR data not pointed at Mercury from
        consideration.
 
     2. Eliminate dark and lamp calibrations.
 
     3. Eliminate CDR data with stuck shutter due to elevated
        temperatures.
 
     4. Divide VIRS radiance at sensor by solar irradiance spectrum
        convolved to VIRS wavelengths and scaled for solar distance.
 
     5. Keep CDR saturated values as NaN or invalid number.
 
     6. Propagate errors the same way.
 
     7. Apply photometric correction.
 
     The processing steps are detailed in the documents
     VIRS_CDR_DDR_SIS and VIRS_CDR2DDR, located in the DOCUMENT
     directory.
 
   Coordinate Systems
   ==================
     MASCS VIRS data are represented in the following coordinate
     systems:
 
     * Planetocentric body fixed: The MBF coordinate system is defined
     by the planetocentric position, Cartesian X, Y, Z coordinates
     related to the planetocentric distance, latitude measured
     positive northward from the equator, and longitude measured
     positive eastward from the prime meridian.
 
     * Cartographic: Surface observations use IAU planetocentric
     system with East longitudes being positive for planetary
     surfaces. The MESSENGER-derived reference system
     (pck00010_msgr_v21.tpc) for cartographic coordinates and
     rotational elements was used for computing latitude and longitude
     coordinates of planets.
 
   Data
   ====
     There are two VIRS DDR data products, one for each detector
     (VIS, NIR). Housekeeping and pointing data from the MASCS EDR
     and CDR are passed through to the DDR product.
 
     The DDR for either the VIS or NIR detector consists of entries
     for the spacecraft time and orientation, target location, values
     for the observing parameters set for the given observation, and
     information about the observation, and is followed by the science
     spectral data. On each detector, the pixel number can be mapped
     to a specific wavelength, allowing a resultant spectra to be
     created. One observation can generate a variable number of
     spectra. All of the data from one commanded observation are
     contained in one CDR.
 
     A separate DDR is created for the VIS and NIR data. Normal MASCS
     operations will acquire data for both VIS and NIR detectors
     simultaneously.
 
     Some CDR data are excluded from conversion to DDR. CDRs of
     shutter-closed observations (dark and lamp calibrations) and
     where the VIRS footprint is always in shadow (on Mercury
     nightside) and/or off the planet, are excluded.
 
     When VIRS is very hot (&gt;44C) the shutter begins to behave
     erratically, failing to close entirely at hotter instrument
     temperatures. This results in bad dark solutions for hot
     VIRS observations beginning in the second mission year,
     primarily in the hot seasons. Observations identified as having
     shutter-dark issues are not released to PDS.
 
     A list of DDRs excluded from delivery (VIRS_DDR_EXCLUDED.TXT) is
     included in the EXTRAS directory. This file will be amended as
     new observations are affected during hot seasons, and as new dark
     subtraction and synthesis methods are developed to mitigate at
     least some of the observations.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
   Confidence Level Overview
   =========================
     The MASCS VIRS Derived Data Record (DDR) consists of the derived
     data converted to units of reflectance and represented in
     physical coordinate systems. Data presented here are an accurate
     representation of the VIRS data as received from the spacecraft,
     and reflect the processing steps from the MASCS VIRS Calibrated
     Data Records (CDRs) to DDR level detailed in the document
     VIRS_CDR2DDR and located in the DOCUMENT directory. The UTC and
     MET time tags have been corrected for timing latencies in the
     instrument so that the UTC and MET correspond to the physical
     time of the observation.
 
   Review
   ======
     The VIRS DDR was reviewed internally by the MASCS team prior to
     release to the PDS. PDS also performed an external review of the
     MASCS VIRS DDRs (both VIS and NIR detectors have separate DDR
     types).
 
   Data Coverage and Quality
   =========================
     Data reported are the derived data received from the spacecraft
     during the flyby and orbital mission phases: Mercury 1 Flyby,
     Mercury 2 Flyby, Mercury Orbit, Mercury Orbit Year 2, Mercury
     Orbit Year 3, Mercury Orbit Year 4, and Mercury Orbit Year 5.
     These mission phases are defined as:
 
                                Start time         End time
     Phase Name                 Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)
     -------------------------  -----------------  ----------------
     MF1: Mercury 1 Flyby       31 Dec 2007 (365)  28 Jan 2008 (028)
     MF2: Mercury 2 Flyby       22 Sep 2008 (266)  20 Oct 2008 (294)
     ORB: Mercury Orbit         04 Mar 2011 (063)  17 Mar 2012 (077)
     OB2: Mercury Orbit Year 2  18 Mar 2012 (078)  17 Mar 2013 (076)
     OB3: Mercury Orbit Year 3  18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)
     OB4: Mercury Orbit Year 4  18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)
     OB5: Mercury Orbit Year 5  18 Mar 2015 (077)  30 Apr 2015 (120)
 
 
     To validate the initial DDR dataset, the MASCS team did the
     following:
 
        * Examined several days of Mercury orbit data in detail.
 
            - Checked all data columns for format and sanity numbers.
            - Compared calibration numbers for earlier independent
              analysis before DDR development.
            - Compared reflectance and photometric conversions to
              previous independent solutions.
 
        * Spot checked additional data sets from orbit.
 
     The orbital DDR dataset was evaluated on an ongoing basis,
     checking for completeness and data integrity.
 
     MASCS VIRS data were collected during all phases except
     Venus 1 Flyby, but only resolved Mercury surface data from flybys
     and orbit are converted to DDR. Data quality information for DDR
     observations is the same as the DQI of matching CDRs.
 
     Cruise operations/observations have additional details in the
     Master Cruise Table (a Microsoft Excel file) in the Extras
     directory.
 
   Limitations
   ===========
     This data set is derived data.  The data are received from the
     spacecraft telemetry and ingested into the MESSENGER Science
     Operations Center (SOC), then run through the MASCS pipeline. No
     data uncharacterized gaps have been identified for any of the
     MASCS operational periods.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

