<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mgn-v-rss-5-gravity-l2-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MGN V RSS SPHERICAL HARMONIC AND GRAVITY MAP DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.magellan::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mgn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.mgn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgn-v-rss-5-gravity-l2-v1.0__browserp_geo_mgn-v-rss-5-gravity-l2-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgn-v-rss-5-gravity-l2-v1.0__dvo_geo_mgn-v-rss-5-gravity-l2-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Special issue, The Geophysics of Venus, Icarus, 112, 1-295, 1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ICARUSMGN1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Konopliv, A.S., and W.L. Sjogren, Venus Gravity Handbook, Jet Propulsion
                   Laboratory Publication 96-2, January 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KONOPLIV-SJOGREN1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Konopliv, A.S., N.J. Borderies, P.W. Chodas, E.J. Christensen, W. Sjogren, B.G.
                   Williams, G. Balmino, and J.P Barriot, Venus Gravity and Topography: 60th
                   Degree and Order Model, Geophysical Research Letters, 20, 2403-2406, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KONOPLIVETAL1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   McNamee, J.B., N.J. Borderies, and W.L. Sjogren, Venus: Global Gravity and
                   Topography, Journal of Geophysical Research, 98, 9113-9128, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MCNAMEEETAL1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Archival Tracking Data File Data Record (ATDFDR), Magellan Software
                   Interface Specification: DSN Document 820-13, Rev. A, TRK-2-25, Jet
                   Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, 1986.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MGN-ATDFDR1986</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Navigation Constants File Data Record (NCFDR), Magellan Software Interface
                   Specification: NAV-103, Rev. A, Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA,
                   1991.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MGN-NCFDR1991</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Orbit Data File Data Record (ODFDR), Magellan Software Interface
                   Specification: DSN Document 820-13, Rev. A, TRK-2-18, Jet Propulsion
                   Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, 1988.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MGN-ODFDR1988</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Small Forces File Data Record (SFFDR), Magellan Software Interface
                   Specification: SES-121, Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, 1987.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MGN-SFFDR1987</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Moyer, T.D., Mathematical Formulation of the Double-Precision Orbit
                   Determination Program (DPODP), TR 32-1527, Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena,
                   CA, 1971.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MOYER1971</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Moyer, T.D., Changes to the ODP and the ODE for processing X-Band Uplink
                   Data, EM-314-430, Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, 1987.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MOYER1987</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Planetary Data System Standards Reference, Jet Propulsion Laboratory Document
                   D-7669, Part 2, 20 November 1992
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PDSSR1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MGN-V-RSS-5-GRAVITY-L2-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MGN V RSS SPHERICAL HARMONIC AND GRAVITY MAP DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1997-08-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1992-09-15</start_time>
        <stop_time>1994-10-12</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>WILLIAM L. SJOGREN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Sjogren, W. L., MGN V RSS SPHERICAL HARMONIC AND GRAVITY MAP DATA
            V1.0, MGN-V-RSS-5-GRAVITY-L2-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            1997
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This archive contains Magellan spherical harmonic models of Venus
            gravity and topography field, and digital maps of the Bouguer
            anomalies, free-air gravity accelerations and errors, geoid
            anomalies and errors, and topography.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The gravitational signature of Venus was determined from velocity
            perturbations of the Pioneer Venus Orbiter (PVO) and the Magellan
            spacecraft as measured from the Doppler shift of the S-band and
            X-band radio tracking signal. The spacecraft were tracked by
            NASA&apos;s Deep Space Network (DSN) at Goldstone, California,
            Canberra, Australia, and Madrid, Spain. The tracking data were
            used to determine the spacecraft orbits about Venus, as well as
            the Venusian gravity field. A detailed description of how the
            spacecraft orbits were computed and an assessment of their
            quality can be found in [KONOPLIV&amp;SJOGREN1996]. For
            information on Magellan gravity investigations see papers in
            [ICARUSMGN1994].
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The gravitational signature of Venus was determined from
      velocity perturbations of the Pioneer Venus Orbiter (PVO) and
      the Magellan spacecraft as measured from the Doppler shift of
      the S-band and X-band radio tracking signal. The spacecraft
      were tracked by NASA&apos;s Deep Space Network (DSN) at
      Goldstone, California, Canberra, Australia, and Madrid, Spain.
      The tracking data were used to determine the spacecraft orbits
      about Venus, as well as the Venusian gravity field. A detailed
      description of how the spacecraft orbits were computed and an
      assessment of their quality can be found
      in [KONOPLIV&amp;SJOGREN1996].  For information on Magellan gravity
      investigations see papers in [ICARUSMGN1994].
 
 
    Data
    ====
      This dataset includes a 120th degree and order spherical harmonic
      gravitational field model and digital gravity maps of the Bouguer
      anomalies, free-air gravity anomalies, free-air gravity errors,
      geoid anomalies, and geoid anomaly errors.
 
      There are three data types for the products found on this volume:
      tabular, array, and image data.
 
      The file containing the spherical harmonic coefficients of the
      Venusian gravity field is in tabular format, with each row in the
      table containing the degree index m, the order index n, the
      coefficients Cmn and Smn, and the uncertainties in Cmn and Smn.
 
      The digital maps of Bouguer anomalies, free-air gravity anomalies,
      free-air gravity errors, geoid anomalies, and geoid anomaly errors,
      are binary images.  There are also ASCII 2-D gridded data arrays
      of all the digital map products, including a byte-scaled image of
      each of these gridded products.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      The gravitational signature of Venus was determined from
      velocity perturbations on the Pioneer Venus Orbiter and
      Magellan spacecraft as measured from the Doppler shift of
      the S-band and X-band radio tracking signal. The Doppler
      data from the DSN stations were acquired with count intervals
      of 1 minute and 10 seconds.
 
      The free-air gravity anomalies (in milligals, mGals, where
      1 mGal = 0.01 mm/s^2) are evaluated at the surface. The
      free-air gravity  errors are also in mGals. Geoid anomalies
      and errors are in meters.  Bouguer anomalies, determined by
      subtracting the gravitational attraction of the surface
      topography from the free-air anomaly, are in mGals.
 
      The free-air gravity values are given by the radial
      (or vertical) acceleration at the reference surface. This is
      the radial gradient of the gravity potential. The reference
      surface is a sphere with radius 6051.0 km. The GM for the
      potential expansion is 324858.5897 km^3/s^2 (from the
      120th degree and order gravity field solution).
 
      The bouguer map is the actual free-air gravity minus the
      theoretical free-air gravity from the topography with no
      compensation. The acceleration difference is at the
      reference surface of 6051.0 km. The reference radius for
      the topography field is 6051.848044 km.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The gravity solution consists of over 3,304,000 observations,
      of which 204,000 were contributed by PVO. The data were
      divided into independent arcs based on considerations of
      data coverage and timing of maneuvers. For each arc certain
      parameters were determined: the spacecraft state (position and
      velocity), a solar radiation pressure coefficient, Doppler
      biases for each station over the arc to account for frequency
      biases, and the mismodeling of the effects of the troposphere
      and ionosphere on the Doppler signal. The a priori model
      that was used included the [KONOPLIVETAL1993] gravity model,
      and included the third-body perturbations due to the Sun,
      the Earth, and all the planets, the solar radiation pressure
      perturbation, the solar-induced solid tides, and appropriate
      relativistic effects. The DE403 planetary ephemeris was used
      in the analyses.
 
      Although each data arc was typically fit to the level of
      less than 0.1 mm/sec, the data were downweighted in order to
      attenuate the power of the high degree terms, and account
      for any systematic mismodeling that might still be present
      in the data. The solution was also derived using an a
      priori constraint that was applied where data coverage was
      poor. This constraint is explained in detail in
      [KONOPLIV&amp;SJOGREN1996].
 
      Extensive experiments were performed in order to select the
      a priori weights for the sets of data in the solution -- and
      care was taken to downweight or delete data that produced
      spurious signals in the anomaly maps.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      Many of the spacecraft parameters can be found in the Navigation
      Constants Document, [MGN-NCFDR1991]. There is a small force
      record, [MGN-SFFDR1987], which lists the times and duration of
      the momentum dumps. There were several maneuvers and their times
      and durations are given in the Maneuver Profile Listing (MPL)
      data product. The spacecraft orientations are all listed in the
      Spacecraft Attitude During Hide Maneuver Listing (SADHML) data
      product.
 
      On every orbit the spacecraft orientation changed with the high
      gain antenna pointing at Venus or at the Earth or some other
      direction to keep the spacecraft temperature within safe bounds.
      The transmitter ramp rates and initiation times are listed in
      the ODFDR (Orbit Data File Data Record) and ATDFDR
      (Archival Tracking Data File Data Record) [MGN-ODFDR1988;
      MGN-ATDFDR1986]. The  equations to incorporate the ramp data
      as well as the complete theoretical Doppler observable are
      given in [MOYER1971; MOYER1987].
 
      A useful product for understanding the errors in the gravity
      solution is the gravity field covariance matrix.  The gravity
      field covariance represents the complete error description for
      the SHG120 gravity field solution, including the coefficient
      variances (sigmas^2), and the correlations between all the
      coefficients.  It is a product of the least squares solution
      that derived SHG120.  The covariance provides a more complete
      description of the error associated with the SHG120 gravity
      field solution, than would be available from the sigmas alone.
      The covariance matrix is large (~857 MB) since it contains the
      correlations of each of the solution parameters with all the
      other parameters. (SHG120 solved for 14756 spherical harmonic
      coefficients, and the Venusian GM value). The full covariance
      matrix was used to compute the error maps for the gravity
      anomalies, and geoid anomalies that are associated with this
      archive. The covariance matrix is available via the internet
      through the World Wide Web:
      http://pds-geophys.wustl.edu/pds/magellan/harmonics_maps_archive.
 
      The covariance matrix is also available on request from the PDS
      Geoscience Node (contact Jim Alexopoulos at 314-935-5365 or
      jim@wuzzy.wustl.edu) or from JPL (contact Alex Konopliv at
      818-354-6105 or ask@krait.jpl.nasa.gov).
 
      More Magellan gravity data and documents are available via the
      internet through the PDS Geophysics Subnode World Wide Web site:
      http://pds-geophys.wustl.edu/pds/magellan
 
      NOTE: All the ancillary data and information to process and
      interpret the Doppler data are located at the PDS Geosciences
      Node, Washington University, St. Louis, MO.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      The coordinate system for the gravity data reduction is
      space-fixed earth-mean-equator referenced to J2000. The
      integration was done in a Venus centered frame. The earth
      orientation parameters were given by the University of Texas,
      Center of Space Research, solution EOP (CSR) 95 L 01.
 
 
    Software
    =========
      N/A
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      This archive will be available electronically via the World-Wide
      Web and anonymous FTP transfer:
      http://pds-geophys.wustl.edu/pds/magellan/harmonics_maps_archive.
      The archive will also be delivered to the National Space Sciences
      Data Center (NSSDC) using compact disk write once (CD-WO) media.
      Formats will be based on standards established by the Planetary
      Data System (PDS).
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      The data noise on the PVO Doppler data ranged from
      0.3 to 1 mm/s, depending on the arc, and most of the data
      were at a count interval of 60 seconds. The  Magellan Doppler
      data from the DSN stations had a data noise of &lt;0.1 mm/s with
      a count interval of 10 seconds.
 
      Errors in the free-air gravity anomalies ranged from
      ~2-12 mGals over the equatorial region (+/- 30 degrees
      latitude), and 15-21 mGals over the high-latitudes.
 
      Errors in the geoid range from ~0.1-2.3 meters.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      The volume containing the Venusian gravity and topography data
      sets was reviewed by Magellan mission scientists and by PDS.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      The Magellan spacecraft was inserted into orbit about Venus on
      August 10, 1990.  The first three cycles (one cycle is one
      Venus rotation period of 243 days) were dedicated to SAR
      imaging and altimetry measurements of the Venus surface. These
      measurements required the high gain antenna to be pointed to
      the Venus surface within about thirty minutes of periapsis
      passage. Thus only high-altitude tracking (&gt;2500 km) was
      obtained when the high gain antenna was returned to point at
      Earth. These data still contain some low resolution
      information on the gravity field and they were used by
      [MCNAMEEETAL1993].  The altitude of periapsis for the first
      three cycles is 250 km and is higher than the cycle four,
      which was dedicated to gravity measurements. Except for the
      periapsis altitude, the orbit shape for cycle four is
      identical to the previous cycles and should contain all the
      gravity information that is in the previous cycles and more.
      In addition to the first three cycles, the modeling of the
      solar pressure force for a rotating antenna through
      periapsis passage is complicated, and solar pressure is a
      significant force for the higher periapses due to diminished
      drag. For these reasons, the first three cycles of data are
      not included in the gravity solution.
 
      There was a week of Doppler periapsis data during the period
      of January 17 to 24, 1992, when the battery was being
      recharged.  The data were at S-Band from the medium gain
      antenna and periapsis was at 280 km.  From April 22 to
      May 16, 1992 (23 days), the periapsis was at 261 km, and
      periapsis data at X-Band were acquired for 16 orbits.  Other
      than these two prior blocks of data, all Doppler gravity
      data from August 1990 to September 1992 were obtained
      when the spacecraft&apos;s altitude was well above 2000 km.
 
      From September 15, 1992 to May 24, 1993 (Cycle 4), the first
      block of high quality and high resolution gravity data were
      acquired.  Periapsis was lowered to 180 km and coverage
      across periapsis was obtained continuously for 360 degrees
      of longitude. Periapsis latitude remained essentially
      constant at 10 degrees N latitude and good resolution was
      maintained within +/- 30 degrees (i.e.  40 degrees N to
      20 degrees S where spacecraft altitudes reached ~450 km).
      There were only a few days where no data were obtained, but
      in general excellent data coverage was maintained providing
      at least two orbits per day and much of the time four or
      five orbits per day.  All of these were X-Band uplink and
      downlink having a noise level of 0.1 mm/sec.  In addition
      there were also two or more orbits with S-Band coverage
      each day.
 
      From May 1993 to August 6, 1993, The Magellan spacecraft
      successfully completed an aerobraking sequence that nearly
      circularized its orbit. This new orbit provided high
      resolution data in the high latitude regions which
      previously had poor gravity model determination.  The orbit
      had a periapsis altitude of 180 km and an apoapsis of
      550 km and provided ~300 - 400 km altitudes over the high
      latitude regions.  The orbital period changed from
      195 minutes to 94 minutes, so there were approximately
      15 orbits per day.
 
      Because of operational sequencing of the onboard computers
      and the necessity to orient the spacecraft for thermal
      conditions, the first good coherent X-Band data were acquired
      on Aug 19, 1993.  There were some short S-Band data blocks
      starting on August 6, 1993.  The data during aerobraking are
      on ODFDR and ATDFDR files, but were not used for any of the
      gravity experiment reductions.  The Doppler data acquired
      during aerobraking were all S-Band at relatively high
      altitudes.  There were no data near periapsis since the
      spacecraft was oriented with its high gain antenna pointed
      along the spacecraft velocity vector and not toward the
      earth.  The daily coverage in this orbit was excellent with
      data for several orbits every day.  However orbital geometry
      of the Earth and Venus have made the coverage redundant for
      some longitudes and non-existent for others.
 
      There was a solar conjunction on January 16, 1994 and as a
      result data from January 6, 1994 to January 26, 1994 are very
      noisy and essentially non-usable for gravity extraction.  The
      data immediately after solar conjunction have low altitude
      passes over Maxwell Montes and provide the very best
      information on this unique feature.
 
      From June 22 to July 14, 1994 (orbits 13298-13635), the
      Doppler radio tracking on each orbit of Magellan was cut
      short due to inadvertent spacecraft event sequencing of
      the thermal control where the spacecraft was turned-off of
      earth-pointing (loss of radio contact) earlier than it should
      have been. This was corrected in the next up-load to the
      spacecraft, making the arcs about another 10 minutes longer.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      N/A
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>89-033B-02E</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>89-033B-02I</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

