<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.vg1-j-spice-6-spk-v2.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>VG1 JUPITER SPICE SPK KERNEL V2.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.voyager::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vg1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.vg1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vg1-j-spice-6-spk-v2.0__browserp_vg1-j-spice-6-spk-v2.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Acton, C.H., The SPICE System - A Brief Overview, Navigation and Ancillary
                   Information Facility, JPL, 1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ACTON1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Acton, Jr. C.H., Ancillary Data Services of NASA&apos;s Navigation and Ancillary
                   Information Facility, Planetary and Space Sciences, 44, Number 1, pp. 65-70,
                   1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ACTON1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>VG1-J-SPICE-6-SPK-V2.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>VG1 JUPITER SPICE SPK KERNEL V2.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1998-05-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1979-02-05T23:59:59.999Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1979-04-08T23:59:59.998Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>NAVIGATION ANCILLARY INFORMATION FACILITY</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            VG1 JUPITER SPICE SPK KERNEL V2.0
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Version 2.0 ----------- This data set replaces the Voyager 1
            Jupiter SPICE data set (DATA_SET_ID = VG1-J-6-SPK-V1.0).
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
 
    Version 2.0
    -----------
      This data set replaces the Voyager 1 Jupiter SPICE data set
      (DATA_SET_ID = VG1-J-6-SPK-V1.0).
 
 
    Data Set Description
    --------------------
      This data set includes the spacecraft trajectory and allied
      planet and satellite ephemeris (SPK) kernel for the Voyager 1
      Jupiter encounter, plus copies of the generic planetary
      constants (PCK) kernel, and the leap seconds (LSK) kernel.
      The SPK kernel provides ephemeris information for the period
      1979-02-05 to 1979-04-08 for Voyager 1, Jupiter, Metis,
      Adrastea, Thebe, Amalthea, Callisto, Ganymede, Europa, Io,
      Earth, Moon, the Sun, and the Barycenters for all nine major
      planets.  This file is provided in both PC binary (EBCDIC)
      and IEEE (Sun) binary format.  The PCK kernel contains
      information specifying Jupiter&apos;s size, shape, and
      orientation.  The LSK kernel is used for transforming between
      ephemeris time, the time system used in the SPK and PCK
      files, and UTC time (also referred to as Spacecraft Event
      Time or SCET).  Both the PCK and LSK kernels are provided in
      ASCII format.
 
      The PCK kernel is PCK_version 00003 (1990-06-25).  The LSK
      kernel includes leap seconds through 1991-01-01.  Information
      regarding the SPK version and contents are detailed below.
 
      This data set is a NAIF SPK file, which is the realization of
      the SPICE S and P-ephemeris kernels.  The SPICE S kernel is
      the logical component of the SPICE kernel concept which
      contains spacecraft trajectory data (position and velocity in
      a Cartesian reference frame).  The SPICE P-ephemeris kernel
      is the logical component of the SPICE kernel concept which
      contains target (one or more of planet, satellite, comet,
      asteroid) ephemeris data (position and velocity in a
      Cartesian reference frame).
 
      NAIF provides a software toolkit, called SPICELIB, containing
      the Fortran 77 source code subroutines which a user needs to
      read SPK files.  Those intending to use SPK kernel files
      should order this SPICELIB toolkit from the PDS (if it is not
      already on hand) and integrate appropriate modules into their
      own applications program.  Users should NOT attempt to write
      their own software to read SPK kernels files.
 
      SPICELIB software is highly documented via internal headers,
      and some additional documentation is available in separate
      SPICELIB ASCII text files called Required Reading files.  The
      SPK Required Reading File, identified as SPK.REQ, describes
      the use of the SPK kernel readers.
 
      This particular data set is a merge of five SPK source files.
      Four of these (T790210, T790213, T790303, and T790318) were
      made from standard Voyager NAV Team archival products which
      were made for SEDR production.  The fifth source file was
      (JUP024_VGR) made from a post-encounter satellite ephemeris
      file which contains ephemeris data for satellites which were
      not included in the standard Voyager NAV Team archival
      products.  These source files are summarized below.
 
 
                                                    NAIF_ID FOR EACH
                                                    BODY INCLUDED
  NAV ID  START TIME           STOP TIME            (See key below)
  --------------------------------------------------------------------
  T790210 1979 FEB 06 00:00:00 1979 FEB 13 00:00:00 1 through 10, 301,
                                                    399, 501 through
                                                    505, 599, -31
  T790213 1979 FEB 13 00:00:00 1979 FEB 19 00:00:00 1 through 10, 301,
                                                    399, 501 through
                                                    505, 599, -31
  T790303 1979 FEB 19 00:00:00 1979 MAR 03 00:00:00 1 through 10, 301,
                                                    399, 501 through
                                                    505, 599, -31
  T790318 1979 MAR 03 00:00:00 1979 APR 09 00:00:00 1 through 10, 301,
                                                    399, 501 through
                                                    505, 599, -31
  JUP...  1979 FEB 01 00:00:00 1979 NOV 03 00:00:00 505, 514 through
   024_VGR                                          516, 599
 
      NAIF body IDs are used within SPICE kernels to label data for
      a specific body.  These IDs must be employed as arguments in
      the SPICELIB SPK kernel readers.
 
      Users might note that not all those bodies for which data are
      available in this file are listed in the Data Set Target
      Template below.
 
      Key to NAIF_IDs:
 
      1 through 9 are planet-satellite system barycenters for
      Mercury through Pluto respectively.
 
      199 through 999 are planet mass centers for Mercury through
      Pluto.
 
      10 is the SUN.
 
      nxx are satellites, where n is the parent planet number.
      Thus, n=3 for Earth, n=4 for Mars, n=5 for Jupiter, etc.
      Satellites which may be found in this particular SPK file
      are: 501=IO, 502=EUROPA, 503=GANYMEDE, 504=CALLISTO,
      505=AMALTHEA, 514=THEBE, 515=ADRASTEA, 516=METIS.
 
      Spacecraft are identified using the numeric IDs assigned by
      JPL&apos;s Deep Space Network (DSN), but with a minus sign
      preceding the number.  Thus Voyager 1 is -31 and Voyager 2 is
      -32.
 
      Processing Level Id            : 6
      Software Flag                  : Y
      Processing Start Time          : 1987-03-26
      Processing Stop Time           : 1989-08-29
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    N/A
 
 
  Source Instrument Parameters
  ============================
    N/A
 
 
  Measurement Information
  =======================
    N/A
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
 
    Processing History
    ------------------
      Source Data Set ID          : NAIF 18
      Software                    : SPICELIB
      Product Data Set ID         : VG1-J-6-SPK-V1.0
 
      Source Data Set ID          : NAIF 19
      Software                    : SPICELIB
      Product Data Set ID         : VG1-J-6-SPK-V1.0
 
      Source Data Set ID          : NAIF 20
      Software                    : SPICELIB
      Product Data Set ID         : VG1-J-6-SPK-V1.0
 
      Source Data Set ID          : NAIF 21
      Software                    : SPICELIB
      Product Data Set ID         : VG1-J-6-SPK-V1.0
 
      Source Data Set ID          : NAIF 121
      Software                    : SPICELIB
      Product Data Set ID         : VG1-J-6-SPK-V1.0
 
 
    Software &apos;SPICELIB&apos;
    -------------------
      SPICELIB contains hundreds of ANSI FORTRAN 77 source code
      subroutines and functions for calculating instrument
      observation geometry.  This software is intended to be
      integrated into a user&apos;s own science analysis application
      programs.  Included in this library are readers for the SPICE
      kernels, which are the principal data sets used in computing
      instrument viewing geometry, or for planning data taking
      sequences.
 
      Additional software is available for then computing such
      items as latitude, longitude, phase angle, and emission angle
      of an instrument&apos;s principal point, or nearly any other
      geometric parameter of interest.
 
      Software Name               : SPICELIB
      Software Type               : NIN
      Software Release Date       : 1990-02-05
      Node ID                     : NAIF
      Cognizant Engineer          : CHARLES H. ACTON
      Software Access Description : NOT ACCESSIBLE THROUGH PDS
                                    CATALOG - CONTACT PDS/NAIF NODE
 
      Note that this is not the official archive for these SPICE
      kernels.  The PDS/NAIF node plans to officially archive these
      data on a separate volume.  These data are provided here for
      use with software designed to generate trajectory or perform
      coordinate transformations.
 
      To learn more about SPICE, or for information about how to
      acquire the official archive version of these kernels, or the
      SPICELIB software, please contact Charles H.  Acton of the
      PDS/NAIF node (INTERNET: cacton@spice.jpl.nasa.gov, DECNET:
      NAIF::CACTON, PHONE: (818)354-3869 ) or check the PDS
      website&apos;s (http://pds.nasa.gov/) link to the NAIF node
      for current NAIF contact information.
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    There is essentially no loss in accuracy when an SPK file is
    made from one or several NAV source files.
 
    Statistics on ephemeris accuracy are not available, but errors
    are very small compared to normal uncertainties in
    reconstructed pointing knowledge for the Voyager science
    instruments.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XM-11A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

