<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.vg2-u-pws-1-edr-wfrm-60ms-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>VG2 URA PWS RAW EXPERIMENT WAVEFORM 60MS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.comet_sl9-jupiter_collision::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.voyager::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vg2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:pws.vg2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.uranus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vg2-u-pws-1-edr-wfrm-60ms-v1.0__browserp_vg2-u-pws-1-edr-wfrm-60ms-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Gurnett, D.A., W.S. Kurth, F.L. Scarf, and R.L. Poynter, First Plasma Wave
                   Observations at Uranus, Science, Vol. 233, p. 106, 1986.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GURNETTETAL1986</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>VG2-U-PWS-1-EDR-WFRM-60MS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>VG2 URA PWS RAW EXPERIMENT WAVEFORM 60MS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1993-02-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1985-11-08T07:04Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1986-08-10T04:34:18Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. WILLIAM S. KURTH</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            VG2 URA PWS RAW EXPERIMENT WAVEFORM 60MS V1.0
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set consists of electric field waveform samples from
            the Voyager 2 Plasma Wave Receiver waveform receiver obtained
            during the Uranus encounter. The waveforms are collections of
            4-bit samples of the electric field measured by the dipole
            electric antenna at a rate of 28,800 samples per second. 1600
            samples are collected in 55.56 msec followed by a 4.44-msec gap.
            Each 60-msec interval constitutes a line of waveform samples. The
            data set includes about 271 frames of waveform samples consisting
            of up to 800 lines, each. The telemetry format for the waveform
            data is identical to that for images, hence the use of line and
            frame as constructs in describing the form of the data. The
            waveform is sampled through a bandpass filter with a passband of
            40 Hz to 12 kHz. The 4-bit samples provide sixteen digital values
            of the electric field with a linear amplitude scale, but the
            amplitude scale is arbitrary because of the automatic gain
            control used in the waveform receiver. The instantaneous dynamic
            range afforded by the 4 bit samples is about 23 db, but the
            automatic gain control allows the dominant signal in the passband
            to be set at the optimum level to fit within the instantaneous
            dynamic range. With the gain control, the overall dynamic range
            of the waveform receiver is about 100 db. The automatic gain
            control gain setting is not returned to the ground, hence, there
            is no absolute calibration for the data. However, by comparing
            the waveform spectrum derived by Fourier transforming the
            waveform to the spectrum provided by the spectrum analyzer data,
            an absolute calibration may be obtained in most cases. The data
            may be plotted in raw form to show the actual waveform useful for
            studying events such as dust impacts on the spacecraft. But the
            normal method of analyzing the waveform data is by Fourier
            transforming the samples from each line to arrive at an amplitude
            versus frequency spectrum. By stacking the spectra side-by-side
            in time order, a frequency- time spectrogram can be produced.
            Additional information about this dataset and the instrument
            which produced it can be found elsewhere in this catalog. An
            overview of the data in this data set can be found in Gurnett et
            al. [1986] and a complete instrument description can be found in
            Scarf and Gurnett [1977].
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      This data set consists of electric field waveform samples from
      the Voyager 2 Plasma Wave Receiver waveform receiver obtained
      during the Uranus encounter.  The waveforms are collections of
      4-bit samples of the electric field measured by the dipole
      electric antenna at a rate of 28,800 samples per second.  1600
      samples are collected in 55.56 msec followed by a 4.44-msec
      gap.  Each 60-msec interval constitutes a line of waveform
      samples.  The data set includes about 271 frames of waveform
      samples consisting of up to 800 lines, each.  The telemetry
      format for the waveform data is identical to that for images,
      hence the use of line and frame as constructs in describing the
      form of the data.  The waveform is sampled through a bandpass
      filter with a passband of 40 Hz to 12 kHz.  The 4-bit samples
      provide sixteen digital values of the electric field with a
      linear amplitude scale, but the amplitude scale is arbitrary
      because of the automatic gain control used in the waveform
      receiver.  The instantaneous dynamic range afforded by the 4
      bit samples is about 23 db, but the automatic gain control
      allows the dominant signal in the passband to be set at the
      optimum level to fit within the instantaneous dynamic range.
      With the gain control, the overall dynamic range of the
      waveform receiver is about 100 db.  The automatic gain control
      gain setting is not returned to the ground, hence, there is no
      absolute calibration for the data.  However, by comparing the
      waveform spectrum derived by Fourier transforming the waveform
      to the spectrum provided by the spectrum analyzer data, an
      absolute calibration may be obtained in most cases.  The data
      may be plotted in raw form to show the actual waveform; this is
      useful for studying events such as dust impacts on the
      spacecraft.  But the normal method of analyzing the waveform
      data is by Fourier transforming the samples from each line to
      arrive at an amplitude versus frequency spectrum.  By stacking
      the spectra side-by-side in time order, a frequency- time
      spectrogram can be produced.  Additional information about this
      dataset and the instrument which produced it can be found
      elsewhere in this catalog.  An overview of the data in this
      data set can be found in Gurnett et al.  [1986] and a complete
      instrument description can be found in Scarf and Gurnett
      [1977].
 
 
      Processing Level Id            : 1
      Software Flag                  : N
      Processing Stop Time           : 19920406000000.000
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;PLASMA WAVE WAVEFORM&apos;
      -----------------------------------------
        A plasma wave waveform is a time series of measurements of
        the electric or magnetic field component of the wave spectrum
        taken through a broadband filter.  The temporal sample rate
        is normally such that samples are made at more than twice the
        analysis filter bandwidth.  A typical waveform will consist
        of the order of 1000 contiguous samples of between 4 and 12
        bits each.  For a 10-kHz analysis bandwidth, the sample rate
        would normally be approximately 25 kHz or 25,000
        samples/second.  Once received, the waveforms are typically
        Fourier transformed in order to provide an amplitude versus
        frequency spectrum across the analysis bandwidth.  The sample
        rate, then, is required to be at least a factor of two
        greater than the filter bandwidth in order to avoid aliasing
        in the transformed spectrum.  The spectra can be stacked
        side-by-side in time to build a frequency-time spectrogram
        (that is, amplitude as a function of time and frequency) in
        order to identify the temporal and spectral variations in the
        wave spectrum.  Alternately, the untransformed time series
        can be used to study the details of the waveform.  This has
        been useful for measuring small-scale structures in the
        plasma and for identifying the signature of micron-sized dust
        impact on the spacecraft.
 
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Data Set Parameter Name        : PLASMA WAVE WAVEFORM
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 0.000035
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : 0.000035
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : 0.000035
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : VOLT/METER
        Noise Level                    : 0.000005
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND
 
 
    Source Instrument Parameters
    ============================
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : PLASMA WAVE WAVEFORM
      Instrument Parameter Name       : ELECTRIC FIELD COMPONENT
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : PLASMA WAVE WAVEFORM
      Instrument Parameter Name       : WAVE ELECTRIC FIELD INTENSITY
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : PLASMA WAVE WAVEFORM
      Instrument Parameter Name       : WAVE MAGNETIC FIELD INTENSITY
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      Processing History
      ------------------
        Source Data Set ID          : N/A
        Software                    : CDREF
        Product Data Set ID         : VG2-U-PWS-1-EDR-WFRM-60MS-V1.0
 
 
      Software &apos;CDREF&apos;
      ----------------
        CDREF is primarily a data format translation routine which is
        used to convert Voyager PWS EDR tape files to CD-ROM files.
        CDREF is written in FORTRAN and is not available for public
        use.  The EDR, or Engineering Data Records, are produced at
        Multi-mission Image Processing Laboratory at JPL as the
        uncalibrated, full-resolution PWS spectrum analyzer data set.
        The CD files contain uncalibrated, full-resolution PWS data
        with minimal ancillary data in a simplified format which may
        be used in CDROM production.
 
        Software Name               : CDREF
        Software Type               : N/A
        Software Release Date       : 1990-04-07
        Node ID                     : IMAGING
        Cognizant Engineer          : MR. JASON J. HYON
        Software Access Description : N/A
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      This data set includes all available waveform receiver data
      obtained during the Uranus encounter.  There has been no
      attempt to clean various interference signals from the data.
      Most of these can normally be easily seen in frequency-time
      spectrograms as narrowband, fixed-frequency tones.  The most
      common include narrow-band tones at 2.4 and 4.8 kHz which are
      power supply harmonics.  There is sometimes a tone near 1.7 kHz
      which is associated with the operation of the spacecraft gyros.
      The spacecraft tape recorder results in a rather intense band
      in the frequency range of a few hundred Hz.  There are few
      times when the data in this frequency range can be used.
      However, there are times when the real signals in this
      frequency range can exceed the intensity of the interference
      sufficiently so that the frequency range near a few hundred Hz
      can be used.  Use of the spectrum analyzer data can be of use
      to determine when these time periods occur.  The stepper motor
      of the LECP instrument also interferes in the frequency range
      of a few hundred Hz, but for periods of a few seconds.  The
      LECP interference is very intense and captures the automatic
      gain control so that real signals, even where there is no
      interference, will appear to decrease in amplitude until the
      LECP interference fades in amplitude.  The PLS instrument
      periodically interferes at 400 Hz and odd harmonics because of
      a 400-Hz square wave used to modulate a grid in the detector.
      The PLS interference lasts for several seconds and ends
      abruptly.  Telemetry errors result in a fairly graceful
      degradation of the waveform data.  Assuming the telemetry
      errors are randomly occurring bursts, they typically appear as
      an enhanced background level in the spectrum.  Since the bursts
      are short, their Fourier transform is a broadband spectrum.
      When looking for relatively narrowband features or features
      with distinct frequency-time characteristics, the result of the
      bursts simply reduce the signal-to-noise in the spectrum.  One
      way of reducing the effect of burst telemetry errors is to pass
      the waveform data through a low-pass filter to despike it,
      prior to running the Fourier transform.  The waveform data is
      not subject to the negative effects of the failure in the
      Voyager 2 Flight Data System which reduces the sensitivity of
      the spectrum analyzer and affects the calibration above 1 kHz.
      In fact, use of the 1 - 12 kHz waveform data is an effective
      way of avoiding the problems with the spectrum analyzer data in
      this frequency range.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XM-11A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

