<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dif-c-hriv-its-mri-5-tempel1-shape-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>PLATE SHAPE MODEL OF COMET 9P/TEMPEL 1, V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_impact::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dii::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:hriv.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:its.dii::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.9p-tempel_1_1867_g1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dif-c-hriv-its-mri-5-tempel1-shape-v1.0__browserp_dif-c-hriv-its-mri-5-tempel1-shape-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Thomas, P.C, J. Veverka, M.J.S. Belton, A. Hidy, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, T.L. Farnham, O.
                   Groussin, J.-Y. Li, L. A. McFadden, J. Sunshine, D. Wellnitz, C. Lisse, P.
                   Schultz, K. J. Meech, and W.A. Delamere, The shape, topography, and geology of
                   Tempel 1 from Deep Impact observations, Icarus, 187, 4-15, 2007,
                   doi:10.1016/j.icarus.2006.12.013.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.THOMASETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DIF-C-HRIV/ITS/MRI-5-TEMPEL1-SHAPE-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>PLATE SHAPE MODEL OF COMET 9P/TEMPEL 1, V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2006-11-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2005-01-01</start_time>
        <stop_time>2005-07-13</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>Tony L. Farnham</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Farnham, T.L. and Thomas, P.C, SHAPE MODEL OF COMET TEMPEL 1,
            DIF-C-HRIV/ITS/MRI-5-TEMPEL1-SHAPE-MODEL-V1.0, NASA Planetary
            Data System, 2006.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Detailed plate shape model of comet 9P/Tempel 1
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Shape model of comet 9P/Tempel 1, as derived from the Deep Impact
            images obtained around the time of closest approach to the comet.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
 
This data set presents the detailed plate shape model of comet
9P/Tempel 1, as derived from the images of the comet that were
obtained by the Deep Impact spacecraft around the time of closest
approach.  Additional information about the model can be found in
Thomas et al., &apos;The Shape, Topography and Geology of Tempel 1 from
Deep Impact Observations&apos;, Submitted to Icarus, 2007 [THOMASETAL2007]
 
The Deep Impact (DI) spacecraft consists of two parts, an impactor and
a flyby spacecraft, that encountered comet 9P/Tempel 1 on July 4,
2005.  During this encounter, the impactor collided with the nucleus
to produce a crater and expose sub-surface material that could be
observed by the flyby spacecraft.
 
During the final approach to the nucleus, three cameras, the High
Resolution Instrument (HRI), the Medium Resolution Instrument (MRI)
and the Impactor Targeting System (ITS) obtained hundreds of images of
the nucleus.  After the impact, in which the ITS was destroyed, the
MRI and HRI continued to image the nucleus for 800 seconds, until the
spacecraft entered shield mode and stopped tracking the nucleus.
While in shield mode, the spacecraft passed its closest approach to
the comet (500 km).  Thirty minutes after closest approach, the
spacecraft again reacquired the nucleus and obtained additional images
as it departed.  The images used for producing the shape model are
contained in the PDS archive of Deep Impact Data for Tempel 1.
The data set IDs are:
     DIF-C-HRIV-2-9P-ENCOUNTER-V1.0
     DII-C-ITS-2-9P-ENCOUNTER-V1.0
     DIF-C-MRI-2-9P-ENCOUNTER-V1.0
 
 
PLATE MODEL
 
A detailed plate model was derived from 70 of the images, using
control points to constrain the shape of the nucleus.  189 different
features on the surface were selected as the control points, with 1520
measurements used in the model determination.  Approximately 30% of
the surface is well-defined from these control points, with the rest
of the surface estimated using other constraints.  These additional
constraints include the positions of the limb and terminator (in both
the approach and lookback images) and the photometric lightcurve of
the nucleus that was measured in the weeks leading up to the
encounter.  Adjustments to the shape were also made to shift the
moment of inertia in such a way that the spin axis of the nucleus
would reproduce the rotation that was observed during the approach
to the comet.
 
The orientation of the spin axis is such that the positive pole points
to a right ascension of 294 deg and a declination of +73 deg (J2000),
with an uncertainty of approximately 5 deg.  The prime meridian is
defined by the center of the 350 meter crater located to the west of
the impact site (in geographic coordinate).  Thus, because longitude
increases in the direction defined by the right hand rule around the
positive pole, the longitude of the impact site is at about 15 degrees.
The latitude is -26 degrees.
 
The model, TEMPEL1_PLAN.TAB, is presented in body-centered
planetocentric coordinates, with vertices at intervals of 2 degrees in
both latitude and longitude.  It consists of 16471 vertices, forming
32400 plates.  The radial distance is given in kilometers and ranges
from a minimum of 2.3260 km to a maximum 3.9564 km.  The shape is such
that it is not well represented by a triaxial ellipsoid.
 
A second version of the model, TEMPEL1_CART.TAB, was derived from the
planetocentric version.  In this version, the vertices are in the same
locations, but are presented in cartesian coordinates.  The X axis is
defined in the direction of the intersection of the equator and the
prime meridian, the Z axis lies along the positive pole and the Y axis
completes the right-hand coordinate system.
 
For detailed analysis of the shape, routines such as the SURFACE and
POLYSHADE routines in IDL can be used.  To simply view the shape
model, go to the browse directory, where the shape model has been
converted to VRML format.  There are two versions, one with the
illumination that mimics that during the encounter, and one that uses
a headlight to reveal the structure in a different manner.  These
models can be viewed using any standard VRML viewer.
 
Author
------
The descriptions in this file were written by Tony Farnham.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
 
The uncertainties in the pole orientation are approximately 5 degrees.
In the regions that are well-defined by control points, the radial
uncertainty of the plate model is approximately 20 m.  In regions not
defined by control points, the uncertainties are likely to be larger.
 
    Review
    ======
The plate model is sceduled for review on Nov 2006.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SUPERSEDED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

