<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dif-x-hriv-3-epoxi-exoplanets-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>EPOXI EXOPLANET TRANSIT OBS - HRIV CALIBRATED IMAGES V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.epoxi::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:hriv.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:star.gj_436::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:star.hat-p-4::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:star.hat-p-7::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:star.tres-2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:star.tres-3::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:star.wasp-3::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:star.xo-2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:star.xo-3::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dif-x-hriv-3-epoxi-exoplanets-v1.0__browserp_dif-x-hriv-3-epoxi-exoplanets-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Ballard, S., D. Charbonneau, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, D. Deming, M.J. Holman, J.L.
                   Christiansen, D.T.F. Weldrake, R.K. Barry, M.J. Kuchner, T.A. Livengood, J.
                   Pedelty, A. Schultz, T. Hewagama, J.M. Sunshine, D.D. Wellnitz, D.L. Hampton,
                   C.M. Lisse, S. Seager, and J.F. Veverka, Transiting Exoplanet Results from the
                   NASA EPOXI Mission, American Astronomical Society, AAS Meeting #213, #402.11,
                   Bulletin of the American Astronomical Society, Vol. 41, p.192, 2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BALLARDETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Ballard, S., D. Charbonneau, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, D. Deming, M.J. Holman, J.L.
                   Christiansen, D.T.F. Weldrake, R.K. Barry, M.J. Kuchner, T.A. Livengood, J.
                   Pedelty, A. Schultz, T. Hewagama, J.M. Sunshine, D.D. Wellnitz, D.L. Hampton,
                   C.M. Lisse, S. Seager, and J.F. Veverka, Preliminary Results on HAT-P-4,
                   TrES-3, XO-2, and GJ 436 from the NASA EPOXI Mission in Transiting Planets,
                   Proceedings of the International Astronomical Union, IAU Symposium, Volume 253,
                   470-473, 2009, doi:10.1017/S1743921308026963.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BALLARDETAL2009B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Christiansen, J.L., D. Charbonneau, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, D. Deming, M.J. Holman, S.
                   Ballard, D.T.F. Weldrake, R.K. Barry, M.J. Kuchner, T.A. Livengood, J. Pedelty,
                   A. Schultz, T. Hewagama, J.M. Sunshine, D.D. Wellnitz, D.L. Hampton, C.M.
                   Lisse, S. Seager, and J.F. Veverka, The NASA EPOXI mission of opportunity to
                   gather ultraprecise photometry of known transiting exoplanets in Transiting
                   Planets, Proceedings of the International Astronomical Union, IAU Symposium,
                   Volume 253, 301-307, 2009, doi:10.1017/S1743921308026525.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CHRISTIANSENETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hampton, D.L., J.W. Baer, M.A. Huisjen, C.C. Varner, A. Delamere, D.D.
                   Wellnitz, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, and K.P. Klaasen, An Overview of the Instrument Suite
                   for the Deep Impact Mission, Space Science Reviews, 117, 43-93, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3390-8.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAMPTONETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., M.F. A&apos;Hearn, M. Baca, A. Delamere, M. Desnoyer, T. Farnham, O.
                   Groussin, D. Hampton, S. Ipatov, J. Li, C. Lisse, N. Mastrodemos, S.
                   McLaughlin, J. Sunshine, P. Thomas, and D. Wellnitz, Deep Impact Instrument
                   Calibration, Rev. Sci. Instrum., 79, 091301, 2008, doi:10.1063/1.2972112.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lindler, D., I. Busko, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, and R.L. White, Restoration of Images of
                   Comet 9P/Tempel 1 Taken with the Deep Impact High Resolution Instrument, PASP,
                   119, 427-436, 2007, doi:10.1086/516829.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LINDLERETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DIF-X-HRIV-3-EPOXI-EXOPLANETS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>EPOXI EXOPLANET TRANSIT OBS - HRIV CALIBRATED IMAGES V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2009-09-30</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2008-01-22T00:22:53.769Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2008-08-31T12:44:54.196Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STEPHANIE MCLAUGHLIN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            McLaughlin, S.A., B. Carcich, D. Deming, D.D. Wellnitz, and K.P.
            Klaasen, EPOXI EXOPLANET TRANSIT OBS - HRIV CALIBRATED IMAGES
            V1.0, DIF-X-HRIV-3-EPOXI-EXOPLANETS-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2009.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Calibrated clear filter images of transiting planet systems
            HAT-P-4, HAT-P-7, GJ 436, TrES-2, TrES-3, XO-2, XO-3 and WASP-3
            acquired from 22 Jan to 31 Aug 2008 by the Deep Impact High
            Resolution Visible CCD during the EPOCh phase of the EPOXI mission
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set set contains calibrated images of eight known
            transiting extrasolar planetary systems (hot Jupiters) acquired
            by the Deep Impact High Resolution Visible CCD during the EPOCh
            phase of the EPOXI mission. From 22 January through 31 August
            2008 the HRIV CCD collected over 172,000 usable,
            photometric-quality visible light images of these transiting
            planet systems: HAT-P-4, HAT-P-7, GJ 436, TrES-2, TrES-3, XO-2,
            XO-3, and WASP-3. Time series of continuous 50-second
            integrations were used with the clear filter (#6) to observe each
            system for about three weeks, typically covering five or more
            transits as well as secondary eclipses. An exception was XO-3
            which was only observed briefly due to the spacecraft entering
            safe mode. The transiting planet systems were observed in the
            integrated light of the planet and star; no spatially resolved
            image of the planet was possible.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set set contains calibrated radiance images of eight known
    transiting extrasolar planetary systems (hot Jupiters) acquired by the
    Deep Impact High Resolution Visible CCD (HRIV) during the EPOCh phase of
    the EPOXI mission.  From 22 January through 31 August 2008, EPOCh took
    advantage of the permanent on-orbit defocus of the HRI telescope by
    using the HRIV CCD to collect over 172,000 usable, photometric-quality,
    visible light images of these exoplanet systems: HAT-P-4, HAT-P-7, GJ
    436, TrES-2, TrES-3, XO-2, XO-3, and WASP-3. Time series of continuous
    50-second integrations in a subframe mode of 128x128 or 256x256 pixels
    with the clear #6 optical filter (350 to 1000 nanometers) were used to
    observe each system for about three weeks, typically covering five or
    more transits as well as secondary eclipses; an exception is XO-3 which
    was observed only briefly before the spacecraft unexpectedly entered
    safe mode.  For most observations the 128x128-pixel subarray was used.
    The larger subarray of 256x256 pixels was commanded during some transit
    and secondary eclipse periods to ensure that pointing jitter did not
    cause the star to fall beyond the edges of the subarray.  The transiting
    planet systems were observed in the integrated light of the planet and
    star; no spatially resolved image of the planet was possible.  The
    out-of-focus HRIV telescope defocuses the images to about 10 pixels or
    4 arcseconds at full-width half-max and introduces visible structure.
 
    The calibrated HRIV images in this data set have been bias-subtracted
    with removal of electronic crosstalk and transfer smear and nominally
    flat-fielded, using calibration exposures of an integrating sphere made
    on the ground before launch.  However, the CCD detector had changed over
    time while in space, and the ground-based flat fields were not adequate
    for precision stellar photometry.  Therefore the EPOCh team used an
    independent bootstrap procedure, fitting aperture photometry derived
    from the calibration images in this data set to a 2-D spline, to define
    corrections to the flat-field calibration.
 
    The following table chronologically lists the EPOCh transiting exoplanet
    observations.  For most targets, preview imaging was performed to
    determine if the pointing bias needed to be modified for that target
    series.
 
        Target   Start Date/DOY  Stop Date/DOY   Comments
        -------  --------------  --------------  --------------------------
        HAT-P-4  2008-01-22/022  2008-02-12/043
        XO-3     2008-02-12/043  2008-02-17/048  S/C entered safe mode
        TRES-3   2008-03-06/066  2008-03-08/068
        XO-2     2008-03-09/069  2008-03-11/071  Preview for pointing bias
        TRES-3   2008-03-11/071  2008-03-18/078
        XO-2     2008-03-20/080  2008-03-28/088
        GJ 436   2008-05-04/125  2008-05-27/148
        TRES-2   2008-06-28/180  2008-06-29/181  Preview for pointing bias
        HAT-P-4  2008-06-29/181  2008-07-08/190
        TRES-2   2008-07-08/190  2008-07-17/199
        WASP-3   2008-07-17/199  2008-07-19/201  Preview for pointing bias
        TRES-2   2008-07-20/202  2008-07-30/212
        WASP-3   2008-07-30/212  2008-08-08/221
        HAT-P-7  2008-08-08/221  2008-08-10/223  Preview for pointing bias
        WASP-3   2008-08-10/223  2008-08-16/229
        HAT-P-7  2008-08-16/229  2008-08-31/244
 
    The time series for each target was typically bracketed by a set of
    dark and internal stimulator lamp frames to monitor changes in the
    CCD detector and to aid transit photometry.  These data are archived
    separately in the raw EPOXI calibrations data set,
    DIF-CAL-HRIV-2-EPOXI-CALIBRATIONS-V1.0.
 
    The general characteristics of the observed planetary systems as
    described by Ballard, et al. (2009) [BALLARDETAL2009] is provided
    here:
 
         Stellar       #Transits
        Target  V_mag  Observed Points of Interest
        ------- ----- --------- -------------------------------------------
        HAT-P-4 11.22     10    Low density planet, large radius for
                                its mass
        XO-3     9.91      1    Eccentric orbit, second planet suspected
        TrES-3  12.40      7    Short period (31 hours), reflected light
                                target
        XO-2    11.18      3    Fainter component in wide visual binary,
                                metal rich
        GJ 436  10.67      8    Eccentric orbit, unseen planet suspected,
                                star is M-dwarf
        TrES-2  11.41      7    Kepler target, additional planets possible
        WASP-3  10.64      8    Strongly heated, reflected light and
                                visible thermal emission possible
        HAT-P-7 10.50      8    Kepler target, even more strongly heated
                                than WASP-3
 
 
    Required Reading
    ---------------
      The following documents are essential for the understanding and
      interpretation of this data set.  Please note the most recent
      version of these documents, including other formats such as ASCII
      text, can be found in the Deep Impact and EPOXI documentation data set,
      DI-C-HRII-HRIV-MRI-ITS-6-DOC-SET-V2.0.
 
      EPOXI_SIS.PDF
        - The Archive Volume and Data Product Software Interface
          Specifications document (SIS) describes the the data set, the
          science data products, and defines keywords in the PDS labels.
 
      CALIBRATION_PAPER_DRAFT.PDF
        - The Deep Impact instrument calibration paper by Klaasen, et al.
          (2008) [KLAASENETAL2006] describes how the instruments were
          calibrated for Deep Impact and similarly for EPOXI and explains
          the calibration process used for both missions.  The published
          version should be available online in the Review of Scientific
          Instruments by the American Institute of Physics.  The EPOXI
          archive provides only an incomplete draft.
 
      INSTRUMENTS_HAMPTON.PDF
        - The Deep Impact instruments paper by Hampton, et al. (2005)
          [HAMPTONETAL2005] provides very detailed descriptions of the
          instruments.
 
      EPOCH_OVERVIEW.PDF
        - This presentation provides an overview of the EPOCh phase of
          the EPOXI mission.
 
      EPOCH_TRANSIT_OBS.PDF
        - This document describes of the EPOCh stellar transit observations
          although most of the information is captured in this data set
          catalog file you are reading.
 
      EPOCH_TRANSIT_OBS_SCLK2BJD.PDF
        - This report describes the calibration of spacecraft clock timing
          and reduction to Barycentric Dynamic Time Julian Date for EPOCh
          observations of transiting extrasolar planets.
 
      HRIV_3_EPOXI_GJ436.TAB
      HRIV_3_EPOXI_HATP4.TAB
      HRIV_3_EPOXI_HATP7.TAB
      HRIV_3_EPOXI_TRES2.TAB
      HRIV_3_EPOXI_TRES3.TAB
      HRIV_3_EPOXI_WASP3.TAB
      HRIV_3_EPOXI_XO2.TAB
      HRIV_3_EPOXI_XO3.TAB
        - These ASCII tables provide image parameters such as the mid-obs
          Julian date, exposure time, mission activity type, and
          description or purpose for each observation (i.e., data product)
          in this data set.
 
      Publications of the preliminary photometry results derived from the
      transiting planet observations in this data set include Ballard, et
      al. (2009) [BALLARDETAL2009B] and Christiansen, et al. (2009)
      [CHRISTIANSENETAL2009].
 
 
    Related Data Sets
    -----------------
      The following PDS data sets are related to this one and may be useful
      for research:
 
      DIF-E-HRIV-2-EPOXI-EXOPLANETS-V1.0
        - Raw HRIV extrasolar planet transit observations
 
      DIF-CAL-HRIV-2-EPOXI-CALIBRATIONS-V1.0
        - Raw HRIV dark frames (exposure IDs 9600000 and 9600001) and
          internal stimulator lamp images (exposure IDs 9600002 and 9600003)
          acquired to monitor changes in the CCD detector for EPOCh transit
          photometry purposes
 
      DI-C-HRII-HRIV-MRI-ITS-6-DOC-SET-V2.0
        - Deep Impact and EPOXI documentation set
 
      DIF-C/E/X-SPICE-6-V1.0
        - EPOXI SPICE kernels
 
      DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV/MRI-6-EPOXI-TEMPS-V1.0
        - HRII, HRIV, and MRI instrument thermal telemetry data for EPOXI
          which may be useful for determining how temperature fluctuations
          affect the science instruments, in particular the IR spectrometer
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The calibrated two-dimensional FITS CCD images and PDS labels in this
    data set were generated by the Deep Impact/EPOXI data pipeline,
    maintained by the project&apos;s Science Data Center (SDC) at Cornell
    University.  For each CCD image, the pipeline generated a calibrated
    uncleaned radiance data product provided in units of Watts/(meter**2
    steradian micron) and identified by the mnemonic &apos;RADREV&apos;.  The RADREV
    data are considered to be reversible because the calibration steps can
    be backed out to return to the original, raw data numbers.  A RADREV
    image can be converted to unitless I-over-F by multiplying by the
    value assigned to the DATA_TO_IOVERF_MULTIPLIER keyword in the PDS
    label although I-over-F data were not used by the EPOXI team.
    Alternatively, a RADREV image can be converted from radiance units to
    calibrated data numbers by multiplying by the value assigned to the
    DATA_TO_DN_MULTIPLIER in the PDS label.
 
    The calibration pipeline performed the following processes on the raw
    HRIV FITS data to produce the RADREV products found in this data set:
 
      - Decompression of compressed images (Earth images were not
        compressed)
      - Correction for bias
      - Subtraction of a dark frame
      - Removal of electronic cross-talk
      - Application of a normalized flat field
      - Removal of CCD transfer smear
      - Conversion of data numbers to units of radiance for an absolute,
        radiometric calibration that is reversible (RADREV)
      - Calibration &apos;cleaning&apos; processes such as interpolating over bad
        and missing pixels, despiking (i.e., cosmic ray removal), and
        denoising is never performed for RADREV data
      - Calculation of multiplicative factors to convert a RADREV image
        to I-over-F or to original DN
      - Deconvolution to correct for the out-of-focus for the HRI telescope
        was *not* performed by the calibration because this potential
        process is part on the RAD stream used to clean RADREV products.
 
    As part of the calibration process, the pipeline updated the
    pixel-by-pixel image quality map, the first FITS extension, to identify:
 
      - Pixels where the raw value was saturated,
      - Pixels where the analog-to-digital converter was saturated,
      - Pixels that were ultra-compressed and thus contain very little
        information, and
      - Pixels considered to be anomalous as indicated by bad pixel
        maps (missing pixels were identified when the raw FITS files
        were created).
 
    The pipeline also created a FITS image extension for a signal-to-noise
    ratio map.  The calibration steps and files applied to each raw image
    are listed in the PROCESSING_HISTORY_TEXT keyword in the PDS data
    label. For a detailed discussion of the calibration pipeline and the
    resulting data, see the Deep Impact instrument calibration document
    and the EPOXI SIS document.
 
 
  Data
  ====
 
    FITS Images and PDS Labels
    --------------------------
      Each calibrated HRIV image is stored as FITS.  The primary data unit
      contains the two-dimensional CCD image which is followed by two
      image extensions that are two-dimensional pixel-by-pixel maps
      providing additional information about the CCD image:
 
        - The first extension uses one byte of eight, bit flags to
          describe the quality of each pixel in the primary image.
          The PDS data label defines the purpose of each bit.
 
        - The second extension provides a signal-to-noise ratio for
          each pixel in the primary image.
 
      For more information about the FITS primary image and the extensions,
      refer to the Deep Impact instrument calibration document or the EPOXI
      SIS document
 
      Each FITS file is accompanied by a detached PDS data label.  The
      EPOXI SIS document provides definitions for the keywords found in a
      data label.
 
 
    File Naming Convention
    ----------------------
      The naming convention for the raw data labels and FITS files is
      HVyymmddhh_eeeeeee_nnn_RR.LBL or FIT where &apos;HV&apos; identifies the HRIV
      instrument, yymmddhh provides the UTC year, month, day, and hour at
      the mid-point of the observation, eeeeeee is the exposure ID
      (OBSERVATION_ID in data labels), nnn provides the image number
      (IMAGE_NUMBER in the data labels) within the exposure ID, and
      RR identifies the type of reduction, RADREV (reversibly
      calibrated, radiance units).
 
      Up to 999 individual images or frames can be commanded for one
      exposure ID.  Therefore, nnn in the file name provides the
      sequentially increasing frame number within an exposure ID and
      corresponds to IMAGE_NUMBER in the data labels.  For example, if 32
      frames were commanded for a scan with an exposure ID of 1000001, the
      first FITS file name would be HV08051200_9200003_000_RR.FIT and the
      last would be HV08051200_9200003_032_RR.FIT.
 
 
    Image Compression
    -----------------
      All data products in this data set are uncompressed.  If the
      associated raw data products was compressed on board the flyby
      spacecraft (and thus received on the ground and archived as
      compressed) then the calibration pipeline uses one of four 8-bit
      lookup tables to decompress the raw image.  However, the EPOCh
      exoplanet transit images acquired acquired during the time period
      covered by this data set were never compressed.  For more information
      about this topic, see the image compression section of the Deep
      Impact instrument calibration documents.
 
 
    Image Orientation
    -----------------
      A true-sky &apos;as seen by the observer&apos; view is achieved by displaying
      the image using the standard FITS convention:  the fastest-varying
      axis (samples) increasing to the right in the display
      window and the slowest-varying axis (lines)
      increasing to the top.  This convention is identified in the data
      labels:  the SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION keyword is set to RIGHT and
      LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION to UP.
 
      The direction to celestial north, ecliptic north, and the Sun is
      provided in data labels by CELESTIAL_NORTH_CLOCK_ANGLE,
      ECLIPTIC_NORTH_CLOCK_ANGLE, and SUN_DIRECTION_CLOCK_ANGLE keywords
      and are measured clockwise from the top of the image when is
      displayed in the correct orientation as defined by
      SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION and LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION.  Please note
      the aspect of the North celestial pole in an image can be computed
      by adding 90 degrees to the boresight declination given by
      DECLINATION in the data labels.
 
      For a comparison of the orientation FITS image data from the three
      science instruments, see the quadrant nomenclature section of the
      Deep Impact instrument calibration document.  Also the EPOXI SIS
      has a brief discussion of this topic.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
    Data Units
    ----------
      The calibrated RADREV image data have units of radiance,
      W/(m**2 steradian micron).
 
 
    Imaging Modes
    -------------
      Two HRIV image modes were used for the EPOCh transiting planet
      observations:
 
                     X-Size  Y-Size
        Mode Name    (pix)   (pix)   Comments
        ---- ------  ------  ------  -------------------------------
          3  SF2S      256    256    Sub-frame, shuttered
          5  SF3S      128    128    Sub-frame, shuttered
 
      All modes are unbinned.  For most observations the 128x128 mode was
      used. The larger subarray of 256x256 pixels was commanded during
      some transit and secondary eclipse periods and for preview imaging
      to ensure that pointing jitter did not cause the star to fall beyond
      the edges of the subarray.  For a thorough description of the
      imaging modes, please see the Deep Impact instruments document or
      the Deep Impact instrument calibration document.  Also the EPOXI SIS
      has a brief discussion of this topic.
 
      Most image modes have a set of bias overclock rows and columns,
      located around the edges of the image array.  All overclock pixels
      were excluded from the calculation of the values for MINIMUM,
      MAXIMUM, MEDIAN, and STANDARD_DEVIATION in the data labels.  These
      overclock areas described in the Deep Impact instruments document
      and the Deep Impact instrument calibration document.
 
 
    Filters
    -------
      One HRIV image mode was used for the EPOCh transiting planet
      observations:
 
        Filter         Center Width
        #  Name        (nm)   (nm)   Comments
        -  ----------  -----  -----  -------------------------------
        6  CLEAR6       650   &gt;700   Not band limited
 
      For more information about the filter, see the Deep Impact
      instruments document or the Deep Impact instrument calibration
      document.  Also the EPOXI SIS has a brief discussion of this topic.
 
 
    Time- and Geometry-Related Keywords
    -----------------------------------
      All time-related keywords in the data labels, except
      EARTH_OBSERVER_MID_TIME, are based on the clock on board the flyby
      spacecraft.  EARTH_OBSERVER_MID_TIME provides the UTC when an
      Earth-based observer should have been able to see an event recorded
      by the instrument.
 
      It is important to note that the spacecraft clock is affected by a
      systematic drift relative to ground clocks due to the changing
      thermal environment of the spacecraft.  The EPOCh team calibrated
      the spacecraft clock versus ground clocks, and the corrected times
      were computed for each transiting system (giving Julian Date and
      Barycentric Julian Date by image file name).  However to aid
      transit timing analysis, the computation was implemented in the
      data pipeline, and the EPOCh team verified that the resulting
      values were consistent with theirs.  Thus the Barycentric Dynamic
      Time Julian Date (BJD) for the mid-point of an observation when
      light reaches the solar system barycenter is provided by the
      KPKSSBJT keyword in the FITS header of each data product.  For more
      information about calculating the BJD, please see the document
      EPOCH_TRANSIT_OBS_SCLK2BJD.PDF.  The pipeline also computed the
      Barycentric Dynamic Time at the mid-point of the observation at the
      spacecraft; it is provided as a Julian Date in the FITS header
      keyword OBSMIDJT.  The project elected to omit these two
      barycentric-related values from the PDS labels.
 
      The SDC pipeline was not able to automatically determine the proper
      geometric information for the target of choice in some cases.  When
      these parameters could not be computed, the corresponding keywords
      in the data labels are set to a value of unknown, &apos;UNK&apos;.  Also if
      GEOMETRY_QUALITY_FLAG is set to &apos;BAD&apos; or GEOMETRY_TYPE is set to
      &apos;PREDICTED&apos; in the PDS labels, then this indicates the geometry
      values may not be accurate and should be used with caution.  For
      example, some HAT-P-4 observations have inaccurate values for
      boresight RIGHT_ASCENSION and DECLINATION because only predicted
      pointing information, and not final reconstructed pointing, was
      available to the data pipeline.  The value &apos;N/A&apos; is used for some
      geometry-related keywords in the data labels because these
      parameters are not applicable for certain calibration targets.
 
      Observational geometry parameters provided in the data labels were
      computed at the epoch specified by the mid-obs UTC, IMAGE_MID_TIME,
      in the data labels.  The exceptions are the target-to-sun values
      that were calculated for the time when the light arrived at the
      target and the earth-observer-to-target values that were calculated
      for the time when the light left the target.
 
      The flyby spacecraft clock SPICE kernels (SCLK) used to convert to
      UTC and to calculate geometry-related parameters for this data set
      have a known accuracy of no better than 0.5 seconds.  However as
      this data set was being produced, the mission operations team
      figured out how to correct raw clock correlation data for the
      flyby spacecraft to allow timing fits that are accurate to at
      least the sub-second level.  The project plans to generate a
      complete, corrected set of correlations since launch.  This will
      ultimately result in a future version of a SCLK kernel that will
      retroactively change correlation for **all** Deep Impact and EPOXI
      data.  When this kernel is available, it will be added to the
      SPICE data sets for the two missions and posted on the NAIF/SPICE
      web site at http://naif.jpl.nasa.gov/naif/.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    The geometric parameters included in the data labels and FITS headers
    were computed using the best available SPICE kernels at the time the
    data products were generated.  NAIF used these kernels to produce the
    EPOXI SPICE data set, DIF-C/E/X-SPICE-6-V1.0.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    Earth Mean Equator and Vernal Equinox of J2000 (EME J2000) is the
    inertial reference system used to specify observational geometry
    parameters in the data labels, unless specified otherwise (e.g,
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LONGITUDE).
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The observations in this data set are in standard FITS format with PDS
    labels, and can be viewed by a number of PDS-provided and commercial
    programs.  For this reason no special software is provided with this
    data set.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The data files in this data set were reviewed internally by the EPOXI
    project.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    This data set is archived at the PDS Small Bodies Node (SBN) and the
    Multi-Mission Archive at STScI (MAST).  It passed a peer review held
    by SBN on 23 July 2009; MAST personnel participated.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    There are no unexpected gaps in this data set.  All Earth observations
    received on the ground were processed and included in this data set.
 
    Horizontal striping through some images indicates missing data.  The
    image quality map extension identifies where pixels are missing.  If
    the second most-significant bit of a pixel in the image quality map is
    turned on, then data for the corresponding image pixel is missing.  For
    more information, refer to EPOXI SIS document.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
 
 
    HRI Telescope Focus
    -------------------
      Images of stars acquired early during the Deep Impact mission in
      2005 indicated the HRI telescope was out of focus.  In-flight
      bakeouts during late February and early March 2005 reduced the
      defocus from about 1.0 cm to about 0.6 cm, resulting in a decrease
      in the width of stars from about 12 pixels to 9 pixels.  For more
      details, please see the Deep Impact instrument calibration paper by
      Klaasen, et al. (2006) [KLAASENETAL2006] and the Deep Impact image
      restoration paper by Lindler, et al. (2007) [LINDLERETAL2007].
 
 
    CCD Horizontal Gap
    ------------------
      Calibration analysis combining Deep Impact and early EPOXI data
      determined the two halves of the HRIV CCD - the boundary being the
      two horizontal central lines 511 and 512 (zero based) - while
      physically consistent across the boundary, are biased during
      integration so that the centers of the two halves are apparently
      1/6 pixel closer to the center, and the two boundary rows show a
      decrease in sensitivity of 1/6.  Reconstructed image files space
      all lines evenly, so the true image is erroneously vertically
      pushed apart by 1/3 pixel at its center in these reconstructions.
      When making science measurements from HRIV images, one must
      therefore be very careful to properly account for the two flaws
      introduced by the apparently narrow central lines on the CCD - a
      geometric error that separates the image by an extra 1/3 pixel at
      the horizontal quadrant boundary, and 2) insertion of extra total
      radiance into calibrated images due to the flat-field correction,
      which corrects for an apparent radiance deficit in the two central
      rows because of the smaller number of photons actually incident on
      those rows.
 
 
    Out-of-Frame Target
    -------------------
      Some exoplanet transit images in this data set do not contain the
      star because of deviations in pointing.  However the intended target
      is specified by the TARGET_NAME keyword in the data labels.
 
 
    Displaying Images
    -----------------
      Flight software writes an image header over the first 100 bytes of
      quadrant A.  These image header pixels were included in the calibrated
      FITS images.  Since the values in these pixels vary dramatically,
      it is recommended that the values of the MINIMUM and MAXIMUM
      keywords in the data label (or the MINPVAL and MAXPVAL in the FITS
      header) be used to scale an image for display because these values
      exclude the header bytes as well as the overclock rows and columns
      located around the edge of the CCD image.  For more information,
      see the quadrant nomenclature section of the Deep Impact instrument
      calibration document or the EPOXI SIS document.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

