<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.go-j-uvs-3-rdr-sl9-g-fragment-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GO UVS TABULAR DATA FROM THE SL9-G IMPACT WITH JUPITER V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.comet_sl9-jupiter_collision::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.galileo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:uvs.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.sl9::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-j-uvs-3-rdr-sl9-g-fragment-v1.0__browserp_go-j-uvs-3-rdr-sl9-g-fragment-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hord, C.W., W.R. Pryor, A.I.F. Stewart, K.E. Simmons, J.J. Gebben, C.A.
                   Barth, W.E. McClintock, L.W. Esposito, W.K. Tobiska, R.A. West, S.J.
                   Edberg, J.M. Ajello, and K.L. Naviaux, Direct Observations of the Comet
                   Shoemaker-Levy 9 Fragment G Impact by Galileo UVS, Geophysical Research
                   Letters 22: 1565-1568, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HORDETAL1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GO-J-UVS-3-RDR-SL9-G-FRAGMENT-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GO UVS TABULAR DATA FROM THE SL9-G IMPACT WITH JUPITER V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1996-07-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1994-07-18T07:02:14.445Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1994-07-18T07:13:21.712Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>KAREN E. SIMMONS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Simmons, K.E., GO UVS TABULAR DATA FROM THE SL9-G IMPACT WITH
            JUPITER V1.0, GO-J-UVS-3-RDR-SL9-G-FRAGMENT-V1.0, NASA Planetary
            Data System, 1996.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Galileo UVS tabular data from the P/Shoemaker-Levy 9 fragment G
            impact with Jupiter
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The UltraViolet Spectrometer (UVS) on the Galileo spacecraft took
            unique data of Comet Shoemaker-Levy/9&apos;s impact with Jupiter.
            A preliminary analysis of this data is presented in this
            submission to the Planetary Data System (PDS). It consists of
            four small tables with detached labels and documentation.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The UltraViolet Spectrometer (UVS) on the Galileo spacecraft took
      unique data of Comet Shoemaker-Levy/9&apos;s impact with Jupiter.  A
      preliminary analysis of this data is presented in this submission to
      the Planetary Data System (PDS).  It consists of four small tables
      with detached labels and documentation.
 
 
    Background
    ==========
      Galileo observed the SL9 fragment G impact by oscillating the
      scan-platform so that the fields of view of the scan-platform
      instruments moved to-and-fro across Jupiter. Each to-and-fro &apos;swath&apos;
      lasted 10 2/3 sec, and consisted of two 5 1/3 sec &apos;passes&apos;.  A total
      of 124 passes were played back, 73 full or partial passes were
      useful from these and 52 of these were complete passes used in the
      analysis. The detection pass was a complete pass.
 
      During the observations, the UVS acquired one measurement every 7.6
      msec (more precisely, 4.0/528 sec); during each measurement, the
      counting gate was open for 6.0 msec. Thus, each 10 2/3 sec swath
      contained 1408 6-msec samples. The data-taking was, however, not
      continuous, and the data received was occasionally corrupted.  The
      data presented here and used in [HORDETAL1995] has all been
      inspected and verified.
 
      Each 10 2/3 sec swath consists of two 5 1/3 sec &apos;passes&apos;, labelled
      &apos;even&apos; and &apos;odd&apos;. Because the crescent Jupiter was much smaller than
      the UVS slit, the wavelength range of the light passing through the
      exit slit changed slightly as the crescent passed across the
      instrument field of view. Thus, the &apos;profiles&apos; obtained during each
      pass do not have flat tops; the &apos;slope&apos; of the profile tops reflect
      the wavelength dependence of the reflected solar spectrum in the
      neighborhood of 292 nm. When preparing the &apos;average&apos; pass profile to
      compare with the &apos;impact flash&apos; profile, the profiles from even-
      numbered passes were reversed to allow for this effect.
 
      The UVS data-taking began at S/C clock time 2486477, corresponding
      to Spacecraft Event Time (SCET) 94199/07:02:14.445 UTC. The One-Way
      Light Travel (OWLT) time from Jupiter to Earth was 00h:42m:51s and
      the OWLT from Jupiter to the Galileo spacecraft was 00h:13m:20s.
      The OWLT found in the data files, of 00h:29m:30.73s, converts from
      spacecraft time to Jupiter event time as seen at the Earth.
 
      Jupiter&apos;s angular diameter as seen by GLL was less than the UVS slit
      width. The half-maximum points recorded by UVS as Jupiter entered
      and left the slit therefore correspond to the instants when
      Jupiter&apos;s center of light entered and left the slit. Because the UV
      flash of the G fragment impact lay to the left of Jupiter&apos;s center
      of light, and was of approximately constant brightness for a period
      longer than its traverse time, the traverse of the flash across the
      slit was slightly displaced in time when compared with the traverse
      of Jupiter.
 
 
    Tables in the Dataset
    =====================
      The data provided here for the G event are of four types:  swaths,
      passes, impact, and flash.
 
      G_SWATHS DATA
      -------------
      record 0 contains the elapsed time in seconds since the beginning
               of each to-and-fro swath (a swath consists of an &apos;even&apos;
               pass, occupying words 0-703 of a &apos;swath&apos;, and an &apos;odd&apos;
               pass occupying words 704-1407)
      record 1 contains the number of times a &apos;good&apos; measurement was
               obtained at a given time (out of a maximum of 62)
      record 2 contains the average of the counts obtained during the
               &apos;good&apos; measurements
      record 3 contains a triangular smooth of record 2, with a FWHM of
               13 words (approximately 0.10 sec)
      record 4 contains the mask that isolates the 1.25-sec interval used
               to characterize the average signal from Jupiter when its
               crescent was fully within the slit during &apos;even&apos; passes
               (ie #s 0, 2, 4, ...)
      record 5 contains the same as 4, except for &apos;odd&apos; passes (1, 3, ..)
      record 6 contains a mask isolating the 0.75-sec (99-word) interval
               used to estimate the scattered-light background for &apos;even&apos;
               passes
      record 7 contains the same as 6 for &apos;odd&apos; passes (except a 1.0-sec,
               132-word interval was used)
 
      G_PASSES DATA
      -------------
      record 0 contains flags indicating whether a given pass was good
               (1) or bad (0)
      record 1 contains the adjustment to the timing of each pass needed
               to compensate for small errors in the scan-platform
               pointing
      record 2 contains the elapsed SCET at which the center-of-light of
               Jupiter was at the center of the slit during each pass
      record 3 contains the corresponding Earth Observation Time (EOT),
               expressed as seconds after 94-199/07:30:00.0 UT
      record 4 contains the average of the counts obtained during the
               1.25-sec interval when Jupiter&apos;s crescent was fully within
               the UVS slit (see G_SWATHS.DAT, records 4 and 5)
      record 5 contains the average of the counts obtained during the
               background intervals (G_SWATHS.DAT, records 6 and 7)
      record 6 contains flags (used=1) indicating the passes used to obtain
               the &apos;average&apos; profile used to compare with the &apos;impact
               flash&apos; profile (ie, with pass #19)
 
      G_IMPACT DATA
      -------------
      record 0 contains the counts recorded during the &apos;impact&apos; pass (#19)
      record 1 contains a triangular smooth of record 0, with a FWHM of
               13 words (0.10 sec)
      record 2 contains the average of 52 passes neighboring #19 (see
               G_PASSES.DAT, record 6)
      record 3 contains a triangular smooth of record 2, with a FWHM of
               13 words (0.10 sec)
 
      G_FLASH DATA
      ------------
      record 0 contains the elapsed times at the centers of 54 13-word
               (0.10-sec) bins, measured from the beginning of pass #19
      record 1 contains the average counts recorded in each of these bins
      record 2 contains the corresponding averaged counts in the 52-pass
               average profile
      record 3 contains the excess of the pass #19 bins over the 52-pass
               average bins
      record 4 contains the 1-sigma uncertainties in these excesses
      record 5 contains a mask isolating the passage of the UV impact
               flash across the UVS slit
      record 6 contains the best straight-line fit to the count rates in
               the &apos;flash&apos; bins
 
      Details of the structure and contents of these tables may be found
      in the detached label accompanying each table and in the UVSRDRS.ASC
      file.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The raw UVS data received from the spacecraft were collected on EDRs
      by the UVS/EUV team at the Laboratory for Atmospheric and Space
      Physics at the University of Colorado at Boulder.  The tables in the
      submitted dataset were generated during the analysis of UVS data
      from the Shoemaker-Levy 9 comet Fragment G impact with Jupiter.  The
      detached PDS labels were prepared by the UVS/EUV team at LASP.  (The
      raw data is provided in the binary file GFRAGTIM.DAT .)
 
 
    Data structure
    ==============
      The table files follow PDS structure and labelling conventions.  A
      detached PDS label accompanies each file, and describes its
      structure and contents using ASCII keyword=value statements.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      The four tables in this dataset are small and in ASCII character
      format.  They are therefore printable and accessible with ordinary
      editing software.  The Reduced Data Records were originally
      constructed by replacing the IDL &apos;plot&apos; function with a &apos;write&apos;
      function and converting the binary &apos;write&apos; file to an ASCII &apos;print&apos;
      file.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      This dataset is an electronic submission to PDS but may be included
      on a future CD-ROM volume of UVS data from the Jupiter Tour.
      Formats are based on standards for table objects established by
      PDS.
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      A one second error associated with a missing leapsecond in early
      versions of this data set has been corrected here.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XD-B3B</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

