<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.near-a-spice-6-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>NEAR SPICE KERNELS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.near_earth_asteroid_rendezvous::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.near::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.near::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.253_mathilde::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.433_eros::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.near-a-spice-6-v1.0__browserp_near-a-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.near-a-spice-6-v1.0__browser_near-a-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.near-a-spice-6-v1.0__browser_wgc_near-a-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.naif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Acton, Jr. C.H., Ancillary Data Services of NASA&apos;s Navigation and Ancillary
                   Information Facility, Planetary and Space Sciences, 44, Number 1, pp. 65-70,
                   1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ACTON1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>NEAR-A-SPICE-6-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>NEAR SPICE KERNELS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2012-12-31</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1996-05-30T23:58:58Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2001-02-28T17:14:46Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>BORIS V. SEMENOV</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Semenov B.V., H.W. Taylor, and C.H. Acton, NEAR SPICE KERNELS
            V1.0, NEAR-A-SPICE-6-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2012.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Navigation and ancillary data in the form of SPICE System kernel
            files for the NEAR spacecraft.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set includes the complete set of NEAR SPICE data files
            (``kernel files&apos;), which can be accessed using SPICE
            software. The SPICE data contain geometric and other ancillary
            information needed to recover the full value of science
            instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft
            and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments,
            spacecraft orientation, and data needed for relevant time
            conversions.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
 
      This data set includes the complete set of NEAR SPICE data files
      (``kernel files&apos;), which can be accessed using SPICE software.
      The SPICE data contain geometric and other ancillary information
      needed to recover the full value of science instrument data. In
      particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft and planetary
      ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments, spacecraft
      orientation, and data needed for relevant time conversions.
 
      This data set was created by assembling the original NEAR SPICE
      data sets
 
        NEAR-A-SPICE-6-CRUISE1-V1.0
        NEAR-A-SPICE-6-MATHILDE-V1.0
        NEAR-A-SPICE-6-CRUISE2-V1.0
        NEAR-A-SPICE-6-EARTH-V1.0
        NEAR-A-SPICE-6-CRUISE3-V1.0
        NEAR-A-SPICE-6-EROS/FLY/BY-V1.0
        NEAR-A-SPICE-6-CRUISE4-V1.0
        NEAR-A-SPICE-6-EROS/ORBIT-V1.0
        NEAR-A-SPICE-6-EROS/SURFACE-V1.0
 
      containing data for individual mission phases into a single data
      set containing data for the whole mission. Most kernels from the
      original data sets were included in this data set with the same
      names and without changing their data. The only exception was
      daily CK files that were merged into tri-monthly CK files to
      reduce the total number of kernels to increase the usability of
      the archive. But even in the case of the CK files the merge was
      done in such way that the original data was not altered. The
      comments in all kernels were changed slightly either by adding a
      copy of the new PDS label at the top or by replacing the copy of
      the old label with a copy of the new label.
 
 
      Data Types (SPICE kernel types)
      ===============================
 
      SPK kernels contain ephemerides for spacecraft, planets,
      satellites, comets and asteroids as well as for moving or fixed
      spacecraft and instrument structures. They provide position and
      velocity, given in a Cartesian reference frame. SPK files are
      located under the ``data/spk&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      PCK kernels contain certain physical, dynamical and cartographic
      constants for target bodies, such as size and shape
      specifications, and orientation of the spin axis and prime
      meridian. PCK files are located under the ``data/pck&apos; directory
      of this data set.
 
      IK kernels (Instrument description kernels) give descriptive and
      operational data peculiar to a particular scientific instrument,
      such as internal timing relative to the spacecraft clock and
      field-of-view model parameters. IK files are located under the
      ``data/ik&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      CK kernels describe pointing, containing a transformation
      traditionally called the C-matrix which is used to determine
      time-tagged pointing (orientation) angles for a spacecraft
      structure upon which science instruments are mounted. CK files
      are located under the ``data/ck&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      EK (Events) kernels are derived from the integrated sequence of
      events used to produce actual spacecraft commands. EK files are
      located under the ``data/ek&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      LSK (Leapseconds) kernels contain the leapseconds and the values
      of other constants required to perform a transformation between
      Universal Time Coordinated (UTC) and Ephemeris time (ET). LSK
      files are located under the ``data/lsk&apos; directory of this data
      set.
 
      SCLK (Spacecraft Clock) kernels contain on-board clock
      calibration data required to perform a mapping between Ephemeris
      time (ET) and spacecraft on-board time (SCLK). SCLK files are
      located under the ``data/sclk&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      FK (Frame Definitions) kernels contain information required to
      define reference frames, sources of frame orientation data and
      connections between these frames and other frames supported
      within the SPICE system. This includes mounting alignment
      information for each instrument. FK files are located under the
      ``data/fk&apos; directory of this data set.
 
 
      Kernel File Details
      ===================
 
      A brief overview of the different types of NEAR kernels included
      in this data set is provided in the CONFIDENCE_LEVEL_NOTE section
      of this file while details specific to individual files are found
      in the ``*info.txt&apos; files in the corresponding data directory.
      The most detailed description of the data in each file is
      provided in metadata included inside the file -- in the
      description area of text kernels or in the comment area of binary
      kernels.
 
 
      Software
      ========
 
      The SPICE Toolkit contains software modules needed to read SPICE
      kernel files. SPICE software is highly documented via internal
      headers. Additional documentation is available in separate ASCII
      text files called Required Reading files. For example, the S- and
      P- Kernel (SPK) Required Reading File, named SPK.REQ, describes
      use of the SPK kernel file readers and contains sample programs.
 
      The latest SPICE Toolkit for a variety of computer platforms such
      as PC, Mac, SUN, etc. is available at the NAIF Node of PDS
      electronically (via anonymous FTP and WWW servers). Refer to
      information in ``software/softinfo.txt&apos; for details regarding
      obtaining this software. Each version of the Toolkit is also
      archived at the NASA National Space Science Data Center.
 
 
      Loading Kernel Files into a SPICE-based Application
      ===================================================
 
      The easiest way to make data from a collection of SPICE kernels
      available to a SPICE-based application is to list these kernels
      in a meta-kernel and load it into the program using the high
      level SPICE data loader routine FURNSH. This data set provides
      such meta-kernel(s) under the ``extras/mk&apos; directory. For more
      information about the NEAR meta-kernel(s), see the file
      ``extras/mk/mkinfo.txt&apos;.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      Confidence Level Overview
      =========================
 
      This volume contains SPICE kernel files created during mission
      operations only. No post processing has been done on these data
      except for merging daily CK files into tri-monthly CK files in
      such way that the original data was not altered.
 
      Some general information about this collection follows here, but
      the prospective user is also referred to extensive descriptions
      about each file that are stored inside each kernel file. These
      metadata provide detailed information regarding the information
      source from which the data were derived, the type of processing
      applied to the source data, applicability of the data, etc.
      Metadata are located in the ``comment area&apos; for binary kernel
      types (SPK, CK, ESQ), accessible using either the COMMNT or
      SPACIT utility program found in the NAIF Toolkit. Metadata are
      located after ``\begintext&apos; markers within the text kernel types
      (PCK, IK, FK, LSK, SCLK, MK), accessible by using any available
      text file display tool such as a word processor, text editor, or
      the unix ``more&apos; or ``cat&apos; commands.
 
      Where there are questions about data accuracy or ``confidence&apos;
      not addressed herein the reader is invited to contact the NAIF
      node of the Planetary Data System for possible further
      information.
 
 
      SPK Files
      =========
 
      Three kinds of SPK files are provided in this archive: SPK files
      for the spacecraft orbit; SPK files for the Solar System planets
      and asteroids (Eros, Earth, Sun, etc); and SPK files with the DSN
      station locations. Each kind of file is briefly described below;
      more information is available in the file ``data/spk/spkinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      Spacecraft Orbit SPK Files
      --------------------------
      SPK files for the spacecraft were created by the NEAR
      Navigation team/JPL, NEAR Radio Science Team/JPL, and NLR
      Team/GSFC.
 
      The SPK files by NEAR Navigation team/JPL were specifically
      created for science users and distributed through the Science
      Data Center. These kernels were merged from series of final
      operational reconstructed OD solution SPKs. Combined, these SPKs
      cover the whole mission.
 
      The SPK kernels by the NEAR Radio Science Team/JPL and NLR
      Team/GSFC were created as a by-product of science processing of
      the Eros orbital data by these teams and cover only the Eros
      orbit part of the mission.
 
      Solar System Body SPK Files
      ---------------------------
      The solar system body SPK files were provided by the JPL
      Navigation team by way of the NAIF group. The accuracies for the
      bodies in each file can be obtained by inspecting the comment
      portion of each file. The asteroid SPK files were provided
      directly from the JPL Navigation team. The comment portion of the
      Mathilde and Eros SPK files provide detailed information
      regarding their usage and accuracy.
 
      Station Locations SPK Files
      ---------------------------
      The DSN station locations SPK file was provided by the NAIF
      group. It contains locations of the four tracking stations used
      by the NEAR mission.
 
 
      CK Files
      ========
 
      C-kernel files provide orientation of the spacecraft. With the
      exception of NIS, the NEAR instruments have fixed orientation.
      MSI, NIS, XGRS and NLR all nominally are oriented along the
      spacecraft positive X-axis. The Solar panels and high gain
      antenna are nominally oriented in the positive z-axis. The small
      difference of instrument orientation from the X-axis are given in
      the instrument kernel (IK) files. The data CK files are taken
      directly from the attitude telemetry produced by the spacecraft
      Flight Computer (FC). The FC data is reformatted at full
      resolution into the CK files.
 
      More information about the CK files included in this data set is
      available in the file ``data/ck/ckinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      EK Files
      ========
 
      Events kernel files are often used to digitally represent an
      experimenter&apos;s notebook (ENB EKs) or to list a summary of all
      commands sent to a spacecraft, as is the case with Sequence EKs.
      In the case of NEAR, E-kernels are used in a very different way:
      to efficiently represent the shape of Eros. This representation
      is often referred to as a ``shape&apos; or ``plate&apos; model.
 
      There are two plate models of Eros in this delivery, one at a
      lower resolution, having only 1566 plates and another at a higher
      resolution, having 7516 plates. These plate E-kernels are
      specifically designed for use with the SPICE plate library,
      developed specifically for NEAR. This library is used to perform
      geometric calculations related to fields of view, observing
      geometry, etc. for shape models defined as a plate E-Kernel.
 
      More information about the EK files included in this data set is
      available in the file ``data/ek/ekinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      PCK Files
      =========
 
      PCK files provide size, shape and orientation data for ``target&apos;
      bodies such as Mathilde and Eros. A description of these data
      items and reference to their source is provided inside the text
      PCK files, which are simple text files that can be viewed using
      any word processor, text editor or text display utility, or in
      the comment areas of the binary PCK files.
 
      More information about the PCK files included in this data set is
      available in the file ``data/pck/pckinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      IK Files
      ========
 
      Instrument kernel files provide specifications for the mounting
      alignment and where applicable field-of-view size, shape and
      orientation for the named instrument. NEAR IKs also include the
      definitions of the spacecraft and instrument reference frames.
      Metadata describing these estimates are provided in each IK file
      included in this archive. Parameter values were determined from
      pre-launch measurements or from manufacturing blueprints.
 
      More information about the IK files included in this data set is
      available in the file ``data/ik/ikinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      SCLK Files
      ==========
 
      Spacecraft Clock kernel files provide a tabulation of data needed
      for converting time measurements between ephemeris time (ET) and
      spacecraft clock time (SCLK). The SPICE SCLK file is produced by
      the NEAR Mission Operations Center.
 
      The time correlation accuracy provided in SCLK files is
      informally reported by the MOPS team to be better 20 milliseconds
      during orbital phases. This accuracy has been corroborated by
      independent estimates to within 500ms.
 
      SPICE software does not prohibit an SCLK file from being used for
      time conversions occurring for ``future times&apos; (or more
      accurately, for epochs that occur later than the epoch of the
      last telemetry data used in producing the last correlation
      coefficients found in the SCLK file). Such ``predict&apos; time
      conversions are likely to be inaccurate (changed somewhat) once
      the epoch of interest has been passed.
 
      More information about the SCLK files included in this data set is
      available in the file ``data/sclk/sclkinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      LSK Files
      =========
 
      Leapseconds kernel files provide a tabulation of ``leapseconds&apos;
      and some other terms used in converting time measurements between
      ephemeris time (ET) and Universal Time (UTC). ``Spacecraft Event
      Time&apos; (SCET) is the commonly used name for UTC events measured
      at the spacecraft.
 
      Metadata describing how the LSK data are obtained or computed is
      contained inside the LSK text file. The time conversion provided
      by SPICE LSK files is accurate to approximately 0.000030 seconds.
 
      More information about the LSK files included in this data set is
      available in the file ``data/lsk/lskinfo.txt&apos;.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

