<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ear-x-i2041-5-ch3dicespec-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CH3D ICE ABSORPTION COEFFICIENTS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.support_archives::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.lab9884::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:i2041.lab9884::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:terrestrial_sample.ch3d_diluted_in_ch4_methane_ice::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:terrestrial_sample.ch3d_diluted_in_n2_nitrogen_ice::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-x-i2041-5-ch3dicespec-v1.0__browserp_ear-x-i2041-5-ch3dicespec-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Grundy, W.M., S.J. Morrison, M.J. Bovyn, S.C. Tegler, and D.M. Cornelison,
                   Remote sensing D/H ratios in methane ice: Temperature-dependent absorption
                   coefficients of CH3D in methane ice and in nitrogen ice. Icarus 212, 941-949,
                   doi:10.1016/j.icarus.2011.01.034, 2011.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GRUNDYETAL2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>EAR-X-I2041-5-CH3DICESPEC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CH3D ICE ABSORPTION COEFFICIENTS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2014-01-13</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2010-07-21</start_time>
        <stop_time>2010-08-25</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>WILL GRUNDY</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Grundy, W.M., Morrison, S.J., Bovyn, M.J., Tegler, S.C., and
            Cornelison, D.M., CH3D ice absorption coefficients V1.0.
            EAR-X-I2041-5-CH3DICESPEC-V1.0. NASA Planetary Data System, 2014.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            We record laboratory spectra at wavelengths of 2.47, 2.87, and
            4.56 microns to study CH3D. We report temperature-dependent
            absorption coefficients of these bands when the CH3D is diluted
            in CH4 ice and also when it is dissolved in N2 ice.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set is the result of laboratory transmission
            spectroscopy experiments performed within a sealed cell in the
            ice laboratory at Northern Arizona University. We record spectra
            at wavelengths from 1 to 6 microns to study CH3D bands at 2.47,
            2.87, and 4.56 microns (as indicated by &apos;25&apos;,
            &apos;29&apos; and &apos;45&apos; in the data file names). We
            report temperature-dependent absorption coefficients of these
            bands when the CH3D is diluted in CH4 ice and also when it is
            dissolved in N2 ice. These absorption coefficient spectra can be
            combined with data from the literature to simulate arbitrary D/H
            ratio absorption coefficients for CH4 ice and for CH4 in N2 ice.
            The data were originally published in 2011 in Icarus, vol. 212,
            pp. 941-949, and that paper should be consulted for details about
            laboratory procedures and limitations of the data.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    Quoting from the Icarus paper:
 
    &apos;Samples were mixed at room temperature in [a 2 liter] volume using CH4
    and N2 gases supplied in high pressure cylinders by Airgas Specialty
    Gases. These were connected through separate pressure regulators and
    valves to the mixing volume. The reported purities were &gt;=99.99% for the
    CH4 and &gt;=99.9% for the N2. To these gases, we could add CH3D purchased in
    a lecture bottle from Sigma Aldrich (product number 490237, with a
    reported purity of &gt;=98%).  Unlike in water, proton-deuteron exchange is
    negligible in methane at room temperature and below, so we did not need to
    consider the formation of other isotopomers such as CH2D2 and CHD3 (Sigma
    Aldrich Stable Isotope Department, personal communication 2010). After
    mixing gases to the desired composition at room temperature in the mixing
    volume, we opened a valve to allow the gas to flow into the empty, cold
    cell, condensing it as a liquid. We froze this liquid by
    reducing its temperature, maintaining a vertical thermal gradient of about
    2 K across the 15 mm diameter sample by means of heaters (see Fig. 1), so
    that it would freeze from the bottom upward, with the location of the
    freezing front being controlled by the cell temperature. Each new mixture
    requires some experimentation to find appropriate cooling rates, but rates
    for freezing samples were typically in the range of -0.01 to -0.1 K/min.
    It was sometimes necessary to freeze an initial polycrystalline mass and
    then melt almost all of it to obtain a small seed crystal before
    re-freezing slowly, in order to obtain an optical-quality ice sample.
    After a suitable sample had been frozen, we removed the thermal gradient
    by smoothly shifting temperature-control heating from the upper to the
    lower heating element over a period of 10-20 min. Using only the
    bottom heater for temperature control resulted in a thermal gradient
    across the sample of just a few tenths of a Kelvin.
 
    &apos;Spectra were recorded with a Nicolet Nexus 670 Fourier transform infrared
    (FTIR) spectrometer at a sampling interval of 0.24 cm-1, resulting in a
    spectral resolution of 0.6 cm-1 (measured full width at half maximum of
    unresolved lines). The spectrometer beam was focused to a few mm spot
    inside the cell. We typically averaged over 100 spectral scans to improve
    the signal/noise ratio. After a sample spectrum had been recorded, we
    would ramp to a new temperature, at rates typically in the range of
    0.1-0.5 K/min. We recorded spectra through our ice samples at every
    multiple of 10 K between 40 K and the host ice melting points (90.7 K for
    CH4 ice, 63.1 K for N2 ice).
 
    &apos;Before each ice sample was prepared we also recorded spectra through the
    empty, cold cell, and did the same after each sample was eliminated.
    Filled-cell spectra were divided by empty-cell spectra to remove gross
    effects of lamp emission, detector sensitivity, and absorptions by the
    windows and air, resulting in approximate transmission spectra T(k). These
    spectra are affected by subtle, spurious slopes from a variety of sources.
    Wavelength-dependent refractive index contrasts exist between ice and cell
    windows leading to slightly different transmission through the ice-window
    interface than through the vacuum-window interface.  The room temperature
    refractive index n(k) of sapphire decreases gradually with wavelength from
    about 1.76 to 1.59 from 1.0 to 5.5 microns (Malitson et al., 1958;
    Gervais, 1991) but methane ice shows almost no wavelength dependence in
    its refractive index (except at wavelengths near 3.3 microns where
    absorption is so strong that we measure no transmission whatsoever; Pearl
    et al., 1991). If we knew the temperature dependent n(k) of both
    sapphire and ice, and the ice-window interfaces were solely responsible
    for these slopes, we could easily correct for the effect. But as the ice
    and the surrounding cell contract on cooling, each with their own
    distinct temperature-dependent coefficients of thermal expansion, the
    sample is stressed and can fracture or pull away from the windows, opening
    additional ice-vacuum interfaces that can produce wavelength-dependent
    scattering that varies with temperature, with thermal history, and
    with location within the sample. In addition to imparting slopes,
    these effects lead to a decline in overall transmission, by as much as
    a factor of three in an ice sample cooled relatively rapidly from 90 to
    40 K. Slow drifts in lamp filament temperature or detector sensitivity
    over the course of experiments lasting multiple days can also contribute
    spurious slopes. Slopes arising from any combination of the above factors
    were removed by fitting a line or low-order polynomial to continuum
    regions adjacent to absorption bands to be quantified and dividing by
    this function to &apos;straighten out&apos; the continuum. The continuum-corrected
    transmission spectra were then converted to Lambert absorption coefficient
    spectra alpha(lambda) via the Beer-Lambert absorption law, rearranged
    as alpha(lambda) = -ln(T(lambda))/d, where d is the path length through
    the cell (d = 5.4 +- 0.1 mm for all experiments reported in this paper).
 
    &apos;We added a small amount of CH3D to CH4 to produce a deuterium-enriched
    sample that remained dominated by normal CH4 absorptions. Addition of 0.5%
    CH3D (D/H ratio of 1.25 x 10-4) produced ice having sufficiently strong
    CH3D absorption to be easily measurable, but not so strong as to be
    saturated in transmission though our 5.4 mm optical path length. We were
    not able to directly measure the D/H ratio in our ice sample, so we
    assumed zero fractionation between the gas phase and the liquid condensed
    from it, and again zero fractionation between the liquid and the solid
    crystallized from it.
 
    &apos;We subtracted the ordinary methane absorption coefficients to isolate
    the contribution of the CH3D. The resulting CH3D ice absorption
    coefficients were divided by the 0.5% concentration of the CH3D
    (assuming the composition was unchanged by condensation and freezing)
    to obtain effective absorption coefficients for CH3D in methane as
    if it were pure CH3D. These values can be combined with ordinary CH4
    ice absorption coefficients, scaled by their relative abundances, to
    approximate absorption coefficients for arbitrary CH3D/CH4 mixing ratios.
 
    &apos;We performed an experiment with CH3D diluted in the hexagonal beta phase
    of N2 ice. N2 ice melts at 63.1 K, so this experiment spanned a smaller
    range of temperatures. Uncertainty over the CH3D concentration in the
    ice presented even more of a challenge with this experiment. The CH3D/N2
    ratio mixed in the gas phase in the mixing volume could not be expected
    to remain unchanged in the ice, for two reasons. First, methane is much
    less volatile than nitrogen. On condensing the N2-dominated gas into
    the cell as a liquid at about 65 K, some of the deuterated methane could
    have condensed as frost somewhere in the inlet tube rather than making
    it into the cell. Second, compositional gradients appear on freezing,
    as a result of the separation between liquidus and solidus curves of
    the binary phase diagram of nitrogen and methane (e.g., Prokhvatilov
    and Yantsevich, 1983; unfortunately, the two curves are difficult to
    distinguish in their figure). Quirico and Schmitt (1997) assumed that
    the integrated absorptions of CH4 bands remain unchanged on dilution
    in N2 ice in order to estimate the composition of their samples. Making
    the same assumption for CH3D, we used the integrated absorption of the
    4.56 micron CH3D band to estimate the CH3D fraction in our mixed CH3D + N2
    ice sample as 0.0024 +- 0.0002 (about a factor of two below its gas phase
    abundance of 0.005). As before, we subtracted the absorption coefficients
    of the host N2 ice, studied in an otherwise identical separate experiment
    in our laboratory, to isolate the CH3D absorptions.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    Temperatures uncertainty is about +- 0.5K.
 
    Cell thickness uncertainty is about +- 0.1 mm.
 
    Composition uncertainty is not well determined.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

