<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.grail-l-lgrs-2-edr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GRAIL MOON LGRS RAW SCIENCE V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.gravity_recovery_and_interior_laboratory::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.grail-a::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:lgrs-a.grail-a::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.grail-l-lgrs-2-edr-v1.0__browserp_grail-l-lgrs-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.grail-l-lgrs-2-edr-v1.0__dvo_grail-l-lgrs-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Rogstad, T.D., Telemetry Dictionary (TD) Gravity Recovery Processor Assembly
                   (GPA) Flight Software Rev. E (Telemetry dictionary documentation extracted from
                   JPL D-49059), Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, 2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ROGSTAD2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GRAIL-L-LGRS-2-EDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GRAIL MOON LGRS RAW SCIENCE V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2014-04-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2012-03-01</start_time>
        <stop_time>2012-12-18</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DANIEL S. KAHAN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            KAHAN, D.S., GRAIL LGRS Raw Science Data Set V1.0,
            GRAIL-L-LGRS-2-EDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2012.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw science data originating from the Lunar Gravity Ranging
            System (LGRS) on each of the two spacecraft comprising the
            Gravity Recovery and Interior Laboratory (GRAIL) mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains archival raw science data, acquired from
            the Lunar Gravity Ranging System (LGRS) on each of the two
            spacecraft comprising the Gravity Recovery and Interior
            Laboratory (GRAIL) mission. The data are at NASA Level 0 and were
            archived for historical purposes only. All Level 0 products were
            processed to NASA Level 1A in the LGRS CDR data set by the GRAIL
            Science Data System (SDS). The observations were used in
            generating high-resolution gravity field models of the Moon. The
            data set includes all of the LGRS raw data collected by GRAIL
            (March-December 2012).
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Gravity Recovery and Interior Laboratory (GRAIL) Lunar
      Gravity Ranging System (LGRS) Experimental Data Record Archive
      is a time-ordered collection of raw and partially processed data
      collected during the GRAIL mission to the Moon.
 
      The DATA_SET_ID &apos;GRAIL-L-LGRS-2-EDR-V1.0&apos; includes the following
      components:
          Instrument host (i.e., &apos;GRAIL&apos;)
          Target (i.e., &apos;L&apos; for Lunar)
          Instrument (i.e., &apos;LGRS&apos; for Lunar Gravity Ranging System)
          CODMAC Data processing level number (i.e., &apos;2&apos;)
          Description (i.e., &apos;EDR&apos; for Experiment Data Record)
          Version number (i.e., &apos;V1.0&apos;)
 
      This data set was collected between March and December 2012.
 
      Most of the data were extracted from spacecraft telemetry
      (packet data) [ROGSTAD2012]. They were corrected for telemetry
      errors and have been split or decommutated. Data are tagged with
      time and location of acquisition within the spacecraft frame.
 
      Each telemetry packet generated by the LGRS flight software was
      wrapped inside a packet called a BlackJack Protocol Frame, which
      ensured the integrity of the data; Blackjack was inherited from
      the predecessor Gravity Recovery and Climate Experiment (GRACE)
      terrestrial gravity mission. The documents
      GPA_TD_D_71987_REVE.TXT and BLACKJACKDLP.TXT in the DOCUMENT
      directory describe the format of the Blackjack binary data for
      processing to Level 1A.
 
      Typical users of GRAIL products will not need this data set.
      The data are provided for the advanced user who wishes to
      recreate the Level 1A LGRS CDR data products from scratch.
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      The Standard Formatted Data Unit (SFDU) products S7200, S7300,
      and STC00 are binary and contain (besides the appropriate
      headers) the unscaled, encoded instrument communication
      packets. For information on extracting the SFDU data contents,
      see the following in the DOCUMENT directory:
 
          0161_TELECOMM_L5_8.TXT
          0171_TELECOMM_NJPL_L5.TXT
          090_REVC_1.TXT, and
          0172_TELECOMM_CHDO_REVE_L5.TXT
 
      The remaining nine LGRS EDR product types are in ASCII format.
      Of those, eight originated from telemetry queries from the GRAIL
      Ground Data System (GDS).
 
      File type TDE00 (Time Transfer System Direct to Earth)
      originated from S-Band ranging data from the Time Transfer
      System in the LGRS that was collected on the ground. It was
      included in this Level 0 data set because it was an important
      input to the creation of the Level 1 products in the LGRS CDR
      data set.
 
      All types except LTB00 are spacecraft-specific.
 
      Each Level 0 product is accompanied by a minimal PDS label that
      points to relevant documentation.
 
      For additional information on parameters in this data set, see
      the DATA section below.
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      Data in this set were extracted from telemetry (packet data).
      They have been corrected for telemetry errors and have been
      split or decommutated. They are tagged with time and location of
      acquisition.
 
      Level 0 files were provided by the GRAIL SDS; they are
      constructed so that each file contains the data for one day.
 
    Data
    ====
 
      Time Correlation Data Record File (DRF) (DTC00)
      -----------------------------------------------
        Clock correlation between Real Time Clock (RTC),
        Binary Time Code (BTC),
        and the 1-per-second pulse
        associated with LGRS time (ASCII).
 
      Spacecraft Engineering Housekeeping data (EHK00)
      ------------------------------------------------
        Includes temperature sensor data for locations near the LGRS
        instrumentation (ASCII).
 
      LGRS Time Bias of the Lunar Gravity Ranging System (LTB00)
      ----------------------------------------------------------
        Accumulated list of biases over the complete mission in BTC
        time (ASCII). One file combined for BOTH spacecraft.
 
      Satellite Mass Data (MAS00)
      ---------------------------
        Accumulated list of center of mass and spacecraft mass over
        the complete mission (ASCII).
 
      Engineering SFDU ID #72 (S7200)
      -------------------------------
        Spacecraft unscaled, binary encoded instrument communication
        packets.
 
      Science SFDU ID #73 (S7300)
      ---------------------------
        Spacecraft unscaled, binary encoded instrument communication
        packets.
 
      Solar Array Eclipse data (SAE00)
      --------------------------------
        Includes solar array short circuit currents and open circuit
        voltages, to identify eclipse events for spacecraft ephemeris
        models (ASCII).
 
      Star Tracker Data (SCA00)
      -------------------------
        Includes attitudes from an on-board Kalman filter that
        processes Star Tracker attitude data and Inertial Measurement
        Unit (IMU) angular rotation data (ASCII).
 
      Time Correlation SFDU (STC00)
      -----------------------------
        Spacecraft unscaled, binary encoded instrument communication
        packets.
 
      Time Transfer System Direct to Earth (TDE00)
      --------------------------------------------
        Measured time correlation between LGRS time and UTC, using
        Time Transfer System (TTS) S-Band ranging collected at DSS-24.
 
      Thruster Activation Data (THR00)
      --------------------------------
        Includes time tags, counts of cumulative work cycles for each
        thruster, recent thruster on time, and cumulative thruster on
        time (ASCII).
 
      Wheel Rotational Speed Data (WRS00)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        WRS00 describes rotational wheel speed of each of four
        Reaction wheels as determined by a digital tachometer (ASCII)
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      Data from the LGRS are typically related to their location
      within the spacecraft frame. For more information about the
      spacecraft mechanical frame, see GRAILCOMPONENTS.PDF in the
      CALIB directory.
 
    Naming Conventions
    ==================
      For all LGRS data, the product identifier, in conjunction with
      either a date or a range of dates in a specified format,
      determines the filename containing the data product.
 
      The file naming convention for most Level 0/1A/1B LGRS products
      is:
 
        PRDID_YYYY_MM_DD_S_VV.EXT
 
        where
 
        PRDID   product identification label, e.g. CLK1B
        YYYY    year
        MM      month
        DD      day of month
        S       GRAIL satellite identifier:
                        A     GRAIL-A
                        B     GRAIL-B
                        X     combined product of GRAIL-A and GRAIL-B
        VV      data product version number (starting from 00)
        EXT     file extension indicating binary (DAT) or ASCII (ASC)
                files
 
      The Product ID (PRDID) is of the form XXXLL, where:
        XXX     is a three-character mnemonic, and
        LL      specifies the data product Level (00, 1A, 1B).
 
      The only exception to this naming convention is TDE00. To
      accommodate multiple direct-to-earth measurements within the
      same day, the convention is:
 
        PRDID_YYYY_MM_DD_S_NNNNN_VV.EXT
 
        where
 
        PRDID   product identification label, e.g. CLK1B
        YYYY    year
        MM      month
        DD      day of month
        S       GRAIL satellite identifier:
                        A     GRAIL-A
                        B     GRAIL-B
                        X     combined product of GRAIL-A and GRAIL-B
        NNNNN   seconds past midnight start time (1 to 5 digits)
        VV      data product version number (starting from 00)
        EXT     file extension indicating binary (DAT) or ASCII (ASC)
                files
 
      The Product ID (PRDID) is of the form XXXLL, where:
      XXX       is a three-character mnemonic, and
      LL        specifies the data product Level (00).
 
    Files in the CALIB Directory
    ============================
      One file, GRAILCOMPONENTS.TXT is included in the CALIB
      directory. It describes the Spacecraft bus component model with
      dimensions and orientations, as well as the spacecraft
      components specular/diffuse reflectivity properties. It is
      likely to have wide applicability in working with the raw data.
 
    Software
    ========
      Software for parsing, reducing, and analyzing data such as
      these has been developed at JPL and elsewhere. Because such
      software must usually operate at the bit-level and is written
      for a narrow range of platforms, it is not suitable for general
      distribution. No distributable software is included with this
      archival data set.
 
      The SOFTWARE directory contains examples of utilities or
      application programs to aid the user in viewing or extracting
      data from the Level 0 data product files. The codes are provided
      as illustrations of how to extract the Blackjack packets from
      Blackjack binary data.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this archival data set have been collected to support
      derivation of the gravity field of the Moon. These are similar
      to data collected using the GRACE spacecraft and are believed to
      be generally of good quality.
 
    Review
    ======
      This archive underwent PDS external review from August 31, 2012
      to November 30, 2012.
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Files in this data set were constructed to cover one day each.
 
      Data coverage includes the science phase (March 1, 2012, to May
      29, 2012), the extended mission phase (August 29, 2012, to
      December 12, 2012), and the decommissioning phase (December 12,
      2012, to December 18, 2012) as described in the mission catalog.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      Certain spacecraft events have an impact on the science
      processing. These events include propulsive maneuvers, Ka
      boresight calibration attitude maneuvers, telecommunication
      configuration changes, and Lunar Gravity Ranging System (LGRS)
      events.
 
      Both spacecraft performed propulsive maneuvers. The mass change
      history for both spacecraft can be found in the MAS1A/B Level-1
      products, and the thruster on-times are available in the THR1A/B
      level-1 products. LGRS measurements are taken during the
      propulsive maneuvers, but it is recommended to break science
      data arcs at the propulsive maneuver event times, since the
      velocity changes imparted on the spacecraft are not known with
      sufficient accuracy for science processing.
 
      LGRS measurements are taken during the angular momentum
      desaturation maneuvers, but it is recommended to break science
      data arcs at the desaturation maneuver event times, since the
      velocity changes imparted on the spacecraft are not known with
      sufficient accuracy for science processing. For detailed
      thruster on time histories see level-1 product THR1A/B.
 
      The LGRS Gravity Processor Assemby (GPA) rebooted several times
      resulting in the loss of Ka range and the Time Transfer System
      (TTS) observables for about 1.5 minutes. After a GPA reboot the
      LGRS clock is synched with the LGRS clock on the non-rebooting
      spacecraft using the TTS system. GPA reboots will cause a gap in
      the inter-satellite range data products (KBR1B, SBR1B) of about
      2 minutes.
 
      On GRAIL-B the TTS phase measurement is reset to zero due to a
      software bug in the LGRS software. The TTS ranging measurement
      is not affected, but the relative LGRS clock reconstruction
      analysis needs to be restarted at a phase reset.
 
      Due to orbital viewing geometry, the GRAIL spacecraft are
      changing between the +X and -X S-band and X-band (Radio Science
      Beacon) antennas approximately every 14 days. The complete
      history for the antenna change are listed in the VGS1B product
      (S-band) and VGX1B (X-band).
 
      During the primary and extended missions, the GRAIL spacecraft
      were in nominal science attitude called orbiter point attitude
      mode. For  this mode the solar arrays of the spacecraft are
      parallel to the orbital plane and the Ka boresight vectors (2.1
      degrees off the -Z axis in the YZ spacecraft frame) are pointed
      in the direction of line of sight toward the other spacecraft.
      The GRAIL spacecraft remained in orbit point attitude mode
      except during Ka boresight vector calibration maneuvers when the
      spacecraft performed two orthogonal slews of 3 degrees about the
      line of sight vector between the two spacecraft. LGRS
      measurements are taken during the maneuvers but should not be
      used in the science processing because the measured range change
      is the sum of orbit geometry, lunar gravity and range change
      induced by spacecraft attitude variation. Ka boresight vector
      data contain range corrections for the phase center to center of
      mass offset during the maneuvers but these corrections are not
      reliable and should not be used.
 
      For specific dates of the above events, see the operational
      considerations section in LGRS_A_INST.CAT and LGRS_B_INST.CAT.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

