<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.phx-m-met-3-pt-rdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>PHOENIX MARS METEOROLOGICAL PRESSURE / TEMPERATURE RDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.phoenix::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.phx::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:met.phx::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.phx-m-met-3-pt-rdr-v1.0__browserp_phx-m-met-3-pt-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.phx-m-met-3-pt-rdr-v1.0__browser_geo_phx-m-met-3-pt-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.phx-m-met-3-pt-rdr-v1.0__dvo_atm_phx-m-met-3-pt-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Taylor, P. et al., Meteorology Station MET on the Phoenix Mars Lander:
                   Pressure, Temperature and Wind Speed, J. Geophys. Res. E00A10,
                   doi:10.1029/2007JE003015, 2008.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TAYLOR2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>PHX-M-MET-3-PT-RDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>PHOENIX MARS METEOROLOGICAL PRESSURE / TEMPERATURE RDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2008-12-23</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2008-05-26T00:08:36.308Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2008-06-25T18:14:37.816Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>CAMERON S. DICKINSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Dickinson, C. D., PHX METEOROLOGICAL DATA V1.0, NASA Planetary
            Data System, 2008.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            PHX MET calibrated Pressure and Temperature Data
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The PHX METEOROLOGICAL DATA product contains calibrated
            temperature and pressure data. The temperature data was collected
            at 250, 500 and 1000mm above the Phoenix Lander deck, and the
            pressure data was collected at (nearly) the height of the Lander
            deck. Nominally the data was collected at 2 sec resolution, but
            is also provided at 512 sec averages (with distribution
            statistics). Owing to the placement of a heater near the pressure
            sensor, a corrected set of values was required, and is provided
            for the pressure data.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Modification History
  ====================
    Version 1 data volumes include volumes MS000 through LS029, released
    Dec 2008.  These volumes contain MET data collected May 2008
    through June 2008, sols 0-29.
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
 
    The Phoenix Mars Lander arrived at 68.2184N, 234.2487E on May 25, 2008.
 
    The PHX METEOROLOGICAL DATA product contains calibrated values of pressure
    and temperature data, as well as corrected values of pressure data.
    Each product is approximately 24 hours (LMST) in duration, and was
    collected continuously over the entire mission at a data rate of 2 sec.
 
    The Data are organized into &apos;High Resolution&apos; (2 sec) and &apos;Low
    Resolution&apos; (512 sec).  There are three temperature sensors
    along the vertical 1.0 m MET Mast (250, 500 and 1000mm), a
    reference Platinum Resistance Thermometer (PRT) at the base, and a
    pressure sensor on the Lander Deck on the Payload Electronic
    Box.  [TAYLOR2008]
 
    The collection of High Resolution Data is determined by the setting
    of P &amp; T threshold values ranging from setting the thresholds to
    zero (constantly triggering, creating continuous 2 sec data) to
    essentially infinity (never triggering, creating no 2 sec data).
    Owing to favorable transmission bandwidth, the unit was operated over
    the entire mission in triggered (2 sec) mode.
 
    During surface operations, it was discovered that a dissipative heater
    was causing interference with the pressure measurements, owing to its
    placement very near to the sensor head.  A corrective algorithm
    was developed, employing housekeeping temperature measurements made
    internal to the pressure sensor head once every 512 sec, and with the
    interpolated corrections applied to the 2 sec resolution data.  A
    further two tables are included which contain these data.
 
    The Data is organized by a unique identifier (Token) is keeping with
    the other Phoenix instruments.  The token for the PT was nominally
    set each sol, when the PT instrument stopped recording to allow
    for transfer of data to the Lander (and hence telemetry to Earth).
    The token is provided as a 4 byte hex value.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
    Each RDR file contains time as the seconds since START_TIME.
 
    The MET PT instruments were nominally operated 24 hours of each Martian
    sol.  Once each sol, the instrument was transitioned out of RECORD
    to allow for transfer of data from MET flash to the Lander.  Thus
    there will nominally be a ~20 min gap each sol.
 
    The MET P&amp;T threshold was commanded each sol, to trigger constantly,
    creating 2 sec data.  The calibration constants used internally onboard
    the unit were determined prior to launch, and outlined in the CCC report.
 
    During surface operations the MET PT was operated continuously, with a
    gap early in the mission (Sol 19/20) owing to a spacecraft event.
    Smaller data gaps exist, from dropouts in telemetry, but these were
    often recovered owing to use of the MET PT internal flash and data
    retransmits.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
 
    The RDR products have had the following changes as compared to the EDRs:
 
    1.  The data has been changed and reordered where required to be
      consistent with the SIS.
 
    2.  The Frame Count is converted to the duration of each
      measurement in Earth seconds.
 
    3.  Temperature Digital Numbers have been converted to degrees
      Kelvin.
 
    The Pressure Corrected data, has been modified as outlined in the
    SIS document.  Very briefly, a thermocap, internal to the pressure
    sensor head, was employed as a proxy of the pressure sensor
    temperature, and used to correct the temperature effects in the
    data.
 
    Finally, the data were converted to PDS format, converting the
    tab-delimited fields to fixed-width fields, and exchanging the
    multiple packet headers for a single session header by the MET GDS.
 
    Address:     Cameron Dickinson
                 Dept. of Earth and Space Science Engineering
                 York University
                 4700 Keele St
                 Toronto, ON M3J 1P3
 
    Phone:       (416) 736-2100 X 23870
    Email:       cameron.dickinson@gmail.com
 
    For science related questions about the data, please contact the
    MET Instrument Science Team Lead:
 
    Address:     James Whiteway
                 Dept. of Earth and Space Science Engineering
                 York University
                 4700 Keele St
                 Toronto, ON M3J 1P3
 
    Phone:       (416) 736-2100 X 22310
    Email:       whiteway@yorku.ca
 
 
  Data
  ====
 
    All of the data in this data set are contained in ASCII tabular files
    with detached PDS labels.  Data is stored in a separate directory
    relating to the sol in which the recording of data commenced (i.e.
    data acquired from 003 10:00 local to 004 10:15 will be in the sol
    3 directory)
 
    Individual filenames are constructed as follows:
 
                             MS000RMH_00896227243_10CCM0.LBL
 
        1: The first character will always be an &apos;M&apos;, representing MET
           data.
        2: The second character will be an &apos;S&apos;, signifying surface
           data (versus &apos;C&apos; for Cruise)
      3-5: The next three characters provide the sol number of the data
           file.
      6-8: The next three characters describe the type of MET data,
           EML - EDR MET LOW (Resolution)
           EMH - EDR MET HIGH (Resolution)
           RML - RDR MET LOW (Resolution)
           RMH - RDR MET HIGH (Resolution)
           RMC - RDR MET Corrected (Pressure Corrected Values)
           RMA - RDR MET Ancillary (Pressure Sensor Temperatures)
        9: Blank
    10-20: SCLK - Spacecraft clock
       21: Blank
    22-25: Operations Token
       26: Producer (M for MET Team)
       27: Version
       28: Period
    29-31: Extension, LBL or TAB
 
    The tabular files are formatted so that they may be read directly into
    many database management systems (DBMS) or spreadsheet programs on
    various computers.  Each of the files contains two tables.  The first
    is the header table, and is only a single record in length.  The
    second table contains all of the data records for a session and varies
    in length.
 
    All fields in the tables are stored in columns of fixed width and are
    right justified.  The records are of fixed length; since the header
    records are shorter than the data records, they have been padded with
    blank spaces at the end of the record.  The last two bytes of each
    record contain the ASCII carriage return and line feed characters.
    This allows the tables to be treated as fixed length record files on
    computers that support this file type and as normal text files on
    other computers.
 
    The PDS labels are object-oriented. The object to which the labels
    refer (the tables) is denoted by a statement of the form:
 
        ^object = location
 
    in which the carat character (&apos;^&apos;, also called a pointer in this
    context) indicates that the object starts at the given location.  For
    an object located outside the label file (as in this case), the
    location denotes the name of the file containing the object, along
    with the starting record.  For example:
 
        ^TABLE = &apos;MS013RML_00126907202_15C6M1.TAB&apos;
 
    indicates that the TABLE object is in the same directory as the
    detached label file. (Records are counted starting at 1, not 0.)
 
    The detached label files are stream format files, with a carriage
    return (ASCII 13) and a line feed character (ASCII 10) at the end of
    each record.  This allows the files to be read by the MacOS, DOS,
    UNIX, and VMS operating systems.
 
 
  Software
  ========
 
    The EDR/RDR tables can be displayed on UNIX, Macintosh,
    and PC platforms as simple ASCII files, or using the PDS developed
    program, NASAView.  This software is freely available from the PDS
    Central Node and may be obtained from their web site at
    http://pds.nasa.gov/.  For more information or help in obtaining
    the software, contact the PDS operator at the following address:
 
    Address:     Planetary Data System, PDS Operator
                 Jet Propulsion Laboratory
                 4800 Oak Grove Drive
                 Pasadena, CA 91109
 
    Phone:       (818) 354-4321
    Email:       pds_operator@jpl.nasa.gov
    WWW URL:     http://pds.nasa.gov/
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Review
  ======
 
    The contents of this data have been peer reviewed by the following
    people:
 
    Lyle Huber        - PDS Atmospheres Node, New Mexico State University
    Jim Murphy        - PDS Atmospheres Node, New Mexico State University
    Cameron Dickinson - MET/Lidar Data Manager, York University
    Jim Whiteway      - MET/LIDAR Instrument Co-Investigator, York University
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

