<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.go-a-nims-3-gaspraspec-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>NIMS RADIANCE POINT SPECTRA OF GASPRA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.galileo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:nims.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.951_gaspra::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.gaspra::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-a-nims-3-gaspraspec-v1.0__browserp_go-a-nims-3-gaspraspec-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Carlson, R.W., P.R. Weissman, W.D. Smythe, J.C. Mahoney, and the NIMS Science
                   and Engineering Teams, Near-Infrared Mapping Spectrometer Experiment on
                   Galileo, Space Science Reviews 60: 457-502, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CARLSONETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Carlson, R.W., P.R. Weissman, W.D. Smythe, L.C. Byrne, A.C. Ocampo, and 5
                   others, Gaspra: Spatially resolved infrared spectra from Galileo, Bulletin of
                   the American Astronomical Society 24, 932, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CARLSONETAL1992B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Wolf, A.A., Jet Propulsion Laboratory Interoffice Memorandum GLL-NAV-92-90,
                   Satellite Tour 92-14A Data Package, May 12, 1992, (replaced by WOLF1992).
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GLLIOM1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GO-A-NIMS-3-GASPRASPEC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>NIMS RADIANCE POINT SPECTRA OF GASPRA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2014-05-16</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1991-10-29T21:38:18Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1991-10-29T22:15:36Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JAMES GRANAHAN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Granahan, J.C., NIMS Radiance Point Spectra of Gaspra V1.0.
            GO-A-NIMS-3-GASPRASPEC-V1.0. NASA Planetary Data System, 2014.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Radiometrically corrected point spectra of asteroid 951 Gaspra as
            acquired by Galileo NIMS on October 29, 1991.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data volume contains radiometrically corrected point spectra
            of asteroid 951 as acquired by the Galileo spacecraft Near
            Infrared Mapping Spectrometer (NIMS) on October 29, 1991. They
            record the spectra collected as the Galileo spacecraft approached
            the target asteroid. These data are products of the calibration
            of the raw data number files gap015tn.qub, gap035tn.qub,
            gap036tn.qub, gap037tn.qub, and gap038tn.qub (DATA SET ID
            =&apos;GO-A-NIMS-3 TUBE-V1.0&apos;) with calibration factors
            acquired during the first Earth/Moon encounter of the Galileo
            mission. These raw data .qub files are archived in the Imaging
            Node of the NASA Planetary Data System (PDS). The calibrated
            spectra consist of radiance measurements for wavelengths between
            0.7 - 5.2 micrometers.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    951 Gaspra radiance Near Infrared Mapping Spectrometer point spectra data
    description
 
    1    -    INTRODUCTION
 
    This data volume contains a radiometrically corrected point spectra of
    asteroid 951 Gaspra as acquired by the Galileo spacecraft Near Infrared
    Mapping Spectrometer (NIMS, Carlson et al., 1992) on October 29, 1991
    (Carlson et al., 1992B). These spectra record the observations of the NIMS
    sensor as the Galileo spacecraft approached the asteroid. These data are
    products of the calibration of the raw data number files gap015tn.qub,
    gap035tn.qub, gap036tn.qub, gap037tn.qub, and gap038tn.qub (DATA SET ID
    =&apos;GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0&apos;) with calibration factors (DATA SET ID =
    &apos;GO-E-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0&apos;) acquired during the first Earth/Moon encounter
    of the Galileo mission.  These raw data .qub files are archived in the
    Imaging Node of the NASA Planetary Data System (PDS). These calibrated
    spectra consist of radiance measurements for wavelengths between 0.7 - 5.2
    micrometers.  The data files are named by combining the name of the raw
    data source file and the data product type.  For instance
    gap015radiance.tab is a combination of the first six characters of the
    source data file gap015tn.qub and the radiance data type.  The .tab suffix
    indicates that the file is a PDS formatted text table file.  The radiance
    data type refers to files that contain radiance spectra.  The iof data
    type refers to
    files that with incidence over flux spectra.
 
    2    -     DATA OVERVIEW TABLE
 
    File                Bands  Object     Observation Target
                                           Start(UT)  Distance(km)
    gap015radiance.tab   329   951 Gaspra  22:01:16   14820.1
    gap015iof.tab        329   951 Gaspra  22:01:16   14820.1
    gap035radiance.tab    17   951 Gaspra  21:38:18   26585.1
    gap035iof.tab         17   951 Gaspra  21:38:18   26585.1
    gap036radiance.tab    17   951 Gaspra  21:51:36   21024.7
    gap036iof.tab         17   951 Gaspra  21:51:36   21024.7
    gap037radiance.tab   100   951 Gaspra  21:54:29   17624.2
    gap037iof.tab        100   951 Gaspra  21:54:29   17624.2
    gap038radiance.tab   100   951 Gaspra  22:07:13   10391.9
    gap038iof.tab        100   951 Gaspra  22:07:13   10391.9
 
    3    -     GALILEO MISSION DESCRIPTION
 
    Galileo was a mission to Jupiter to perform long-term studies of the
    Jovian atmosphere and detailed studies of the Galilean satellites (Wolf,
    1992).  It consisted of a two part spacecraft, an orbiter and an
    atmospheric probe. Both components were launched from the space shuttle
    Atlantis on October 18, 1989. The orbiter contained remote sensing,
    particles, and wave sensors.  The remote sensing instruments included the
    Solid State Imager and the Near Infrared Mapping Spectrometer.  The
    atmospheric probe contained in-situ sensors to directly measure the
    atmosphere of Jupiter. The Galileo spacecraft encountered Venus (February
    10, 1990), the Earth Moon system (December 8, 1990 and December 8, 1992),
    asteroid 951 Gaspra (October 29, 1991), asteroid 243 Ida (August 28, 1993)
    before entering the orbit of Jupiter on December 8, 1995.  This data set
    is from the asteroid 243 Ida encounter. The Galileo mission investigated
    the Jovian system by deploying its atmospheric probe on July 13, 1995 and
    conducting observations until plunged into Jupiter on September 21, 2003.
 
    4    -     INSTRUMENT DESCRIPTION
 
    The Near Infrared Mapping Spectrometer (Carlson et al., 1992) instrument
    was an imaging spectrometer covering the wavelength region 0.7 to 5.2
    micrometers.  Its spectral resolution is 0.025 micron beyond 1 micron, and
    0.0125 microns below 1 micron, yielding 204 spectral elements in nominal
    mode.  The nominal pixel size is a square 0.5 x 0.5 milliradians.  The
    instrument acquires data in the order: (1) sampling of 17 detectors, (2)
    stepping of the scan mirror (20 elements in cross-cone), (3) stepping of
    the grating (nominally 12 steps per cycle).  The nominal 204 wavelength
    cycle requires 4 1/3 seconds.  The detectors (2 silicon, 15 indium
    antimonide) sample approximately uniformly across the spectrum.  The
    stepping of the grating provided NIMS with a variety of spectral data
    collection modes that ranged from 17 channels (no grating step movements)
    to 408 channels (24 grating step movements).
 
    5   -      951 GASPRA ASTEROID ENCOUNTER NIMS OBSERVATIONS
 
    The Galileo spacecraft performed a flyby encounter of asteroid 951 Gaspra
    with its closest approach occurring at 22:37:00 on October 29, 1991 UTC.
    The closest approach was at 951 Gaspra&apos;s dark
    side, 3.9 degrees north ecliptic latitude, at a 1600 kilometer range.
 
    NIMS conducted four types of science observations during the 951 Gaspra
    encounter.  The highest priority observation was two scans of the asteroid
    in fixed map mode (17 spectral channels) at a time near the closest
    approach.  The goal was to collect spatially resolved spectral data of 951
    Gaspra.  The second priority observation time was to collect short map
    mode (102 spectral channels) at broken intervals with low phase angles.
    The goal of these observations was to acquire the best spectral
    observations during the 951 Gaspra encounter.   The third priority
    observation type was to collect full map mode (408 spectral channels)
    during every 90 degrees of asteroid rotation.  This was to provide the
    highest spectral sampling of the asteroid as it rotated.  The lowest
    priority observations for NIMS was to collect short map mode data every 30
    degrees and fixed map mode data at every 15 degrees of asteroid rotation.
    Thirty two observations of all of these types were conducted by the NIMS
    sensor during this encounter.  Radiometric and photometric calibration
    observations were conducted by NIMS after the completion of the science
    observation sequence.
 
    The products in this data volume are a subset of the NIMS observations of
    asteroid 951 Gaspra.  They do not include the closest approach fix map
    mode data.  That data has been calibrated and archived as the
    GO-A-NIMS-4-GASPRACUBE-V1.0 in the PDS Small Bodies Node.  They do include
    five files containing two fixed map, two short map, and a full map mode
    observation that occurred just prior to the closest approach observations.
    Thirty seven files are archived the NIMS observations of 951 Gaspra in the
    PDS Imaging Node.  The data set was reduced to five observations by
    calibrating only the data that had significant target signal and that did
    not include the closest approach data.
 
 
    6   -      DATA FILE FORMAT DESCRIPTION
 
    The data files for the 951 Gaspra radiance Near Infrared Mapping
    Spectrometer point spectra are ASCII (American Standard Code for
    Information Interchange) text files.  Each data file contains columns of
    floating point numeric values separated by spaces.  The radiance files
    consist of columns of wavelength values (micrometers), radiance
    (microwatts*centimeters**-2*steradians** -1*micrometers**-1), and
    instrument radiance precision (microwatts*centimeters**-2*steradians**
    -1*micrometers**-1).  The calibration files consist of columns of
    wavelength values (micrometers), sensitivity
    (micrometers*steradians*centimeters**2*microwatts**-1), and dark values
    (data number). The sol (short for solar) files consist of columns of
    wavelength values (micrometers) and radiance
    (microwatts*centimeters**-2*steradians** -1*micrometers**-1). The iof
    files consist of columns of wavelength values (micrometers), incidence
    over flux ratio values, and instrument incidence over flux ratio precision
    values.
 
    7   -    DATA PROCESSING HISTORY
 
    The radiance data in this data volume are derived from archived NIMS
    spectral images files available from the NASA PDS Imaging Node.  The 951
    Gaspra NIMS observations are archived in the Imaging Node as spectral
    image files of data number or instrument count values (DATA SET ID
    =&apos;GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0&apos;). These data number values were converted into
    radiance using the following equation: radiance value = (data number value
    - dark value)/sensitivity value. The dark value was determined through an
    average of background sky pixels for the observation.  The sensitivity
    value was obtained from recorded values used to process the NIMS
    observations of the Earth and Moon (DATA SET ID =
    &apos;GO-E-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0&apos;) that employed the same instrument collection
    modes and gains as the 951 Gaspra observations. Full map and short map
    mode data were subjected to a running box filter average to compensate for
    spacecraft/scan platform motion (jitter) while the NIMS sensor cycled
    through multiple grating positions. This small (jitter) motion causes
    unresolved observations to have small variations in their optical path
    through the sensor as a multiple grating step spectrum is being collected.
    If the motion is of sufficient scale, it can impart a periodic variation
    in radiance in wavelength space. The box filter sample size was determined
    when a repetition of saw teeth like radiance values were no longer present
    in the spectral data.  The solar radiance spectra were modeled from NIMS
    solar radiance spectra archived in observations of the Earth and Moon DATA
    SET ID = &apos;GO-E-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0&apos;) and the 951 Gaspra, Galileo
    spacecraft, and Sun geometry data stored in the Galileo mission SPICE
    kernels.  The inverse square law was used to scale the values from the
    Earth/Moon observation data set to the appropriate values for the 951
    Gaspra observations.  The incidence over flux spectra were created by
    ratioing the radiance spectra with the modeled solar radiance spectra.
    File specific processing information can be found in the following
    paragraphs of this section.
 
    The file gap015radiance.tab is derived from DN values from line 9 sample
    11 in PDS file GAP015TN.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0) and
    calibrated with values from the PDS file E1WANTA2CI.QUB (DATA SET ID
    GO-E-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0).  Radiance data was subjected to a running box
    average filter of 21 samples.  Channels with no signal are not included in
    this data file.
 
    The file gap015calibration.tab contains the calibration values from the
    PDS file E1WANTA2CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-E-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to
    create gap015radiance.tab.  The calibration coefficients include the
    sensitivity offset calculated by the running box average filter.
 
    The gap015sol.tab contains the modeled radiance solar spectrum that
    illuminated asteroid 951 Gaspra as observed by the Galileo spacecraft Near
    Infrared Mapping Spectrometer at 22:01:16 UT on October 29, 1991.  It was
    modeled using solar radiance data archived in the NASA PDS Imaging Node
    file E1WANTA2CI.QUB from the GO-E-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0 data set.
 
    The gap015iof.tab contains the incidence over flux spectrum of asteroid
    951 Gaspra as observed by the Galileo spacecraft Near Infrared Mapping
    Spectrometer at 22:01:16 UT on October 29, 1991.  It was created by a
    ratio of gap015radiance.tab by gap015sol.tab with a 50% pixel fill factor.
 
    The file gap035radiance.tab is derived from DN values from line 69 sample
    4 in PDS file GAP035TN.QUB(DATA SET ID =GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0) and
    calibrated with values from the PDS file E1WANTA2CI.QUB (DATA SET ID
    GO-E-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0).
 
    The file gap035calibration.tab contains the calibration values from the
    PDS file E1WANTA2CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-E-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to
    create gap035radiance.tab.
 
    The gap035sol.tab contains the modeled radiance solar spectrum that
    illuminated asteroid 951 Gaspra as observed by the Galileo spacecraft Near
    Infrared Mapping Spectrometer at 21:38:18 UT on October 29, 1991.  It was
    modeled using solar radiance data archived in the NASA PDS Imaging Node
    file E1WANTA2CI.QUB from the GO-E-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0 data set.
 
    The gap035iof.tab contains the incidence over flux spectrum of asteroid
    951 Gaspra as observed by the Galileo spacecraft Near Infrared Mapping
    Spectrometer at 21:38:18 UT on October 29, 1991.  It was created by a
    ratio of gap035radiance.tab by gap035sol.tab with a 33% pixel fill factor.
 
    The file gap036radiance.tab is derived from DN values from line 252 sample
    18 in PDS file GAP036TN.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0) and
    calibrated with values from the PDS file E1WANTA2CI.QUB (DATA SET ID
    GO-E-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0).
 
    The file gap036calibration.tab contains the calibration values from the
    PDS file E1WANTA2CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-J-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to
    create gap036radiance.tab.
 
    The gap036sol.tab contains the modeled radiance solar spectrum that
    illuminated asteroid 951 Gaspra as observed by the Galileo spacecraft Near
    Infrared Mapping Spectrometer at 21:51:36 UT on October 29, 1991.  It was
    modeled using solar radiance data archived in the NASA PDS Imaging Node
    file E1WANTA2CI.QUB from the GO-E-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0 data set.
 
    The gap036iof.tab contains the incidence over flux spectrum of asteroid
    951 Gaspra as observed by the Galileo spacecraft Near Infrared Mapping
    Spectrometer at 21:51:26 UT on October 29, 1991.  It was created by a
    ratio of gap036radiance.tab by gap036sol.tab with a 33% pixel fill factor.
 
    The file gap037radiance.tab is derived from DN values from line 34 sample
    18 in PDS file GAP037TN.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0) and
    calibrated with values from the PDS file E1WANTA2CI.QUB (DATA SET ID
    GO-E-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0). Radiance data was subjected to a running box
    average filter of 9 samples.
 
    The file gap037calibration.tab contains the calibration values from the
    PDS file E1WANTA2CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-E-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to
    create gap037radiance.tab.  The calibration coefficients include the
    sensitivity offset calculated by the running box average filter.
 
    The gap037sol.tab contains the modeled radiance solar spectrum that
    illuminated asteroid 951 Gaspra as observed by the Galileo spacecraft Near
    Infrared Mapping Spectrometer at 21:54:29 UT on October 29, 1991.  It was
    modeled using solar radiance data archived in the NASA PDS Imaging Node
    file E1WANTA2CI.QUB from the GO-E-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0 data set.
 
    The gap037iof.tab contains the incidence over flux spectrum of asteroid
    951 Gaspra as observed by the Galileo spacecraft Near Infrared Mapping
    Spectrometer at 21:54:29 UT on October 29, 1991.  It was created by a
    ratio of gap037radiance.tab by gap037sol.tab with a 33% pixel fill factor.
 
    The file gap038radiance.tab is derived from DN values from line 49 sample
    17 in PDS file GAP038TN.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-A-NIMS-3-TUBE-V1.0) and
    calibrated with values from the PDS file E1WANTA2CI.QUB (DATA SET ID
    GO-E-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0).  Radiance data was subjected to a running box
    average filter of 7 samples.
 
    The file gap038calibration.tab contains the calibration values from the
    PDS file E1WANTA2CI.QUB (DATA SET ID GO-E-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0) used to
    create gap038radiance.tab.  The calibration coefficients include the
    sensitivity offset calculated by the running box average filter.
 
    The gap038sol.tab contains the modeled radiance solar spectrum that
    illuminated asteroid 951 Gaspra as observed by the Galileo spacecraft Near
    Infrared Mapping Spectrometer at 22:07:13 UT on October 29, 1991.  It was
    modeled using solar radiance data archived in the NASA PDS Imaging Node
    file E1WANTA2CI.QUB from the GO-E-NIMS-4-MOSAIC-V1.0 data set.
 
    The gap038iof.tab contains the incidence over flux spectrum of asteroid
    951 Gaspra as observed by the Galileo spacecraft Near Infrared Mapping
    Spectrometer at 22:01:13 UT on October 29, 1991.  It was created by a
    ratio of gap038radiance.tab by gap038sol.tab with a 66% pixel fill factor.
 
    8   -    POINT SPECTRA SUPPORT INFORMATION
 
    The point spectra support data information can be found in the table file
    science_index.tab.  This information includes the name of the data file,
    the name of the source file archived in the Imaging Node of the PDS, the
    instrument spacecraft mission name, the instrument name, the spacecraft
    mission phase name, the target of the observation, the instrument
    observation type/mode, the observation identifier, the observation start
    and stop time (Universal Time), the observation start and stop time in
    Julian date, the observation start and stop time as recorded by the
    spacecraft clock, the instrument to target center distance (kilometers),
    the target to Sun distance (kilometers),  the spacecraft to Sun position
    vector in the J2000 reference frame (kilometers), the target to Sun
    position vector in the J2000 reference frame (kilometers),  the target to
    Earth distance (kilometers),  the spacecraft to Earth position vector in
    the J2000 reference frame (kilometers),  the Earth to target position
    vector in the J2000 reference frame (kilometers), the horizontal pixel
    scale (kilometers), the vertical pixel scale (kilometers), the observation
    phase angle (degrees), the Earth to spacecraft state vector in the J2000
    reference frame (position in kilometers, velocity in kilometers/second),
    and the Earth to target state vector in the J2000 reference frame
    (position in kilometers, velocity in kilometers/second). These geometry
    values were calculated using the SPICE Tool kit and the following SPICE
    data files: s970311a.bsp, naif0008.tls, mips010314.tpc, and mk00062a.tsc.
 
    9   -    REFERENCES
 
    Carlson, R. W., P. R. Weissman, W. D. Smythe, J. C. Mahoney,
    NIMS-Science-Team, and NIMS-Engineering-Team (1992), Near-Infrared Mapping
    Spectrometer Experiment on Galileo, Space Science Reviews, 60, 457-502.
 
    Carlson, R. W., P. R. P.R. Weissman, W. D. Smythe, L. C. Byrne, A. C.
    Ocampo, L. A. Soderblom, H. H. Kieffer, F. Fanale, J. Granahan, and T. B.
    McCord (1992B), Gaspra: Spatially resolved infrared spectra from Galileo,
    Bulletin of the American Astronomical Society, 24, 932.
 
    Wolf, A. A. (1992), Jet Propulsion Laboratory Interoffice Memorandum
    GLL-NAV-92-90, Satellite Tour 92-14A Data Package, May 12, 1992.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The radiance data in this data volume are in cgs units
    (microwatts*centimeters**-2*steradians**-1*micrometers**-1).
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

