<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ch1-orb-l-mrffr-1-pdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CH1-ORB MOON MINI-RF 1 PACKETIZED DATA RECORD V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.chandrayaan-1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.ch1-orb::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mrffr.ch1-orb::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ch1-orb-l-mrffr-1-pdr-v1.0__pds.geo.chandrayaan1.webservices::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Nozette, S., P. Spudis, B. Bussey, K. Raney, H. Winters, C.L. Lichtenberg, W.
                   Marinelli, J. Crusan, and M. Gates, The LRO Miniature Radio Frequency (Mini-RF)
                   technology demonstration, Space Sci. Rev., submitted, 2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NOZETTEETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CH1-ORB-L-MRFFR-1-PDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CH1-ORB MOON MINI-RF 1 PACKETIZED DATA RECORD V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2008-01-01</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>MINI-RF POC</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Chandrayaan-1 Forerunner Raw Data Set V1.0,
            CH1-ORB-L-MRFFR-1-PDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2009.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw telemetry packet files and ancillary files from the Mini-RF
            (Mini-SAR) Forerunner lunar mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains archival raw data acquired from the
            Mini-RF (Forerunner) instrument during the Chandrayaan-1 mission.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Raw Packetized Data Records (PDRs) are in the form of raw binary
      telemetry in Consultative Committee for Space Data systems (CCSDS)
      packet format that have been extracted from frames downlinked from
      the instrument.  PDRs have duplications removed and include any
      ancillary information needed to understand what is in a given packet.
      They are retained so that future researchers can reproduce the
      higher-level products if they so desire.  These data will not be
      reformatted or processed further and are delivered to the PDS with
      detached minimal PDS labels.  Because the higher-level products can be
      reprocessed as often as desired, there may be a one-to-many
      relationship a raw data product to a processed data product.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      See individual SIS documents, which are located in the
      DOCUMENT directory, for detailed descriptions of each file
      contained in this data archive.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      A minimal PDS label accompanies each raw data file and gives
      only a high-level description of the content and format.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      The formats of these packets are identical, but their contents differ.
      Each of these packets is composed of five segments:  the CCSDS Primary
      Header which contains packet identification information, the CCSDS
      Secondary Header which contains the packet time stamp, the Science
      Header which contains associated metadata, the Science Data which
      contains the data samples, and a trailer (Other Data) which contains
      transmission information.  Byte values are 8-bits long, Integer values
      are 32-bits long, short (integers) are 16-bits long, and floating
      point values are 32-bit IEEE numbers.  These data only are provided in
      big-endian format.
 
      The science data are time-ordered and consist of Vertical (V) or
      Horizontal (H) polarization channel samples contained within a pulse.
      The packets will contain either H or V channel data, never both in the
      same packet.  The V/H Channel Indicator flag in the Science Header
      indicates if the data are H or V channel.  Data gaps in the derived
      products or breaks in the sequence count field in the primary CCSDS
      packet header would indicate missing packets. Please see documentation
      in the DOCUMENT directory for additional information on the data files
      and their format.
 
      These data are stored in the DATA/SAR/&lt;orbit&gt;/RAW directory on
      archival volumes. File names are described in MRFFR_DP_SIS.PDF.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      Each raw science product is accompanied by a text metadata file
      that contains the parameters that describe the state the instrument
      was in at the time of data collection and location and timing
      information about the data set.  This file is referenced in the
      PDS label associated with the science data product.
 
      This data set includes the complete set of Mini-SAR SPICE data
      files (kernels), which can be accessed using SPICE
      software from the PDS NAIF Node (http://naif.jpl.nasa.gov/naif/).
      The SPICE data contain geometric and other ancillary
      information needed to recover the full value of science
      instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft
      and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments,
      spacecraft orientation, and data needed for relevant time
      conversions. The SPICE files are in the GEOMETRY directory of
      this archive. See GEOMTERY/GEOMINFO.TXT for more information.
 
    Housekeeping Data
    =================
      Instrument housekeeping data is included with this data set.  These
      data are provided in text files in comma separated value (CSV)
      spreadsheet-type format.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      Raw data products are not dependent on definition of a
      coordinate system.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      No software is included with this archival data set.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
 
      These products are delivered on a hard-drive or by ftp and
      not on a specific formatted medium.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this data are collected from orbits around the Moon.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was reviewed by the Mini-RF
      Team prior to submission to the Planetary Data System (PDS).
 
      Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data
      set, key elements of the archive were distributed for
      preliminary review.  These included electronic versions of
      example PDS labels, CATALOG files, and Software Interface
      Specifications.  These materials were distributed to PDS
      personnel, the experiment investigator, and others,
      as appropriate.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      The coverage on each archival volume is associated with the
      orbit number.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

