<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lro-l-lamp-3-rdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LRO MOON LAMP 3 REDUCED DATA RECORD V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:lamp.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-lamp-3-rdr-v1.0__browserp_lro-l-lamp-3-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-lamp-3-rdr-v1.0__dvo_imaging_lro-l-lamp-3-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-lamp-3-rdr-v1.0__pds.geo.lro.orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Gladstone, G.R., S.A. Stern, K.D. Retherford, R.K. Black, D.C. Slater, M.W.
                   Davis, M.H. Versteeg, K.B. Persson, J.Wm. Parker, D.E. Kaufmann, A.F. Egan,
                   T.K. Greathouse, P.D. Feldman, D. Crider, W.R. Pryor, and A.R. Hendrix, LAMP:
                   The Lyman Alpha Mapping Project on NASA&apos;s Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter Mission,
                   Space Sci. Rev., submitted (2008).
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GLADSTONEETAL2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LRO-L-LAMP-3-RDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LRO MOON LAMP 3 REDUCED DATA RECORD V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2010-03-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2009-01-01</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID E. KAUFMANN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Kaufmann, D.E., LRO L LAMP REDUCED DATA RECORD V1.0,
            LRO-L-LAMP-3-RDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2009.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter (LRO) Lyman Alpha Mapping
            Project (LAMP) CODMAC Level 3 Reduced Data Record is a collection
            of the far ultraviolet photon detections obtained by the LAMP
            instrument, corrected, calibrated, and located in space and time.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter (LRO) Lyman Alpha Mapping
            Project (LAMP) CODMAC Level 3 Reduced Data Record is a collection
            of the far ultraviolet photon detections obtained by the LAMP
            instrument, corrected for instrumental effects, radiometrically
            calibrated, and correlated with the auxiliary information needed
            to locate the observations in space and time. These data are
            organized, in a manner very similar to the EDR product files from
            which they are derived, into extensions within files formatted
            according to the Flexible Image Transport System (FITS) standard,
            version 2.1b. The LAMP RDR archive enables reprocessing of the
            corrected and calibrated science data into far ultraviolet map
            products as map processing routines improve. Investigators
            interested in applying advanced mapping methods or needing to
            understand the properties of the corrected and calibrated data
            will find the RDR products useful. Many investigators, however,
            will be interested in using the LAMP CODMAC Level 5 far
            ultraviolet map products directly.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  DATA SET OVERVIEW
  =================
    The Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter (LRO) Lyman Alpha Mapping Project (LAMP)
    CODMAC Level 3 Reduced Data Record is a collection of the far ultraviolet
    photon detections obtained by the LAMP instrument, corrected for
    instrumental effects, radiometrically calibrated, and correlated with the
    auxiliary information needed to locate the observations in space and time.
    These data are organized, in a manner very similar to the EDR product
    files from which they are derived, into extensions within files formatted
    according to the Flexible Image Transport System (FITS) standard, version
    2.1b.  The LAMP RDR archive enables reprocessing of the corrected and
    calibrated science data into far ultraviolet map products as map
    processing routines improve. Investigators interested in applying advanced
    mapping methods or needing to understand the properties of the corrected
    and calibrated data will find the RDR products useful.  Many
    investigators, however, will be interested in using the LAMP CODMAC Level
    5 far ultraviolet map products directly.
 
 
  PARAMETERS
  ==========
    The fundamental derived parameters contained in the LAMP RDR data set are
    the absolute time tag for each of the detected far ultraviolet photons,
    the weight factor applied to each to account for instrumental effects, the
    radiometric and wavelength calibrations and the geometric locations.  From
    these derived parameters in the RDR data set further processing will be
    able to compute monochromatic fluxes (photons/sec/cm^2/Angstrom) at the
    LAMP location.
 
 
  PROCESSING
  ==========
    LAMP RDR data products will be generated at the LAMP Science Operations
    Center (SOC), located at the Southwest Research Institute in Boulder,
    Colorado.  The products will be generated by an automated pipeline
    process. The LAMP instrument will nominally generate one housekeeping
    telemetry file and one science data file per orbit.  Once per day these
    LAMP-generated files will be retrieved from the LRO spacecraft by the LRO
    Mission Operations Center (MOC) and then transferred by the MOC to the
    LAMP SOC. The automated LAMP SOC pipeline will ingest these files and
    invoke software to process them, in pairwise fashion (one housekeeping and
    one science data file at a time), into EDR data product files.  The
    pipeline will then invoke software to read these EDR data product files,
    apply instrumental corrections and calibrations (for detector deadtime,
    dark counts, flatfield, effective area, and wavelength), spatially locate
    the data with the aid of input SPICE kernels, and write the results out
    into the RDR data product files.  The FITS header of the RDR data product
    file will contain information regarding which corrections and calibrations
    were performed, and how.
 
 
  DATA
  ====
    The LAMP RDR data product file will contain the following ten types of
    data:
 
    1) Calibrated Spectral Image (Aperture Door Open) - This is a
    reconstructed histogram generated from the pixel list data in the EDR data
    product but with instrumental calibrations applied.  Only the pixel list
    data acquired when the aperture door was open are included in this
    dataset.  If the aperture door state is unavailable (i.e., there are no
    housekeeping data available), all calibrated pixel list data are included
    in this histogram. If the EDR data product contains only data acquired
    with LAMP operating in histogram mode, this dataset will contain a copy of
    the first histogram image but with instrumental calibrations applied.
    This summary image is used as a &apos;quick-look&apos; check on data quality.
    [Extension 0, primary FITS header and data unit (HDU)]
 
    2) Calibrated Spectral Image (Aperture Door Closed) - This is similar to
    the     first dataset, but the reconstructed histogram here is generated
    from pixel list data acquired when the aperture door was closed.  If
    housekeeping data are unavailable, this dataset will be empty.  If the EDR
    data product contains only data acquired in histogram mode, this dataset
    will contain a copy of the second histogram image with instrumental
    calibrations applied. This summary image is used as a &apos;quick-look&apos; check
    on data quality. [Extension 1]
 
    3) Acquisition List - This dataset contains a list of the generated frame
    acquisitions as determined from the housekeeping data file.  The list
    includes, for each frame, the instrument frame sequence number, start and
    stop times, mode type, aperture door and other instrument state
    information. These data are simply copied as is from the EDR data product.
    The frame acquisition times and instrument state data contained in this
    list are used to cross-reference with the pixel list mode data in
    Extension 3 for purposes of selecting data and checking timing
    consistency.  [Extension 2]
 
    4) Calibrated Pixel List Mode Data - This dataset contains a calibrated
    version of the complete pixel list science dataset from the EDR data
    product, plus propagated estimated errors introduced by the separate
    calibration steps, plus ancillary spatial location and pointing
    information that is needed on a per-photon basis.  If the input EDR data
    product contains only histogram data, then this extension will be empty.
    These are the primary science data for use in making maps and other pixel
    list derived science products.  [Extension 3]
 
    5) Ancillary Data - This dataset contains ancillary spatial location and
    pointing information that varies smoothly and slowly over the LRO orbit.
    Also included in this extension are other slowly varying instrument-
    related quantities such as the detector locations of the STIM pixels, a
    measure of the background dark signal, and data quality flags.  Entries in
    this table are typically separated by one-minute intervals instead of on a
    per-photon basis in order to reduce data volume and computation time.
    [Extension 4]
 
    6) Calibrated Histogram Mode Data - This dataset contains a calibrated
    version     of the complete histogram science dataset from the EDR data
    product, plus propagated estimated errors introduced by the separate
    calibration steps.  If there are N histogram mode spectral images in the
    input EDR data product, this extension will consist of a stacked image
    cube containing 2N total images (i.e., N data + error image pairs).  If N
    is greater than 1, then the Acquisition List (Extension 2) will be used to
    time-order the data + error image pairs within the image cube, from
    earliest to latest.  If the input EDR data product contains only pixel
    list data, which will normally be true, then this extension will be empty.
    [Extension 5]
 
    7) Calibrated Calculated Count Rate - This dataset contains a high-
    resolution sequence of UV photon count rates computed from the calibrated
    pixel list data for each acquisition (nominally the whole orbit).  The
    resolution of this count rate sequence depends on the commanded &apos;hack
    time&apos; interval.  If no consecutive pixel list science data are available,
    e.g., if data are acquired only in histogram mode, then this dataset will
    contain the lower resolution (1-Hz) count rate data that are available
    from the housekeeping data file.  This sequence will be used to assess the
    variation in bulk far-UV signal throughout the orbit, and may be
    especially useful when trending data obtained near the terminator or
    during exceptional events (e.g., solar flares).  [Extension 6]
 
    8) LTS Data - LAMP housekeeping data contain up to 10 values per second of
    gain     and offset corrected measurement values from each of the two LAMP
    Lunar Terminator Sensors (LTS).  This dataset provides the full 10-Hz LTS
    dataset. These data are simply copied as is from the EDR data product.
    These coincident LTS data will be used with the count rate sequence in
    Extension 6 to confirm that LAMP is viewing the appropriate
    day/night/shadow scenes.  (Raw 14-bit LTS data sampled at the 1-Hz HK rate
    is included together with this 10-Hz gain and offset corrected LTS dataset
    in the housekeeping data Extension 8.) [Extension 7]
 
    9) Housekeeping Data - This dataset contains the complete housekeeping
    dataset,     both in raw format and, where applicable, in calibrated
    engineering units. These data are simply copied as is from the EDR data
    product.  HK data are included here to assist with joint instrument and
    data quality trending analyses (foreseen and unforeseen).  [Extension 8]
 
    10) Wavelength Lookup Image - This dataset contains a 1024 x 32 image
    whose     floating-point pixel values are the wavelengths corresponding to
    the pixel locations on the detector.  This wavelength calibration image is
    provided to be used with Extensions 0 and 1 for quick-look checks, but NOT
    for scientific analysis.  Its file-averaged wavelength solution makes it
    generally unsuitable to be used with pixel list data.  [Extension 9]
 
 
  ANCILLARY DATA
  ==============
    Ancillary data used in the generation of the LAMP RDR data set include
    those calibration values required to apply instrumental corrections and
    calibrations to the science data as well as trajectory and pointing
    information for the LRO spacecraft and clock conversion tables required to
    enable the geometric calibration of the science data.  The source of the
    instrumental calibration data are the LAMP engineers and LAMP scientists
    at the Southwest Research Institute in San Antonio, Texas [see
    GLADSTONEETAL2008 for further details], while the source of the spacecraft
    trajectory, pointing, and clock data are SPICE kernels provided to the
    LAMP SOC by the LRO MOC, having been ultimately generated by the MOC
    itself, the Flight Dynamics Facility (FDF) at GSFC, or the Navigation and
    Ancillary Information Facility (NAIF) at JPL.
 
 
  COORDINATE SYSTEM
  =================
    The Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter mission uses a standard coordinate system
    to describe all RDR data, namely lunar planetocentric/body-fixed
    coordinates with east-positive longitude from 0 to 360 degrees.  A mean
    Earth/polar axis (ME) reference system (also called the mean
    Earth/rotation system) is used, with the z-axis being the mean rotational
    pole and with the prime meridian (zero degrees longitude) defined by the
    mean Earth direction.
 
    The ME reference system is used for all LRO archival data.  This LRO
    standard     is documented in &apos;A Standardized Lunar Coordinate System for
    the Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter, LRO Project White Paper, 451-SCI-000958,
    Version 3, January 30, 2008&apos;.  Using coordinates in the ME system is
    consistent with recommendations from the International Astronomical Union
    (IAU)/ International Association of Geodesy (IAG) Working Group on
    Cartographic Coordinates and Rotational Elements.
 
    A Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) planetary and lunar ephemeris and
    corresponding Euler angle set are used to define an ME frame to which the
    LRO data are registered.  The LRO Data Working Group (LDWG) determines
    which ephemeris and Euler angle set should be used.  Alternatively, LRO
    data can be registered to an existing or new reference frame in the ME
    system, via ties to surface points known in the frame (examples include
    Lunar Laser Ranging (LLR) retroreflectors, points in images and Digital
    Elevation Models).
 
    When a JPL planetary and lunar ephemeris is used, the JPL Navigation and
    Ancillary Information Facility (NAIF) provides the necessary lunar
    ephemeris file (SPK) and binary lunar orientation file (PCK) in a
    Principal Axes (PA) reference frame for use with the SPICE Toolkit.  NAIF
    also provides the frames kernel (FK) used for accessing the PA orientation
    in the PCK and for transforming from the PA frame to the ME frame.
 
    Alternatively, the JPL lunar ephemeris information is available in an
    ASCII format not requiring the use of the SPICE Toolkit.  This information
    is available from a JPL website: http://ssd.jpl.nasa.gov.
 
 
  SOFTWARE
  ========
    Because the LAMP RDR data product files adhere to version 2.1b of the FITS
    standard, all FITS readers up to this standard should be able to
    successfully read these files.  There are many such FITS readers freely
    available in the public domain.
 
 
  MEDIA/FORMAT
  ============
    The LAMP RDR data product files are written in FITS format, and the format
    of each file is described in an accompanying detached PDS label.  The RDR
    archive itself will be written on hard drive media and physically
    delivered from the LAMP SOC to the PDS Imaging Node, where it will be made
    generally available via the World Wide Web.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence level information will be provided after more thorough analysis
  of the data.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

