<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-e-v-h-mla-3-4-cdr-rdr-data-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER E/V/H MLA 3/4 CDR/RDR DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mla.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mla-3-4-cdr-rdr-data-v1.0__browserp_mess-e-v-h-mla-3-4-cdr-rdr-data-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mla-3-4-cdr-rdr-data-v1.0__browser_mess-e-v-h-mla-3-4-cdr-rdr-data-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mla-3-4-cdr-rdr-data-v1.0__dvo_mess-e-v-h-mla-3-4-cdr-rdr-data-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Cavanaugh, J.F., J.C. Smith, X. Sun, A.E. Bartels, L. Ramos- Izquierdo, D.J.
                   Krebs, A.M. Novo-Gradac, J.F. McGarry, R. Trunzo, J.L. Britt, J. Karsh, R.B.
                   Katz, A. Lukemire, R. Szymkiewicz, D.L. Berry, J.P. Swinski, G.A. Neumann, M.T.
                   Zuber, and D.E. Smith, The Mercury Laser Altimeter instrument for the MESSENGER
                   mission, Space Science Reviews, 131, 451-479, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CAVANAUGHETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Sun, X., and G.A. Neumann, Calibration of the Mercury Laser Altimeter on the
                   MESSENGER Spacecraft, IEEE Transactions on Geoscience and Remote Sensing, Vol.
                   53, Issue 5, pp. 2860-2874, doi:10.1109/TGRS.2014.2366080, 2015.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SUN-NEUMANN2014</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-E/V/H-MLA-3/4-CDR/RDR-DATA-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESSENGER E/V/H MLA 3/4 CDR/RDR DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-05-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-08-19T17:09:06Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-04-30T11:18:11Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>GREGORY A. NEUMANN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            G. A. Neumann (GSFC), MESSENGER E/V/H MLA 3/4 CDR/RDR DATA V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 2010.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The MESSENGER MLA calibrated and reduced observations consist of
            laser ranges and instrument data collected by the MLA instrument
            during fly-by and orbital operations of Mercury. Also included
            are observations of Earth and Venus for calibration purposes.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== This data set consists of the MESSENGER Mercury
            Laser Altimeter (MLA) Calibrated Data Record (CDR) and Reduced
            Data Record (RDR) products. The MLA is a solid-state pulsed laser
            that measures the distance between the spacecraft and the surface
            of Mercury. The CDR products contain the science and auxiliary
            data products calibrated to physical units. The RDR products
            contain the calibrated, geolocated range data as profile
            measurements of the planetary radius.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
   Data Set Overview
   =================
     The data set consists of Calibrated Data Records (CDR), Reduced Data
     Records (RDR) (profile data), and Radiometric Active Data Records
     (RADR).
 
     The CDRs are calibrated science, status, and hardware diagnostics
     data. The RDRs contain time-of-flight profile data and the RADRs are
     radiometric data. The RDRs and RADRs are produced by merging spacecraft
     geometry and attitude data with range data and a planetary orientation
     model.
 
     The label file that accompanies each product defines the start time and
     end time of the observations, the product creation time and release
     information, and describes the different fields within the table. The
     three MLA CDR products correspond to the three EDR data products
     delivered in the accompanying EDR data set. Each MLA CDR data product
     consists of two files. One contains the data itself, and is arranged in
     a PDS compliant ASCII table file. The other is a PDS label file that
     describes the content of the table file. The MLA RDR and RADR products
     correspond to the Science CDR products. The RADR is a profile data
     product that gives active radiometric measurements of the Mercury
     surface using the laser as a source and is produced with the same
     geometric information used in the RDR, but contains only those pulses
     for which radiometry can be measured. The reflectance at 1064 nm
     measures surface reflectivity in permanently-shadowed regions as well
     as sunlit regions.
 
     During the Mercury-Orbit mission phase, a single data file contains
     the observations obtained in one orbit of the spacecraft around
     Mercury.  Prior to the Mercury-Orbit mission phase, a single data file
     aggregated the observations such that all data within the file are
     taken during the same year, month, day, and hour, an efficient way to
     archive data resulting from instrument commands that would turn the
     instrument on, generate data for upwards of several hours, and then
     turn the instrument off.
 
     In addition to the science data, associated instrument parameters are
     included.
 
   Instrument Overview
   ===================
     The Mercury Laser Altimeter (MLA) uses a solid-state pulsed laser to
     measure the distance between the spacecraft and the surface of
     Mercury.  This allows the science team to take detailed
     measurements of Mercury&apos;s shape and surface structure.  The MLA is a
     bi-static system, meaning that it consists of separate transmitter and
     receiver systems.
 
     See the MLAINST.CAT file for more information and [CAVANAUGHETAL2007]
     and [SUN&amp;NEUMANN2014] for full details.
 
   Calibration Overview
   ====================
     This data set contains calibrated and reduced sensor measurements. The
     raw (EDR) products are provided in a separate accompanying data set.
     The final geolocated altimetry product provides geolocated
     measurements of the Mercury radius in a planetocentric coordinate
     system as described in the MLA CDR/RDR Software Interface
     Specification (MLA CDR/RDR SIS).
 
   Parameters
   ==========
     The principal parameters when observing with the MLA are as follows:
 
     * MLA_GOTO_KEEP_ALIVE: This parameter transitions the instrument to
     low-power mode where only the CPU, the Analog Electronics Module, and
     the laser diode&apos;s thermo-electric cooler are powered.
 
     * MLA_GOTO_STANDBY: This parameter transitions the instrument to a
     state similar to the Keep-Alive mode, except the Range Measurement
     Unit is also powered. Laser firing may also be enabled in Standby mode
     in order to perform calibration and ranging experiments under manual
     control, which would be overridden by the Science mode algorithms.
 
     * MLA_GOTO_SCIENCE: This parameter transitions the instrument to a
     state similar to the Standby mode, except the laser power supply is on
     and the laser fires. The Science task provides variable-rate,
     partially-compressed RMU data at 1 Hz.
 
     The default algorithm automatically sets parameters associated with
     acquisition of laser ranges; these parameters can be manually set. The
     MLA also includes modes for testing the instrument and maintenance
     activities. Analog and status telemetry data may be
     generated at a prescribed time interval in any instrument mode.
 
   Data
   ====
     The three advanced data products are generated from the EDRs and are
     calibrated to physical units. The science RDR is derived from the
     science EDR, and is used to make the GDR products. Each 1-s Science EDR
     is broken into 8-Hz records, one for each laser shot, while Status and
     Hardware Diagnostic records are calibrated one for one.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
   Confidence Level Overview
   =========================
     This CDR/RDR data release covers the whole of MLA data from the initial
     TEST data set through the altimetry science measurements of a solid
     body (Mercury). The laser altimeter range is limited to distances less
     than 1800 km. Neither the Earth nor Venus were suitable targets during
     cruise. Earlier data were primarily used in calibration and monitoring
     of performance. When enabled, the detector continuously triggers on
     optical signals passing through the receiver telescope at a roughly
     exponentially-increasing rate with optical power, at any given
     threshold, making it useful as a &apos;one-pixel camera&apos; with a very narrow
     spectral bandwidth and a 400-microradian field of view. The Range
     Measurement Unit operates at 8 Hz, so that scanning across the
     illuminated surface of a target in a raster pattern provides a
     boresight calibration. In addition, triggers may be received from
     Earth-based lasers within a 14-ms subinterval of each 8-Hz cycle, so
     that the time-of-flight may be measured repeatedly.
 
     The MESSENGER spacecraft employs an ovenized, quartz-crystal-based
     oscillator whose frequency is stable to a few parts per trillion over
     the course of an hour.  The MLA acquires its time base from the
     spacecraft via a one-pulse-per-second (1PPS) tick along with the
     corresponding mission elapsed time (MET) message over the data bus. The
     1PPS signal uncertainty during ground testing was 0.021 ms. The 1 PPS
     offset, and the offset between the MLA event time reference and the
     1PPS, are very stable over short intervals of time. The latter is
     monitored by the instrument at 125-ns resolution. While the spacecraft
     clock can be related to the MLA timing only to tens of microseconds in
     an absolute sense, over intervals of an hour or so they are precisely
     coupled. When laser firing is enabled, the time of fire is recorded and
     may be matched with pulses received at at an earth station. Transmit
     and receive times may be correlated on the ground to measure the
     effective 2-way time-of-flight and clock drift. The resolution of the
     MLA timing measurement is roughly 400 ps, and the demonstrated overall
     precision of an individual time-of- flight measurement between MLA and
     Earth is approximately 0.65 ns (20 cm) root-mean-square, owing to
     signal variations and atmospheric delays. Ranging to planetary surfaces
     entails additional error sources related to terrain effects acting
     on a finite-sized laser footprint, but approaches 20 cm precision
     for triggers on Channel 1 under optimal conditions.
 
     To ensure accurate altimetric measurements, the absolute time
     correlation of the spacecraft clock is maintained to better than 1 ms
     via radio tracking, while the spacecraft position relative to Mercury
     center of mass should be known to better than a few tens of meters
     while in orbit. With repeated altimetry crossing tracks, the orbit was
     be further constrained, limited by the roughness of the surface at the
     shot-to-shot scale. A further source of uncertainty in geolocation is
     the MLA boresight vector, since geolocation multiplies the optical
     range by the direction cosines of this vector with respect to an
     inertial reference system. The spacecraft attitude control and
     knowledge is derived from an inertial measurement unit and star
     trackers, whose performance is monitored by instrument calibrations.
     The MLA scans of Earth and Venus have characterized the boresight
     alignment repeatedly during cruise, and on two occasions, the MLA laser
     beam has been observed on Earth, providing an improved laser boresight
     vector. Further tests during cruise confirmed the current system
     attitude knowledge, which at present is known to be repeatable to
     within 50 microradians from day to day.
 
     The radiometric measurements are produced from the threshold crossing
     times of the received pulses at two discriminator voltages on channel
     one simultaneously, a low threshold for maximum sensitivity, and a
     threshold roughly twice as high, to give four sample points of the
     received pulse waveform. A laser pulse may result in triggers at one or
     both thresholds or not at all. Ranging with low threshold detections is
     possible at ranges up to 1500 km, but steady returns that cross both
     the low and high thresholds are best obtained at altitudes less than
     ~600 km with near-nadir (&lt;20 degree) incidence angles. When a pulse is
     detected by a pair of discriminators, its energy and duration may be
     inferred assuming a model waveform that accounts for the dispersion in
     time of return pulses due to surface slope and/or roughness. We adopt a
     simple triangular model that fits the rising and falling edges of the
     trigger at each threshold. This model generates values nearly equal to
     the ideal Gaussian waveform model for well-constrained pulses. The
     reflectance is derived using a direct measurement of the outgoing pulse
     energy and instrument calibrations from ground test data, via the lidar
     link equation. The measurement of radiance factor (relative to an ideal
     diffusive reflector) has an associated uncertainty of 30% for each
     measurement at low altitude, with an approximately lognormal
     distribution.
 
   Calibration Observations
   =========================
     On May 27 and 31, 2005, two-way detection of laser pulses was achieved
     at a distance of 24 million km between MESSENGER and Earth. In the
     weeks prior to detection, passive scans of Earth were conducted to
     refine the MLA pointing with respect to the spacecraft reference frame.
     The two-way detection was the first successful end-to-end test of the
     MLA hardware in space.
 
     A total of 40 MLA downlink pulses were detected at the NASA Goddard
     Geophysical and Astronomical Observatory (GGAO), and 90 uplink
     observations were obtained during observing sessions on 27 and 31 May
     2005. The uplinks were relayed to Earth in the hardware diagnostic
     packets, along with the laser transmit timing. Ranging analysis
     established that these uplinks corresponded to the times of fire of a
     16-mJ laser operating at 240 Hz at GGAO. Although tens of thousands of
     noise triggers were also received, a dozen or more uplink triggers were
     obtained within a 10-second interval on May 27. No clear uplinks were
     seen on May 31. The uplinks on May 27 showed several cases where the
     MLA coarse clock counter recorded the 200-ns clock edge following the
     trigger. After correcting for the 200-ns offset, these triggers match
     the predicted time of arrival of ground pulses. These offsets are not
     generated when operating in the Science mode.
 
     During the second Venus flyby, 5 June 2007, the hardware and flight
     software were exercised to produce the first targeted science
     observations of the cloudy atmosphere of Venus. The performance of the
     instrument and flight software were nominal, but no returns from the
     surface were seen, owing to the strong absorption of 1064-nm light by
     the CO2 atmosphere. Although many detector triggers occurred while the
     laser beam was directed at Venus, a clearly-resolved layering of clouds
     was not seen in the data. While laser altimeters can be designed for
     atmospheric studies, the Venus clouds were probably too diffuse for the
     relatively short MLA laser pulses and detector subsystem time
     constants.
 
     During the week of June 17-24, several attempts were made to repeat the
     two-way ranging experiment at a distance greater than 100 million
     kilometers. All instrument data were acquired as planned and there were
     no anomalies. Passive detection of earthshine verified the pointing of
     the MLA instrument, but active detection of a 48-Hz, 250-mJ pulsed
     laser at GGAO was not achieved. Detection of the MLA laser on the
     ground using a photon-counting detector could not be confirmed.
     Alignment problems related to the relatively large velocity aberrations
     for interplanetary trajectories together with problems in the ground
     telescope control systems and poor visibility during part of the week
     hampered this effort.
 
   Mercury Flyby 1 Observations
   ============================
     The MLA was turned on two days in advance of the flyby so as to warm up
     to operating temperature and configure instrument parameters. Using a
     stored command to enter Standby Mode, the instrument range measurement
     unit was powered on 45 minutes prior to the flyby closest approach
     (CA). At 2 minutes and 40 seconds prior to CA, MLA entered Science Mode
     and the laser commenced firing 43 seconds later as diode current
     reached operational level. Science data were collected until 9 minutes
     after CA. Altimetric measurements commenced at a range of 600 km and a
     laser incidence/emission angle of 71 degrees. Pointing of the
     spacecraft to nadir was achieved well after CA, by which time ranges
     were increasing above 1000 km. MLA demonstrated ability to range with
     more than 50% probability of detection when operating at nadir below
     1200 km, and usable ranges were acquired at more than 1600 km. The
     precision of measurement is greatest at nadir, where the least
     spreading of the laser footprint and reflected pulse occurs. A pair of
     threshold measurements are made independently for such pulses, which
     allows the estimation of pulse energy. Such paired returns were
     obtained out to 1400 km, after which the 1/R^2 decline in signal
     strength prevented triggers at the higher threshold. A total of 5537
     valid altimetric ranges were obtained during the flyby.
 
     Nine days following the flyby, passive scan observations of the
     half-moon illuminated shape of Mercury were performed, as well as a
     dark noise-vs-threshold test. The instrument was then commanded off.
     These observations served to improve the calibration of the detector&apos;s
     response to Mercury surface conditions and verified the
     spacecraft-instrument alignment.
 
   Mercury Flyby 2 Observations
   ============================
     Several months prior to the flyby, a sequence was tested that commanded
     the MLA to use the MP-B clock signal for its range measurement
     hardware. This successful test corrected the previous use of the coarse
     oscillator signal during flyby 1 and ensured accurate ranging and
     timing. Otherwise, Flyby M2 operations were identical to those of Flyby
     M1. The MLA ranged to the surface successfully for nearly 12 minutes,
     during which period 4388 successful ranges were taken, more than half
     of which triggered on more than one channel. Instrument health and
     sensitivity has been unchanged since launch. Passive scan observations
     of the half-moon illuminated shape of Mercury were performed after
     Flyby 2, with nearly identical results.
 
   Mercury Flyby 3 Observations
   ============================
     Mercury Flyby 3 was aborted 21 seconds prior to MLA entering Science
     Mode. While the spacecraft was quickly recovered and the primary goal
     of the flyby was achieved, placing MESSENGER in position for its final
     encounter, the laser did not fire, and no science data were obtained.
     Prior to that time, and during the passive scan that followed a few
     days later, the operation of the instrument was nominal, and the
     alignment of the detector field of view remains close to that of the
     earlier flybys.
 
   Mercury Orbital Observations
   ============================
     MLA enters Science Mode on each orbit prior to periapse. Configuration
     via stored sequences places the instrument in Standby for 10 minutes,
     switches the Range Measurement Unit (RMU) to Oscillator B to select the
     active precision time source, and transitions to Science Mode 1 when
     the predicted slant range and emission angle fall below a predetermined
     set of values, initially 1800 km at nadir. Within 45 seconds the laser
     commences firing at 8 Hz. The instrument is placed in Keepalive mode
     when predictions exceed the predetermined values, allowing for some
     period of operation in case of orbital error.  Almost all triggers of
     the RMU are noise at that altitude. As the orbital geometry changes from
     noon-midnight to dawn-dusk attitude remains near nadir and in-range for
     up to 2500 s without violating the Sun Keep-In (SKI) constraint. Shorter
     observations occur when the spacecraft is commanded off-nadir for thermal
     protection, observations, or to maintain SKI within + or - 10 degrees.
     Any period of time when predicted range exceeds 1920 km for more than
     255 seconds causes demotion to Science mode 0, a less sensitive
     acquisition configuration.
 
     Science mode ranges are expressed in nominal counts of a 5 MHz clock,
     or 200 ns coarse ranges, interpolated to ~400 ps by fine counts. A
     single clock may be faster or slower by a few tens of parts per billion,
     an amount smaller than the least significant fine count of the RMU.
 
     Laser pulses are recorded at leading and trailing edge threshold
     crossings relative to each minor frame start by the RMU. An estimate of
     the fire time is given by the mean of the two crossings. Multiple
     triggers may be sensed by three matched filter channel discriminators,
     with a dead time of a few microseconds between triggers. The RMU sets a
     channel id bit (1, 2, 4) when the range is latched. Some triggers
     set multiple bits owing to the dead time. Such events are assigned
     to the matched filter with the shortest system delay, 10, 60, or 540 ns,
     respectively. If triggered, a single high-threshold crossing is recorded
     (id bit 0) which is often paired with a lower-threshold event. When the
     paired event has id 1, it is usually within 1 ns of the high event and
     provides an estimate of the total return pulse width and energy. Such
     pairs may be considered accurate to 0.2 m if coming from the ground.
     If the channel id cannot be determined (leading and trailing edges are
     inconsistent), the id #3 is assigned and the range is less certain.
     Ranges with ids 1, 2 and 4 are determined with accuracy about 1/3 of
     the corresponding matched filter width or 0.5, 3, and 25 m respectively.
     Calibrations for system delay, spacecraft position, and offset to the
     spacecraft center of mass are applied to accurately determine the
     planetary shape. At the extremes of the orbital range, the size of the
     laser footprint expands and the topographic accuracy is degraded.
 
     For altimetric performance to fully meet expectations for the mission
     science objectives, it is necessary to indicate the quality of any
     given trigger as a likely ground return or a noise trigger. This
     &apos;quality&apos; can only be provided after geolocation and inspection, so the
     description of quality flag below pertains only to RDR data, but is
     provided here for reference. Quality of range data is indicated by a
     Boolean value that is contained within the Reduced Data Record product
     CHANID column. This column is described as COLUMN_NUMBER = 7.
 
     BYTES          = 2
     DATA_TYPE      = ASCII_INTEGER
     FORMAT         = &apos;I2&apos;
     START_BYTE     = 64
     DESCRIPTION    = &apos;Receiver channel of ground or noise trigger -
                       =0 channel 1 high threshold.
                       =1 channel 1 low
                       =2 channel 2 low
                       =3 ambiguous, assigned to channel 1 low
                       =4 channel 3 low.
                       =5 channel 1 high noise trigger
                       =6 channel 1 low noise trigger
                       =7 channel 2 low noise trigger
                       =8 unassigned noise trigger
                       =9 channel 3 low noise trigger.&apos;
 
     A Boolean value consists of CHANID/5, where 1=noise and 0=ground. The
     uncertainty of each ground return in meters is roughly
     SIGMA_RANGE = 2^CHANID taking into account the reduced precision of the
     higher channels.
 
     The value below is contained in the Science CDR and RDR tables to
     denote observations whose ranges are imprecise:
 
      NAME             = STARTPLS_WIDTH
      MISSING_CONSTANT = 99.9
      DESCRIPTION      = &apos;Width of transmit laser pulse in nanoseconds, used
        to determine centroid time of outgoing pulse. A value of 99.9
        denotes a measurement whose pulse width is invalid.&apos;
 
   Review
   ======
     This archival data set has been approved by the Instrument Scientist.
     The final data set, including calibrated and reduced data records, will
     be examined by a peer review panel prior to its acceptance by the
     Planetary Data System (PDS). The peer review will be conducted in
     accordance with PDS procedures.
 
   Data Coverage and Quality
   =========================
     Data reported are the full-rate processed data received from the
     spacecraft during the mission phases: Launch, Earth Cruise,
     Venus 1 Cruise, Venus 2 Flyby, Mercury 1 Cruise, Mercury 1 Flyby,
     Mercury 2 Cruise, Mercury 2 Flyby, Mercury 3 Cruise, Mercury 3 Flyby,
     Mercury 4 Cruise, Mercury Orbit, Mercury Orbit Year 2, Mercury Orbit
     Year 3, Mercury Orbit Year 4, and Mercury Orbit Year 5. The mission
     phases are defined as:
 
     Phase Name Date       Start Date (DOY)   End Date (DOY)
     --------------------  -----------------  -----------------
     Launch                03 Aug 2004 (216)  12 Sep 2004 (256)
     Earth Cruise          13 Sep 2004 (257)  18 Jul 2005 (199)
     Earth Flyby           19 Jul 2005 (200)  16 Aug 2005 (228)
     Venus 1 Cruise        17 Aug 2005 (229)  09 Oct 2006 (282)
     Venus 1 Flyby         10 Oct 2006 (283)  07 Nov 2006 (311)
     Venus 2 Cruise        08 Nov 2006 (312)  22 May 2007 (142)
     Venus 2 Flyby         23 May 2007 (143)  20 Jun 2007 (171)
     Mercury 1 Cruise      21 Jun 2007 (172)  30 Dec 2007 (364)
     Mercury 1 Flyby       31 Dec 2007 (365)  28 Jan 2008 (028)
     Mercury 2 Cruise      29 Jan 2008 (029)  21 Sep 2008 (265)
     Mercury 2 Flyby       22 Sep 2008 (266)  20 Oct 2008 (294)
     Mercury 3 Cruise      21 Oct 2008 (295)  15 Sep 2009 (258)
     Mercury 3 Flyby       16 Sep 2009 (259)  14 Oct 2009 (287)
     Mercury 4 Cruise      15 Oct 2009 (288)  03 Mar 2011 (062)
     Mercury Orbit         04 Mar 2011 (063)  17 Mar 2012 (077)
     Mercury Orbit Year 2  18 Mar 2012 (078)  17 Mar 2013 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 3  18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 4  18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 5  18 Mar 2015 (077)  30 APR 2015 (120)
 
 
     Operational periods of the MLA dictated by orbital geometry were:
 
     Start time  (DOY)  End time (DOY)     Purpose
     -----------------  -----------------  ----------------------
     2004-232T17:09:06  2004-233T20:09:43  Checkout
     2005-129T15:10:53  2005-154T23:32:00  Earth ranging
     2006-249T13:40:54  2006-250T12:26:30  Venus scan
     2007-073T00:20:55  2007-073T23:15:02  FSW upload
     2007-146T00:00:53  2007-158T06:51:11  Venus flyby
     2007-168T06:05:47  2007-176T02:16:46  Earth ranging
     2008-012T12:00:54  2008-023T12:40:11  Mercury Flyby 1
     2008-168T19:26:08  2008-189T18:39:50  Cruise test
     2008-269T23:01:54  2008-290T11:42:57  Mercury Flyby 2
     2009-259T23:01:00  2009-283T22:50:00  Mercury Flyby 3
     Mercury Orbit:
     2011-088T02:04:05  2011-144T10:37:39  Mercury Orbit cycle 1
     2011-158T00:05:12  2011-231T21:16:56  Mercury Orbit cycle 2
     2011-246T20:47:32  2011-319T10:22:37  Mercury Orbit cycle 3
     2011-335T21:48:47  2012-042T16:46:29  Mercury Orbit cycle 4
     2012-058T21:19:24  2012-107T07:38:15  Mercury Orbit cycle 5
     2012-114T22:46:30  2012-132T15:20:25  Mercury Orbit cycle 6
     2012-146T06:58:01  2012-225T23:38:29  Mercury Orbit cycle 7
     2012-233T15:15:23  2012-313T23:56:04  Mercury Orbit cycle 8
     2012-321T15:34:12  2012-334T23:44:55  Mercury Orbit cycle 9
     2012-342T15:43:05  2013-057T00:18:54  Mercury Orbit cycle 10
     2013-064T16:05:05  2013-144T00:30:38  Mercury Orbit cycle 11
     2013-152T16:29:53  2013-219T17:08:14  Mercury Orbit cycle 12
     2013-243T00:57:35  2013-317T17:30:33  Mercury Orbit cycle 13
     2013-330T17:34:15  2014-040T18:00:22  Mercury Orbit cycle 14
     2014-058T01:58:46  2014-128T10:37:06  Mercury Orbit cycle 15
     2014-146T02:37:45  - continuous operation through year 5 in the
     low-altitude campaign except for OCM-10 on September 12, 2014.
 
     During the lowest altitude phases, when the altimeter range was as low
     as 25 km distance at periapse, ranges from altitudes lower than the
     design range of 200 km were obtained successfully but with some unusual
     responses. A ghost of topography appeared in some of the profiles below
     50 km, at varying altitudes. It is believed that the laser emits weak
     pulses 1-3 microseconds prior to the main pulse, that produce surface
     returns at close range but are not strong enough to trigger the start
     pulse detector electronics. Some indication that this occurs was seen
     during ground testing but it was not documented at that time and it
     is still unclear whether this is the cause of ghosts. In any case the
     main altimetric pulse provides ranges at the expected altitude.
 
     At very low altitudes, signal strength causes pulse widths measured at
     the three applicable electronic thresholds to exceed values for which
     a symmetric pulse waveform may be assumed. To avoid excessive range
     walk, i.e. biases due to variations in signal strength, the ranges are
     calculated assuming that the leading-edge receive time is reliable and
     that the pulse centroid occurs 15 ns following the leading edge trigger.
     Equivalently, the pulse width is limited to 30 ns when calculating the
     centroid (midpoint of leading and trailing edges), while the measured
     width on channel 1 is 90 ns or greater.
 
     Unlike passive remote-sensing instruments, an altimeter is limited to
     observations within range of a visible reflective surface.
     Opportunities for such observations did not occur until the first
     Mercury flyby on 14 January 2008 at a velocity of approximately 7 km/s,
     at which time the first-ever observations of the equatorial region of
     Mercury were obtained along a single, sparsely-sampled profile. Noise
     returns may outnumber ground signal at the limits of instrument range,
     especially at high emission angles. Since the data are essentially
     single independent observations, dropouts or corruption of individual
     packets will not have a significant scientific impact. No such gaps
     have been detected.
 
     On 2012-04-16 (day 107) a transition to an 8-hour orbit was
     accomplished, following which MLA was scheduled to range to Mercury
     three times per day when constraints permit. Ranging was performed from
     23 May up to 11 May 2012 when it was paused for power reasons during
     eclipse, and resumed 25 May 2012. A fault protection rule was
     implemented that prevents ranging when the instrument housing
     temperature exceeds 30C, to extend the longevity of the instrument, and
     power cycling was implemented during the hottest portion of the orbital
     cycle to further mitigate the higher average temperatures experienced
     during the 8-hour orbit. Altimetric analysis tools are being used to
     refine the pre-launch and in-flight calibrations. All of the instrument
     data obtained to date are of satisfactory quality. MLA instrument
     performance fully meets expectations for the mission science
     objectives. Quality issues during the orbital phase are addressed in the
     final release of Reduced Data Products.
 
     The EDR files listed below were corrupted for several minutes due to a
     lack of detection and timing of the laser start pulse, the origin for
     MLA time-of-flight measurements.  As a result, the start pulse time
     defaulted to the diode pump switchout time.  This was later than that
     of the pulses themselves, which were too weak to trigger the start
     pulse detector.
 
     MLASCI1206030658.DAT
     MLASCI1206051512.DAT
     MLASCI1206061513.DAT
     MLASCI1206062302.DAT
     MLASCI1206070702.DAT
     MLASCI1206080703.DAT
     MLASCI1206111505.DAT
     MLASCI1206112306.DAT
     MLASCI1207130719.DAT
     MLASCI1207160711.DAT
     MLASCI1207231506.DAT
     MLASCI1207252307.DAT
     MLASCI1208231543.DAT
     MLASCI1208222342.DAT
     MLASCI1208242348.DAT
     The affected data have been edited as noise triggers in the RDR CHANID
     column.
 
     In the file below the laser amplifier never reached operating
     temperature owing to a late instrument turnon.
     MLASCICDR1207160711.TAB
 
     Other CDRs with no associated RDRs include:
 
     MLASCICDR1206061513.TAB  MLASCICDR1207130719.TAB  MLASCICDR1208242348.TAB
 
     There are fewer RADR files than there are RDR files as in some passes,
     no suitable pairs of channel 1 low/high threshold return pairs were
     obtained. As well, RADR records whose height values differ by more than
     1 km from polar and cylindrical digital elevation models are removed
     as noise. For these reasons, the following RADR files that might
     otherwise be expected are not included in the data delivery or contain
     very few valid entries:
 
     MLARADR1206030658.TAB  MLARADR1206051512.TAB  MLARADR1206070702.TAB
     MLARADR1206080703.TAB  MLARADR1206100704.TAB  MLARADR1206112306.TAB
     MLARADR1208241546.TAB
 
     This &apos;filtering&apos; for noise has been performed on all RADRs from the start
     of the mission and all previously published RADRs are replaced in this
     delivery.
 
     In mid-July 2012, it was noticed that the data were corrupted
     for several minutes due to a lack of detection and timing of the laser
     start pulse, the time origin for MLA time-of-flight measurements.
     As a result, the start pulse time defaulted to the previous time
     detected.  A command macro to lower the start pulse detection
     threshold from 15 to 14 counts was requested on July 30, 2012,
     as provided for in the instrument design and concept of operations.
 
     On August 3, 2012, a command at the end of DPU power-on macro 22 was
     uploaded to load the new threshold value into a FSW table. On
     initialization the science algorithm loads this value into a DAC. This
     table value does not persist between power cycles so it must be added
     to the macro for MLA power-on.
 
     As noted in the Operational period list of the Data Coverage and
     Quality section, the instrument has had periods during which data have
     not been acquired.  Non-operational periods are due to factors
     including off-nadir passes to accommodate data collection by other
     onboard instruments, as well as instances in which the instrument is
     powered off by command due to environmental concerns.  The
     non-operational periods are as follows:
 
     Start time         End time
     -----------------  -----------------
     2004-233T20:09:43  2005-129T15:10:53
     2005-154T23:32:00  2006-249T13:40:54
     2006-250T12:26:30  2007-073T00:20:55
     2007-073T23:15:02  2007-146T00:00:53
     2007-158T06:51:11  2007-168T06:05:47
     2007-176T02:16:46  2008-012T12:00:54
     2008-023T12:40:11  2008-168T19:26:08
     2008-189T18:39:50  2008-269T23:01:54
     2008-290T11:42:57  2009-259T23:01:00
     2009-283T22:50:00  2011-088T02:05:11
     2011-144T10:40:00  2011-158T00:05:56
     2011-231T21:16:56  2011-246T20:48:47
     2011-319T10:22:37  2011-335T21:49:10
     2012-043T16:46:29  2012-058T21:20:10
     2012-107T07:38:15  2012-114T22:46:30
     2012-132T15:20:24  2012-146T06:58:01
     2012-225T23:38:28  2012-233T15:15:23
     2012-273T16:01:36  2012-275T05:47:06
     2012-281T23:29:26  2012-283T15:13:38
     2012-289T16:00:13  2012-291T00:29:26
     2012-313T23:56:04  2012-321T15:34:12
     2012-334T00:02:57  2012-342T15:34:04
     2012-347T16:11:43  2012-349T07:14:04
     2012-361T16:13:18  2012-363T04:44:15
     2013-056T00:29:58  2013-064T15:47:49
     2013-069T16:33:43  2013-071T07:35:10
     2013-144T00:30:38  2013-152T16:29:53
     2013-229T17:08:14  2013-243T00:57:52
     2013-317T17:30:33  2013-330T17:34:15
     2014-040T18:00:22  2014-058T01:58:46
     2014-128T10:37:06  2014-146T02:37:45
     2014-255T04:09:16  2014-257T04:02:40 for OCM-10.
 
     Starting with Mercury Orbit cycle 5, laser performance began to show
     significant degradation due to the rapidly changing thermal environment
     as the spacecraft periapse longitude approaches the Mercury hot pole.
     During this season, the Radio Transmitter system requires protection as
     well, resulting in several days when operation ceases entirely. At
     the peak of the hot pole season, when operating outside of its optimal
     thermal range, the laser sometimes fails to produce a pulse within 255
     microseconds of optical pumping, at which point an internal protection
     timer switches off the pump diode current, the switchout limit.
 
     The lack of laser fires causes gaps in the RDR time series. Such gaps
     extend from one pulse to several minutes in duration. Thermal
     management of the instrument environment has mitigated this problem
     somewhat, but gaps recur at each hot pole season, typically for a few
     days at the beginning and end of each cycle.
 
     On September 11, 2013, at the request of the MLA team, the detection
     threshold was again lowered by one count to 13 counts via the DPU
     power-on macro because of further decline in laser output and missing
     start pulses. A final reduction to 7 occurred on September 19, 2014.
 
     The switchout limit is intermittently exceeded during science passes,
     when the laser amplifier temperature is below 10 deg. C, and toward the
     end of some passes over the day side due to excessive heating. The
     output is becoming less predictable as time progresses, and thermal
     excursions are more common in the 8-hour orbit of the extended mission,
     in which case the laser ceases to fire and the TX_ENERGY data value is
     zero.
 
     In the current state of operation, the laser may also fire each shot
     but the start pulse time may not be recorded correctly owing to a lack
     of start pulse trigger. Ranges may still be returned from the surface.
 
     The symptom of this anomaly is that the TX_ENERGY is within normal
     limits, but the STARTPLS_TIME and STARTPLS_WIDTH, normally varying from
     shot to shot, are not updated. The RMU does not clear these values before
     each shot, so the previous values of both time and width are repeated.
     The lack of a start trigger is detected by the RMU and passed
     to the FSW, but owing to a software error it is not being recorded and
     downlinked correctly. The cause for this is under investigation.
 
     Excerpts from an email December 23, 2013: &apos;I did find where we used to
     set the bit in the science packet to indicate a problem. I don&apos;t know why
     it was taken out.&apos; Response: &apos;... what you found was conclusive that the
     flag for the start pulse detection was not passed on to the telemetry.
     We did not have to use it since the laser never missed a beat during
     ground testing and we always intended to keep it that way. However, the
     problem has become more serious after MLA passed its designed lifetime.&apos;
 
     One hypothesis is that the laser undergoes Amplified Spontaneous
     Emission (ASE) if the switchout limit is exceeded. In this case the
     energy is recorded but the peak energy is too low to be detected by the
     timing hardware.
 
     The STARTPLS_INVALID telemetry point, defined as
       &apos;=0 all start pulses for the second were valid.
        =1 at least one start pulse during the second was invalid.&apos;
     does not respond to the case when neither the leading nor the trailing
     edge of the laser pulse is detected. With this in mind, the MLASCICDR
     flags repeated values by setting the STARTPLS_WIDTH value to 99.9. In
     this case the time of flight data, derived from a difference between
     the start pulse time and a return pulse time, may be invalid.
 
     As a workaround, the MLASCICDR ground data processing has been modified
     to flag repeated timing values by setting the STARTPLS_WIDTH to 99.9 ns
     and to assume that the laser fire occurred within 30 ns of the previous
     recorded time. The time of flight data, derived from the difference of
     the start pulse and return pulse times, may be useful in spite of the
     uncertain origin and drifts only slightly from the true value, but the
     accuracy is typically no better than about 200 ns or 30 m in range.
     The following field is recorded in the calibrated data product:
 
      NAME             = STARTPLS_WIDTH
      MISSING_CONSTANT = 99.9
      DESCRIPTION      = &apos;Width of transmit laser pulse in nanoseconds, used
        to determine centroid time of outgoing pulse. A value of 99.9
        denotes a measurement whose pulse width is invalid and for which
        the precision of any associated ground return is degraded.&apos;
 
     The field is also added to the Reduced Data Record, to indicate shots
     for which the range calculation is uncertain.
 
     In the first year of operation, repeated start times occurred a few
     times per orbit and did not affect data quality. In July 2012, repeats
     became more frequent, indicating the need to lower the start detection
     threshold as described above. By the third year of operation in orbit
     (March 2013) the laser output energy had further declined, resulting
     in bursts of several seconds where the start pulse time was repeated,
     but with sufficient energy to produce ground returns. Further
     reductions in transmit threshold on September 11, 2013 and September 19,
     2014 did not completely eliminate start pulse repeats. Returns are
     obtained from the planet but such ranges should be interpreted with
     caution as the start time and therefore range is uncertain. In the
     current release all CDRs have been regenerated to modify STARTPLS_WIDTH.
     The validity of such ranges as ground returns is determined in the RDR
     on an individual basis.
 
   Limitations
   ===========
     The first Mercury flyby used the spacecraft coarse oscillator, whose
     accuracy is estimated to be within a few parts per million of nominal
     rate. Range measurement accuracy is therefore uncertain by 2-10 meters,
     depending on range. Subsequent observations use the more precise USO
     time reference, accurate to 10 parts per billion or better. OCX-B is
     now selected by instrument command. A limitation of this data set is
     that it is preliminarily calibrated data. The data are received from
     the spacecraft telemetry and ingested into a database, whence the
     instrument data products are extracted and reformatted in a reversible
     fashion. Calibration of the range and housekeeping data are performed
     in a subsequent processing step to produce the Calibrated Data Record
     (CDR) data products in scientific units. A final step applies the
     spacecraft and planetary position and geometry data to the calibrated
     ranges, to produce geodetic profiles and ancillary data. The Reduced
     Data Record (RDR) data product entails classification, or editing, of
     the Science data to distinguish noise from ground returns. The accuracy
     of the data relies on the quality of the Precision Orbit Determination
     procedures employed, as well as internal crossover analysis and
     correlation with other datasets, and is expected to improve as the
     data are reprocessed with more accurate geometry.
 
     Further refinement and resampling of the RDR product produces the
     Gridded Data Record (GDR) data products. Note that during the low-
     altitude periapse periods, the detector gain settings were adjusted
     dynamically to mitigate saturation effects. One of these effects was the
     appearance of cloud-like returns above the surface, mimicking the
     topography. These artifacts are the result of pre-lasing prior to the
     timed laser fire of the main pulse, resulting in an apparent higher-than-
     normal topographic surface, and are manually excluded in the RDR
     processing pipeline.
 
   RADR DATA PROCESSING AND CONFIDENCE NOTE
   ========================================
     The RADR tables are a derived data product that use differences
     of digital range measurements, where possible, to infer reflectance.
     They must be treated with caution, as the measurements are sensitive
     to errors that arise under non-ideal signal conditions, offnadir
     ranging, and other noise sources.
     The CDR2SCI_PAIR program locates pairs of low and high threshold
     returns with matching times within the Science CDR. If there is a
     high threshold trigger, a corresponding trigger on the low threshold
     channel 1 discriminator should also be recorded. Valid pairs of
     of measurements of the electronic return pulse width may be
     modeled to infer the received pulse area in volt-seconds, and pulse
     energy is obtained from the receiver model. In the low altitude orbits
     during the Extended Mission, a high threshold trigger was often paired
     with a trigger on channel 2, whose leading edge occured earlier than
     that of channel 1 owing to the greater sensitivity of channel 2 to the
     extended pulse waveform at low threshold. The low threshold lockout
     circuitry would then mask the low threshold channel 1 trigger. In such
     cases, the waveform area could not be reliably inferred, and the
     CDR2SCI_PAIR program did not output a match.
 
     Each pair of returns is geolocated by the SCI2RDR program. Those pairs
     for which the altitude lies outside a +/- 1 km tolerance with respect
     to a ~1 km or finer digital elevation model are rejected. Each pair
     of RDR records is then radiometrically calibrated by the BECHO program.
     BECHO uses the time difference, or pulse width, of each threshold&apos;s
     leading and trailing edge triggers to infer an
     electronic pulse area in volt-amperes that can be scaled by detector
     responsivity to yield received pulse energy and thereby reflectivity
     via the laser link equation. An ideal return waveform would have a
     symmetrical Gaussian shape, whose amplitude and standard deviation
     can be solved for knowing the width at two thresholds. In practice,
     the amplitude is very sensitive to small amounts of noise as well as
     waveform distortion and crosstalk. A more robust approach
     assumes a triangular waveform with linearly rising and falling
     shape that is fit with a slope and intercept, for which the
     asymmetry does not matter, only the width of the pulse at each of
     the two thresholds. The result is nearly the same for a
     symmetrical Gaussian shape sampled appropriately. In the few cases
     where the pulse width difference is negative, no solution exists.
     In any case the pulse area is a strongly nonlinear function of
     the two pulse widths. Its statistical distribution is long-tailed,
     better characterized by a lognormal distribution. Under ideal
     conditions in the laboratory a standard deviation equivalent to a
     ratio of 80% to 125% of the true value, and under typical flight
     conditions the standard deviation may be 2-3 times higher,
     so robust averaging techniques are required.
 
   Erratum
   =======
     In the MLA Calibration document SUN&amp;NEUMANN2014, the last
     coefficient in Equation 14 is in error. The correct equation should read
     Etx(T)= 38.873 - 5.3897*T + 0.49348*T^2 + 0.017589*T^3 + 0.00020891*T^4
     This error does not affect any of the calibrations applied to the MLA
     datasets.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

