<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.gp-j-epi-3-entry-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GALILEO PROBE EPI RAW DATA SET</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.galileo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.gp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:epi.gp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.gp-j-epi-3-entry-v1.0__browserp_gp-j-epi-3-entry-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Fischer, H.M., E. Pehlke, G. Wibberenz, L.J. Lanzerotti and J.D. Mihalov,
                   High-Energy Charged Particles in the Innermost Jovian Magnetosphere, Science
                   272, pp. 856-858, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FISCHERETAL1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GP-J-EPI-3-ENTRY-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GALILEO PROBE EPI RAW DATA SET</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1996-12-08</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1995-12-07T19:06:48Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1995-12-07T21:54:18Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>HARALD FISCHER</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Galileo Probe Energetic Particles Investigation (EPI) Raw
            Data Set
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Galileo Probe Energetic Particles Investigation (EPI) Raw
            Data Set contains two tables of the EPI raw data values sorted by
            sampling time. The counter table contains the raw counter values
            as measured and the countrate table contains the countrates as
            derived from counter values, but without any correction. The
            tables are split into omnidirectional and sectorized data. The
            distance to Jupiter is given in Jupiter radii, Rj, and was
            derived from the Probe trajectory data. The time of probe entry
            is taken to be 1995-12-07T22:04:44Z when the probe reached an
            altitude of 450 km above the 1 bar pressure level.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The Galileo Probe Energetic Particles Investigation (EPI) Raw
    Data Set contains two tables of the EPI raw data values sorted by
    sampling time.  The counter table contains the raw counter values
    as measured and the countrate table contains the countrates as
    derived from counter values, but without any correction.  The
    tables are split into omnidirectional and sectorized data.  The
    distance to Jupiter is given in Jupiter radii, Rj, and was
    derived from the Probe trajectory data.  The time of probe entry
    is taken to be 1995-12-07T22:04:44Z when the probe reached an
    altitude of 450 km above the 1 bar pressure level.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The counter values are numbers without unit, while the countrates
    are given in counts per second.  The sampling time for the
    omnidirectional channels E12, E22, E32, P12, P31, P32 was 17.145
    s, for the omnidirectional HE2 channel it was 46.72 s, for the
    omnidirectional channel HVY in sample 1 - 4 it was 128 s and for
    the omnidirectional channels HVY1-HVY4 in sample 5-15 it was 64
    s.  For the sectorized channels E11S, E21S, E31S, P11S, P21S,
    P22S the sampling time was 2.143 s and for the sectorized HE1S
    channel it was 11.43 s.
 
    1 Rj = 71372 km.
 
    This value for Rj was selected to be consistent with the value
    used by the Pioneer 10 and 11 investigations.  The Pioneers were
    the only other spacecraft to fly to low jovian altitudes.  Users
    should be cautioned when comparing data sets organized by
    distance when the units provided are jovian radii.  Many
    different values have been selected by the Pioneer, Voyager,
    Ulysses, and Galileo teams.  In particular, the value used here
    is inconsistent with the value widely adopted by orbiter
    scientists who use the value 71492 km.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The EPI RAW DATA SET comprises five tables:
 
        (1) Counter Table - Omnidirectional
        (2) Counter Table - Sector
        (3) Countrate Table - Omnidirectional
        (4) Countrate Table - Sector
        (5) Housekeeping Table
 
    (1-2) Counter Tables
 
    These tables contain the raw counter values as measured. The data
    are sorted by their distance to Jupiter given in Jupiter radii, Rj.
 
    (3-4) Countrate Tables
 
    These tables contain the raw countrates derived from the counter
    values. The data are sorted by their distance to Jupiter given in
    Jupiter radii, Rj.
 
    (5) Housekeeping Table
 
    This table contains the detector leakage currents and the
    temperature of the EPI sensor.  The data are sorted by their
    distance to Jupiter given in Jupiter radii, Rj.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    Trajectory and timing information were obtained from the Galileo
    Project.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    The data are presented according to the radial distance of the
    probe to Jupiter as given by the project office.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The EPI data are transmitted completely without gaps from the
    orbiter to Earth and the sample overwriting for the last samples
    was done correctly.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    For the samples 5 and 6 there are no housekeeping data.  The
    housekeeping data in these samples belong to the samples 16 and
    17.  This is a consequence of the sample overwriting procedure,
    which was introduced to cover in any case the region of particle
    population down to the innermost edge of the magnetosphere
    independently of an early or late arrival of the probe.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    These data are raw data.  For a correct interpretation of the
    data the knowledge of the response functions of the instrument as
    well as a dead-time and stray-coincidence correction are
    necessary.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

