<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.co-e-sw-j-s-mag-4-summ-averaged-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CASSINI ORBITER MAG CALIBRATED SUMMARY AVERAGED V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mag.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.saturn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:plasma_stream.solar_wind::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.co-e-sw-j-s-mag-4-summ-averaged-v1.0__browserp_co-e-sw-j-s-mag-4-summ-averaged-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CO-E/SW/J/S-MAG-4-SUMM-AVERAGED-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CASSINI ORBITER MAG CALIBRATED SUMMARY AVERAGED V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2000-01-20T02:28:30Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JOSEPH N. MAFI</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Dougherty, M.K., S. Kellock, A.P. Slootweg, N. Achilleos, S.P.
            Joy, and J.N. Mafi, CASSINI ORBITER MAG CALIBRATED SUMMARY
            AVERAGED V1.0, CO-E/SW/J/S-MAG-4-SUMM-AVERAGED-V1.0, NASA
            Planetary Data System, 2006
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains calibrated summary averaged Cassini
            magnetometer data, for the entire Cassini mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains calibrated summary averaged Cassini
            magnetometer data, for the entire Cassini mission.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
      This data set contains magnetic-field data acquired during the
      cruise and tour phases of the Cassini mission to Saturn. The data
      set begins with data collected on 16 August (day 228), 1999 and ends
      on 17 November (day 321), 2005 when the instrument failed.
      On 16 August, 1999 two days before the spacecraft commenced Earth
      swingby, the magnetometer boom was unfurled into its extended
      position; a  configuration it maintained for the remainder of the
      mission.  Magnetic-field data acquired prior to boom deployment are
      limited and are significantly affected by spacecraft noise. These
      data are of no scientific value and, consequently, do not form part
      of this data set.
 
      Cassini carried two magnetometers: a fluxgate magnetometer (FGM)
      and a vector-helium magnetometer capable of operating in both
      vector and scalar mode (V/SHM). This data set contains calibrated,
      and averaged magnetic-field data recorded by the FGM instrument.
      The data are provided in both 1 second and 1 minute averages. The
      1 second averaged data files span 1 quarter of year prior to arrival
      at Saturn, and 1 Saturn orbit following arrival at Saturn. The 1
      minute data are provided in year files. The data are provided in
      RTN coordinates throughout the mission. After arrival at Saturn, the
      Saturn-centered KRTP, KSO, and KSM coordinates are also provided.
      Earth-centered, and Jupiter-centered coordinates are provided for
      the flybys of those two planets. All data files are ASCII.
 
      These data were calibrated, and rotated into geophysical coordinates
      by the Cassini MAG team at Imperial College (IC), and provided to
      the PDS/PPI node via the Cassini MAG team Co-I at UCLA. In other
      words these data use the same calibration as the data routinely
      delivered to the Cassini MAG team. The 1 minute data were also
      averaged at IC. Averaging for the 1 second data was performed at
      PDS/PPI. The data were reformatted into their current ASCII format,
      add trajectory information was added to the 1 minute data at
      PDS/PPI.
 
      Product Versions
      ----------------
      PRODUCT_VERSION_ID 1 data were calibrated at the PDS/PPI node at
      UCLA using software (CAL02), and calibration data provided by the
      Cassini MAG team. The process used the same calibration data that
      was provided with the Raw Magnetometer data archive (Data Set ID:
      CO-E/SW/J/S-MAG-2-REDR-RAW-DATA-V1.0). The data were then rotated
      into geophysical coordinates using MAG team additonal MAG team
      provided code (TRANSCAL) and spice kernels obtained from NAIF.
      Additional processing, including averaging, reformatting to ASCII,
      and the addition of trajectory to the 1 minute data was performed
      using code developed at PDS/PPI.
 
      PRODUCT_VERSION_ID 2 data were calibrated, and rotated into
      geophysical coordinates by the Cassini MAG team at Imperial
      College, and provided to the PDS/PPI node via the MAG team Co-I at
      UCLA. The 1 minute data were also averaged at IC. Averaging for the
      1 second data was performed at PDS/PPI. The data were reformatted
      at PDS/PPI to match the format used for the version 1 data.
 
      PRODUCT_VERSION_ID 3 data were processed following the same
      procedure that was followed for the version 2 data. However,
      subsequent to the release of the version 2 data it was discovered
      that the coordinate system trasformation for some of those data had
      been performed using predict SPICE kernels, rather than
      reconstructions. The version 3 were reprocessed using reconstructed
      ephemeris kernels for all of the data.
 
      PRODUCT_VERSION_ID 4 data were processed following the same
      procedure that was followed for the version 2 and 3 data. These
      data, however, were processed using only reconstructed SPK&apos;s to
      generate the trajectory data, thus correcting the errors which
      were present in the version 3 data. The MAG data do not differ
      between versions 3 and 4.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
N/A
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SUPERSEDED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

