<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.fexp-e-daed-3-rdr-spectrum-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>FIELD EXP E DAEDALUS SPECTROMETER CALIB RDR SPECTRUM V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.geologic_remote_sensing_field_experiment::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.fexp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:daed.fexp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.fexp-e-daed-3-rdr-spectrum-v1.0__browserp_geo_fexp-e-daed-3-rdr-spectrum-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.fexp-e-daed-3-rdr-spectrum-v1.0__dvo_geo_fexp-e-daed-3-rdr-spectrum-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Daedalus Enterprises, Inc., AA440 Spectrafax User&apos;s Guide,
                   P.O. Box 1869, Ann Arbor, Michigan 48106.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DAEDALUS1988</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>FEXP-E-DAED-3-RDR-SPECTRUM-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>FIELD EXP E DAEDALUS SPECTROMETER CALIB RDR SPECTRUM V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1991-05-28</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1989-07-15T18:31:17.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1989-07-19T17:48:21.000Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>EDWARD A. GUINNESS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Guinness, E. A., FIELD EXP E DAEDALUS SPECTROMETER CALIB RDR
            SPECTRUM V1.0, FEXP-E-DAED-3-RDR-SPECTRUM-V1.0, NASA Planetary
            Data System, 1991
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Daedalus Spectrometer Archive contains calibrated reduced
            data records (RDRs) acquired by the Daedalus Spectrometer during
            the earth-based 1989 Geologic Remote Sensing Field Experiment
            (GRSFE).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set was acquired during GRSFE with the Daedalus AA440
            spectrafax instrument. The data set consists of over 500 data
            files. The values stored in each data file are raw instrument
            counts, which are proportional to radiance. The purpose of these
            measurements was to provide ground calibration for AVIRIS and
            ASAS data.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      This data set was acquired during GRSFE with the Daedalus AA440
      spectrafax instrument.  The data set consists of over 500 data
      files.  The values stored in each data file are raw instrument
      counts, which are proportional to radiance.  The purpose of
      these measurements was to provide ground calibration for AVIRIS
      and ASAS data.
 
      A number of reflectance measurements were made to estimate the
      average reflectance of an area about 50 by 50 meters in size
      (i.e., the size of several AVIRIS pixels).  Measurements were
      made at Lunar Lake to characterize the reflectance of the
      spectral components at each GRSFE modeling site.
 
      The detached PDS labels for each spectrum contain a brief
      description of the site and purpose of the measurement.  The
      data set was acquired during the July 1989 field campaign.
 
      The reflectance of a bright and dark target area was
      characterized with the Daedalus spectrafax instrument at Kelso
      Dunes and the Cima Volcanic Field.  The reflectance of Trail
      Canyon Fan, the salt deposit at the Devil&apos;s Golf Course, Death
      Valley Dunes, and the tephra deposit at Ubehebe Crater were
      also characterized with the instrument.
 
      At each site measurements were made along 2 or 3 traverses.
      The reflectance of the natural surface was measured at points
      along the traverse.  Samples were spaced about 3 meters apart
      with 10 to 12 samples per traverse.  The spectralon calibration
      standard was generally measured at the beginning and end of
      each traverse.  Additional samples of vegetation and other
      significant components of the site (e.g., coated rocks) were
      also measured.
 
      Nearly 200 measurements were made at Lunar Lake for the purpose
      of calibrating the airborne GRSFE data, characterizing the
      reflectance of end-member materials in the modeling sites, and
      comparing reflectance spectra made by the field spectrometers
      used during GRSFE.  The procedure used to collect data for the
      calibration of airborne data was the same as describe in the
      previous paragraph.  Data for this purpose were collected at
      the playa, disturbed playa, and cobble sites at about 8:00am,
      9:30am, and 11:00am (local time).
 
      Measurements were also made for characterizing spectral
      end-members at the disturbed playa and the cobble site.  The
      smooth playa site was not characterized because the instrument
      batteries wore down.  However, the playa site is very uniform
      and there should be sufficient data from the airborne
      calibration experiment to characterized the spectral components
      of this playa.  There are no Daedalus spectrafax measurements
      of the lava flow site, again because the instrument batteries
      wore down before visiting that site.  Several measurements were
      made at Lunar Lake to compare spectra from the Daedalus
      spectrafax and SIRIS instruments.  In this experiment, both
      spectrometers measured the same calibration standard and then
      measured the same sample of undisturbed and disturbed playa,
      along with a large basalt cobble.
 
      Processing Level Id            : 3
      Software Flag                  : N
      Processing Start Time          : 1989-07-20T00:00:00.000
      Processing Stop Time           : 1991-05-28T00:00:00.000
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;RADIANCE&apos;
      -----------------------------
        Radiance is the amount of energy per time per projected area
        per steradian.
 
        Data Set Parameter Name        : RADIANCE
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Name        : WAVELENGTH
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : NANOMETER
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : 450
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : 2400
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 5.4
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : 5.4
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : N/A
        Noise Level                    : UNK
 
 
    Source Instrument Parameters
    ============================
      Instrument Host ID              : FEXP
      Data Set Parameter Name         : RADIANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
 
    Measurement Information
    =======================
 
      Atmospheric Conditions
      ----------------------
        Not Applicable
 
 
      Source
      ------
        Reflected sunlight provides the source of the energy detected
        by the spectrometer.
 
 
      Calibration Standard
      --------------------
        Spectralon calibration target used.
 
 
      Wavelength Calibration
      ----------------------
        Not Applicable
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      Processing History
      ------------------
        Source Data Set ID          : N/A
        Software                    : UNK
        Product Data Set ID         : FEXP-E-DAED-3-RDR-SPECTRUM-V1.0
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      Measurements made with the Daedalus spectrafax instrument
      during GRSFE were hand held with the instrument height only
      approximately fixed.  Thus, there can be a small difference in
      the height used to measure the calibration standard and a given
      sample.  Such a height difference will produce a systematic
      error in the absolute reflectance value.  Each centimeter
      difference in height will produce about a 2% change in
      reflectance.
 
      During GRSFE the instrument showed two operating problems.  One
      problem was the result of saturation in the electronics that
      affected channels in the wavelength range of about 0.73 to 0.97
      micrometers.  This problem can be readily seen in the spectra
      of the calibration standard.  The radiance values in the
      affected wavelength range are approximately constant and well
      below the values expected for these wavelengths.  Data in this
      wavelength range should be considered bad.  The second problem
      involved the filter wheel not properly rotating during data
      collection.  Measurements with the filter wheel problem have
      been removed from the GRSFE archive.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XD-21A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

