<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.fexp-e-parb-3-rdr-spectrum-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>FIELD EXP EARTH PARABOLA CALIBRATED RDR SPECTRUM V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.geologic_remote_sensing_field_experiment::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.fexp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:parb.fexp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.fexp-e-parb-3-rdr-spectrum-v1.0__browserp_geo_fexp-e-parb-3-rdr-spectrum-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.fexp-e-parb-3-rdr-spectrum-v1.0__dvo_geo_fexp-e-parb-3-rdr-spectrum-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Deering, D.W., and P. Leone, A sphere-scanning radiometer
                   for rapid directional measurements of sky and ground
                   radiance, Remote Sensing of the Environment, 19, 1-24,
                   1986.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DEERING-LEONE1986</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>FEXP-E-PARB-3-RDR-SPECTRUM-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>FIELD EXP EARTH PARABOLA CALIBRATED RDR SPECTRUM V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1991-05-28</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1989-07-17T21:32:00.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1989-07-19T16:17:00.000Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DONALD W. DEERING</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Deering, D. W., FIELD EXP EARTH PARABOLA CALIBRATED RDR SPECTRUM
            V1.0, FEXP-E-PARB-3-RDR-SPECTRUM-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 1991
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The PARABOLA Archive contains calibrated reduced data records
            (RDRs) acquired by the PARABOLA instrument during the earth-based
            1989 Geologic Remote Sensing Field Experiment (GRSFE).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            PARABOLA data were obtained at three GRSFE modeling sites in the
            Lunar Crater Volcanic Field. The playa site, the cobble site, and
            the mantled flow site. Each site was imaged by PARABOLA at a
            variety of solar incidence angles to characterize the scattering
            properties of the surface completely. This information can be
            used as a reference to correct airborne data from ASAS and AVIRIS
            from any lighting and viewing geometry, or as a base data set to
            test radiative transfer models. Six sets of data from the playa
            site were gathered primarily on July 17, 1989 with solar
            incidence angles that varied from 28 to 71 degrees. Five sets of
            cobble site data were gathered during the morning of July 18,
            1989 with incidence angles from 19 to 57 degrees. Data from the
            mantled flow site was obtained six times during the afternoon of
            July 18 with incidence angles from 21 to 73 degrees. In all, over
            1000 data points exist for each site to characterize its
            scattering properties. Additionally, an equal number of points
            exist for the sky above the sites.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      PARABOLA data were obtained at three GRSFE modeling sites in
      the Lunar Crater Volcanic Field.  The playa site, the cobble
      site, and the mantled flow site.  Each site was imaged by
      PARABOLA at a variety of solar incidence angles to characterize
      the scattering properties of the surface completely.  This
      information can be used as a reference to correct airborne data
      from ASAS and AVIRIS from any lighting and viewing geometry, or
      as a base data set to test radiative transfer models.  Six sets
      of data from the playa site were gathered primarily on July 17,
      1989 with solar incidence angles that varied from 28 to 71
      degrees.  Five sets of cobble site data were gathered during
      the morning of July 18, 1989 with incidence angles from 19 to
      57 degrees.  Data from the mantled flow site was obtained six
      times during the afternoon of July 18 with incidence angles
      from 21 to 73 degrees.  In all, over 1000 data points exist for
      each site to characterize its scattering properties.
      Additionally, an equal number of points exist for the sky above
      the sites.
 
      The data are presented in two formats.  The first set of files
      contain the complete, though filtered, data set consisting of
      almost all the individual pixels from the three replicate scans
      of the same site.  Because of the scanning pattern of PARABOLA,
      the pixels are not at equidistant angles in the off-nadir or
      azimuth viewing planes.  For users who prefer average sets of
      data binned into even intervals, the second set of files were
      created.  In these files, the raw data of the first set of
      files has been averaged into bins with centers every 15 degrees
      in off-nadir and 30 degrees in azimuth.
 
      Throughout the days during which PARABOLA data were being
      gathered, a white barium sulfate reference plate was
      periodically measured by PARABOLA.  This plate is known to be
      Lambertian within a correctable amount.  The measured radiance
      of this plate was plotted as a function of the time of day (or
      solar zenith angle) and fit to a sinusoid.  In this way, the
      radiance from a Lambertian reference is known at any time
      during the data gathering period.
 
      Processing Level Id            : 3
      Software Flag                  : N
      Processing Start Time          : 1989-07-20T00:00:00.000
      Processing Stop Time           : 1991-05-28T00:00:00.000
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;RADIANCE&apos;
      -----------------------------
        Radiance is the amount of energy per time per projected area
        per steradian.
 
        Data Set Parameter Name        : RADIANCE
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : WATT/(METER*METER)/STERADIAN
        Sampling Parameter Name        : WAVELENGTH
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : MICROMETER
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : 0.65
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : 1.69
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 0.2
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : N/A
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : N/A
        Noise Level                    : UNK
 
 
    Source Instrument Parameters
    ============================
      Instrument Host ID              : FEXP
      Data Set Parameter Name         : RADIANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
 
    Measurement Information
    =======================
 
      Atmospheric Conditions
      ----------------------
        Not Applicable
 
 
      Source
      ------
        The source is sunlight or reflected sunlight.
 
 
      Calibration Standard
      --------------------
        Not Applicable
 
 
      Wavelength Calibration
      ----------------------
        Not Applicable
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      Processing History
      ------------------
        Source Data Set ID          : N/A
        Software                    : UNK
        Product Data Set ID         : FEXP-E-PARB-3-RDR-SPECTRUM-V1.0
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      In averaged data files, the last column gives the number of
      points used to compute the average of the bin.  If there are
      gaps due to instrument shadows, instrument noise, or other
      causes, the value of the bin is taken from its mirror bin (this
      assumes symmetry of data across the solar principal plane).  To
      identify these cases, the number of data points averaged is
      assigned a negative (mirror image) value.  If for some reason,
      there is no data for substitution, an interpolated value is
      used.  Since interpolated values are not real data, the user is
      cautioned by placing a zero in the last column.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XD-21A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

