<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.go-v-e-ssi-2-redr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GALILEO VENUS AND EARTH SOLID STATE IMAGING 2 RAW EDR V1</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.comet_sl9-jupiter_collision::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.galileo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:ssi.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.black_sky::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.non_science::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-v-e-ssi-2-redr-v1.0__browserp_go-v-e-ssi-2-redr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-v-e-ssi-2-redr-v1.0__dvo_imaging_go-v_e-ssi-2-redr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Cribbs, M.A., and D.A. Wagner, Planetary Science Data Dictionary, JPL Document
                   D7116, November, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CRIBBS1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   McLaughlin, Bruce, EJ-7 Shoemaker-Levy 9 DMS Data Return
                   Strategy,GLL-MDT-94-096.IOM, May 13, 1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MCLAUGHLIN1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Wainio, Lisa, SSI REDR Software Interface Specification (SIS), JPL Document
                   D12109, April 20, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.WAINIO1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   White, Mitchell, SSI REDR CD-ROM Software Interface Specification (SIS),
                   JPL Document D232-15, July 9, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.WHITE1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GO-V/E-SSI-2-REDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GALILEO VENUS AND EARTH SOLID STATE IMAGING 2 RAW EDR V1</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1992-11-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1989-10-26T16:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1990-12-17T20:36Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>HELEN B. MORTENSEN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>not applicable</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set has been generated by NASA&apos;s Galileo Project
            in order to distribute the images acquired by the Solid State
            Imaging (SSI) camera to the scientists and later to the Planetary
            Data System (PDS).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>not applicable</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set has been generated by NASA&apos;s Galileo Project in
    order to distribute the images acquired by the Solid State
    Imaging (SSI) camera to the scientists and later to the
    Planetary Data System (PDS).  The collection resides on volumes
    GO_0002 thru GO_0006 and consists of all images acquired by the
    Galileo spacecraft during the period from launch in 1989
    through the first encounter with the Earth (SCLK 3061100
    through 62303500).  Included are images of Venus, the Earth&apos;s
    Moon and the Earth taken during the 1990 encounters, as well as
    additional star, calibration and other test data.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The Galileo SSI camera acquires data in a digital raster-format
    containing 800 scan lines and 800 samples per scan line.  Each
    picture element (pixel) in the two dimensional image array is
    represented as an 8-bit value between 0 and 255, proportional
    to the amount of light detectessssssd at that point (with 0 being
    the least amount of light and 255 being the greatest amount of
    light).  The camera is equipped with seven color filters and a
    clear filter such that images taken through complementary
    filters can be combined during ground processing to produce
    color images.  To make full scientific use of the image
    collection, the radiometric and geometric properties of the
    camera system should be understood.
 
    The ancillary disc, GO_0001, will provide calibration files and
    technical documentation necessary for the understanding of the
    images produced by the SSI camera.  Presently, calibration
    files and software are available through the VICAR software
    system at MIPS and SPICE files are available through the
    Galileo Science Data Team.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
 
    REDR Processing
    ---------------
      The Raw Experiment Data Records (REDRs) were produced by the
      Multimission Image Processing Subsystem (MIPS) at the Jet
      Propulsion Laboratory using several Video Image
      Communications and Retrieval (VICAR) programs.  The
      processing included the following steps:
 
      --The original telemetry data was processed into
        raster-formatted files (GLLTELEMPROC)
 
      --Multiple versions of each data file obtained from separate
        downlinks or playbacks were merged together to create the
        best version of the data (SSIMERGE)
 
      --The VICAR label was updated to reflect the most recent
        pointing information (CATLABEL)
 
      --Bad data value information was then added to the Telemetry
        Header (BADLABELS)
 
      --Missing line gaps of two lines or less were filled in, as
        specified by the SSI Team. (GLLFILLIN)
 
      --The PDS  Index table and detached PDS label files were
        generated. (CDGEN)
 
      --The VICAR files and PDS files were premastered onto a WORM
        CD-ROM which was validated.
 
      --The WORM CD-ROM was sent to a vendor and CD-ROM&apos;s were
        generated.
 
      --A final CD-ROM was compared bit-by-bit with the original data
        to ensure the quality of the vendor product.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    Each volume contains approximately 800 images stored as VICAR
    files.  A detached PDS label has been included for each image.
    Documentation files have been provided which inform the user
    about the organization and contents of the disc, and the
    definition of the labels.  An index files have also been
    provided which contain information about the images in the data
    set.
 
    The REDR data are generated by MIPS using procedures
    specifically developed or adapted for Galileo.  The files are
    generated on a VAX and are written in VAX compatible (LSByte
    first) format.
 
 
    REDR File Format
    ----------------
      The Galileo REDR format (WHITE1993) was originally reserved
      for SSI calibration data or data which should not be
      radiometrically corrected.  The SSI Team recently decided
      that the REDR format will be used to archive all raw SSI
      data.
 
      Each REDR file consists of a VICAR label, the telemetry
      header, the bad-data value header records (if there are any),
      and the Image Data which is preceded by a Binary Prefix.
      There are 800 line records of image data.  All records are
      fixed length.  The line record length is 1000 bytes; 200
      bytes of a binary line prefix and 800 bytes of 8 bit pixel
      data.  (Note, for the AI8 format or summation mode, the
      record length is still 1000, but the data is placed in the
      first 400 pixel samples and 400 lines only.) There will be a
      one-to-one correspondence between line records and image
      lines.  Data not received will be zero-filled.
 
      The BINARY HEADER is composed of a Telemetry header and a
      Bad-Data Value Header containing ancillary information
      specific to the image.  The TELEMETRY HEADER is split into
      two physical records.  The first 1000 bytes are placed in the
      first physical record after the VICAR label, and the last 800
      bytes are placed in the next physical record.  The last 200
      bytes are zero filled.  The BAD-DATA VALUE HEADER is composed
      of records describing several types of bad data values.  Each
      record describes only one type and depending on the number of
      bad pixels, they may span over several physical records.
      Each record is identified by the Record IDS field which is
      located at byte 0.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    All document files and detached label files contain a carriage
    return character (ASCII 13) and a line feed character (ASCII
    10) at the end of each record.  This allows the files to be
    read by the MacOS, DOS, Unix, and VMS operating systems.
    Tabular files are also described by a detached PDS label.  The
    PDS label file has the same name as the data file it describes,
    with the extension .LBL; for example, the file IMGINDEX.TAB is
    accompanied by the detached label file IMGINDEX.LBL in the same
    directory.  The detached PDS labels for REDR images contain
    information pertaining to the image.
 
    Tabular files are formatted so that they may be read directly
    into many database management systems on various computers.
    All fields are separated by commas, and character fields are
    enclosed in double quotation marks.  Character fields are left
    justified, and numeric fields are right justified.  The start
    byte and bytes values listed in the labels do not include the
    commas between fields or the quotation marks surrounding
    character fields.  The records are of fixed length, and the
    last two bytes of each record contain the ASCII carriage return
    and line feed characters.  This allows a table to be treated as
    a fixed length record file on computers that support this file
    type and as a normal text file on other computers.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The following CD-ROM copy, display and processing software has
    been successfully tested using the Galileo SSI data:
 
 
    Copy Software
    -------------
      -- DCL  COPY (VMS) - available with VMS
 
      -- VICAR Copy (VMS and UNIX) - Available with VICAR package
         from COSMIC.
 
 
    Display Software
    ----------------
      -- VICAR JDISP  (VMS and UNIX) - Available with VICAR package
         from COSMIC.
 
      -- PIXEL PUSHER (Apple Macintosh) - Available from COSMIC.
 
      -- NIH IMAGE  (Apple Macintosh) - A public domain program
         available from the National Institute of Health.
 
      -- CDBROWSE  (UNIX/Motif) - Software may be obtained from
         richard@ben.jpl.nasa.gov on the internet.
 
      -- IMDISP (IBM PC) - Program and information  about this
         program are available from PDS.
 
 
    Processing Software
    -------------------
      --VICAR (VMS and UNIX) - Available from COSMIC
 
      --ISIS (VMS and UNIX) - Available through the USGS in Flagstaff
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    N/A
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The SSI REDRs contain raw data as received from Galileo
    telemetry.  All the images received were processed and are
    contained on this volume.  Included in the limitations section
    are explanations of the VICAR and PDS keywords and values, as
    well as a description of a problem found with one frame in the
    data set.  This data set contains all of the data acquired
    during the Venus and Earth 1 period, the processing has been
    verified, and is currently in use by science team members in
    their analysis
 
 
  Review
  ======
    The SSI REDRs are reviewed prior to archiving by the SSI team.
    Data received is compared with data expected, and replays of
    missing data is requested.  The status and validity information
    on the REDRs themselves is examined.  Format and documentation
    of the CD-ROM archive volume is reviewed by PDS and is
    documented in WAINIO1992.  The mastered and replicated CD-ROM
    volumes received from the vendor are compared bit-by-bit with
    the original data to ensure the quality of the product.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
 
    Sequences and Objectives
    ------------------------
    VFWS     Venus Pre-Encounter Lightning
    VVLM     Venus Limb
    WFT      Venus Feature Track
    WGL      Venus Global
    WLT      Venus Departure Lighning
    LESH     Lunar Single Filter include Earthshine
    LCLR     Lunar Multispectral
    WZGF     Earth Zoom Geology Feature
    WSPN     Earth Spin Movie
    WROT     Earth Rotation Movie (daily samples)
    WDRK     Earth Darkside
    LCAL     Earth Camera Calibration
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    This section documents the known bad images, blank or saturated
    lunar frames and any problems which have been currently
    identified in the Venus/Earth I dataset.  For the purpose of
    this memo CD&apos;s refers to the five Earth I SSI REDR CD-ROM&apos;s
    (GO_0002 through GO_0006).  GO_0001 is scheduled to be
    generated after all of the IDA has been received sometime in
    the mid-1994 time period.
 
 
    General Information
    -------------------
      The following datasets are included on the CD&apos;s.  The
      starting and ending SCLK&apos;s (rim + mod91) have been identified,
      as well as any general information that might be needed to
      document the dataset.
 
 
    Post Launch Checkout
    --------------------
    (data taken after launch)
 
      SCLK range: 3061100 - 3061945
      - No SPICE info available
 
      - VICAR/PDS labels incomplete due to lack of SPICE info.
       (e.g. no SCET)
 
 
    MINICAL
    -------
    (calibration frames taken before Venus)
 
      SCLK range: 11890900 - 11895526
      - No SPICE info available
 
      - VICAR/PDS labels incomplete due to lack of SPICE info.
       (e.g. no SCET)
 
 
    VENUS
    -----
      SCLK range: 18062552 - 19064100
      - SPICE available
 
      - PICNO not available in Mini-E kernel
       (i.e. not in VICAR/PDS labels)
 
      - Activity id not in standard format.
 
 
    PRE-EARTH CALIB
    ---------------
      SCLK range: 59335800 - 59905000
      - SPICE available
 
      - Additional no shutter frames were captured for which no
        predict/SPICE info was available
        (identified as activity_id=NO_SHUTTER
 
 
    EARTH I/MOON
    ------------
      SCLK range: 60959100 - 62303500
      - SPICE available
 
 
    Bad Frames
    ----------
      The following is a the list of known bad SSI frames provided
      by Ken Klaasen on April 9, 1992.  This is not an all
      inclusive list, but it does provide the major problems
      identified through Earth I.  Appendix A contains the listing
      of lunar frames which were blank, saturated or redundant.
 
      11894613 - 11894726 - Garbled Jupiter frames due to IM-4
                            problem.
 
      18062600 - 18062639 - Venus darkside frames saturated due to
                            scattered light.
 
      59466845 - 59480800 - PCT frames that missed target due to
                            error in pointing command.
 
 
  VICAR Labels
  ============
    Definitions for VICAR field names can be found in WHITE1993.
 
    A) The RAD field (ring radius at frame center) within the VICAR
       label was not applicable and is equal to 0.0, for the entire
       set of CD&apos;s,.
 
    B) The following fields in the VICAR label were not implemented
       for the entire set of CD&apos;s.
 
       CONE                             = 0.0
       HRA                              = -999.0
       SMEAR                            = -999.0
       SMRAZ                            = 0.0
       SOLRANGE                         = 7.779091
       TCA                              = &apos;closest time&apos;
 
    C) For targets other than a planetary body or asteroid (e.g.
       black sky, stars, calibration etc.) most pointing information
       is not available. A listing of the missing fields is provided
       below.  More detailed information can be found in the
       CATSTATUS.TXT file which located in the Documents directory on
       all of the CD&apos;s,.
 
       EMA                              = -999.0
       HSCL                             = 0.0
       INA                              = -999.0
       LAT                              = 0.0
       LON                              = 0.0
       NORAZ                            = 0.0
       PHA                              = -999.0
       PLRANGE                          = 0.0
       SCAZ                             = 0.0
       SLRANGE                          = 0.0
       SUNAZ                            = 0.0
       VSCL                             = 0.0
 
    D) When SPICE information is unavailable (e.g.  Post launch
       checkout, Minical, additional No shutter frames) the following
       CATSTATUS for more detailed information.
 
       DEC                              = 0.0
       EMA                              = -999.0
       HSCL                             = 0.0
       INA                              = -999.0
       LAT                              = 0.0
       LON                              = 0.0
       NORAZ                            = 0.0
       PHA                              = -999.0
       PICNO                            = &apos;?&apos;
       PLRANGE                          = 0.0
       RA                               = 0.0
       SCAZ                             = 0.0
       SCETYEAR                         = -32768
       SCETDAY                          = -32768
       SCETHOUR                         = -32768
       SCETMIN                          = -32768
       SCETSEC                          = -32768
       SCETMSEC                         = -32768
       SLRANGE                          = 0.0
       SUNAZ                            = 0.0
       TWIST                            = 0.0
       VSCL                             = 0.0
 
    E) PLRANGE is equivalent to the spacecraft target range instead
       of the spacecraft central body range.  This affects the lunar
       frames only since the PLRANGE defines the distance from the
       Moon rather than from the Earth.  For the rest of the dataset,
       the spacecraft target range is equivalent to the spacecraft
       central body range so PLRANGE is correct.
 
 
  PDS Labels
  ==========
    Definations for PDS field names can be found in CRIBBS1992.
 
    A) The following PDS fields were not applicable for the entire
       set of CD&apos;s .
 
    BLEMISH_FILE_NAME                = &apos;N/A&apos;
    CENTER_RING_RADIUS               = 0.0
    DARK_CURRENT_FILE_NAME           = &apos;N/A&apos;
    EDR_FILE_NUMBER                  = &apos;N/A&apos;
    EDR_TAPE_ID                      = &apos;N/A&apos;
    MEAN_RADIANCE                    = &apos;N/A&apos;
    MEAN_REFLECTANCE                 = &apos;N/A&apos;
    ORBIT_NUMBER                     = &apos;unk&apos; or 12613
    RADIANCE_SCALING_FACTOR          = &apos;N/A&apos;
    REFLECTANCE_SCALING_FACTOR       = &apos;N/A&apos;
    SHUTTER_OFFSET_FILE_NAME         = &apos;N/A&apos;
    SLOPE_FILE_NAME                  = &apos;N/A&apos;
    SPICE_FILE_NAME                  = &apos;unk&apos;
    UNEVEN_BIT_WEIGHT_CORR_Flag      = &apos;N/A&apos;
 
    B) The following PDS fields were not implemented for the entire
        set of CD&apos;s.
 
    CONE_ANGLE                       =0.000
    LOCAL_HOUR_ANGLE                 =&apos;unk&apos;
    SMEAR_AZIMUTH                    =0.000
    SMEAR_MAGNITUDE                  =&apos;unk&apos;
    SOLAR_DISTANCE                   =7.779091
 
    C) For targets other than a planetary body or asteroid (e.g.
        black sky, stars, calibration etc.) the following pointing
        information is not available in the PDS labels.
 
    A_AXIS_RADIUS                    = &apos;unk&apos;
    B_AXIS_RADIUS                    = &apos;unk&apos;
    C_AXIS_RADIUS                    = &apos;unk&apos;
    CENTER_LATITUDE                  = 0.00000
    CENTER_LONGITUDE                 = 0.00000
    CENTRAL_BODY_DISTANCE            = 0.00000
    EMISSION_ANGLE                   = &apos;unk&apos;
    HORIZONTAL_PIXEL_SCALE           = 0.00000
    INCIDENCE_ANGLE                  = &apos;unk&apos;
    NORTH_AZIMUTH                    = 0.000
    PHASE_ANGLE                      = &apos;unk&apos;
    SATELLITE_TIME_FROM_CLST_APR     = &apos;unk&apos;
    SLANT_DISTANCE                   = 0.00000
    SUB_SOLAR_AZIMUTH                = 0.000
    SUB_SOLAR_LATITUDE               = &apos;unk&apos;
    SUB_SOLAR_LONGITUDE              = &apos;unk&apos;
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_AZIMUTH           = 0.000
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LATITUDE          = &apos;unk&apos;
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LINE              = &apos;unk&apos;
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LINE_SAMPLE       = &apos;unk&apos;
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LONGITUDE         = &apos;unk&apos;
    TARGET_CENTER_DISTANCE           = &apos;unk&apos;
    TIME_FROM_CLOSEST_APPROACH       = &apos;unk&apos;
    VERTICAL_PIXEL_SCALE             = 0.00000
 
    D) When SPICE information is unavailable (e.g. Post launch
       checkout, Minical, additional No shutter frames) the following
       pointing fields in the PDS label are not available.
 
    A_AXIS_RADIUS                    = &apos;unk&apos;
    B_AXIS_RADIUS                    = &apos;unk&apos;
    C_AXIS_RADIUS                    = &apos;unk&apos;
    CENTER_LATITUDE                  = 0.000
    CENTER_LONGITUDE                 = 0.000
    CENTRAL_BODY_DISTANCE            = 0.00000
    DECLINATION                      = 0.000
    EMISSION_ANGLE                   = &apos;unk&apos;
    HORIZONTAL_PIXEL_SCALE           = 0.00000
    IMAGE_ID                         = &apos;unk&apos;
    IMAGE_TIME                       = &apos;unk&apos;
    INCIDENCE_ANGLE                  = &apos;unk&apos;
    NORTH_AZIMUTH                    = 0.000
    PHASE_ANGLE                      = &apos;unk&apos;
    RIGHT_ASCENSION                  = 0.000
    SATELLITE_TIME_FROM_CLST_APR     = -73T... or &apos;unk&apos;
    SLANT_DISTANCE                   = 0.00000
    SUB_SOLAR_AZIMUTH                = 0.000
    SUB_SOLAR_LATITUDE               = &apos;unk&apos;
    SUB_SOLAR_LONGITUDE              = &apos;unk&apos;
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_AZIMUTH           = 0.000
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LATITUDE          = &apos;unk&apos;
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LINE              = &apos;unk&apos;
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LINE_SAMPLE       = &apos;unk&apos;
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LONGITUDE         = &apos;unk&apos;
    TARGET_CENTER_DISTANCE           = &apos;unk&apos;
    TIME_FROM_CLOSEST_APPROACH       = -73T... or  &apos;unk&apos;
    TWIST_ANGLE                      = 0.000
    VERTICAL_PIXEL_SCALE             = 0.00000
 
    E) On CD-ROM  GO_0002 only, the INVERTED_CLOCK_STATE_FLAG  was
       incorrectly set using the LIGHT_FLOOD_STATE_FLAG.  The
       INVERTED_CLOCK_STATE_FLAG should have read NOT INVERTED for
       all frames except for the 59335800, 59335900, 59336000,
       59336100, 59336200, 59336400.
 
    F) ORBIT_NUMBER for Earth and Moon frames incorrectly reads
       12613 instead of UNK.
 
 
  PDS Index Table
  ===============
    A) The following fields in the PDS Index table were not
       applicable for the entire set of CD&apos;s, .
 
    CENTER_RING_RADIUS               = 0.0
    MEAN_RADIANCE                    = &apos;N/A&apos;
    MEAN_REFLECTANCE                 = &apos;N/A&apos;
    ORBIT_NUMBER                     = &apos;unk&apos; or 126
    RADIANCE_SCALING_FACTOR          = &apos;N/A&apos;
    REFLECTANCE _SCALING_FACTOR      = &apos;N/A&apos;
 
    B) The following fields in the PDS Index table were not
       implemented for the entire set of CD&apos;s.
 
    CONE_ANGLE                       = 0.000
    LOCAL_HOUR_ANGLE                 = &apos;unk&apos;
    SMEAR_AZIMUTH                    = 0.000
    SMEAR_MAGNITUDE                  = &apos;unk&apos;
    SOLAR_DISTANCE                   = 7.779091
 
    C) For targets other than a planetary body or asteroid (e.g.
       black sky, stars, calibration etc.) some pointing information
       is not available.  A listing of the missing fields is provided
       below.
 
    CENTER_LATITUDE                  = 0.00000
    CENTER_LONGITUDE                 = 0.00000
    CENTRAL_BODY_DISTANCE            = 0.00000
    EMISSION_ANGLE                   = &apos;unk&apos;
    HORIZONTAL_PIXEL_SCALE           = 0.00000
    INCIDENCE_ANGLE                  = &apos;unk&apos;
    NORTH_AZIMUTH                    = 0.000
    PHASE_ANGLE                      = &apos;unk&apos;
    SATELLITE_TIME_FROM_CLST_APR     = -73T... or &apos; unk&apos;
    SLANT_DISTANCE                   = 0.00000
    SUB_SOLAR_AZIMUTH                = 0.000
    SUB_SOLAR_LATITUDE               = &apos;unk&apos;
    SUB_SOLAR_LONGITUDE              = &apos;unk&apos;
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LATITUDE          = &apos;unk&apos;
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LINE              = &apos;unk&apos;
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LINE_SAMPLE       = &apos;unk&apos;
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LONGITUDE         = &apos;unk&apos;
    TARGET_CENTER_DISTANCE           = &apos;unk&apos;
    TIME_FROM_CLOSEST_APPROACH       = -73T... or  &apos;unk&apos;
    VERTICAL_PIXEL_SCALE             = 0.00000
 
    D) When SPICE information is unavailable (e.g. Post launch
       checkout, Minical, additional No shutter frames) the following
       pointing fields in the Index table are not available.
 
    CENTER_LATITUDE                  = 0.00000
    CENTER_LONGITUDE                 = 0.00000
    CENTRAL_BODY_DISTANCE            = 0.00000
    DECLINATION                      = 0.000
    EMISSION_ANGLE                   = &apos;unk&apos;
    HORIZONTAL_PIXEL_SCALE           = 0.00000
    IMAGE_ID                         = &apos;unk&apos;
    IMAGE_TIME                       = -3276.. or 0-00-00T..
    INCIDENCE_ANGLE                  = &apos;unk&apos;
    NORTH_AZIMUTH                    = 0.000
    PHASE_ANGLE                      = &apos;unk&apos;
    RIGHT_ASCENSION                  = 0.000
    SATELLITE_TIME_FROM_CLST_APR     = -73T... or  unk&apos;
    SLANT_DISTANCE                   = 0.00000
    SUB_SOLAR_AZIMUTH                = 0.000
    SUB_SOLAR_LATITUDE               = &apos;unk&apos;
    SUB_SOLAR_LONGITUDE              = &apos;unk&apos;
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LATITUDE          = &apos;unk&apos;
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LINE              = &apos;unk&apos;
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LINE_SAMPLE       = &apos;unk&apos;
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LONGITUDE         = &apos;unk&apos;
    TARGET_CENTER_DISTANCE           = &apos;unk&apos;
    TIME_FROM_CLOSEST_APPROACH       = -73T... or  &apos;unk&apos;
    TWIST_ANGLE                      = 0.000
    VERTICAL_PIXEL_SCALE             = 0.00000
 
    E) When TARGET_CENTER_DISTANCE  or CENTER _BODY_DISTANCE are
       equal to UNK, the right double quote is missing in the index
       table.
 
 
  REDO Directory (GO_0006)
  ========================
    The following files have been reprocessed and placed in the
    REDO directory located on GO_0006.  The files were previously
    located in the Target and Directory indicated in the below
    table.  There were three cases in which data was reprocessed.
    Case 1 - several files had bad VICAR labels as indicated
    earlier in this memo.  Case 2 - when gap fill in was requested
    and either the line above or below the gap contained a
    Reed-Solomon overflow error.  Case 3 - there was one file in
    which the data on the CD-ROM was found to be corrupted.  All
    data was reprocessed, a new PDS label created and the
    information added to the INDEX table on GO_0006.
 
    18062639 - Venus - C001806 - Bad VICAR label
    18241745 - Venus - C001824 - Bad VICAR label &amp; Reed-Solomon
               fillin problem
    18353518 - Venus - C001835 - Bad VICAR label
    18518445 - Venus - C001851 - Bad VICAR label
    59469700 - Black Sky - C005946 - Bad VICAR label
    59471700 - Black Sky - C005947 - Bad VICAR label
    60964000 - Moon - C006096 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61078900 - Earth - C006107 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61116300 - Moon - C006111 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61116600 - Moon - C006111 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61424500 - Earth - C006142 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61441500 - Earth - C006144 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61469100 - Earth - C006146 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61508200 - Earth - C006150 - Bad image
    61509700 - Earth - C006150 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61510400 - Earth - C006151 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61510800 - Earth - C006151 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61512600 - Earth - C006151 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61516300 - Earth - C006151 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61516400 - Earth - C006151 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61516700 - Earth - C006151 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61522100 - Earth - C006152 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61525200 - Earth - C006152 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61526200 - Earth - C006152 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61530600 - Earth - C006153 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61531400 - Earth - C006153 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61531700 - Earth - C006153 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61533800 - Earth - C006153 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61535500 - Earth - C006153 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61539600 - Earth - C006153 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
    61542500 - Earth - C006154 - Reed-Solomon fillin problem
 
 
  Reed-Solomon Overflow
  =====================
    Many of the images in this dataset contain a Reed-Solomon
    overflow.  This feature may be seen in images which were
    Reed-Solomon encoded by the Galileo spacecraft.  If the data
    was received on the ground and the Reed-Solomon decoder was
    unable to completely decode the data, this overflow feature is
    present in the data.
 
    The Reed-Solomon overflow feature may be identified by the
    following criteria.  It is present on a single line or series
    of lines.  It starts about midway through a line and always
    continues through sample 800.  The data numbers (dn&apos;s) can
    shift between white, black or shades of gray.  In some cases,
    the dn&apos;s may be just a few dn brighter or darker than the
    surrounding lines.  Reed-Solomon overflows should not be
    confused with the data gaps caused by the decompression of
    data.  Decompression gaps are usually at the extreme right of
    an image, they always have a dn=0 (black) and they are clearly
    identified in the VICAR Binary Prefix.
 
    It should be noted that the Reed-Solomon overflows have not
    been identified in any way within this dataset.  Future data
    acquired by the SSI instrument will have a flag, in the Binary
    Prefix of the VICAR label, which will identify when a
    Reed-Solomon overflow has occurred.
 
 
    New Information About Venus/Earth I data set
    --------------------------------------------
      After the final Venus/Earth I data set memorandum was
      released, additional information about the data set has been
      identified.  First, one black sky image was found to be
      missing from the data set.  This frame (59466445) was
      processed and placed in the REDO directory located on
      GO_0007.
 
      The longitude values for the VENUS frames in the various
      headers are in WEST longitude not the more commonly used EAST
      longitude.
 
      The text file name CATSTATUS.TXT is too long for the ISO
      convention of 8.3.  This has been shortened to CATSTAT.TXT
      for the Earth 2 CDs.
 
      The PDS fields TIME_FROM_CLOSEST_APPROACH and
      SATELLITE_TIME_FROM_ CLST_APR are not in the standard PDS
      DATE/TIME format.  Since these fields are not a date and only
      a time, PDS is in the process of defining a new data type for
      these keywords.  PDS software is being modified to handle the
      Galileo usage of these fields.
 
      The PDS fields RIGHT_ASCENSION and TWIST are not in the PDS
      defined range of values.  These keywords should have values
      in the range of 0 to 360 degrees and instead have been
      defined in the range of -180 to 180 degrees.  To get the 0 to
      360 range, software should take the value from the PDS label,
      add 360 and then take the mod of 360.  It should be noted
      that the VICAR header and various VICAR software use the -180
      to 180 degree convention.  The PDS fields in the Earth 2 CDs
      are provided in the 0 to 360 degree conventions.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>89-084B-10C</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

