<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.go-d-gdds-5-dust-v3.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GALILEO DUST DETECTION SYSTEM V3.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.galileo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:gdds.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:dust.dust::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-d-gdds-5-dust-v3.0__browserp_go-d-gdds-5-dust-v3.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Goller, J.R., and Gruen E., Calibration of the Galileo/Ulysses dust detectors
                   with different projectile materials and at varying impact angle, Planet. Space
                   Sci. 37, 1197-1206, 1989.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GOLLER-GRUEN1989</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Goller, J.R., Kalibrationsmessungen an Mikrometeoritendetektoren fur die
                   Missionen Ulysses, Galileo, und Giotto. Inaugural- Dissertation, Universitat
                   Heidelberg, 1988.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GOLLER1988</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Gruen, E., M. Baguhl, N. Divine, H. Fechtig, D.P. Hamilton, and 14 others, Two
                   years of Ulysses dust data, Planet. Space Sci, 43, 971-999, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GRUENETAL1995A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Gruen, E., M. Baguhl, N. Divine, H. Fechtig, D.P. Hamilton, and 14 others,
                   Three years of Galileo dust data, Planet. Space Sci, 43, 953-969, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GRUENETAL1995B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Gruen, E., M. Baguhl, D.P. Hamilton, J. Kissel, D. Linkert, and 2 others,
                   Reduction of Galileo and Ulysses dust data, Planet. Space Sci, 43, 941-951,
                   1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GRUENETAL1995C</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Krueger, H., E. Gruen, M. Landgraf, M. Baguhl, S. Dermott, and 16 others, Three
                   years of Ulysses dust data: II. 1993 to 1995, Planetary and Space Science 47,
                   363-383, 1999.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KRUEGERETAL1999A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Krueger, H., E. Gruen, D. Hamilton, M. Baguhl, S. Dermott, and 16 others, Three
                   years of Galileo dust data: II. 1993 to 1995, Planetary and Space Science 47,
                   85-106, 1999.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KRUEGERETAL1999B</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GO-D-GDDS-5-DUST-V3.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GALILEO DUST DETECTION SYSTEM V3.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2003-08-12</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1989-12-28T17:20Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2001-12-31T11:54Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>MARK V. SYKES</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Krueger, H., E. Gruen, A. Grapps, D. Bindeschadler, M. Baghul, S.
            Dermott, N. Divine, H. Fechtig, B.A. Gustafson, D.P. Hamilton,
            M.S. Hanner, M. Horanyi, J. Kissel, B.-A. Lindblad, D. Linkert,
            G. Linkert, I. Mann, J.A.M. McDonnell, G.E. Morfill, C.
            Polanskey, R. Riemann, G. Schwehm, N. Siddique, P. Staubach, R.
            Srama, and H.A. Zook., GALILEO DUST DETECTION SYSTEM V3.0.
            GO-D-GDDS-5-DUST-V3.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2003.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains all Dust Detector data submitted by the
            DDS team. All data from spacecraft launch through the Io 31 Orbit
            is supplied.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Detector responses and derived quantities from the Galileo dust
            detector as well as spacecraft geometry information for reliable
            impacts from launch through 2001. See Gruen et al. (Plan. Sp.
            Sci. 43, 953-969, 1995) and Krueger et al. (Plan. Sp. Sci. 47,
            85-106, 1999; Plan. Sp. Sci. 49, 1285-1301, 2001) for more
            information.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
   Dataset Overview
   ================
 
    This data set contains information on the dust environment in
    interplanetary space within the inner solar system and in the Jupiter
    system, within and without the Jovian magnetosphere and around the
    Galilean satellites. This information is collected with a dust impact
    experiment, DDS, from which may be inferred direction of motion, mass,
    velocity and charge (see GO_DDS_INST.CAT). The data presented in this
    dataset include instrumental readouts, inferred metadata, calibration
    information and a calendar of events. Specifically:
 
    1) galddust.tab - data received from the dust detector, the spacecraft,
       and physical properties derived from the detector data for reliable
       dust impacts (Gruen et al. 1995b and Krueger et al. 1999b).
 
    2) galdevnt.tab - data received from the dust detector, the spacecraft,
       and physical properties derived from the detector data for reliable
       dust impacts plus noise events.
 
    3) galdcode.tab - value ranges corresponding to codes found in
       galddust.tab.
 
    4) galdcalb.tab - laboratory calibration data used to relate instrument
       responses to physical properties of the impacting dust particles.
 
    5) galdsen*.tab - the area of the dust detector exposed to particles as a
       function of their velocity direction relative to the detector axis.
 
    6) galdstat.tab - time history of Galileo mission and dust detector
       configuration, tests and other events.
 
    The data received from the spacecraft are used for determining
    the location and orientation of the spacecraft and instrument. Given
    are the SPACECRAFT-SUN DISTANCE, ECLIPTIC LONGITUDE, ECLIPTIC
    LATITUDE, SPACECRAFT-EARTH DISTANCE, ROTATION ANGLE, DETECTOR
    ECLIPTIC LONGITUDE, and DETECTOR ECLIPTIC LATITUDE.
 
    Data received from the dust detector are given in an integer code
    format.  Some of the integer codes represent a range of values within
    which the data could fall (e.g., ION AMPLITUDE CODE), some may represent
    a specific value (e.g., ION COLLECTOR THRESHOLD), and others, a
    classification based upon other integer codes (e.g., EVENT CLASS).
 
    The instrument data consists of cataloging information, instrument
    status, instrument readings at time of impact, and classification
    information.  The cataloging information includes the SEQUENCE NUMBER
    (impact number), JULIAN DATE (time of impact), and SECTOR (the
    pointing of the instrument at time of impact).  The instrument status
    data are the threshold levels of the detectors and the CHANNELTRON
    VOLTAGE LEVEL.
 
    The instrument readings include the amplitude codes of the detectors
    aboard the instrument and the integer codes representing the charge
    level rise times of the detectors, the difference in starting times
    of the ion signal and the electron signal, electron and ion signal
    coincidence, and ion and channeltron signal coincidence.
 
    The classification information is used to assist in classifying an
    event into probable impact and non-impact categories.  There are three
    variables used in classification:  EVENT DEFINITION which records which
    detectors begin a measurement cycle; ION AMPLITUDE RANGE which is the
    classification of the ION AMPLITUDE CODE into 6 subranges (used with
    EVENT CLASS); and EVENT CLASS which categorizes events into a range of
    probable impacts to probable non-impacts.
 
    The PARTICLE SPEED and PARTICLE MASS and their corresponding error
    factors are determined from the instrument and calibration data given in
    galddust.tab and galdcalb.tab, respectively.
 
   Calibration Data
   ================
 
    ION RISE TIME, ELECTRON RISE TIME, ION CHARGE MASS RATIO, and ELECTRON
    CHARGE MASS RATIO were measured for iron, glass, and carbon particles
    of known mass and impacting at known speeds. Since the composition of
    particles striking the Galileo spacecraft is unknown, logarithmic
    averages of the above values are used to infer the particle speed and
    mass from the instrumental measurements. See [GOLLER1988].
 
    The data were provided in a private communication to M. Sykes (Jun 29
    03:04 MST 1995) by M. Baguhl. They are the results of these experiments
    for impacts at an angle of 34 degrees from the detector axis.
 
   Processing Level
   ================
 
    The data contain different levels of processing.  Some processing
    was done at the time of the impact observation.  This processing
    categorized the detector responses to transmit the data efficiently
    back to Earth.  Data received on Earth is given as an integer code.
    These integer codes can, for example, represent ranges of values, or
    can be a classification determined from other integer codes.  On Earth,
    these integer codes were then fit to calibration curves to determine
    the speed and mass of the impacting particle ([GOLLER&amp;GRUEN1989];
    [GRUENETAL1995C]).
 
    This data set contains the information from the spacecraft instrument as
    received on Earth, information about the location and pointing
    direction of the spacecraft, and the physical properties determined from
    the data analysis.
 
    The calibration data are included as part of this dataset.
 
   Sampling Parameters
   ===================
 
    The occurrence of an impact with the instrument begins a measurement
    cycle.  The on-board detectors measure a charge accumulation versus
    time in order to measure the rise time of the accumulation and any
    coincidences between detector readings.  The on-board computer converts
    these measurements to integer codes to minimize the amount of data
    that is transferred back to Earth.  After the conversion, the integer
    codes are categorized to determine if an event is more likely to be an
    impact or noise event.  The data are then stored until it is time to
    transmit to Earth.
 
   Data Reduction - Impact Speed
   =============================
 
    Impact speed (V) is obtained from the rise-time measurements of the ion
    and electron detectors (IT and ET, respectively) using procedures
    described in part in [GRUENETAL1995C] and a private communication
    to M. Sykes (Jul 22 03:43 MST 1995) from M. Baguhl. The calibration
    tables used correspond to the mean values obtained for the three
    different projectile materials with which the instruments were calibrated
    ([GOLLER&amp;GRUEN1989]; [GRUENETAL1995C]). A rise-time measurement is
    started when the respective signal exceeds its threshold and is stopped
    by a flag pulse from the peak-detector. Impact calibration was performed
    in the speed interval from about 2 km/s to 70 km/s, so impact speeds
    derived from rise-time measurements will be limited to this range.
 
    Dust accelerator tests as well as experience with flight data have shown
    that (1) the shape of the ion signal is less susceptible to noise than
    the shape of the electron signal and (2) for true impacts, ELECTRON
    AMPLITUDE CODE values (EA) are generally greater than the ION AMPLITUDE
    CODE values (IA) by 2 to 6.  As a consequence, the electron rise-time is
    only used for impact speed determination if 2 =&lt; EA-IA =&lt; 6. Since both
    speed measurements, if available, are independent, one obtains two (often
    different) values VIT and VET, respectively. The impact speed is then
    taken to be the geometric mean of VIT and VET.
 
    Determining VIT:
 
       If IA &gt; 16 and IT &gt; 12, then fix IT=14.
       Else, if IA &gt; 16 and IT =&lt; 12, then add 2 to the corresponding
           value of IT.
       VIT is then found in Table 5a of Gruen et al. (1995c) or galdcode.tab.
 
       Note: If IT=0, then VIT is invalid. This differs from
             Gruen et al. (1995c).
 
    Determining VET:
 
       If EA &gt; 16 and ET &gt; 12, then fix ET=14.
       Else, if EA &gt; 16 and ET =&lt; 12, then add 2 to the corresponding
          value of ET.
       VET is then found in Table 5a of Gruen et al. (1995c) or galdcode.tab.
 
       Note: If ET=0, then VET is invalid. This differs from
             Gruen et al. (1995c).
 
    If IA=49, or IA=18, or IA&lt;3, then IT is not valid, and only VET is used
    to determine impact speed.
 
    If EA=49, or EA=31, or EA&lt;5, then ET is not valid, and only VIT is used
    to determine impact speed.
 
    If IT is invalid and 6&lt;EA-IA or EA-IA&lt;2, then there is no valid impact
    speed.
 
    If neither IT nor ET is valid, then there is no valid impact speed.
 
 
   Data Reduction - Impact Speed Error Factor
   ==========================================
 
    The upper and lower estimates of impactor speed are obtained by
    multiplying and dividing, respectively, the mean particle speed by the
    velocity error factor, VEF. If only one speed is measured, and is from
    the electron detector, the minimum uncertainty is VEF=2. If only one
    speed is measured, and is from the ion detector, the minimum uncertainty
    is VEF=1.9. It is assumed that minimum error of 1.6 is achieved if both
    individual speeds agree to within a factor of 4. This error corresponds
    to the logarithmic mean of the minimum errors in the two cases when only
    a single speed is valid.
 
    Since these are all 1-sigma errors, it may happen that VIT or VET fall
    outside the error bar given for the mean impact speed, V. In order to
    avoid this, the error factor is &apos;stretched&apos; to contain the values:
 
    If VIT &gt; 4*VET, then
 
        VEF=(VIT/VET-4.)/31.*(1.6*sqrt(35.)-1.6)+1.6
 
    If VET &gt; 4*VIT, then
 
        VEF=(VET/VIT-4.)/31.*(1.6*sqrt(35.)-1.6)+1.6
 
    (private communication to M. Sykes from M. Baguhl, Mar  6 03:57 MST
    1996).
 
    If the ratio of both speeds exceeds 4, then the uncertainty can increase
    to about 10 in the calibrated speed range. In any case, a speed value
    with an uncertainty factor VEF&gt;6 should be ignored.
 
   Data Reduction - Impactor Mass
   ==============================
 
    Once a particle&apos;s impact speed (V) has been determined, the charge to
    mass ratio can be determined from calibration measurements (Figure 3,
    [GRUENETAL1995C]); galdcalb.tab). The charge to mass ratio for a given
    impact speed (V) is determined by linear interpolation of the calibration
    table (galdcalb.tab) on a double logarithmic scale, yielding a separate
    value for the ion grid measurement (QIM) and electron grid measurement
    (QEM).
 
    From these values and the respective impact charges (QI and QE)
    corresponding to IA and EA, respectively (Table 4, Gruen et al. (1995c);
    galdcalb.tab), mass values (MQI=QI/QIM and MQE=QE/QEM) are determined
    corresponding to the ion and electron grid measurements. When both MQI
    and MQE are valid, the impact particle mass, M, is the geometric
    mean of these two values, or the value corresponding to the valid
    measurement if the other is invalid. If there is no valid impact speed,
    then there is no valid impactor mass.
 
    Note: when V is invalid, M is invalid.
 
    Note: when IA=0, QI is invalid and MQI is invalid.
 
    Note: when EA=0, QE is invalid and MQE is invalid.
 
   Data Reduction - Impactor Mass Error Factor
   ===========================================
 
    The upper and lower estimate of impactor speed is obtained by multiplying
    and dividing, respectively, the mean particle speed by the mass error
    factor, MEF. If the speed is well determined (VEF=1.6) then the mass value
    can be determined with an uncertainty factor MEF=6. Larger speed
    uncertainties can result in mass uncertainty factors greater than 100.
 
    The mass error is calculated from the speed error, keeping in mind that
    mass detection threshold is proportional to speed to the 3.5th power.
    In addition, there is an error factor of 2 from the amplitude
    determination. Added together (logarithmically) these yield
 
    MEF=10**(sqrt((3.5*log(VEF))**2+(log(2.))**2))
 
    (Private communication to M. Sykes from M. Baguhl, Mar  6 03:57 MST 1996.
    This differs from the exponent of 3.4 given in [GRUENETAL1995A])
 
 
   Coordinate System
   =================
 
    The coordinates of the spacecraft are given in heliocentric ecliptic
    latitude and longitude (equinox 1950.0), where the pointing direction
    of the sensor is given in spacecraft centered ecliptic latitude and
    longitude (equinox 1950.0).
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
   Impact times
   ============
 
   The impact times during the Cruise phase of the mission were recorded
   with an accuracy of 1.1 hours. After June 25, 1990, inclusive, the
   accuracy was 4.3 hours (this value has been set in order to bridge gaps
   in the data transmission as long as one month) ([GRUENETAL1995B];
   [KRUEGERETAL1999B]). There were also periods in which more frequent
   memory reads resulted in a time resolution of 2/3 seconds.
 
   Time Error Value (TEV)
   ======================
 
   Prior to 1993, data were not released with individual TEV values. Time
   resolutions given by [GRUENETAL1995B] and applied retrospectively
   to data prior to 1993 yields the following distribution of TEV across
   those impact and noise events:
 
        galddust                             galdevnt
 
        IMPACT SEQUENCE NUMBER  |  TEV       EVENT SEQUENCE NUMBER  |  TEV
        ------------------------------       -----------------------------
                 001-099        |   66              0001-0607       |    0
                 100-138        |  259              0608-1099       |   66
                 139-147        |    0              1100-1218       |  259
                 148-344        |  259              1219-1851       |    0
                 345-352        |    0              1852-3244       |  259
                 353-359        |  259              3245-4627       |    0
                                                    4628-5446       |  259
 
   These values were confirmed in a private communication to M. Sykes
   (Dec  9 05:06 MST 1998) by H. Krueger.
 
   Based on information in [KRUEGERETAL1999B], TEV values were changed
   for the following events to the values below:
 
        IMPACT SEQUENCE NUMBER  |  TEV       EVENT SEQUENCE NUMBER  |  TEV
        ------------------------------       -----------------------------
               2762-2767        |   70              8991-8996       |   70
               2768-2837        |    2              8997-9069       |    2
               2848-2851        |   33              9080-9083       |   33
               2852-2869        |    2              9084-9101       |    2
 
   NOTE: In the current (1998) PDS release, the Galileo DDS Status File
   (galdstat.tab) extends only through the end of 1995. Thus, Time
   Error Factors for 1996 and 1997 impact and event data cannot be checked
   against the sampling mode of the DDS until the release of the updated
   status file.
 
   Sector
   ======
 
   In V1.0 of this data set, SECTOR was reported in degrees. In V2.0
   Sector is reported as its original 8-bit word, and has a value between
   0 and 255 (when valid). Conversion to degrees may be accomplished
   through scaling by 1.40625.
 
   Ion Channeltron Coincidence (ICC)
   =================================
 
   The designation ICC is used following [GRUENETAL1995B] and
   [KRUEGERETAL1999B], noting that in [GRUENETAL1995A] and [GRUENETAL1995C],
   and [KRUEGERETAL1999A], the designation is IIC.
 
   Entrance Grid Amplitude Code (PA)
   =================================
 
   In the data that have been published in the literature and electronically
   prior to 11/98, there are values of PA which exceed 47. In a private
   communication to M. Sykes (Mar  6 03:57 MST 1996), Michael Baguhl
   and Rainer Riemann stated:
 
       &apos;Values of PA greater 47 are caused by a bit flip (caused by a
        timing bug in the sensor electronics) of the MSB. For values
        greater 47, a value of 16 has to be subtracted.&apos;
 
   This correction was made to all PDS DDS files prior to 11/98.
 
   As a consequence of subsequent uncertainty about the origin
   of PA values greater than 47, in a private communication to M. Sykes
   (Nov  6 04:07 MST 1998), H. Krueger requested that PA values greater
   than 47 be corrected to &apos;99&apos;. This has been done in releases of the
   DDS data through the PDS after 11/98.
 
   Channeltron Voltage Level (HV)
   ==============================
 
   The nominal high voltage HV=4 (1250V) could not be used because of
   unexpected noise on the channeltron. It is assumed that the nearby
   radioactive thermal generators (RTGs) are to blame, although other
   causes cannot be excluded. During ground tests (without RTGs) no such
   noise was observed. See [GRUENETAL1995B].
 
   Spacecraft Earth distance
   =========================
 
   The value for the same impact event in galddust.tab and galdevnt.tab
   is different, but less than 7500 km.
 
   Impact speed
   ============
 
   In a private communication to M. Sykes (Jul 22 03:43 MST 1995), M. Baguhl
   stated that the reason for the exclusion of the values IA=49 and EA=15 is
   empirical. These values are close to the switching points of the amplifier
   ranges and therefore produce incorrect time measurements. The adjustment
   of the times in amplifier range 2 was made in order to prevent illegal
   time values.
 
   Calibration data
   ================
 
   Instrumental values were extrapolated for particle masses and speeds
   outside the range of those tested, and are so marked. The accuracy of
   these numbers is unknown. An explication of the experiments and data
   used to generate the calibration may be found in [GOLLER1988].
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SUPERSEDED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

