<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.vg2-u-pws-2-rdr-sa-4sec-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>VG2 URA PWS EDITED RDR UNCALIB SPECTRUM ANALYZER 4SEC V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.comet_sl9-jupiter_collision::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.voyager::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vg2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:pws.vg2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.uranus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vg2-u-pws-2-rdr-sa-4sec-v1.0__browserp_vg2-u-pws-2-rdr-sa-4sec-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Gurnett, D.A., W.S. Kurth, F.L. Scarf, and R.L. Poynter, First Plasma Wave
                   Observations at Uranus, Science, Vol. 233, p. 106, 1986.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GURNETTETAL1986</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>VG2-U-PWS-2-RDR-SA-4SEC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>VG2 URA PWS EDITED RDR UNCALIB SPECTRUM ANALYZER 4SEC V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1993-02-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1986-01-23T00:00:00.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1986-01-31T00:00:00.000Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. WILLIAM S. KURTH</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            VG2 URA PWS EDITED RDR UNCALIB SPECTRUM ANALYZER 4SEC V1.0
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set consists of 4-second edited, wave electric field
            intensities from the Voyager 2 Plasma Wave Receiver spectrum
            analyzer obtained in the vicinity of the Uranian magnetosphere.
            For each 4-second interval, a field strength is determined for
            each of the 16 spectrum analyzer channels whose center
            frequencies range from 10 Hertz to 56.2 kiloHertz and which are
            logarithmically spaced in frequency, four channels per decade.
            The time associated with each set of intensities (16 channels) is
            the time of the beginning of the scan. During data gaps where
            complete 4-second spectra are missing, no entries exist in the
            file, that is, the gaps are not zero-filled or tagged in any
            other way. When one or more channels are missing within a scan,
            the missing measurements are zero-filled. Data are edited but not
            calibrated. The data numbers in this data set can be plotted in
            raw form for event searches and simple trend analysis since they
            are roughly proportional to the log of the electric field
            strength. Calibration procedures and tables are provided for use
            with this data set described below.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      This data set consists of 4-second edited, wave electric field
      intensities from the Voyager 2 Plasma Wave Receiver spectrum
      analyzer obtained in the vicinity of the Uranian magnetosphere.
      For each 4-second interval, a field strength is determined for
      each of the 16 spectrum analyzer channels whose center
      frequencies range from 10 Hertz to 56.2 kiloHertz and which are
      logarithmically spaced in frequency, four channels per decade.
      The time associated with each set of intensities (16 channels)
      is the time of the beginning of the scan.  During data gaps
      where complete 4-second spectra are missing, no entries exist
      in the file, that is, the gaps are not zero-filled or tagged in
      any other way.  When one or more channels are missing within a
      scan, the missing measurements are zero-filled.  Data are
      edited but not calibrated.  The data numbers in this data set
      can be plotted in raw form for event searches and simple trend
      analysis since they are roughly proportional to the log of the
      electric field strength.  Calibration procedures and tables are
      provided for use with this data set; the use of these is
      described below.
 
      Use of Voyager PWS Calibration Tables
 
      The Voyager PWS calibration tables are given in two plain ASCII
      text files named VG1PWSCL.TAB and VG2PWSCL.TAB (for Voyagers-1
      and -2, respectively).  These provide information to convert
      the uncalibrated `data number&apos; output of the PWS 16-channel
      spectrum analyzer to calibrated antenna voltages for each
      frequency channel.  Following is a brief description of these
      files and a tutorial in their application.
 
      The first column lists an uncalibrated data number followed by
      the corresponding value in calibrated volts for each of the 16
      frequency channels of the PWS spectrum analyzer.  Each line
      contains calibrations for successive data number values ranging
      from 0 through 255.  (Data number 0 actually represents the
      lack of data since the baseline noise values for each channel
      are all above that.)
 
      A data analysis program may load the appropriate table into a
      data structure and thus provide a simple look-up scheme to
      obtain the appropriate voltage for a given data number and
      frequency channel.  For example, the following VAX FORTRAN code
      may be used to load a calibration array for Voyager 2 PWS:
 
        real*4 cal (16,0:255)
        open ( unit=10, file=&apos;vg2pwscl.tab&apos;, status=&apos;old&apos; )
        do i=0,38
         read (10,*) ! skip 38 lines of label info
        end do
        do i=0,255
         read (10,*) idn, (cal(ichan,i),ichan=1,16)
        end do
        close (10)
 
      Then, given an uncalibrated data value idn for the frequency
      channel ichan, the corresponding calibrated antenna voltage
      would be given by the following array reference:
 
             volts = cal (ichan, idn)
 
      This may be converted to a wave electric field amplitude by
      dividing by the effective antenna length in meters, 7.07m.
      That is:
 
             efield = cal(ichan, idn) / 7.07
 
      Spectral density units may be obtained by dividing the square
      of the electric field value by the nominal frequency bandwidth
      of the corresponding spectrum analyzer channel.
 
        specdens = (cal(ichan,idn)/7.07)**2 / bandwidth(ichan)
 
      Finally, power flux may be obtained by dividing the spectral
      density by the impedance of free space in ohms:
 
      pwrflux=((cal(ichan,idn)/7.07)**2/bandwidth(ichan))/376.73
 
      Of course, for a particular application, it may be more
      efficient to apply the above conversions to the calibration
      table directly.
 
      The center frequencies and bandwidths of each PWS spectrum
      analyzer channel for the Voyager 2 PWS are given below:
 
            VOYAGER 2 PWS SPECTRUM ANALYZER
 
                                         Voyager-2
        Channel    Center Frequency      Bandwidth
 
         1             10.0 Hz             2.16  Hz
         2             17.8 Hz             3.58  Hz
         3             31.1 Hz             4.50  Hz
         4             56.2 Hz            10.7   Hz
         5            100.  Hz            13.8   Hz
         6            178.  Hz            28.8   Hz
         7            311.  Hz            39.8   Hz
         8            562.  Hz            75.9   Hz
         9           1.00   kHz           75.9   Hz
         10          1.78   kHz          151.    Hz
         11          3.11   kHz          324.    Hz
         12          5.62   kHz          513.    Hz
         13         10.0    kHz          832.    Hz
         14         17.8    kHz         1260.    Hz
         15         31.1    kHz         2400.    Hz
         16         56.2    kHz         3800.    Hz
 
      A failure in the Voyager 2 Flight Data System which occurred
      about 3 months after launch has adversely affected the
      calibration of PWS channels 9 through 16.  An algorithm has
      been devised to partially correct for this failure, and has
      proven useful for Voyager 2 Jupiter, Saturn, and Uranus
      encounters, but is not valid for Earth-Jupiter cruise and may
      be modified in the future.  The following implementation of
      this correction algorithm in VAX FORTRAN assumes that
      uncalibrated data numbers are stored in a 16-element integer
      array, idn, with the array index equal to the PWS channel
      number:
 
       real*4 tonl(9:16) ! the old noise level for v2
       data tonl/2.0,1.0,-1.0,-2.0,-3.0,1.0,2.0,1.0/
 
        do ichan=9,16
         if (idn(ichan).gt.0) then
          if(idn(ichan).lt.64) idn(ichan)=64
           if (idn(ichan).le.72) then
            idn(ichan)=int(tonl(ichan)-530.4+8.6
                       *real(idn(ichan)))
            else
              idn(ichan)=int(tonl(ichan)+20.113+0.99
                         *real(idn(ichan)))
          end if
         end if
        end do
 
      This correction should not be applied permanently to the
      Voyager 2 calibration table since it is valid for a limited
      time span and may be modified in the future.
 
      Additional information about this dataset and the instrument
      which produced it can be found elsewhere in this catalog.  An
      overview of the data in this data set can be found in Gurnett
      et al.  [1986] and a complete instrument description can be
      found in Scarf and Gurnett [1977].
 
      Processing Level Id            : 2
      Software Flag                  : Y
      Processing Start Time          : 1988-08-01
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;PLASMA WAVE SPECTRUM&apos;
      -----------------------------------------
        A set of derived parameters consisting of wave electric field
        intensities or electric field spectral densities at various
        contiguous frequencies over a range of frequencies.  The MKS
        units are: Volts/Meter or Volts**2/(Hertz.Meter**2),
        respectively.
 
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Data Set Parameter Name        : PLASMA WAVE SPECTRUM
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 4.000000
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : 197708201553.000000
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : 4.000000
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : 4.000000
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : VOLT/METER
        Noise Level                    : 0.000005
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND
 
 
    Source Instrument Parameters
    ============================
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : PLASMA WAVE SPECTRUM
      Instrument Parameter Name       : ELECTRIC FIELD WAVEFORM
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : PLASMA WAVE SPECTRUM
      Instrument Parameter Name       : ELECTRIC FIELD COMPONENT
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : PLASMA WAVE SPECTRUM
      Instrument Parameter Name       : MAGNETIC FIELD COMPONENT
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : PLASMA WAVE SPECTRUM
      Instrument Parameter Name       : WAVE ELECTRIC FIELD INTENSITY
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : PLASMA WAVE SPECTRUM
      Instrument Parameter Name       : WAVE MAGNETIC FIELD INTENSITY
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      Processing History
      ------------------
        Source Data Set ID      : N/A
        Software                : CDMAKE
        Product Data Set ID     : VG2-U-PWS-2-RDR-SA-4SEC-V1.0
 
 
      Software &apos;CDMAKE&apos;
      -----------------
        CDMAKE is primarily a data format translation routine which
        is used to convert Voyager Plasma Wave Spectrometer (PWS) MSF
        tape files to CD files.  The MSF, or Master Science Files,
        are produced at the University of Iowa as the primary,
        ordered, full-information PWS spectrum analyzer data set.
        The CD files contain uncalibrated, full-resolution PWS data
        with minimal ancillary data in a simplified format which may
        be used in CDROM production.
 
        Note: SOFTWARE IS NOT AVAILABLE FOR PUBLIC USE.
 
        Software Name               : CDMAKE
        Software Type               : N/A
        Software Release Date       : 1988-08-01
        Node ID                     : PPI-IOWA
        Cognizant Engineer          : MR. LARRY J. GRANROTH
        Software Access Description : N/A
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      This data set includes all available spectrum analyzer data
      within the interval of time covered.  The data set has been
      cleaned as well as possible for periodic noise spikes due to a
      stepper motor operating on the LECP and a modulated grid within
      the PLS.  The &apos;bad&apos; points remain in the data set as negative
      numbers with the same absolute value as the original data point
      so that the point can be skipped in normal data processing by
      testing for negative values or recovered for special inspection
      by converting the sign back to a positive one.  Other possible
      sources of noise which have not been eliminated include random
      intense spikes of noise below 1 kiloHertz due to the operation
      of attitude control thrusters.  Other randomly occurring spikes
      or time periods of intense spikes over the entire frequency
      range are indicative of telemetry errors.  No attempt has been
      made to remove spikes since some could be valid data, i.e.
      real bursts of wave activity.  The 17.8-Hz channel is sometimes
      contaminated by interference from the PRA instrument, depending
      on that instrument&apos;s mode.  This interference is at a
      relatively constant level.  A failure in the Voyager 2 flight
      data system a few months after launch has decreased the
      sensitivity and the calibration accuracy of the upper 8
      spectrum analyzer channels (i.e.  1 kiloHertz and higher).
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XM-11A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

