<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mpfl-m-asimet-2-3-edr-rdr-edl-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MPFL MARS ATM STRUCT INST AND MET PKG RAW AND CALIB EDL V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_pathfinder::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mpfl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:asimet.mpfl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mpfl-m-asimet-2-3-edr-rdr-edl-v1.0__browserp_mpfl-m-asimet-2-3-edr-rdr-edl-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mpfl-m-asimet-2-3-edr-rdr-edl-v1.0__dvo_atmos_mpfl-m-asimet-2-3-edr-rdr-edl-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Golombek, M.P., R.A. Cook, T. Economou, W.M. Folkner, A.F.C. Haldemann,
                   P.H. Kallemeyn, J.M. Knudsen, R.M. Manning, H.J. Moore, T.J. Parker, R.
                   Rieder, J.T. Schofield, P.H. Smith, and R.M. Vaughan, Overview of the Mars
                   Pathfinder Mission and Assessment of Landing Site Predictions, Science,
                   278, 1743-1748, 1997.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GOLOMBEKETAL1997B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mellstrom, J. and K. Lau, Mars Pathfinder AIM Phasing and Coordinate Frame
                   Document, JPL Document 12103, PF-300-4.0-04, 38 pp., 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MELLSTROM-LAU1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Meyer, Donald, EDL Packet Telemetry Formats, JPL Interoffice Memorandum,
                   DFM 96-XXX, October 11, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MEYER1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SCHOFIELD1996A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SCHOFIELD1996B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SCHOFIELD1997A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Schofield, J.T., J.R. Barnes, D. Crisp, R.M. Haberle, J.A. Magalhaes, J.R.
                   Murphy, A. Seiff, S. Larsen, and G. Wilson, The Mars Pathfinder Atmospheric
                   Structure Investigation/Meteorology (ASI/MET) Experiment, Science, 278,
                   1752-1758, 1997.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SCHOFIELDETAL1997</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Seiff, A., J.E. Tillman, J.R. Murphy, J.T. Schofield, D. Crisp, J.R.
                   Barnes, C.KaBaw, C. Mahoney, J.D. Mihalov, G.R. Wilson, and R. Haberle, The
                   Atmosphere Structure and Meteorology Instrument on the Mars Pathfinder
                   Lander, J. Geophys. Res., 102, 4045-4056, 1997.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SEIFFETAL1997</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Vaughan, R., Mars Pathfinder Project Planetary Constants and Models, JPL
                   Document 12947, PF-100-PMC-01, 136 pp., December, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.VAUGHAN1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MPFL-M-ASIMET-2/3-EDR/RDR-EDL-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MPFL MARS ATM STRUCT INST AND MET PKG RAW AND CALIB EDL V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1998-01-04</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1997-07-04T16:36:50.172Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1997-07-04T18:30:06.190Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JOHN T. SCHOFIELD</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            MPFL MARS ATM STRUCT INST AND MET PKG RAW AND CALIB EDL V1.0
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Mars Pathfinder bounced down and rolled to a stop on the surface
            of Mars on July 4, 1997. It landed in an ancient floodplain in
            the Ares Vallis region of Chryse Planitia at 19.17 degrees North
            latitude, and 33.21 degrees West longitude.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    Mars Pathfinder bounced down and rolled to a stop on the surface
    of Mars on July 4, 1997.  It landed in an ancient floodplain in
    the Ares Vallis region of Chryse Planitia at 19.17 degrees North
    latitude, and 33.21 degrees West longitude.
 
    The Atmospheric Structure Instrument and Meteorology Package
    collected data during six sequential, non-overlapping, time
    intervals while the spacecraft was descending to the surface.
    These intervals are described below:
 
      - Free-fall Data Capture
 
        Commenced as a timed event exactly 15 minutes after Cruise Stage
        separation, at an altitude in excess of 160 kilometers.
 
      - Entry Data Capture
 
        Commenced as a timed event exactly 29 minutes and 30 seconds
        after Cruise Stage separation (hence 30 seconds before the
        defined time of atmospheric entry) coincident with the start of
        the accelerometer-based algorithm to determine the parachute
        mortar firing time.
 
      - Descent Data Capture
 
        Commenced as a timed event exactly 20 seconds after parachute
        mortar firing, coincident with the firing of the group 2
        heatshield separation nuts pyros.
 
      - Terminal Data Capture
 
        Commenced as a timed event exactly 48 seconds after parachute
        mortar firing, coincident with the enabling of the radar
        altimeter transmitter.
 
      - Landing Data Capture
 
        Commenced as a timed event exactly one half second after bridle
        cut pyro firing, coincident with powering off the radar
        altimeter.
 
      - Deployment Data Capture
 
        Commenced as a timed event exactly 60 seconds after bridle cut
        pyro firing, coincident with the start-roll-stop-algorithm
        event, and terminated with the end-of-surface-deployment event.
 
    This table shows the timing of many of the major entry events (table
    taken from [GOLOMBEKETAL1997B]):
 
     Event                       Time       Altitude    Velocity
     -----                       ----       --------    --------
     Cruise stage separation   L - 35 min
     Entry                     L - 5 min     130 km     7470 m/s
     Parachute deployment      L - 134 s     9.4 km     370 m/s, 16g
     Heatshield separation     L - 114 s
     Lander separation         L - 94 s
     Radar ground acquisition  L - 28.7 s    1.6 km     68 m/s
     Airbag inflation          L - 10.1 s    355 m
     Rocket ignition           L - 6.1 s     98 m       61.2 m/s
     Bridle cut                L - 3.8 s     21.5 m
     Landing                   2:58 a.m.     0          14 m/s, 19g
     Roll stop                 L + 2 min
     Deflation                 L + 20 min
     Airbag retracted          L + 74 min
     Petals opened             L + 87 min
 
    The sampling rate of ASI/MET data during EDL was determined
    automatically by the Attitude Information Management system and
    was linked to the EDL phase.
 
    Data were directed to RAM, science EEPROM &amp; critical EEPROM, each
    of which had different sampling rates.  The parameters directed
    to each also varied.  No real-time data were transmitted during
    EDL.
 
    Data type   Parameters  EDL phase and duration (Seconds)  Data Vol
                  x Bits                                      (kBytes)
                        Free-fall Entry Descent Terminal Landing
                            870    210    27      92      60
 
                                   Samples per second
RAM
Accel, 3-axes      3x16      1     32     32      32      32      79.9
Accel., Hsk.      13x16    0.125  0.125  0.125   0.125   0.125     4.3
MET, Sci.         12x16    0.125  0.125    2       2       1      11.5
MET, Hsk.         12x16      0      0    0.25     0.25   0.125     1.0
                                                                  96.7
Science EEPROM
Accel.3-axes       3x16     0.5     8      2       2       8      17.4
Accel., Hsk.      13x16    0.063  0.063  0.063   0.063   0.063     2.1
MET, Sci.          4x16    0.125  0.125    1       1     0.125     2.3
MET, Hsk.         12x16      0      0    0.125   0.125   0.125     0.6
                                                                  22.4
Critical EEPROM
Accel. Z-axis      1x16    0.031    1    0.125   0.125    0.25     0.5
Accel., Hsk.       2x16    0.031  0.031    0       0       0       0.1
                                                                   0.6
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    For details on the format of the EDL telemetry packets, please
    see [MEYER1996].
 
    Three ASI/MET instruments produced data during EDL.  These were
    the science and engineering accelerometers and the MET
    instrument.  The accelerometers each produced identical sets of
    science and housekeeping parameters and the MET instrument
    produced science parameters, housekeeping parameters, and
    Aeroshell Instrumentation Package (AIP) data.
 
    All data records are tagged with a spacecraft clock start count
    and an elapsed time.
 
    Spacecraft Clock Start Count - The value of the spacecraft clock
    at the time the related data were acquired.
 
    Elapsed Time - The elapsed time, in seconds, since a set time.
    In each case, this T=0 time is specified as an SCLK and a UTC
    time.
 
 
    Accelerometer Data
    ------------------
      The accelerometer data files contain measurements of
      acceleration and the gain states of the relevant accelerometer
      at the time the measurement was taken.  While all six
      accelerometer values were stored in ROM and Science EEPROM,
      only the engineering +YZ and science Z axis accelerometer
      values were stored in Critical EEPROM.
 
      Acceleration - There are three engineering and three science
          accelerometers.  Each set of three accelerometers is
          orthogonal.  The engineering accelerometers measure
          acceleration along the +YZ, -YZ, and X axes of the spacecraft.
          (+YZ indicates halfway between the +Y and +Z axes.)  The
          science accelerometers measure acceleration along the X, Y,
          and Z axes.  (See section on Coordinate Systems below.)  The
          raw acceleration values are in raw counts, while the
          calibrated values are in units of Earth gravity,
          9.795433 m/s**2.
 
      Accelerometer Gain Range - The accelerometers can each be set to
          one of three different gain ranges, 0.016g, 0.800g, or 40.0g
          (where g = 1 Earth g, 9.795433 m/s**2).
 
      The following accelerometer housekeeping values were also
      recorded:
 
      Accelerometer First Amplifier Temperature - The first amplifier
          temperature sensor values are provided for each of the six
          accelerometers.  The calibrated measurements are in units of
          degrees Kelvin.
 
      Accelerometer Head Temperature - These values provide the
          temperature of the accelerometer head sensor for each of the
          six accelerometers.  The calibrated values are in units of
          degrees Kelvin.
 
      Accelerometer Multiplexer Temperature - The engineering and
          science accelerometer multiplexer temperature sensor values
          were recorded.  The calibrated values are in units of degrees
          Kelvin.
 
      Accelerometer Volt Reference - These are the values of the 0 Volt,
          -2.5 Volt, and 2.5 Volt references for both the engineering
          and science accelerometers.  The calibrated values are in
          units of Volts.
 
      Accelerometer Volt Reference Temperature - These are the
          temperatures of the +2.5 Volt reference for both the
          engineering and science accelerometers.  The calibrated values
          are in units of degrees Kelvin.
 
      Analog to Digital Converter Temperature - These are the values of
          the engineering and science accelerometer analog-to-digital
          converter temperature sensors.  The calibrated values are in
          units of degrees Kelvin.
 
      Hygrometer Voltage - These are the values of the hygrometer
          sensors for both the science and engineering accelerometers.
          The calibrated values are in units of Volts.
 
 
    MET Data
    --------
      The MET data files contain primarily measurements of
      atmospheric pressure, temperature, and wind.  The following
      science parameters were recorded.
 
      Pressure - The air pressure was measured in two ranges, zero to
          twelve millibars, and six to ten millibars.  Raw values are
          reported as raw counts, and calibrated values as millibars.
 
      Temperature - This was measured by four thermocouples, labeled
          &apos;top&apos;, &apos;middle&apos;, &apos;bottom&apos;, and &apos;descent&apos;.  The top
          thermocouple is located 103.8 cm above the plane of the lander
          petal; the middle and bottom thermocouples are 50.8 and
          27.3 cm above this plane.  The descent thermocouple is located
          just below the wind sensor at the top of the mast.  Calibrated
          units for the temperatures are degrees Kelvin.
 
      Wind Sensor Element Temperature - These are the measured
          temperatures of each of the six wind sensor segments
          (or elements).  Calibrated values are shown in degrees Kelvin.
 
      The following MET housekeeping values were also recorded:
 
      +/-12 Volt Power Supply Voltage - The voltage from the twelve volt
          power supply is provided in units of Volts.
 
      +5 Volt Reference Voltage - The calibrated units for this
          reference voltage are provided in Volts.
 
      +5 Volt ADC - The voltage of the positive five Volt analog to
          digital converter supply, measured in Volts.
 
      -5 Volt ADC - The voltage of the negative five Volt analog to
          digital converter supply, measured in Volts.
 
      Circuit Board Temperature - The temperature of the MET circuit
          board is reported in units of degrees Kelvin.
 
      Wind Sensor Thermocouple Temperature - This is the measured
          temperature of the wind sensor thermocouple.  The calibrated
          values are shown in degrees Kelvin.
 
      Wind Sensor Current - The calibrated current from the wind sensor
          is measured in units of milliamps.
 
      PRT4 Temperature, Drive Current Voltage, and Sensor Voltage - The
          temperature of the mast base isothermal platinum resistance
          thermometer (PRT4) is reported in units of degrees Kelvin.
          Its drive current voltage and sensor voltage are measured in
          Volts.
 
      PRT5 Temperature and Drive Current Voltage - The temperature of
          the pressure sensor platinum resistance thermometer (PRT5) is
          reported in degrees Kelvin, and the drive current voltage in
          units of Volts.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The raw data values in this data set have been converted from
    14-bit binary numbers to ASCII.
 
    The calibrated values have been converted from the raw counts
    from each sensor to engineering units.  The steps used to produce
    the engineering units vary with the type of data, but are all
    described in the &apos;Calibration&apos; section of the ASI/MET instrument
    description.  More information is also available in these
    references: [SCHOFIELD1996A, SCHOFIELD1996B, and SCHOFIELD1997A].
 
 
  Data
  ====
    All of the data in this data set are contained in ASCII tabular
    files, (file extension &apos;.TAB&apos;) with detached PDS labels (file
    extension &apos;.LBL&apos;).  The files are named as follows:
 
    Critical EEPROM Engineering Accelerometer Science Data  C_EACC_S.TAB
    Critical EEPROM Engineering Accelerometer Housekeeping  C_EACC_H.TAB
    Critical EEPROM Science Accelerometer Science Data      C_SACC_S.TAB
    Critical EEPROM Science Accelerometer Housekeeping      C_SACC_H.TAB
 
    Science EEPROM Engineering Accelerometer Science Data   S_EACC_S.TAB
    Science EEPROM Engineering Accelerometer Housekeeping   S_EACC_H.TAB
    Science EEPROM Science Accelerometer Science Data       S_SACC_S.TAB
    Science EEPROM Science Accelerometer Housekeeping       S_SACC_H.TAB
    Science EEPROM FE &amp; DTL MET Science Data                S_MET_S.TAB
    Science EEPROM Descent/Term/Landing MET Housekeeping    SD_MET_H.TAB
 
    RAM Engineering Accelerometer Science Data              R_EACC_S.TAB
    RAM Engineering Accelerometer Housekeeping              R_EACC_H.TAB
    RAM Science Accelerometer Science Data                  R_SACC_S.TAB
    RAM Science Accelerometer Housekeeping                  R_SACC_H.TAB
    RAM Free-fall/Entry MET Science Data                    RF_MET_S.TAB
    RAM Descent/Terminal/Landing MET Science Data           RD_MET_S.TAB
    RAM Descent/Terminal/Landing MET Housekeeping           RD_MET_H.TAB
 
    The tabular files are formatted so that they may be read directly
    into many database management systems (DBMS) or spreadsheet
    programs on various computers.  All fields in the tables are
    separated by commas, and are right justified.  The &apos;start byte&apos;
    and &apos;bytes&apos; values listed in the PDS labels do not include the
    commas between fields.  The records are of fixed length, and the
    last two bytes of each record contain the ASCII carriage return
    and line feed characters.  This allows the tables to be treated
    as fixed length record files on computers that support this file
    type and as normal text files on other computers.
 
    The PDS labels are object-oriented.  The object to which the
    labels refer (the TABLE) is denoted by a statement of the form:
 
        ^object = location
 
    in which the carat character (&apos;^&apos;, also called a pointer in this
    context) indicates that the object starts at the given location.
    For an object located outside the label file (as in this case), the
    location denotes the name of the file containing the object.
    For example:
 
        ^TABLE = &apos;R_SACC_S.TAB&apos;
 
    indicates that the TABLE object is in the file R_SACC_S.TAB, in
    the same directory as the detached label file.
 
    The detached label files are stream format files, with a carriage
    return (ASCII 13) and a line feed character (ASCII 10) at the end
    of each record.  This allows the files to be read by the MacOS,
    DOS, Unix, and VMS operating systems.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    The X, Y, and Z axes of the accelerometers are those of the Mars
    Pathfinder Entry Vehicle Coordinate System.  This coordinate
    system is described by [MELLSTROM&amp;LAU1996].  The coordinate
    system is right handed, orthogonal, and defined by axes Xe, Ye,
    and Ze.  The Xe/Ye plane is defined as the plane of the entry
    vehicle interface pads located at the top of the backshell
    interface plate.
 
    Xe lies in the entry vehicle separation plane (Xe/Ye plane),
    positively directed outward in the entry vehicle separation plane
    from the Ze axis and orthogonal to Ye and Ze.
 
    Ye lies in the Xe/Ye plane and positively directed outward in the
    entry vehicle separation plane outward from the Ze axis toward
    the Star Scanner Assembly (SSA) when the entry vehicle and the
    cruise stage are attached to each other (-Ye passes through the
    interface bushing #1).
 
    Ze is coincident with the nominal spacecraft spin axis, through
    the geometric center of the three interface bushing holes for
    connecting the entry vehicle to the cruise stage, and positively
    directed outward from the spacecraft center of mass towards the
    heatshield.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The MET EDR/RDR tables can be displayed on UNIX, Macintosh, and
    PC platforms as simple ASCII files, or using the PDS developed
    program, NASAView.  This software is freely available from the
    PDS Central Node and may be obtained from their web site at
    http://pds.nasa.gov/.  For more information or help in
    obtaining the software, contact the PDS operator at the following
    address:
 
    Address:     Planetary Data System, PDS Operator
                 Jet Propulsion Laboratory
                 4800 Oak Grove Drive
                 Pasadena, CA 91109
 
    Phone:       (818) 354-4321
    Email:       pds_operator@jpl.nasa.gov
    WWW URL:     http://pds.nasa.gov/
 
 
  Media / Format
  ==============
    The ASI/MET EDL raw and calibrated data will be stored on compact
    disc-read only memory (CD-ROM) media.  The CD will be formatted
    according to ISO-9660 and PDS standards.  The data files will not
    include extended attribute records (XARs), and will therefore not
    be readable on some older VMS operating systems.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The quality of the raw data from the accelerometer and MET
    instruments is good throughout EDL.  There are no gaps, and all
    the planned data were returned to Earth.
 
    The reduced/calibrated data are also complete.  In general, the
    accuracy of calibration is best for the accelerometer and MET
    science parameters, and is less accurate for the housekeeping
    parameters and AIP temperatures.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    The contents of this CD have been peer reviewed by the following
    people:
 
    Lyle Huber       - PDS Atmospheres Node, New Mexico State University
    Julio Magalhaes  - MPF ASI/MET Team, NASA Ames Research Center
    Jim Murphy       - MPF ASI/MET Team &amp; PDS Atmospheres Node, New
                       Mexico State University
    Tim Schofield    - MPF ASI/MET Team Lead, Jet Propulsion Laboratory
    Rob Sullivan     - MPF Participating Scientist, Cornell University
    Betty Sword      - PDS Central Node Data Engineer, Jet Propulsion
                       Laboratory
    John Wilson      - Non-MPF scientist, Geophysical Fluid Dynamics
                       Laboratory/NOAA, Princeton University
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    The accelerometer data are of high quality throughout EDL.
    However both raw and calibrated acceleration measurements for a
    particular accelerometer should not be used for a period of 1
    second following a gain change.  Gain changes produce an
    acceleration pulse which is an artifact of the electronic time
    constant of the sensor.  Gain changes only occur in the science
    accelerometer measurements.
 
    MET science and housekeeping data are also of good quality
    throughout EDL.  Pressure, temperature and wind data accurately
    describe the properties of the appropriate sensors.  However,
    during free-fall and entry, the heatshield is in place and these
    properties are determined less by the atmosphere than by the
    internal lander environment.  After heatshield separation sensor
    properties are influenced both by the atmosphere and the lander
    environment.
 
    Dynamic pressure measurements are most reliable.  The descent
    temperature sensor is exposed for EDL but the exposure is not
    good enough to prevent serious contamination from the lander
    environment so that its results can not readily be converted to
    atmospheric temperature during the parachute descent, terminal or
    landing phases of EDL.  Measurements by the other temperature
    sensors and the wind sensor are essentially meaningless during
    all phases of EDL, as these sensors are designed for operation
    after landing.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    The accelerometer data set has been used to reconstruct the entry
    vehicle trajectory and derive the vertical density, pressure, and
    temperature structure of the atmosphere above 10 km.  In order to
    repeat this analysis various supplementary data, not included in
    this data set, are required.  Such supplementary data include
    spacecraft mass, cross-sectional area and aerodynamic drag
    coefficient, as well as navigation solutions for entry vehicle
    position and velocity relative to Mars immediately before entry.
 
    Although the calibrated MET data are of good quality, only the
    pressure measurement gives good information on the vertical
    profile of the atmosphere during parachute descent for the
    reasons discussed above.  As the pressure is a dynamic
    measurement made through a Pitot tube, it must be corrected for
    atmospheric flow velocity around the lander and orientation
    relative to this flow before it can be converted to static
    atmospheric pressure.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

