<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-e-v-h-sw-epps-3-fips-cdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER E/V/H/SW EPPS CALIBRATED FIPS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:epps.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-sw-epps-3-fips-cdr-v1.0__browserp_mess-e-v-h-sw-epps-3-fips-cdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Andrews, G.B., T.H. Zurbuchen, B.H. Mauk, H. Malcom, L.A. Fisk, G. Gloeckler,
                   G.C. Ho, J.S. Kelley, P.L. Koehn, T.W. LeFevere, S.S. Livi, R.A. Lundgren, and
                   J.M. Raines, The Energetic Particle and Plasma Spectrometer instrument on the
                   MESSENGER spacecraft, Space Science Reviews, 131, 523-556, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ANDREWSETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-E/V/H/SW-EPPS-3-FIPS-CDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESSENGER E/V/H/SW EPPS CALIBRATED FIPS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-05-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-229T19:54:49Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-120T15:08:18Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JIM RAINES</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Jim Raines
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The MESSENGER EPPS calibrated observations consist of energetic
            particle and plasma data collected by the EPPS instrument during
            fly-by and orbital operations of Mercury. Also included are
            cruise observations for calibration purposes.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== This data set consists of the MESSENGER
            Energetic Particle and Plasma Spectrometer (EPPS) calibrated
            observations, also known as CDRs. The system encompasses 2
            instrument subsystems - the Energetic Particle Spectrometer (EPS)
            and the Fast Imaging Plasma Spectrometer (FIPS). This data set
            contains FIPS instrument data. FIPS covers the energy/charge
            range of &lt; 50 eV/q to 20 keV/q. There are five FIPS CDR data
            products.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The data set consists of calibrated observations, also known as
      CDRs.
 
      For all the CDR products there is a detached PDS label file that
      describes the contents of one data file. Each label file will have
      the same base name as the data file it is describing, with the
      extension .LBL to denote a label file. The label file defines the
      start time and end of the observation, product creation time, and
      the structure of the binary (or ASCII) tables. Each data product
      is identified within the PDS label by a STANDARD_DATA_PRODUCT_ID
      value, shown in parentheses in the table below.
 
      The FIPS portion of the data archive currently consists of five
      CDR data products. The following table shows the different FIPS
      data products and their files. Following is a description of each
      of the current FIPS CDRs. A more complete description of each may
      be found in the EPPS CDR SIS document, located in the DOCUMENT
      directory of the document volume.
 
      Additionally, ancillary calibration products, FIPA_*.TAB, are included
      as part of this data set, but reside separately in the Documentation
      Volume (MESSEPPS_DOC) in the CALIBRATION directory.
 
 
      Current FIPS Data Products:
 
        FIPS High Priority Spectra (FIPS_HI_SPECTRA)
 
          Spectra Data file contains flux spectra and proton velocity
          distribution.
 
        FIPS Medium Priority Spectra (FIPS_MED_SPECTRA)
 
          Spectra Data file contains flux spectra and proton velocity
          distribution.
 
        FIPS Pulse Height (FIPS_PULSE_HEIGHT)
 
          Contains FIPS Pulse Height Analysis data.
 
        FIPS SCAN (FIPS_SCAN)
 
          Contains flux spectra. Available only after the FSW6 upload.
 
        FIPS High Resolution Proton Velocity Distribution
        (FIPS_HIRES_PROTON_V)
 
          Contains a 32 x 32 high resolution proton velocity distribution,
          integrated over a 10 scan sequence. Available only after the FSW6
          upload.
 
 
    Instrument Overview
    ===================
      The FIPS sensor consists of an electrostatic analyzer (ESA), located
      at the entrance to the sensor, a post-acceleration chamber between
      the output of the ESA and the carbon foil, and a time-of-flight
      telescope. The ESA at the entrance to the FIPS acts as a wide-angle
      lens for ions. It only allows ions with a specific energy/charge band
      to enter through its output plane.
 
      See the EPPSINST.CAT file for more information and
      [ANDREWSETAL2007] for full details.
 
 
    Calibration Overview
    ====================
 
      This data set is calibrated.  Spectral rates have been converted from
      raw counts to counts/sec and, where possible, to fluxes.  Pulse height
      measurements are reported in calibrated keVs.  See the calibration
      implementation document for details.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      The energy per charge (E/q) tables are programmable as described in
      the CDR SIS document and EDR to CDR calibration document.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      The FIPS CDR data set products are described as follows (the STANDARD_
      DATA_PRODUCT_ID value is given in parentheses). The notes provided
      in brackets give the current status of the data product in version 2
      of the data set.
 
      The High Priority FIPS Spectra CDR (FIPS_HI_SPECTRA_CDR)
      contains flux spectra collected in scan 10 of the 10 scan sequence
      and proton velocity distribution (8x8) for scan 10 of the 10 scan
      sequence.
 
      The Medium Priority FIPS Spectra CDR (FIPS_MED_SPECTRA_CDR)
      contains flux spectra collected in scans 1-9 of the 10 scan sequence
      and proton velocity distribution (8x8) for scans 1-9 of the 10 scan
      sequence.
 
      The FIPS Pulse Height CDR (FIPS_PULSE_HEIGHT_CDR) contains
      FIPS Pulse Height Analysis events collected in scans 1-10 of the
      10 scan sequence.
 
      The FIPS Scan CDR (FIPS_SCAN_CDR) contains Flux spectra collected
      in scans 1-9 of the 10 scan sequence.
 
      The FIPS High Resolution Proton Velocity Distribution
      (FIPS_HIRES_PROTON_V_CDR) contains high resolution proton velocity
      distribution (32x32) for scans 1-10 of the 10 scan sequence.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      The EPPS CDR data are the processed data set released for the
      EPPS.  Data presented here are an accurate representation of the EPPS
      data as received from the spacecraft and have been processed from
      instrument unit to physical unit.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      The EPPS CDR was reviewed internally by the EPPS team prior to
      release to the PDS. PDS also performed an external review of the
      EPPS CDR.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Data reported are the processed data received from the
      spacecraft during the following mission phases: Launch, Earth Cruise,
      Earth Flyby, Venus 1 Cruise, Venus 1 Flyby, Venus 2 Cruise,
      Venus 2 Flyby, Mercury 1 Cruise, Mercury 1 Flyby, Mercury 2 Cruise,
      Mercury 2 Flyby, Mercury 3 Cruise, Mercury 3 Flyby, Mercury 4 Cruise,
      Mercury Orbit, Mercury Orbit Year 2, Mercury Orbit Year 3, Mercury
      Orbit Year 4, and Mercury Orbit Year 5.
      These mission phases are defined as:
 
                             Start time         End time
      Phase Name             Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)
      -----------------    ----------------   ----------------
      Launch               03 Aug 2004 (216)  12 Sep 2004 (256)
      Earth Cruise         13 Sep 2004 (257)  18 Jul 2005 (199)
      Earth Flyby          19 Jul 2005 (200)  16 Aug 2005 (228)
      Venus 1 Cruise       17 Aug 2005 (229)  09 Oct 2006 (282)
      Venus 1 Flyby        10 Oct 2006 (283)  07 Nov 2006 (311)
      Venus 2 Cruise       08 Nov 2006 (312)  22 May 2007 (142)
      Venus 2 Flyby        23 May 2007 (143)  20 Jun 2007 (171)
      Mercury 1 Cruise     21 Jun 2007 (172)  30 Dec 2007 (364)
      Mercury 1 Flyby      31 Dec 2007 (365)  28 Jan 2008 ( 28)
      Mercury 2 Cruise     29 Jan 2008 (029)  21 Sep 2008 (265)
      Mercury 2 Flyby      22 Sep 2008 (266)  20 Oct 2008 (294)
      Mercury 3 Cruise     21 Oct 2008 (295)  15 Sep 2009 (258)
      Mercury 3 Flyby      16 Sep 2009 (259)  14 Oct 2009 (287)
      Mercury 4 Cruise     15 Oct 2009 (288)  03 Mar 2011 (062)
      Mercury Orbit        04 Mar 2011 (063)  17 Mar 2012 (077)
      Mercury Orbit Year 2 18 Mar 2012 (078)  17 Mar 2013 (076)
      Mercury Orbit Year 3 18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)
      Mercury Orbit Year 4 18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)
      Mercury Orbit Year 5 18 Mar 2015 (077)  30 Apr 2015 (120)
 
      No EPPS data were collected during Venus 1 Flyby phases.  The EPPS
      was on for brief periods during the other six mission phases prior to
      Venus 2 Cruise.
 
      During these planned operational periods, the EPS sensor on the EPPS
      did not have high voltage enable, hence no Time-of-flight data and
      only spectra data were collected.  The EPS was turned on for the
      Venus 2 Flyby and to be remained on throughout the remainder of the
      mission phases.  EPPS data were collected during all Mercury Flybys.
 
      EPS High Ion Sector 1 and 5 have malfunction detectors and do not
      produce any data product.
 
      The lowest energy channel (32 to 55 keV) on the High Ion Sector 3
      and 5 have periodic high count that are due to flight software
      interaction with the instrument and should not be used.  User of
      EPS data should consult with the instrument team at JHU/APL to
      verify the quality of specific data in certain time interval prior
      to publication.
 
      On 18 Aug 2008 (231), a new Flight Software (FSW) was uploaded to EPPS.
      This new FSW (v6) enhances the energy resolution for EPS and adds a
      high-resolution proton distribution data packet on FIPS. Description of
      these new data products are included in the FMT file.  In addition, the
      new FSW v6 fixed the data spikes in the EPS data (as mentioned in the
      previous paragraph).
 
      On 18 Aug 2009 (230), another new FSW was uploaded to EPPS.  This new
      FSW (v7) only affects the FIPS data.
 
      In the nominal flight configuration, the FIPS sensor on the EPPS
      field-of-view will not measure the solar wind.  Periodically, the
      spacecraft was rotated such that the FIPS field-of-view can detect
      the nominal radial flowing solar wind.  These periods typically lasted
      less than 3 hours and are identified as:
 
                         Start time         End time
      Phase Name         Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)
      ----------------- ----------------   ----------------
      Earth Cruise      05 Apr 2005 (105)  05 Apr 2005 (105)
      Earth Flyby       02 Aug 2005 (214)  02 Aug 2005 (214)
                        07 Aug 2005 (219)  07 Aug 2005 (219)
      Venus 1 Cruise    27 Feb 2006 (058)  27 Feb 2006 (058)
                        06 Sep 2006 (249)  10 Sep 2006 (253)
      Venus 1 Flyby     No Data
      Venus 2 Cruise    01 Mar 2006 (060)  01 Mar 2006 (060)
 
      A dark count signature was discovered in the FIPS PHA data.
      These counts appear in a time-of-flight -- E/q histogram of PHA
      data as straight tracks in E/q, centered at about 8 different
      time-of-flights.  These dark counts significantly complicate the
      analysis of FIPS PHA data, though not significantly for low mass
      ions (H+, He+ and He2+).  All data since launch is affected.
      This situation has been well characterized by the FIPS team and
      models/algorithms for removing these counts have been developed.
      These algorithms are currently being refined and will be published
      and included in PDS documentation soon.
 
      A small bug was found in FSW v7 which causes only the high order
      4 bits of the wedge, strip and zigzag values are transmitted in
      the data.  This has the effect of reducing the position
      resolution for heavy ions in the FSW v7 data.  A software patch
      which eliminates this bug was uploaded to the spacecraft at 19:15Z on
      16 Dec 2009 (350).
 
      Most of the Mercury 4 cruise phase was spent running flight tests in
      support of the dark counts investigation.  As such, this data is not
      useful for scientific studies.  There are two periods which are
      exceptions, but the instrument was run in somewhat different voltage
      configurations during those periods, so care should be taken during
      data analysis:
 
                         Start time         End time          MCPHV  PAHV
      Phase Name         Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)        (V)    (kV)
      ----------------- ----------------   ----------------   -----  -----
      Mercury 4 cruise  09 Jul 2010 (190) 29 Jul 2010 (210)   -2500  -10.5
      Mercury 4 cruise  01 Nov 2010 (305) 31 Nov 2010 (335)   -2520  -9.5
 
      In orbit (Mercury Orbit phase), FIPS is regularly taken out of
      nominal configuration for various spacecraft operations, such as
      commanded momentum dumps and eclipses, typically prevent possible
      high voltage discharge within FIPS or for power considerations.
      On occasion, the EPPS flight software autonomously takes FIPS out
      of nominal configuration in response to an anomaly.  There
      intervals are marked as bad in the data quality field with a
      value of 1.  (Good data contains a 0 in this field.)
 
     FIPS regularly experiences penetrating radiation which serves as an
     additional noise source in the start and stop single-coincidence rates.
     These counts are identified in start and stop rate spectra as relatively
     constant streaks across the energy spectrum, because they bypass the
     electrostatic analyzer energy selction when they pass through the FIPS
     solid structures to trigger the detectors.  Typically, these signals do
     not occur in double-coincidence and therefore do not affect the science
     data. (That is, they do not generate PHA events or add to the valid
     event or proton rate.) When double-coincidences do occur, they are often
     so short in duration (&lt; 1 min) that they can be ignored in all but the
     most fine time scale analysis. Occasionally, events occur that are of
     sufficient intensity and duration as to make the double coincidence data
     unusable, such as long duration solar energetic particle (SEP) events.
     These events should be excluded from science analysis and are listed in
     the table below.
 
     Start time          End time               Description
     -----------------   -----------------      -----------------------------
     2011-155T11:37:00   2011-161T07:00:00      High intensity SEP event
     2011-155T15:00:00   2011-159T00:00:00      High intensity SEP event
     2011-266T07:00:00   2011-266T12:00:00      High intensity SEP event
     2011-277T01:00:00   2011-278T17:00:00      High intensity SEP event
     2011-308T01:00:00   2011-308T20:00:00      High intensity SEP event
     2012-028T01:00:00   2012-031T09:00:00      High intensity SEP event
     2012-065T10:30:00   2012-071T10:30:00      High intensity SEP event
     2012-148T11:00:00   2012-150T21:00:00      High intensity SEP event
     2012-194T16:40:00   2012-196T05:20:00      High intensity SEP event
 
     As of the 10th PDS delivery, FIPS CDR data has a new quality flag
     system, which  automatically flags SEP events and other issues which
     would affect data quality.  This quality flag is a bit field, with each
     bit set signifying the condition  detailed below:
 
     Flag                               Bit Position        Decimal Value
     ------------------------------     ------------        -------------
     Bad data (reason undefined)         0                      1
     PHA hot pixel*                      1                      2
     Scan hard limit reached*            2                      4
     SEP event                           3                      8
     Start rate anomaly*                 4                     16
     Instrument off                      7                    128
     Bad data (manually marked bad)     15                  32768
 
     Multiple conditions set multiple bits, effectively adding the numbers in
     the value column.  (This is the same as performing a logical OR on the
     binary values.)  For example, if PHA hot pixel and SEP event are both
     set, the flag will have the decimal value 10 (binary: 1010).  If the
     start rate anomaly and scan hard limit reached flags are set in
     addition, the decimal value would be 30 (binary: 11110).
 
     For most science uses, only data with a quality flag value of 0 should
     be used.  However, data with the flags marked with &apos;*&apos; above is often
     usable for science. Users should consult with the instrument team for
     details.
 
     From May-Sept 2013, MCP voltages higher than the nominal -2520V were
     tested on FIPS with a goal of recovering counting efficiency lost
     through use thus far in the mission.  Since the counting efficiency is a
     little different for each of these voltages, users are advised to
     consult the actual MCP voltage stored in housekeeping when using data
     from this period.
 
     An extensive revision of FIPS efficiencies was implemented for delivery
     12. These efficiencies incorporate in-flight from the orbital mission as
     well as ground calibration data.  This release represents a significant
     improvement in the calibration of these CDR values.
 
     During 05-07 Mar 2015, FIPS post-acceleration voltage was raised in
     steps from the 10.5 kV run throughout the orbital mission to 13 kV.
     This change was made to increase time-of-flight resolution and had been
     delayed until the end of mission for risk reduction.  This new voltage
     has been included in the relevant processing in this data set.  However,
     it must also  be included in any user processing which makes use of ion
     total energy in the time-of-flight telescope.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      This data set is minimally processed data.  The data are received
      from the spacecraft telemetry and ingested into the MESSENGER
      Science Operations Center (SOC).
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

