<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ear-a-i0046-3-reddyvesta-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>REDDY VESTA ROTATIONALLY RESOLVED NEAR-INFRARED SPECTRA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.support_archives::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.obs376t3::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:i0046.obs376t3::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.4_vesta::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-a-i0046-3-reddyvesta-v1.0__browserp_ear-a-i0046-3-reddyvesta-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Reddy, V., J.A. Sanchez, J-Y. Li, K. Archer, R.A. Tucker, and 6 others,
                   Photometric, Spectral Phase and Temperature Effects on Vesta and HED
                   Meteorites: Implications for Dawn Mission, Icarus (Submitted), 2011.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.REDDY2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>EAR-A-I0046-3-REDDYVESTA-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>REDDY VESTA ROTATIONALLY RESOLVED NEAR-INFRARED SPECTRA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2011-05-31</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2010-03-27T04:58:17Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2010-03-27T11:22:32Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>VISHNU REDDY</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Reddy, V., Reddy Vesta Rotationally Resolved Near-Infrared
            Spectra V1.0. EAR-A-I0046-3-REDDYVESTA-V1.0. NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2011.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Low resolution rotationally resolved spectra of Vesta, from Reddy
            (2011).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains low-resolution near-infrared (~0.7-2.5
            microns) spectra of main belt asteroid (4) Vesta observed with
            the SpeX instrument on NASA Infrared Telescope Facility (IRTF) on
            Mauna Kea, Hawai&apos;i, and reported in Reddy et al. (2011).
            This data set archives reduced, calibrated spectra that were
            obtained as part of ground-based characterization of Vesta prior
            to the arrival of Dawn spacecraft. They have been used for
            detailed rotationally-resolved mineralogical/compositional
            analysis.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    All spectral observations were obtained using the SpeX instrument on NASA
    IRTF in low-resolution mode. Observations were made remotely and in
    classical mode on site. SpeX in low resolution mode (0.8 arcsecond slit)
    has resolving powers of R~100 across the wavelength region from 0.75 to
    2.5 microns.  An infrared guider is available to guide on calibration
    stars (sidereal rates) and near-Earth asteroids (non-sidereal rates). The
    main spectrograph uses a 1024x1024 Aladdin 3 InSb array and the guider
    uses a 512x512 Aladdin 2 InSb array [RAYNERETAL2004]. Low-resolution
    spectrographs like SpeX are ideal for resolving broad absorption features
    produced by abundant mafic minerals like olivine and pyroxene that make up
    many asteroid surface assemblages. The low resolution prism mode also
    helps in obtaining spectra with higher signal-to-noise-ratios (SNR) and
    asteroids as faint as Vmag~17.5 are routinely observed.
 
    Spectral observations for this data set were made by taking nodded
    spectral image pairs of the target asteroid, local standard star (for
    telluric correction), solar-analog stars, and calibration flat-field and
    argon arc-lamp images. The placement of these stellar observations,
    temporally and spatially on the sky, in relation to the asteroid is
    important for producing good quality spectra. If the atmosphere over Mauna
    Kea is stable throughout the observing run, then the log of the flux
    (apparent magnitude) of the object will decrease linearly with increasing
    air mass. Hence, all objects are typically observed at air masses less
    than 1.5, which corresponds to a zenith angle of less than 50 degrees.
    However, if the atmosphere is unstable over Mauna Kea, whether due to an
    orographic cap cloud or rapid variability of water vapor content, it often
    produces a non-linear magnitude-air mass relationship.
 
    Local (or extinction) standard stars close to the asteroid are observed to
    correct for the terrestrial atmospheric water vapor features. Generally,
    the greater the distance between the local standard star and the asteroid,
    the poorer is the monitoring of the sky conditions for the asteroid.
    During a typical observing run, a local standard star with spectral
    properties similar to our Sun (i.e., G-type, main sequence stars), is
    paired with an asteroid and is observed over a wide air mass range that
    bracket the air mass range of the asteroid observations. These standard
    star observations were used to create an atmospheric model that was then
    used to correct for the telluric water bands. Solar analog stars are
    observed to remove the solar continuum from the asteroid spectrum. The
    solar analog star we used is GSC04914-00950.
 
 
    The spectra were normalized to unity at 1.5 microns by dividing all the
    reflectance values with the reflectance at 1.5 microns. SpeX prism data
    was processed using IDL-based Spextool provided by the NASA IRTF
    [CUSHINGETAL2004]. Vesta has a rotation period of 5.342129760+/-0.00000096
    [DRUMMONDETAL1998] and based on this the relative rotational phases are
    listed below assuming 0 rotation phase for the first observation.
    File Name Rot.Phase
    vesta01.tab 0.00
    vesta02.tab 0.05
    vesta03.tab 0.09
    vesta04.tab 0.13
    vesta05.tab 0.16
    vesta06.tab 0.20
    vesta07.tab 0.30
    vesta08.tab 0.34
    vesta09.tab 0.37
    vesta10.tab 0.41
    vesta11.tab 0.48
    vesta12.tab 0.55
    vesta13.tab 0.64
    vesta14.tab 0.68
    vesta15.tab 0.71
    vesta16.tab 0.75
    vesta17.tab 0.82
    vesta18.tab 0.86
    vesta19.tab 0.92
    vesta20.tab 1.00
    vesta21.tab 1.05
    vesta22.tab 1.09
 
    A pdf file with thumbnail plots of all the spectra is available in the
    document directory for browse purposes.
 
    For further information about these data, see REDDYETAL2011.
 
 
    Cited References
 
    Drummond, J.D., Fugate, R.Q., Christou, J.C., Hege, E.K., Full adaptive
    optics images of Asteroids Ceres and Vesta; Rotational poles and triaxial
    ellipsoid dimensions. Icarus 132 (1), 80-99, 1998.  [DRUMMONDETAL1998]
 
    Cushing, M.C., W.D. Vacca, and J.T. Rayner, Spextool: A spectral
    extraction package for SpeX, a 0.8-5.5 micron cross-dispersed
    spectrograph, PASP 116, 362-376, 2004. [CUSHINGETAL2004]
 
    Rayner, J.T., P. M. Onaka, M. C. Cushing and W. D. Vacca, Four Years of
    Good SpeX, in Ground-based Instrumentation for Astronomy, A. F. M.
    Moorwood and M. Iye, Eds., Proceedings of the SPIE, vol. 5492, pp.
    1498-1509, 2004.  [RAYNERETAL2004]
 
    Reddy, V., J.A. Sanchez, J-Y. Li, K. Archer, R.A. Tucker, and 6 others,
    Photometric, Spectral Phase and Temperature Effects on Vesta and HED
    Meteorites: Implications for Dawn Mission, Icarus (Submitted), 2011.
    [REDDYETAL2011]
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    Uncertainties in spectral parameters for near-IR data are crucial for
    detecting and quantifying surface composition. No systematic variations
    either in reflectance or wavelength  were found in the Spextool data sets.
    The average wavelength resolution of SpeX data reduced with Spextool is
    0.016 microns using the 0.8 arcsecond slit. This is due to spectral
    resolution based on the wavelength calibration. The errors plotted with
    the data are standard errors of the mean. Uncertainties in the data arise
    primarily due to low SNR of the final average spectrum, incomplete
    correction of telluric absorption features, and variable sky/weather
    conditions.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

