<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.go-v-rss-1-tdf-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GALILEO VENUS RANGE FIX RAW DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.galileo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.en::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GO-V-RSS-1-TDF-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GALILEO VENUS RANGE FIX RAW DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2000-01-31</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1990-02-01T11:40:25Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1992-02-15T15:59:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>GALILEO CELESTIAL MECHANICS TEAM</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Anderson, J. D., S. W. Asmar, R. Herrera, P. Priest, and R. A.
            Simpson, Galileo Venus Range Fix Raw Radio Tracking Data,
            GO-V-RSS-1-TDF-V1.0 (GORS_0801 Version 3), NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2000.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw radio tracking data from the Galileo Venus Range Fix
            Observations conducted during the Galileo Venus flyby in 1990.
            Included are one NASA DSN ATDF, media calibration data, and
            documentation.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Raw radio tracking data used to determine the precise distance to
            Venus (and improve knowledge of the Astronomical Unit) from the
            Galileo flyby on 10 February 1990.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
 
      This data set contains raw radio tracking data from the Galileo
      (GLL) Venus Range Fix Observations conducted during the GLL
      Venus flyby centered on 10 February 1990.
 
      The data set includes one NASA Deep Space Network (DSN) Archival
      Tracking Data File (ATDF or TDF), media calibration data, and
      documentation.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      Each 288-byte ATDF data record contains 117 parameters, stored
      at rates of up to 10 records per second.  The parameters include
      outputs from the DSN ranging system, estimates of Doppler
      offsets, estimates of received signal strength, and status
      information on components of the DSN system.  The ATDF is
      described by a Software Interface Specification (SIS), included
      as TRK_2_25.TXT in the DOCUMENT directory of the archival
      volume.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      Radiometric data are received by the DSN Network Operations
      and Control Center (NOCC) Navigation Subsystem (NAV) in the
      form of Intermediate Data Records (IDRs).  These IDRs are
      processed to generate ATDFs.  An ATDF contains all radiometric
      data received from the Deep Space Communications Complexes
      (DSSCs) tracking a single spacecraft for one or more passes
      or days.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      ATDFs contain precise radio range and Doppler measurements made
      between DSN ground stations and a spacecraft.  During the
      Galileo Venus encounter, coded waveforms were transmitted from
      the Earth, relayed by the on-board Galileo telecommunications
      system, and received back on Earth.  Cross correlation between
      the transmitted and received waveforms yielded a measurement
      of the round trip distance, which could then be related to the
      Earth-Venus distance during the flyby.  Doppler shift from the
      same measurements could be interpreted as relative velocity
      along the propagation path.
 
      An ATDF has a file name of the form  ydddeeeX.TDF  where  y
      is the least significant digit of the year and  ddd  is the
      day-of-year for the first ATDF record.  The  eee  gives
      day-of-year for the last data record in the ATDF, and  X  is
      set to  &apos;A&apos;.
 
      Each ATDF is accompanied by a full PDS detached label with name
      ydddeeeX.LBL  which completely describes the contents of the
      ATDF.  The format and contents are also described in
      TRK_2_25.TXT in the DOCUMENT directory of each archival volume.
      Both the ATDF and its label are stored in the TDF directory of
      an archival volume.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
 
      The ancillary files are stored in the CALIB directory.  Each
      ancillary file is accompanied by a detached PDS label having
      the same file name except for the extension &apos;LBL&apos;.
 
      Low-Gain Antenna (LGA) Radiation Pattern
      -----------------------------------------
        The radiation pattern of the low-gain antenna (LGA) is
        described in files LGA1_DL.TAB and LGA1_UL.TAB. These files
        provide the radiation patterns for downlink and uplink,
        respectively.
 
      Media Calibration Files
      -----------------------
        Media calibration files give model and measurement results
        which can be used to correct radiometric tracking data for
        effects of the Earth&apos;s ionosphere and troposphere.  Ionosphere
        Calibration files have names of the form  ydddeeeV.ION  where
        y  is the least significant digit in the year,  ddd  is the
        3-digit day-of-year at the start of the file,  eee  is the
        3-digit year at the end of the file, and V  indicates version
        of the file (&apos;A&apos; is first, &apos;B&apos; is second, etc.).  Troposphere
        Calibration files have file names of the form  ydddeeeV.TRO
        where meanings are the same.  Each file is accompanied by a
        minimal detached PDS label with the name  ydddeeeV.LBL.
        Media Calibration files and labels are ASCII files with
        records delimited by an carriage-return (ASCII13) line-feed
        (ASCII 10) pair.  Files are described by TRK_2_23.TXT in
        the DOCUMENT directory.
 
      Documentation
      -------------
        Text and 59 TIFF files are included to provide users with
        background on the general objectives and procedures for
        Galileo radio Science observations.  The material is from
        Radio Science Handbook, Volume 4, written several years after
        the Venus Range fix data were collected.  The document which
        would have been applicable to the Venus Range Fix data
        acquisition was not available in electronic form when the
        data set was archived.  A detached PDS label HANDBK4.LBL in
        the DOCUMENT directory of the archival volume points to the
        text and TIFF files.  It also gives a complete citation for
        document which does describe the Venus Range fix observation.
        Also included in the DOCUMENT directory are Software
        Interface Specifications (SIS) for the ATDF and Media
        Calibration files and an (incomplete) abstract mentioning the
        Venus Range Fix results.
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      Most data types are not dependent on definition of a coordinate
      system; for those that are, the user should consult the
      appropriate SIS for information.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      Software for parsing, reducing, and analyzing data such as these
      has been developed at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory and
      elsewhere.  Because parsing must be done at the bit level, its
      implementation may be very sensitive to platform and operating
      system.  No parsing has been written and tested on a variety of
      platforms, so none has been included with the archival data set.
      Users are referred to PDS labels and to Software Interface
      Specifications for detailed information on file formats.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The archival data set is written on CD-WO media using GEAR
      software and a Yamaha CRW4260tx writer.  The CD-WO volume
      conforms to ISO 9660 standards.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      There are no known limitations to use of these data, subject to
      signal-to-noise considerations which would be typical for
      systems of this type.
 
 
    Review
    ======
     Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data set,
     key elements of the archive were distributed for preliminary
     review.  These included electronic versions of example PDS
     labels, CATALOG files, and Software Interface Specifications.
     These materials were distributed to PDS personnel and the PDS
     Radio Science advisor.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
     The data covers the Venus encounter period around 10 February
     1990.  There are no known quality issues which would limit use
     of these data other than the normal signal-to-noise constraints.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      None.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

