<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ro-a-rpcies-2-ast1-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ROSETTA-ORBITER STEINS RPCIES 2 AST1 V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.international_rosetta_mission::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.ro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rpcies.ro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.2867_steins::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ro-a-rpcies-2-ast1-v1.0__browserp_ro-a-rpcies-2-ast1-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Burch, J. et al., IES - The ROSETTA Ion and Electron Spectrometer, Space Sci.
                   Rev., 128(1-4), 697-712, Feb. 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BURCHETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>RO-A-RPCIES-2-AST1-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ROSETTA-ORBITER STEINS RPCIES 2 AST1 V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2011-03-16</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2008-07-11T13:27:10.654Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2008-09-06T04:55:03.554Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>BRAD TRANTHAM</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            2013-07-10 SBN:T.Barnes Corrected . RECORD_TYPE = STREAM OBJECT =
            DATA_SET OBJECT = DATA_SET_MISSION END_OBJECT = DATA_SET_MISSION
            OBJECT = DATA_SET_REFERENCE_INFORMATION REFERENCE_KEY_ID =
            BURCHETAL2007 END_OBJECT = DATA_SET_REFERENCE_INFORMATION OBJECT
            = DATA_SET_INFORMATION DATA_SET_NAME =Trantham, B.,
            ROSETTA-ORBITER STEINS RPCIES 2 AST1 V1.0,
            RO-A-RPCIES-2-AST1-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2013
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This dataset contains EDITED RAW DATA of the asteroid Steins
            encounter (AST1). Included are data taken between 11 Jul 2008 and
            06 Sep 2008.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset contains EDITED RAW DATA of the RPCIES instrument
            taken during the asteroid Steins encounter (AST1). Included are
            the data taken between 11 Jul 2008 and 06 Sep 2008.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The following describes the nature of instrument operation
      during the various periods for which IES data are available in
      this submission.  In all cases the data are raw electron and
      ion counts as function of energy, azimuth (direction in the
      instrument symmetry plane) and elevation (angle above or below
      the symmetry plane).
 
      This data set includes data obtained by IES during the period
      11 July 2008 to 6 September 2008 (referred to as the Steins
      flyby period by ESA for reference although instrument operation
      was not continuous during this period).  The period between
      5 July and 1 August 2008 encompassed the active checkout PC8.
 
      Several tests were performed on IES and although the spacecraft
      was in the solar wind during this period IES was able to see
      the solar wind only briefly because of the spacecraft attitude.
 
      The actual flyby of asteroid Steins occurred at 2038 UT
      spacecraft time on 5 September 2008.  IES apparently saw no
      signature of the asteroid nor did it see the solar wind (except
      very briefly during the spacecraft &apos;flip&apos; at about 1840 UT on
      5 September 2008).
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      All Rosetta Plasma Consortium (RPC) data packets are transmitted
      together during downlinks with Rosetta. RPC data are retrieved
      from the Data Distribution System (DDS) at European Space
      Operations Centre (ESOC) to a central RPC data server at
      Imperial College London. Data for IES is copied from the RPC
      central data server by IESGS at Southwest Research Institute.
 
      The pipeline processing software is the IES Ground System
      (IESGS). IESGS extracts IES CCSDS packets from the RPC
      collective data files stored on the RPC central data server at
      Imperial College. These packets are used to build ion and
      electron data products. The data products are grouped by date
      and written out to PDS compliant archive data files. One data
      file is created for each day. IESGS also generates the labels
      for the archive data files. IES science products, archive and
      label files, and limited spectrograms are available to team
      scientists on the IESGS website.
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      In order to determine IES pointing, attitude data for the
      Rosetta spacecraft is obtained through SPICE kernels and
      converted from the J2000 coordinate system to the HGRTN
      coordinate system.  HGRTN is the heliocentric RTN system such
      that the sun-spacecraft vector defines the positive x-axis and
      the positive y-axis is the cross-product of the heliographic
      polar axis and the HGRTN positive x-axis. J2000 is the inertial
      frame defined by the intersection of the Earth mean equator and
      the ecliptic plane at the J2000 epoch of January 1, 2000 at
      noon.
 
      The pointing for each bin of IES is thereafter determined by
      multiplying the converted spacecraft attitude matrix in HGRTN
      by the vector representation of each particle measurement bin.
      The resulting vectors represent the flow of particles through
      the respective particle measurement bins in HGRTN coordinates.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      This dataset is used by the IES science team after processing.
      This is done to ensure that the archived data contains good,
      valid products.
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was examined by the IES science team
      prior to submission to the Planetary Data System (PDS) and was
      then reviewed by PDS and the Rosetta data archive working group.
      The current set is a resubmission after correcting or
      responding to the various RIDs resulting from that review.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      None.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

