<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ear-a-5-ddr-asteroid-spin-vectors-v4.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ASTEROID SPIN VECTORS V4.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.support_archives::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.publit::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:compil.publit::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.asteroid::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-a-5-ddr-asteroid-spin-vectors-v4.0__browserp_ear-a-5-ddr-asteroid-spin-vectors-v4.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Magnusson, P., Pole Determinations of Asteroids, in Asteroids II, edited by
                   R.P. Binzel, T. Gehrels, and M.S. Matthews, pp. 1180-1190, Univ. of Arizona
                   Press, Tucson, 1989.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MAGNUSSON1989</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Magnusson, P., C.-I. Lagerkvist, M. Dahlgren, A. Erikson, M.A. Barucci, I.
                   Belskaya, and M.T. Capria, The Uppsala Asteroid Data Base, In Asteroids,
                   Comets, Meteors, A. Milani, M. Di Martino and A. Cellini, Eds. (Kluwer
                   Academic Publishers, Dordrecht) pp. 471-476, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MAGNUSSONETAL1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>EAR-A-5-DDR-ASTEROID-SPIN-VECTORS-V4.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ASTEROID SPIN VECTORS V4.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1996-03-29</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1932</start_time>
        <stop_time>1995</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>CAROL NEESE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Determinations of asteroid pole orientations, compiled from the
            publshed literature, 1932-1995
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This is a tabulation of determinations of asteroid pole
            orientations gathered from the literature from 1932 through 1995.
            It is an updated (Dec. 1995) version of the tabulation given in
            Magnusson (1989) [MAGNUSSON1989] in the Asteroids II book. For
            more information about the Uppsala Asteroid Database, of which
            this collection is a part, see Magnusson et al. 1993
            [MAGNUSSONETAL1993].
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This is a tabulation of determinations of asteroid pole orientations
    gathered from the literature from 1932 through 1995.  It is an updated
    (Dec. 1995) version of the tabulation given in Magnusson (1989)
    [MAGNUSSON1989] in the Asteroids II book.  For more information about
    the Uppsala Asteroid Database, of which this collection is a part, see
    Magnusson et al. 1993 [MAGNUSSONETAL1993].
 
  Modification History
  --------------------
    This data set was first introduced into PDS under the name &apos;pole&apos; at
    the April 1994 asteroid datasets review.  It was updated under the
    name &apos;pole&apos; at the March 1995 review.  It was then updated under the
    new name &apos;spin&apos; at the March 1996 review.  An update consists of
    adding data on asteroid spin vectors which have been published since
    the last update.
 
    Note that the prefix of the above DATA_SET_ID was changed from &apos;A-5&apos;
    to &apos;EAR-A-5&apos; effective with version 4.0 of this data set.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The data table &apos;spin.tab&apos; contains an entry for each published
    determination of asteroid spin, plus an additional synthesis entry
    for each asteroid for which such a synthesis is warranted.  Each
    entry has fields for the following parameters: asteroid catalog
    number; a code for the type of data used to make the determination;
    four solutions for the asteroid spin direction (including rejection
    flag and pole latitude and longitude); sidereal period; flag for
    shape model; axial ratios; reference code; and notes.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The data have been taken from the published literature and no
    additional processing has been applied.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The data are included in a single ASCII data table, &apos;spin.tab&apos;.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    The data set also includes a table of full references to the original
    papers in which the data were published.  The references file is
    &apos;spinref.tab&apos;.  Each entry in the data table includes a pointer to the
    reference file giving the reference of the original paper for that
    entry.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    This data set is released in the form of ASCII files which may be
    stored on disk or other magnetic medium and which may be distributed
    by ftp, email, real-time access by remote login, or by whatever means
    is most convenient.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    This is a comprehensive tabulation of determinations of asteroid pole
    orientations and senses of rotation.  No weeding out of vague or
    uncertain results has been made.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    This data set underwent formal external review on March 29, 1996.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    The data set includes data on asteroid pole directions published
    through 1995.  Supplementary information on shape models, albedo
    models, and sidereal period is included, but this data set is not
    intended to be a comprehensive compilation of those parameters.  For
    some asteroids, a large number of independent solutions have been
    published, which may not be in agreement with one another.  The data
    set compiler, Per Magnusson, has provided also a synthesis entry where
    possible.  The synthesis entry is estimated to have an accuracy in the
    spin vector of 10 degrees or less.  They were obtained by taking
    averages of the most recent independent results, with weights based on
    the method used and the amount and type of the input data.  This
    procedure is necessarily somewhat subjective and cannot replace a
    careful evaluation of the original results.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    This data set is intended only to collect data reported in the
    published literature on asteroid pole directions.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SUPERSEDED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>GD-11F</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

