<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lro-l-rss-1-tracking-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LRO MOON RADIO SCIENCE RAW TRACKING DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-rss-1-tracking-v1.0__browserp_lro-l-rss-1-tracking-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-rss-1-tracking-v1.0__dvo_geo_lro-l-rss-1-tracking-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Chin, G., et al., Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter Overview: The Instrument Suite
                   and Mission, Space Sci. Rev. 129:391-419, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CHINETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mazarico, E., F.G. Lemoine, S.-C. Han, and D.E. Smith, GLGM-3: A degree-150
                   lunar gravity model from the historical tracking data of NASA Moon orbiters, J.
                   Geophys. Res., 115, E05-001, 14 PP., 2010
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MAZARICOETAL2010</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Pearlman, M., C. Noll, J. McGarry, W. Gurtner, and E. Pavlis, The International
                   Laser Ranging Service, AOGS Advances in Geosciences: Solid Earth, 2008.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PEARLMANETAL2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   R.L. Ricklefs, C.J. Moore, Consolidated Laser Ranging Data Format (CRD), For
                   the ILRS Data Formats and Procedures Working Group, 2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.RICKLEFSETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Smith, D.E., M.T. Zuber, G.B. Jackson, G.A. Neumann,H. Riris, X. Sun, R.S.
                   Zellar, C. Coltharp, J. Connelly, R.B. Katz, I. Kleyner, P. Liiva, A.
                   Matuszeski, E.M. Mazarico, J.F. McGarry, A.-M. Novo-Gradac, M.N. Ott, C.
                   Peters, L.A. Ramos-Izquierdo, L. Ramsey, D.D. Rowlands, S. Schmidt, V.S. Scott
                   III, G.B. Shaw, J.C. Smith, J.-P. Swinski, M.H. Torrence, G. Unger, A.W. Yu,
                   T.W. Zagwodzki, The Lunar Orbiter Laser Altimeter Investigation on the Lunar
                   Reconnaissance Orbiter Mission, Space Science Reviews, 16 May 2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SMITHETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tracking and Acquisition Handbook for the Spaceflight Tracking and Data
                   Network, Revision 5, Space Communications Program, Goddard Space Flight Center,
                   Greenbelt, Maryland, 1990-2006.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.STDN7241990</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LRO-L-RSS-1-TRACKING-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LRO MOON RADIO SCIENCE RAW TRACKING DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2014-12-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2009-06-23</start_time>
        <stop_time>2014-09-30</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID E. SMITH</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Smith, DE, LRO Raw Radio Science Data Products,
            LRO-L-RSS-1-TRACKING-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2010.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw radio science data and ancillary files from the Lunar
            Reconnaissance Orbiter mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains archival raw, partially processed, and
            ancillary/supporting radio science data acquired during the Lunar
            Reconnaissance Orbiter (LRO) mission. The radio observations were
            carried out using the LRO spacecraft and Earth-based stations of
            the commercial Universal Space Network (USN), the Ka-band ground
            station at White Sands, New Mexico (WS1), and the Next Generation
            Satellite Laser Ranging station in Greenbelt, Maryland (NGSLR).
            Additional data were provided by the NASA Deep Space Network
            (DSN) during commissioning. Ongoing participation by the
            International Laser Ranging Service (ILRS) network of stations
            provides further LR data that are processed by the Lunar Orbiter
            Laser Altimeter (LOLA) Science Operations Center (SOC). Of most
            interest are likely to be the Tracking Data Files in the TRK
            directory.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Lunar Reconnaisance Orbiter (LRO) Radio Science (RS) Raw Data
      Archive (RDA) is a time-ordered collection of raw and partially
      processed data collected during the LRO mission to the Moon
      [CHINETAL2007] [SMITHETAL2009].
 
      This data set was collected beginning in June 2009 after the launch
      of LRO.
 
      Radio Doppler and range tracking to the LRO omnidirectional and
      high-gain antennas (HGA) provide the main source of the radio
      science data. The gimbaled HGA also carries a small, coboresighted,
      optical receiver telescope. One-way time-of-flight from the ground to
      the optical receiver using laser pulses provides an alternate tracking
      data type known as Laser Ranging (LR), which is handled jointly by
      the Lunar Orbiter Laser Altimeter (LOLA) Science Operations Center
      (SOC) and the Crustal Dynamics Data Information System (CDDIS).
 
      The data set includes one primary data type, the tracking data
      files, TRKs.
 
      Typical users of these data might analyze range and Doppler
      measurements in TRKs to reconstruct the spacecraft trajectory.
 
      Users may obtain SPICE kernels related to pointing information of the
      solar array and high gain antenna at the JPL NAIF website:
         naif.jpl.nasa.gov/pub/naif/pds/data/lro-l-spice-6-v1.0/
 
    Data
    ====
      The Station Raw Tracking Data (TRK) provides the data required to
      support tracking of the orbiter and generation of orbit and
      mission products. Each ground station (WS1 and the USN stations)
      that supports tracking for the LRO mission will create the data
      in a format identified as the Universal Tracking Data Format
      (UTDF) as defined in the STDN Tracking and Acquisition Handbook
      [STDN7241990]. TRKs are stored in the TRK directory.  File names are
      of the form LSUTDF_SSSSVV_PAD_YYYY_DDD_HHMM.ext,  where
         File Qualifier =&gt; 6 ASCII characters to identify the type of
         UTDF data
           LSUTDF (indicates low-speed UTDF data)
        Spacecraft Designations =&gt; 6 ASCII characters (SSSSVV) to identify
        the spacecraft
           SSSS = Spacecraft ID (0059 for LRO)
           VV = Vehicle ID (01 for LRO)
        Receiver PADID =&gt; 3ASCII characters (PAD) to identify the station
        receiver
        PAD identifier
           188 for the White Sands station
           189 for the Solar Dynamics Observatory (SDO) Backup station
           103 for USPS for USN Dongara
           105 for USHS for USN South Point, Hawaii
           126 for KU1S (or KU2S) for Kiruna, Sweden
           128 for WU1S (or WU2S) for Wilheim, Germany
        Date Information =&gt; 13 ASCII characters in the  form of YYYY_DDD_HHMM
        to represent the date and time of when the station closed the file;
           YYYY = 4 ASCII characters for year (2008 - 2013)
           DDD = 3 ASCII characters for day of year (001 - 366)
           HHMM = 4 ASCII characters (24 Hour time qualifier)
        ext =&gt; 3-character ASCII extension; TRK (default)
 
      The TRK PDS label has file names of the same form as the data files
      with an extension of LBL.
 
    Secondary Data
    ==============
      A set of ancillary files is needed for proper analysis and
      interpretation of the TRK data.
 
      Small Forces File (SFF Directory)
      ---------------------------------
      The Small Forces File (SFF) or Angular Momentum Desaturation (AMD)
      data provides the cumulative delta-V effect of attitude thruster
      firings over one or more specified intervals of time. In some cases
      it also provides an estimate of the cumulative spacecraft mass loss
      due to the use of propellant in those attitude thrusters. The same
      format file is also produced to model predicted accelerations. The
      primary data portion of a SFF consists of required parameters (in
      this order) separated by commas:
        Record index, record type, record generation time, data start
        time, data stop time, data accumulation period duration, mass
        change, resultant delta-V in J2000 X direction, resultant delta-V
        in J2000 Y direction, and resultant delta-V in J2000 Z direction.
      The secondary data portion is optional and consists of additional
      data requested by mission, for LRO this is TBD.
 
      Weather Data Files (WEA Directory)
      ----------------------------------
      The Weather data are ASCII formatted, space-delimited, information
      sent in a file format. Weather data files are produced at the
      ground stations. The file consists of multiple lines in which the
      first line contains start date (YYYYMMDD), Day of Year (DDD), and
      station identifier information.  Then there are 2:N repeating lines
      that provide the following information:
         Time reference, temperature, Pressure, Relative Humidity, and
         Wind Speed
 
      File names have the form STID_YYYYDDD_HHMM.ext, where:
         Station ID =&gt; 4 ASCII Characters for the station ID
           WS1S = White Sands
           USPS = USN Dongara
           USHS = USN Hawaii
           KI3S = Kiruna, Sweden
           WG1S = Wilheim, Germany
         Scheduled Acquisition of Signal (AOS) time =&gt; 12 ASCII characters
         in the form of YYYYDDD_HHMM, where:
           YYYY = start year designator (2008 - 2013)
           DDD = start day of year (001 - 366)
           HHMM = Hours and Minutes of AOS
             HH = (00 - 23)
             MM = (00 - 59)
         ext =&gt; 3-character ASCII extension, WEA (to represent this
         is a weather file).
 
      For example, a file name for a weather product from White Sands:
        WS1S_2009040_0824.WEA
 
      Each WEA file is accompanied by a PDS label file that has a file name
      of the same form as the WEA file with an extension of LBL.
 
      Laser Ranging Files (RANGE Directory)
      -------------------------------------
      The Laser Ranging file contains the LOLA/SOC-processed one-way laser
      ranging fire time from data processing based on the telemetry that LOLA
      receives from the LRO Mission Operations Center (MOC) as part of the
      real-time and post- pass s/c and instrument housekeeping and
      measurement telemetry, and from station dependent fire time files
      retrieved from the Crustal Dynamics Data Information System (CDDIS)
      which contains files from the Next Generation Satellite Laser Ranging
      (NGSLR) and participating International Laser Ranging Service (ILRS)
      laser ranging sites [PEARLMANETAL2008]. The Laser Ranging files are
      ASCII files formatted as defined in [STDN7241990] and ILRS
      Consolidated Laser Ranging Data Format [RICKLEFSETAL2009].
 
 
      Full Rate Files (RANGE/FULL_RATE Directory)
      -------------------------------------------
      Laser Ranging full rate files contain LOLA SOC-processed one-way
      laser ranging fire time.  Full rate data contains every outgoing ground
      station laser shot together with a corresponding LOLA receive signal
      whose pulse width is larger than 10 ns.
 
 
      Normal Point Files (RANGE/NPT Directory)
      ----------------------------------------
      Laser Ranging normal point files contain LOLA SOC-processed one-way
      laser ranging fire time.  After outliers are removed from full-rate
      data, every 5 second interval with more than 5 full-rate points files
      will form one normal point per the procedure described in [SINCLAIR1997].
 
 
      GEODYN Trajectory Files (SPK Directory)
      ---------------------------------------
      GEODYN SPK files are orbit reconstructions produced by the LOLA
      Precise Orbit Determination Team.  They were used for geolocation of
      LOLA data. These files give spacecraft and planetary ephemerides and
      have the same binary format as SPK files generated by the LRO
      Flight Dynamics Team.  Flight Dynamics SPKs can be found at
      naif.jpl.nasa.gov.
 
      Unlike the majority of this data archive, SPKs are a higher level data
      product (level 5.)  The raw data are level 1.  We include SPKs here
      as an example of a higher level product that can be derived from the
      Radio Science Raw Data Archive.
 
      File names have the form LRO_xxxx_yyyymm_model.BSP where xxxx is the
      mission phase including month, where applicable (CO = Commissioning;
      NO_01, NO_02, etc. stand for Nominal Mission, with the number
      corresponding to the month between stationkeeping maneuvers, yyyymm
      gives the date of generation (or version), and model corresponds to
      the gravity model used for the creation of this particular SPK file
      (e.g., GRGM900C_L600 stands for gravity model GRGM900C of degree and
      order 900 with a power law constraint applied for degree L&gt;600
      [LEMOINEETAL2014]).
 
      Each trajectory file is accompanied by a PDS label with file name
      LRO_xxxx_yyyymmdd.LBL.  Typical SPK files comprise one lunar month,
      with gaps during thrusting maneuvers.
 
      Typical file sizes are approximately 30MB with the exception of
      Commissioning, which has a 72MB file size.
 
      The reconstructed LRO trajectory contained in each SPK has been
      created by the LOLA Precision Orbit Determination (POD) Team in an
      effort to refine the trajectory of the spacecraft and to improve the
      Lunar Gravity field based on LRO tracking data [MAZARICOETAL2010].
 
      The data were originally written out by the GEODYN orbit processor at
      five second intervals. They were then converted from the original
      true of date (IAU of date) coordinates to J2000, and then written in
      SPK files (type 8, discrete states, evenly spaced, Lagrange
      Interpolation).
 
      The orbits were produced from an analysis of the Doppler and range
      data supplied by the LRO project. The primary tracking stations are
      the NASA/LRO White Sands S/Ka-band ground station and the Universal
      Space Network (USN) S-band sites. See the Appendix in CATALOG/INST.CAT
      for a list of LRO tracking stations. Altimetric crossovers constructed
      with LOLA data were also used in the POD to help improve the
      trajectory precision.
 
      The various arcs were combined into SPKs spanning one mission phase
      (about a month). Trajectories from consecutive arcs were (linearly)
      tapered during overlap periods. Because the maneuvers (delta-H and
      station-keeping) were not modeled, the SPKs are discontinuous around
      those maneuvers.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      The SPICE (SPK) files use the J2000 reference frame internally, which is
      equivalent to the International Celestial Reference Frame.  They do
      not depend on planetary ephemerides, but rather are relative to the
      Center of Mass (COM) of the Moon.
 
      DE421 is used as the reference ephemeris of the Moon as specified by
      the Project.  Where there is some dependence on coordinate frame in this
      dataset, it would be the DE421.
 
    Software
    ========
      No software is included with the archival data set.  Spice toolkits can
      be downloaded from naif.jpl.nasa.gov.
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      This data set is stored online at the Planetary Data System
      (http://pds.nasa.gov/) and may be downloaded using a web browser
      or FTP software. A copy may be requested on physical media if
      downloading is not possible. The Planetary Data System maintains
      backup copies of this data set on various media.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this archival data set have been collected to support radio
      science investigations, including derivation of the gravity field of
      the Moon.  These are similar to data collected using other spacecraft
      and are believed to be generally of good quality.
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was reviewed by the LRO Radio Science Team, a
      subunit of the Lunar Orbiter Laser Altimeter (LOLA) Team,
      prior to submission to the Planetary Data System (PDS).  Data
      set design, documentation, and sample products have passed a
      PDS peer review.
 
      Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data
      set, key elements of the archive were distributed for
      preliminary review.  These included electronic versions of
      example PDS labels, example data files, CATALOG files, and
      Software Interface Specifications.  These materials were
      distributed to PDS personnel, the experiment investigator,
      and others, as appropriate.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Data set coverage is given by START_TIME and STOP_TIME except for the
      delivery of SPK files, which are derived products.  These may lag
      delivery of tyhe raw data (TRK files).  There is no significant
      variation in data quality with coverage.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

