<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.vex-v-rss-1-ent-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>VEX DSN RADIO SCIENCE RAW DATA-ENT V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.venus_express::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vex::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.vex::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vex-v-rss-1-ent-v1.0__browserp_vex-v-rss-1-ent-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vex-v-rss-1-ent-v1.0__browser_vex-v-rss-1-ent-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mannucci, A.J., B.D. Wilson, D.N. Yuan, C.H. Ho, U.J. Lindqwister, and T.F.
                   Runge, A Global Mapping Technique for GPS-Derived Ionospheric Total Electron
                   Content Measurements, Radio Science, 33, 565-582, 1998.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MANNUCCIETAL1998</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>VEX-V-RSS-1-ENT-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>VEX DSN RADIO SCIENCE RAW DATA-ENT V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2011-02-28</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2007-10-03</start_time>
        <stop_time>2014-12-31</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>RICHARD A. SIMPSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Simpson, R.A., Haeusler, B., and Paetzold, M., Venus Express DSN
            Radio Science Raw Data Archive - Extended Operations Phase,
            VEX-V-RSS-1-ENT-V1.0, USA_NASA_SUE_VXRS_11XX, Stanford
            University, 2013.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw and partially processed DSN radio science data and ancillary
            files from the Extended Operations phase of the Venus Express
            mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains archival raw, partially processed, and
            ancillary/supporting radio science data acquired during the
            Extended Operations (ENT) phase of the Venus Express (VEX)
            mission using ground facilities of the NASA Deep Space Network
            (DSN). This data set will be combined with other data collected
            using antennas of the European Space Agency (ESA) and submitted
            to the ESA Planetary Science Archive. These observations were
            designed to determine the gravity field of Venus; density of the
            upper atmosphere through drag measurements; the
            temperature-pressure and absorption structure of the neutral
            Venus atmosphere; and the electron density profile of the
            ionosphere. No bistatic radar (BSR) and solar conjunction (SCO)
            observations were conducted during the ENT phase because of a 15
            dB degradation in performance of the S-Band radio system in late
            2006 (before ENT began). Of most interest in the ENT archive will
            be the Radio Science Receiver (RSR) files in the RSR directory,
            which provided the raw input to the radio occultation
            investigations of the neutral atmosphere and ionosphere, and the
            Orbit Data Files (ODFs), which provided the raw input to gravity
            and drag investigations. The ENT phase, for purposes of this
            archive, began after the completion of the Routine Operations
            Phase (2007-10-02, the end of the primary mission) and continued
            to the end of the VEX mission.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Venus Express (VEX) Deep Space Network (DSN) Radio Science ENT
      data set is a collection of raw and partially processed data
      collected during the Extended Operations (ENT) phase of the VEX
      mission to Venus.  It has been prepared following standards of the
      NASA Planetary Data System (PDS).
 
      These data were collected using the ground facilities of the NASA
      DSN and will be combined with other data from the European Space
      Agency (ESA) antenna at New Norcia (NNO), Australia, to become the
      formal Venus Express Radio Science (VeRa) Team archive within the
      ESA Planetary Science Archive (PSA).  The VEX data collected using
      DSN facilities during the Extended Operations phase were from
      gravity, atmospheric drag, and radio occultation observations.
 
      The data set comprises several DVD+R (digital versatile disc
      recordable) volumes.  The first volume contains raw and partially
      processed radio science data and ancillary files from 2008 and
      2009.  Subsequent volumes will contain data collected in 2010 and
      later years, in approximately chronological order.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      DSN open-loop Radio Science Receivers (RSRs) down-converted a narrow
      part of the microwave spectrum near the spacecraft transmitting
      frequency.  For the most comprehensive observations, four RSRs were
      used to capture
 
        X-RCP   X-Band (3.6 cm wavelength) right circular polarization
        S-RCP   S-Band (13 cm wavelength) right circular polarization
        X-LCP   X-Band (3.6 cm wavelength) left circular polarization
        S-LCP   X-Band (13 cm wavelength) left circular polarization
 
      The data were saved as time series of complex (16-bit I, 16-bit Q)
      integer samples of the receiver output voltages at (typically) 2000
      samples per second (sps).  Because of the S-Band degradation, which
      occurred in late 2006, the S-RCP RSR was often not used for gravity
      and drag observations.  LCP could have been collected to support
      studies of depolarization by the solar plasma, but no SCO
      observations were scheduled after loss of the S-Band downlink.
 
      Processing of the RSR data was limited to diagnostic tests to
      ensure that the receivers and recording equipment were functioning
      correctly.  Histograms of RSR samples were constructed, averaged
      power spectra were calculated, and time averages of sample values
      (approximating power in the sample stream) were computed.  Each of
      these was plotted and the results can be found in BRO directories
      in each archive volume.
 
      The Tracking and Navigation File (TNF) is the primary output from
      the DSN closed-loop receiver system.  These are large binary files,
      accumulating at the rate of several megabytes (MB) per hour
      of antenna operation.  The files comprise nearly 20 block types,
      each designed to carry data of interest to a particular navigation,
      telecommunications, or science community.  The blocks are
      described by TNF_SIS.TXT in the DOCUMENT directory.  Fields
      include:
 
        Uplink and downlink antenna numbers
        Spacecraft number
        Equipment identifiers, status flags, and calibration values
        Time tags and frequency bands
        Transmitted and received phase and frequency
        Transmitted and received ranging information
        Noise levels, signal-to-noise ratios, and uncertainties
 
      For many applications the TNF is too cumbersome.  The ODF is an
      edited and partially processed version of the TNF.  It is a smaller
      binary file, often issued in 1-3 day increments of about 0.2 MB each.
      It contains the most important information (range and Doppler) needed
      by spacecraft navigators and investigators interested in determining
      gravitational fields of bodies such as Venus.  Each ODF is
      accompanied by a full PDS label which describes both the
      content and format of the associated file.  ODF data fields
      include:
 
           Narrowband spacecraft VLBI, Doppler mode (cycles)
           Narrowband spacecraft VLBI, phase mode (cycles)
           Narrowband quasar VLBI, Doppler mode (cycles)
           Narrowband quasar VLBI, phase mode (cycles)
           Wideband spacecraft VLBI (nanoseconds)
           Wideband quasar VLBI (nanoseconds)
           One-way Doppler (Hertz)
           Two-way Doppler (Hertz)
           Three-way Doppler (Hertz)
           One-way total count phase (cycles)
           Two-way total count phase (cycles)
           Three-way total count phase (cycles)
           PRA planetary operational discrete spectrum range (range
                units)
           SRA planetary operational discrete spectrum range (range
                units)
           RE(GSTDN) range (nanoseconds)
           Azimuth angle (degrees)
           Elevation angle (degrees)
           Hour angle (degrees)           Declination angle (degrees)
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The open-loop raw data have been assembled from individual
      records (packets) into RSR files, which are saved in the archive
      without further processing, except for the diagnostic tests noted
      above, which lead to BRO files.
 
      The RSR data have been Fourier transformed and averaged to create
      BRO files of Postscript &apos;browse&apos; (BRO) plots from which users can
      make quick judgments about data quality and suitability for further
      study.  The plots show (1) histograms of sample values over a
      single file, (2) a sequence of (typically) 3-minute average power
      spectra, and (3) power in sample values averaged over one second
      and plotted versus time.
 
      There has been no processing (and no quick-look checking) of TNF
      or ODF data.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      The raw (RSR and TNF), partially processed (BRO and ODF), and
      ancillary data are organized to fit chronologically onto a set of
      DVD+R volumes.  All data from 2008 and 2009 fit onto the first
      ENT DVD+R volume; subsequent years will be organized onto later
      volumes.
 
      Each scheduled observation is documented by a file in the MFT
      (manifest) directory.  The MFT file lists the date and time of
      the observation and all of the data files that should be
      associated with the observation.
 
      Ancillary data include the following types.  Sources are shown
      parenthetically; &apos;SPICE&apos; denotes kernels for use with the JPL
      Navigation and Ancillary Information Facility (NAIF) &apos;toolkit&apos;.
 
       BCK  spacecraft attitude (SPICE)
       BSP  spacecraft and planetary ephemerides (SPICE)
       DKF  DSN keyword file (DSN)
       ENB  experimenters notebook (Stanford)
       EOP  Earth orientation parameters (JPL)
       FRK  frames kernel (SPICE)
       HEA  VeRa investigation &apos;health&apos; report (Stanford)
       ION  ionosphere media calibration (DSN)
       LSK  leap second kernel (SPICE)
       MFT  file lists for specific experiments (Stanford)
       PCK  planetary constants kernel (SPICE)
       SCK  spacecraft clock conversion file (SPICE)
       TRO  troposphere media calibration (DSN)
       WEA  weather file (DSN)
 
      Note that some files will not be listed in any MFT because they
      were not associated with a scheduled radio science observation;
      for example, monthly spacecraft and planetary ephemerides -- BSP
      files -- may be included in the archive even though there was no
      radio science activity during the month.  Each RSR, BRO, and TNF
      should appear in a single MFT; ODFs can appear in multiple MFTs,
      but only when a single ODF covers more than one radio science
      event (this would be unusual).
 
      The MFT directory includes a list of both primary and ancillary
      data files (see below) for each observation.  Users should be
      able to locate all files by referring to CUMINDEX.TAB in the
      INDEX directory of the final volume of the data set.
 
      Primary Data
      ------------
        Primary data are the measurements which come from the radio
        science &apos;instrument&apos; or products derived directly from those
        measurements.  For purposes of this discussion, the primary
        data types are RSR, BRO, ODF, and TNF.
 
        Radio Science Receiver Files (RSR Directory)
        --------------------------------------------
        Each RSR generates a stream of packets which can be assembled
        into a file of arbitrary length.  Files a little larger than
        500 MB are the maximum that can be easily accommodated in the
        Stanford processing environment (32-bit machines on which the
        next step is conversion of complex integer samples to double
        precision complex).  A typical ENT observation generates RSRs
        no larger than 100 MB; but the first radio occultation in 2008
        was captured using 16000 sps (because of uncertainty about
        receiver tuning) and those RSRs have 316 MB.
 
        Each RSR file has a name of the form  ydddhhMC.RSR  where  y  is
        the one-digit year when the data began;  ddd  is the three-digit
        day of year when the data began;  M  is the one-digit ten-minute
        mark when the data began (0, 1, 2, 3, 4, or 5); and  C  denotes
        the band, polarization, and file version as shown in the table
        below.  The corresponding PDS label file has name  ydddhhMC.LBL.
 
                C Code         Meaning
                ------    ----------------
                   A      X-RCP, version 1
                   B      S-RCP, version 1
                   C      X-LCP, version 1
                   D      S-LCP, version 1
                   E      X-RCP, version 2
                   F      S-RCP, version 2
                   G      X-LCP, version 2
                   H      S-LCP, version 2
                           ...
                   U      X-RCP, version 6
                   V      S-RCP, version 6
                   W      X-LCP, version 6
                   X      S-LCP, version 6
 
        The one-digit year is &apos;8&apos; or &apos;9&apos; for 2008 or 2009, respectively.
        For 2010 the letter &apos;A&apos; is used, for 2011 the letter &apos;B&apos; is used,
        and the substitution continues until &apos;Z&apos; is used for 2035.
 
        Browse Files (BRO Directory)
        ----------------------------
        Browse files are composite PostScript files summarizing quick-look
        processing of RSR data.  Each file has a name of the form
        ydddhhMC.PS1  where  ydddhhMC  is identical to the character string
        in the source RSR file.  Each BRO file is accompanied by a detached
        PDS label with name  ydddhhMC.LBL.  Each PostScript file is sized
        to fit on a single 8-1/2x11 inch page.  Each landscape format page
        includes four panels showing a histogram of raw data (12-bit)
        samples (upper left), three-minute average power spectra derived
        from the raw samples (upper right), one-second averages of raw
        sample power versus time (lower left), and an extract of the first
        few lines of the source RSR PDS label (lower right).  BRO files may
        be helpful in quickly scanning data to determine which files are
        suitable for closer study.  Typical BRO files have volumes 300 kB.
 
        Tracking and Navigation Files (TNF Directory)
        ---------------------------------------------
        TNFs become available within a few hours of the completion of a
        Venus Express pass and are downloaded to Stanford.  TNFs are
        stored in the TNF directory with file names of the form
        ydddHssC.TNF  where  y  is the one-digit year of the first data in
        the file,  ddd  is the three-digit day of year of the first data,
        H  is a letter code for the hour of the first data (see table
        below),  ss  is the DSN antenna number, and  C  is a single letter
        (beginning with &apos;A&apos;) denoting the sequence in which files with the
        same  ydddHss  were received (ydddHssB.TNF  should be a revision of
        ydddHssA.TNF; but revised TNFs have been extremely rare, and there
        may be none in this data set).  The PDS label has file name
        ydddHssC.LBL.  Typical TNFs have volumes 2-20 MB.
 
                     H Code   Start Hour
                     ------   ----------
                        A         00
                        B         01
                        C         02
                        D         03
                        E         04
                        F         05
                        G         06
                        H         07
                        I         08
                        J         09
                        K         10
                        L         11
                        M         12
                        N         13
                        O         14
                        P         15
                        Q         16
                        R         17
                        S         18
                        T         19
                        U         20
                        V         21
                        W         22
                        X         23
 
        Starting in 2010, the one-digit year is a letter, following the
        same convention as was used in naming RSRs (above).
 
        Orbit Data Files (ODF Directory)
        --------------------------------
        ODFs are abstracts of TNFs, often with averaging to reduce the
        sampling rate (1 s is a common default), and with separate files
        for S- and X-Band data.  Keyword ORIGINAL_PRODUCT_ID in the label
        file often includes a string like &apos;S_1S&apos; or &apos;X_1S&apos;, which
        identifies both the band and the averaging interval.
 
        ODFs are stored in the ODF directory with file names of the form
        ydddeeeC.ODF  where  y  is the one-digit year of the first data in
        the file,  ddd  is the day of year of the first data,  eee  is the
        day of year of the last data in the file, and  C  is a single
        letter (beginning with &apos;A&apos;) denoting the sequence in which files
        with the same  ydddeee  were received.  Starting in 2010, the
        one-digit year is a letter, following the same convention as was
        used in naming RSRs (above).  The corresponding label file has
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical ODFs have sizes 150-200 kB.
 
 
      Ancillary Data
      --------------
        An extensive set of ancillary files is needed for proper analysis
        and interpretation of the primary data.  These are organized in
        parallel with the RSR, BRO, TNF, and ODF directories.  Many
        ancillary files are obtained from the JPL Navigation and
        Ancillary Information Facility (NAIF) which has developed a
        software &apos;toolkit&apos; for users.  The toolkit and data files are
        known as the &apos;SPICE&apos; system for describing observation geometry,
        time, and events.  For more information on NAIF and SPICE see
 
                       http://pds-naif.jpl.nasa.gov/
 
        Binary Spacecraft Attitude Kernels (BCK Directory)
        --------------------------------------------------
        Spacecraft attitude files (also known as C kernels or CK files)
        were produced by the VEX Flight Dynamics Team, then converted to
        IEEE binary format.  C kernels represent the &apos;C&apos; in SPICE,
        originally standing for &apos;camera.&apos;
 
        BCK files have names of the form  ydddzeee.BCK  where  y  is the
        one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the
        day-of-year of the first data in the file,  z  is the one-digit
        year of the last data in the file, and  eee  is the day-of-year of
        the last data in the file.
 
        The one-digit year (&apos;y&apos; and &apos;z&apos;) is represented by a letter for
        years starting in 2010, following the same convention as used in
        naming RSR files (above).
 
        Each BCK file is accompanied by a PDS label with file name
        ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are a few MB.
 
        Binary Spacecraft/Planetary Ephemeris Files (BSP Directory)
        -----------------------------------------------------------
        Spacecraft/planetary ephemeris files (also known as SP kernels or
        SPK files) were produced by the VEX Flight Dynamics Team, then
        converted to IEEE binary format.  SP kernels represent the &apos;SP&apos;
        in SPICE.
 
        BSP files have names of the form  ydddeeeC.BSP  where  y  is the
        one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the
        day-of-year of the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year
        of the last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting the
        file sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee  is in
        the data set.  For years starting in 2010, the one-digit year is
        represented by a letter, using the same convention as was used in
        naming RSR files (above).  The eighth character in the file name
        C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with
        increasing numbers of files covering the same days.  Most BSP
        files cover approximately one month and are reconstructed
        spacecraft trajectories merged with the JPL DE405 planetary
        ephemeris.  Each BSP file is accompanied by a PDS label with file
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are a few MB.
 
      DSN Keyword File (DKF Directory)
      --------------------------------
        DSN keyword files contain configuration instructions and commands
        executed by the DSN tracking station during its support of a Venus
        Express pass.  They are ASCII files with variable length records.
        Each record is delimited by an ASCII carriage-return line-feed pair.
        File names have the form  ydddeeeC.DKF  where  y  is the one-digit
        year of the first data,  ddd  is the three-digit day of year of the
        first data,  eee  is the three-digit day of year of the last data,
        and  C  is a letter denoting sequence of the file when  ydddeee  is
        not unique.  For years starting in 2010, the one-digit year is
        represented by a letter, using the same convention as is used in
        naming RSR files (above).  The eighth character in the file name
        C  starts with &apos;A&apos; for the first file, &apos;B&apos; for the second file,
        etc.  Each DKF is accompanied by a PDS label with name
        ydddeeeC.LBL.  DKFs for VEX typically covered a few days and had
        file sizes of a few kB.  Some observations do not have DKFs.
 
      Experimenters Notebook Files (ENB Directory)
      --------------------------------------------
        Experimenters Notebook files are e-mail messages and other
        notes collected during and shortly after data acquisition.
        They document expectations of various measurements and
        anomalies discovered in subsequent analysis.  File names
        have the form  ENBydddC.TXT,  where  y  is the one-digit
        year,  ddd  is the three-digit day-of-year, and  C  is a letter
        denoting sequence of the file when  yddd  is not unique.  For
        years starting in 2010, the one-digit year is represented by a
        letter, using the same convention as was used in naming RSR
        files (above).  The eighth character in the file name  C  starts
        with &apos;A&apos; for the first file, &apos;B&apos; for the second file, etc.  In
        general the messages in file  ENBydddC.TXT  refer to activities
        on that date regardless of when the message was sent.  These
        are ASCII files with variable length records.  Each record
        is delimited by an ASCII carriage-return line-feed pair.
        ENB files have attached labels.
 
      Earth Orientation Parameter Files (EOP Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Earth Orientation Parameter files were produced by the Time
        and Earth Motion Precision Observation (TEMPO) Group at JPL.
        They documented and predicted Earth rotation (rate and axis).
        These are ASCII files of variable length records.  Each
        record is delimited by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).
        File names have the form  ydddzeee.EOP  where  y  is
        the one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is
        the day-of-year of the first data in the file,  z  is the
        one-digit year of the last data, and  eee  is the day-of-year
        of the last data in the file.  Starting in 2010, the one-digit
        year (&apos;y&apos; and &apos;z&apos;) is represented by a letter, using the
        same convention as was used in naming RSR files (above).
        There are both &apos;long&apos; and &apos;short&apos; EOPs.  The long file covered
        past motion since about 1962 and a prediction for about three
        months into the future; these files have typical sizes of 1 MB.
        The short file covered the most recent nine months of past
        motion and a prediction for three months into the future; these
        files are typically 30 kB.  Each EOP file is accompanied by a
        PDS label with file name  ydddzeee.LBL.
 
        Frames Kernels (FRK Directory)
        ------------------------------
        Frames kernels were produced by the JPL/PDS Navigation Ancillary
        Information Facility (NAIF) for use with NAIF-developed software.
        They specify coordinate frames defined for the VEX mission
        including the spacecraft and many instruments.  These are ASCII
        files of variable length records.  Each record is delimited by an
        ASCII carriage-return line-feed pair, which may need to be
        converted to either a carriage-return or line-feed alone before
        the file is used on the local machine.  Two files are included
        in the archive; one is mission independent, but intended for
        use with ESA missions; the other is VEX-specific. Each is
        accompanied by a PDS label file.
 
        Daily Health Report Files (HEA Directory)
        ---------------------------------------------------
        Daily Health Report Files were created at Stanford; they summarize
        analyses performed on recently acquired open loop radio science
        data, summarize collection of closed loop data, and note any
        anomalies found.  They were issued irregularly, usually when new
        data became available.  HEA files are PDS TEXT objects; each has
        an attached PDS label.
 
        File names have the form  HEAydddC.TXT  where  y  is the one-digit
        year of the report,  ddd  is the three-digit day-of-year of the
        report,  and  C  is a character denoting sequence when more than
        one report or version of the file was issued in a day.  Starting
        in 2010, the one-digit year is represented by a letter, following
        the same convention as was used in naming RSR files (above).  The
        first report on a day would be  HEAydddA.TXT;  subsequent versions
        would be HEAydddB.TXT,  HEAydddC.TXT,  etc.
 
        Occasionally HEA files are accompanied by plots, saved as
        Postscript files.  File names for these plot files have names of
        the form  HEAydddC.PSn  where  y  and  ddd  are as defined above
        and  n  is the figure number.  The PostScript files are
        accompanied by a detached PDS label with name  HEAydddC.LBL.
 
        Both Health Reports themselves and accompanying PostScript files
        have variable length records delimited by carriage-return
        line-feed pairs.
 
        Ionosphere Calibration Files (ION Directory)
        ---------------------------------------------------
        Ionosphere Calibration files were produced by the Tracking System
        Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL.  They documented and
        predicted Earth ionospheric conditions.  Global Ionosphere Map
        (GIM) software created daily maps from Global Positioning System
        (GPS) data. Each day, a final map was created for the UT day
        three days previously and a preliminary map was created for the
        UT day immediately before.  Also created were predict maps a
        couple times a week by averaging recent &apos;normal&apos; days.  Then the
        software evaluated the maps at the spacecraft line-of-sight and
        fitted the results to a normalized polynomial versus time over
        each spacecraft pass.  This was done for all three modes: final,
        preliminary, and predict.  Then the software selected the best
        available calibration for each pass (in priority order final &gt;
        preliminary &gt; predict).  An operator ran a plotting program to
        view all of the calibrations and overrode the default selections
        where desired.  The mapping technique is described by
        [MANNUCCIETAL1998].
 
        ION files are ASCII files of variable length records.  Each
        record is delimited by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).  File
        names have the form  ydddeeeC.ION  where components of the name
        are the same as for BSP files.  ION files were usually released
        at one week intervals to cover a single month; only final files
        covering a full month are included in this archive.  Each ION
        file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are approximately 60 kB.
 
        TSAC did not usually produce ION files for Venus Express.
        Instead, files created to support the Mars Express mission have
        been substituted where VEX files were not available.  These can
        can be identified by ORIGINAL_PRODUCT_ID values starting with
        &apos;gimcal_41&apos; in the PDS label.
 
        Manifest Files (MFT Directory)
        ------------------------------
        For each scheduled radio science observation a file in the MFT
        directory lists all of the primary data files generated and all
        of the ancillary files that should be associated with the
        observation.  File names are given for both the original
        (Stanford) archive and for the archive that will be created by
        the VeRa Team and submitted to the PSA.  MFT files are ASCII
        text files, having variable length records delimited by ASCII
        carriage-return line-feed pairs; they have attached PDS labels.
 
        File names are of the form  ydddHssC.MFT  where  y  is the
        one-digit year of the observation,  ddd  is the three-digit day
        of year,  H  is a letter code giving the hour on which the
        observation began,  ss  is the DSN station number,  and  C  is
        a letter indicating the sequence of the file in case there is
        more than one with  ydddHss  (&apos;A&apos; first, &apos;B&apos; second, etc.).
        Starting in 2010, the one-digit year was represented by a letter,
        following the same convention as was used in naming RSR files
        (above).  The meaning of the  H  code is given here:
 
                     H Code   Start Hour
                     ------   ----------
                        A         00
                        B         01
                        C         02
                        D         03
                        E         04
                        F         05
                        G         06
                        H         07
                        I         08
                        J         09
                        K         10
                        L         11
                        M         12
                        N         13
                        O         14
                        P         15
                        Q         16
                        R         17
                        S         18
                        T         19
                        U         20
                        V         21
                        W         22
                        X         23
 
        Planetary Constants Kernels (PCK Directory)
        -------------------------------------------
        Planetary constants files were produced by JPL/NAIF for use with
        NAIF developed software.  The Planetary Constants file included
        in this archive was issued for the Mars Global Surveyor (MGS)
        project.  The archive includes MGS files because those required
        no modifications to Stanford software, parts of which were being
        used simultaneously by other missions.  PCK files are ASCII files
        of variable length records.  Each record is delimited by an ASCII
        carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10),
        which may need to be converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt; before the
        file is used on the local machine.  File names have the form
        TPCnnnnZ.PCK  where  nnnn  is the sequence number in which the
        file was released and  Z  is a character denoting sub-sequence
        when there was more than one file with the same  nnnn.  Z  starts
        from &apos;A&apos;  and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc.  Planetary Constants
        files are accompanied by PDS label files having names
        TPCnnnnZ.LBL.
 
        Spacecraft Clock Kernels (SCK Directory)
        ----------------------------------------
        Spacecraft clock conversion files were produced by JPL/NAIF for
        use with NAIF software.  These are ASCII files of variable length
        records.  Each record is delimited by an ASCII carriage-return
        &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10), which may need to
        be converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt; before the file is used on the
        local machine.  File names have the form  TSCydddZ.SCK where  y
        is the one-digit year in which the file was created,  ddd  is the
        day-of-year, and  Z  is a character denoting sub-sequence when
        there was more than one file with the same  yddd.  Starting in
        2010, the one-digit year was represented by a letter, following
        the convention used in naming RSR files (above).  Z  starts from
        &apos;A&apos;  and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc.  Each Spacecraft Clock
        Kernel is accompanied by PDS label file having name  TSCnnnnZ.LBL.
 
        Troposphere Calibration Files (TRO Directory)
        ---------------------------------------------
        Troposphere Calibration files were produced by the Tracking System
        Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL.  They documented and
        predicted Earth tropospheric conditions based on measurements
        made using Global Positioning System (GPS) satellites.  These are
        ASCII files of variable length records.  Each record is delimited by
        an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).  File names have the form
        ydddeeeC.TRO  where the file name components are the same as for BSP
        files (above).  TRO files included in this archive typically covered
        one month and were released early in the following month; since no
        TRO files were created by TSAC for VEX, Mars Express files have been
        substituted.  Each TRO file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label
        with file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are 240 kB.
 
        DSN Weather Files (WEA Directory)
        ---------------------------------
        DSN Weather files were produced by the Tracking System Analytic
        Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL.  Files give meteorological
        conditions at a DSN complex in 30 minute time steps. These are
        ASCII files of variable length records.  Each record is delimited
        by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).  File names have the form
        ydddeeeD.WEA  where  y  is the one-digit year of the first data in
        the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of the first data in the file,
        eee  is the day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  D  is a
        single digit denoting the DSN complex at which the data were
        acquired (&apos;1&apos; for Goldstone, &apos;4&apos; for Canberra, or &apos;6&apos; for Madrid).
        Starting in 2010, the one-digit year was repesented by a letter,
        following the same convention as was used in naming RSR files
        (above).  WEA files were typically released weekly and contain all
        weather data for the complex since 1 January.  Each WEA file is
        accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.
        The files grow at the rate of approximately 90 kB per month.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      NAIF toolkit routines can be used to make coordinate transformations
      when SPICE files provide the ephemeris and attitude information.
      Otherwise, the data are not dependent on the definition of a
      coordinate system.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      Software for parsing, reducing, and analyzing data such as these has
      been developed at Stanford University and elsewhere.  Because such
      software must usually operate at the bit level and is written for a
      narrow range of platforms, it is not suitable for general
      distribution.  No software is included with this archival data set.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The archival data set was written on DVD+R media using a Dell
      computer running the Windows XP operating system, DiscJuggler
      application software, and a PlexTor PC-712A writer.  The volumes
      conform to the &apos;UDF ISO 9660 Bridge&apos; standard.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this archival data set have been processed as part of health
      monitoring and preliminary analysis activities of VEX Radio Science
      Team members at Stanford University.  In general, this is believed
      to be a good data set.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was reviewed by the VEX Radio Science Team
      members at Stanford University.  It was then used as the basis for a
      slightly different archive (different file names and repeated
      ancillary data for each primary observation) submitted to the VeRa
      Deputy Principal Investigator, who in turn combined it with data
      obtained from the ESA tracking station at New Norcia and submitted
      the result to the ESA Planetary Science Archive (PSA).
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Data are from gravity, atmospheric drag, and radio occultation
      observations as listed below:
 
         Date    DOY DSS Observation Band/Polns RSR ksps    Notes (0)
      ---------- --- --- ----------- ---------- -------- ---------------
      2008-01-31 031  43 Occultation   S/X RCP    2,16
      2008-02-02 033  43 Occultation   S/X RCP    2, 8
      2008-02-04 035  43 Occultation   S/X RCP    2, 8
      2008-08-01 214  43 Occn + Drag   X RCP      2, 8          (1)
      2008-08-02 215  43 Occn + Drag   X RCP      2, 8          (1)
      2008-08-06 219  45 Drag          X RCP      2, 8          (1)
      2008-08-08 221  45 Drag          X RCP        2
      2008-08-09 222  45 Drag          X RCP        2
      2008-08-18 231  45 Drag          X RCP      2, 8
      2008-08-20 233  45 Drag          X RCP      2, 8
      2008-08-22 235  45 Drag          X RCP        2
      2008-11-04 309  45 Occultation   X RCP                    (2)
      2008-11-16 321  43 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2008-12-08 343  43 Occultation   X RCP        2           (3)
      2008-12-26 361  43 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2009-04-20 110  43 Gravity       X RCP        2
      2009-04-27 117  43 Gravity       X RCP        2
      2009-04-29 119  43 Gravity       X RCP        2
      2009-05-01 121  43 Gravity       X RCP        2
      2009-05-25 145  43 Gravity       X RCP        2
      2009-05-27 147  43 Gravity       X RCP        2
      2009-05-29 149  43 Gravity       X RCP        2
      2009-05-31 151  43 Gravity       X RCP        2
      2009-06-27 178  43 Gravity       S/X RCP      2
      2009-06-29 180  43 Gravity       S/X RCP      2
      2009-07-01 182  43 Gravity       S/X RCP      2
      2010-02-22 053  43 Drag          X RCP        2
      2010-02-24 055  43 Drag          X RCP        2
      2010-02-25 056  43 Drag          X RCP        2
      2010-02-26 057  43 Drag          X RCP        2
      2010-02-28 059  43 Drag          X RCP        2
      2010-06-14 165  34 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2010-06-16 167  34 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2010-06-26 177  34 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2010-06-28 179  45 Occultation   S/X RCP      2           (4)
      2010-07-01 182  45 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2010-07-02 183  45 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2010-07-03 184  45 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2010-07-04 185  34 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2010-07-05 186  34 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2010-07-07 188  34 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2010-07-08 189  45 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2010-07-09 190  43 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2010-07-10 191  43 Occultation   S/X RCP      2           (5)
      2010-07-11 192  45 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2010-10-17 290  45 Drag          X RCP                    (2)
      2010-10-18 291  45 Drag          X RCP                    (2)
      2010-10-19 292  34 Drag          X RCP                    (2)
      2011-01-17 017  45 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2011-01-19 019  45 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2011-01-22 022  34 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2011-01-26 026  45 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2011-02-10 041  43 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2011-03-05 064  34 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2011-03-10 069  34 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2011-03-14 073  45 Occultation   S/X RCP                  (2)
      2011-03-21 080  45 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2011-03-22 081  45 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2011-05-24 144  43 Drag          X   RCP      2
      2011-05-26 146  43 Drag          X   RCP      2
      2011-05-28 148  43 Drag          X   RCP      2
      2011-05-30 150  43 Drag          X   RCP      2
      2011-06-01 152  43 Drag          X   RCP      2
      2011-06-03 154  43 Drag          X   RCP      2
      2011-06-14 165  45 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2011-06-15 166  43 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2011-06-16 167  43 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2011-06-18 169  43 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2011-06-20 171  43 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2011-06-23 174  45 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2011-06-25 176  43 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2011-07-01 182  34 Occultation   S/X RCP      2
      2011-09-17 260  43 Drag          S/X RCP      2
      2011-09-19 262  43 Drag          S/X RCP      2
      2011-09-23 266  43 Drag          S/X RCP      2
 
 
      2012-01-14 014  43 Drag          S/X RCP      2           (6)
 
 
      2012-01-15 015  43 Drag          S/X RCP      2
 
 
      2012-01-16 016  43 Drag          S/X RCP      2
 
 
      2012-01-17 017  43 Drag          S/X RCP      2
 
 
      2012-01-18 018  43 Drag          S/X RCP      2
 
 
      2012-01-19 019  43 Drag          S/X RCP      2
      2012
 
-12-04 339  45 Drag          S/X RCP      2
      2012
 
-12-06 341  45 Drag          S/X RCP      2
      2012
 
-12-08 343  45 Drag          S/X RCP      2
      2012
 
-12-10 345  45 Drag          S/X RCP      2
      2012
 
-12-14 349  45 Drag          S/X RCP      2
 
      Notes:
      (0) All S-Band data were degraded by approximately 15 dB relative
          to design following a spacecraft radio sub-system failure in
          late 2006.
      (1) The early &apos;drag&apos; measurements were compromised by grazing
          occultations and difficulty in acquiring 2-way tracking.  The
          data did not prove to be useful for either occultation or drag
          analysis.
      (2) ODF and TNF X-RCP data only.
      (3) No S-Band enabled on the spacecraft, no signal received at DSN
      (4) Failed; ground station &apos;red&apos;
      (5) Radio occultation ingress, but not egress (not enough time)
      (6) Complex-wide power failure; little or no good data
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The limitations in this data set follow from the quality of
      the execution, which is described above under Data Coverage
      and Quality.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

