<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.near-a-msi-5-eros-shape-models-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>NEAR MSI SHAPE MODEL FOR 433 EROS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.near_earth_asteroid_rendezvous::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.near::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:msi.near::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.eros::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.near-a-msi-5-eros-shape-models-v1.0__browserp_near-a-msi-5-eros-shape-models-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.THOMASETAL2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>NEAR-A-MSI-5-EROS-SHAPE-MODELS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>NEAR MSI SHAPE MODEL FOR 433 EROS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2001-09-30</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1996-02-17</start_time>
        <stop_time>2001-02-14</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>BRIAN CARCICH</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Thomas P.C., J. Joseph, B.T. Carcich, A.C. Raugh, NEAR MSI SHAPE
            MODEL FOR 433 EROS V1.0, NEAR-A-MSI-5-EROS-SHAPE-MODELS-V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 2001.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set consists of a shape model, in varying resolutions
            and formats, of the surface of 433 Eros, derived from
            observations made by the NEAR Multi-Spectral Imager (MSI)
            instrument.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains the Peter Thomas shape model for asteroid
            433 Eros, based on optical data from the NEAR MSI instrument.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
        This data set contains the Peter Thomas shape model for
        asteroid 433 Eros, based on optical data from the NEAR
        MSI instrument.  The current version of this data set contains
        the following shape model files and PRODUCT_ID&apos;s
 
        eros_2001012_001708.tab       PLATE-EROS-2001012-001708
        eros_2001012_007790.tab       PLATE-EROS-2001012-007790
        eros_2001012_010152.tab       PLATE-EROS-2001012-010152
        eros_2001012_022540.tab       PLATE-EROS-2001012-022540
        eros_2001012_088398.tab       PLATE-EROS-2001012-088398
        eros_2001012_200700.tab       PLATE-EROS-2001012-200700
        erosrgst_2001012.tab          RGST-EROS-2001012
 
        Each shape model file also has a detached label file, with a
        suffix of .lbl, which describes the respective formats.
 
        The first six files are in a plate model format and only
        represent the model shape.  The last file is in a modified
        Peter Thomas RGST model format and includes shape, gravity,
        slope and topograpic information.
 
        N.B.:  In the RGST-EROS-2001012 product, some radii starting from
        the model center intersect the surface in more than one point.
        This happens mostly around 160 degrees west longitude.  That means
        that the RGST format used in that product is not able to adequately
        represent the shape model&apos;s surface.  Caveat emptor.  If this is an
        issue, users may use one of the plate models.
 
        The plate file naming convention uses three fields, separated by
        underscores:  the first field is the target, eros; the second
        field represents the version of the base shape model, 2001012;
        the third field gives the number of plates in that file&apos;s
        representation of the base shape model.
 
        All files represent the same Eros shape model (2001012)
        only the resolution and format changes between files.
 
        These shape models are distinct from the Peter Thomas shape
        models based on optical data from other sources, included
        in a separate data set:  EAR-A-5-DDR-SHAPE-MODELS-V2.0.
 
        These shape models are also distinct from the shape models
        based on radar observations, included in a separate
        data set:  EAR-A-5-DDR-RADARSHAPE-MODELS-V1.0.
 
 
      Parameters
      ==========
        A single data table contains both the cartesian coordinates
        of the vertices and the list of vertices defining
        triangular facets.  Details of mapping and production of the
        model are given in the Processing section below, and
        further details are given in the relevant published paper.
        [THOMASETAL2001].
 
 
      Processing
      ==========
        Shape model derived via stereogrammetry of 1,888 NEAR MSI
        images.  The model is based on 31,532 observations of 6,328
        control points.  The actual plate models have triangular
        plates, with  vertices interpolated from the control
        points.  To transform the set of individual coordinates of
        control points into these plate model files, we make use of
        software internally called &apos;WaG,&apos; currently being developed
        by Applied Research Associates NZ Limited.
 
 
      Coordinate System
      =================
        The 433 Eros body-fixed planetocentric coordinate system is
        defined as follows:
 
        North Spin Pole with respect to the J2000 reference frame:
 
          RA = 11.350 Dec = 17.216, +/- 0.02 degrees
 
        Prime Meridian:
 
          W = 326.027 + 1639.38864745 d, degrees
 
          (d in days after the J2000 epoch, JD 2451545.0)
 
        The body-fixed ``Planetocentric&apos;&apos; coordinate system referred to
        here is defined for solar system bodies as follows:
 
         --   The x-axis of the Planetocentric coordinate system for a
              specified body lies both in the body&apos;s equatorial plane and
              in the plane containing the body&apos;s prime meridian.
 
         --   The z-axis is parallel to the body&apos;s mean axis of rotation
              and points North of the invariable plane of the solar system
              (regardless of the body&apos;s spin direction). The north pole is
              this pole of rotation.
 
         --   The y-axis is defined as the cross product of the z and x
              axes, in that order. Thus, the frame is right-handed.
 
        The above definition implies that the axes of a planetocentric
        system are time-varying. Thus a complete specification of the
        axes requires identification of an epoch as well as the body.
        This frame is relative to J2000.
 
 
      Software
      ========
        The plate model format is compatible with software developed
        at Cornell.  The two packages are POINTS, written by Jonathan
        Joseph, which is used to collect and solve for the control
        points that are the basis for the shape model, and ORBIT,
        written by Brian Carcich, which used the model to aid science
        planners when they created the sequences of images during
        the NEAR mission.  None of these software packages will
        be archived with these shape models.
 
 
      Media/Format
      ============
        These data are included as part of the NEAR mission archive,
        and are also available for Internet download.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
      Confidence Level Overview
      =========================
        The center of figure is within 50 m of the center of mass
        provided by the NEAR Navigation team at JPL.
 
        The control point RMS error is less than 10 m.  The error
        at any point on the surface is typically less than 50 m.
 
 
      Review
      ======
        External review of the NEAR mission archive, including this
        data set, was peformed in August, 2001.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>DVD-R</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>1996-008A-01A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

