<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mgn-v-rss-1-rocc-v2.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MAGELLAN RADIO OCCULTATION RAW DATA RECORDS V2.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.magellan::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mgn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.mgn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgn-v-rss-1-rocc-v2.0__browserp_mgn-v-rss-1-rocc-v2.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hinson, D.P., and J.M. Jenkins, Magellan Radio Occultation Measurements of
                   Atmospheric Waves on Venus, Icarus, 114, 310-327, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HINSON-JENKINS1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Jenkins, J.M., P.G. Steffes, D.P. Hinson, J.D. Twicken, and G.L. Tyler, Radio
                   Occultation Studies of the Venus Atmosphere with the Magellan Spacecraft: 2.
                   Results from the October 1991 Experiments, Icarus, 110, 79-94, 1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JENKINSETAL1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Steffes, P.G., J.M. Jenkins, R.S. Austin, S.W. Asmar, D.T. Lyons, E.H. Seale,
                   and G.L. Tyler, Radio Occultation Studies of the Venus Atmosphere with the
                   Magellan Spacecraft: 1. Experimental Description and Performance, Icarus, 110,
                   71-78, 1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.STEFFESETAL1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MGN-V-RSS-1-ROCC-V2.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MAGELLAN RADIO OCCULTATION RAW DATA RECORDS V2.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1996-06-30</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1991-10-05</start_time>
        <stop_time>1994-10-12</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>RICHARD A. SIMPSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            RICHARD A. SIMPSON, MAGELLAN RADIO OCCULTATION RAW DATA RECORDS
            V2.0, MGN-V-RSS-1-ROCC-V2.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 1996
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            MAGELLAN RADIO OCCULTATION RAW DATA ARCHIVE
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Magellan (MGN) Radio Occultation (ROCC) Raw Data Archive
            (RDA) is a time-ordered collection of raw and partially processed
            data from radio occultation experiments conducted using the
            Magellan spacecraft while it orbited Venus.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Magellan (MGN) Radio Occultation (ROCC) Raw Data Archive
      (RDA) is a time-ordered collection of raw and partially
      processed data from radio occultation experiments conducted
      using the Magellan spacecraft while it orbited Venus.
 
      The spacecraft radio system was used as the signal source.  The
      spacecraft high-gain antenna (HGA) beamed those signals through
      the atmosphere of Venus toward Earth, where they were received
      at stations of the NASA Deep Space Network (DSN).  Changes in
      the amplitude and frequency of the received signal can be
      related to the refracting and absorbing properties of the
      atmosphere as a function of raypath penetration depth.  These
      parameters can then be inverted to give the temperature and
      pressure structure and the density of absorbing species in the
      atmosphere.
 
      Transmit polarization along the boresight of the spacecraft
      antenna was linear at the S-band wavelength (13 cm, or 2298
      MHz) and circular at the X-band wavelength (3.5 cm, or 8415
      MHz).  Signals could be received coherently in both right- and
      left-circular polarizations at both wavelengths when a 70-m
      antenna was used at the DSN station.  When a 34-m antenna was
      used, only a single polarization at each wavelength could be
      received; and, in some cases, only one wavelength was captured.
 
      During these experiments, frequency of the spacecraft
      transmitter was controlled by a signal radiated from the
      ground.  The spacecraft oscillator locked to the &apos;uplink&apos;
      signal, then generated &apos;downlink&apos; signals coherently at both S-
      and X-band.  Perturbations on the radio signal during TWO
      passes through the atmosphere must be considered during
      analysis of these data.
 
      During several experiments, the spacecraft attitude was
      adjusted during the occultation to compensate for refractive
      bending in the Venus atmosphere.  These &apos;limb-track&apos; maneuvers
      allowed deepest penetration of the atmosphere and were usually
      scheduled when a 70-m ground antenna was available.
 
      The first set of experiments (5-6 October 1991) and their
      results have been described in the literature
      [STEFFESETAL1994], [JENKINSETAL1994], [HINSON&amp;JENKINS1995].
 
      The data set includes Original Data Records (ODRs), which are
      digitized recordings of baseband receiver output, and Archival
      Tracking Data Files (ATDFs or TDFs), which are edited records
      of closed-loop receiver output and related parameters.  The
      ATDF also contains coefficients that can be used to derive the
      frequency of the &apos;uplink&apos; signal transmitted from the ground.
 
      Typical users of the data set would derive the frequency and
      amplitude of the signal captured by the DSN receiving antenna
      from ODRs (or, for low resolution, from an ATDF).  After
      correction for known geometrical effects, the residual
      frequency could be attributed to the radially variable index of
      refraction of the atmosphere.  Reduction of the signal
      amplitude from the predicted level could be attributed
      partially to refractive spreading (which may be estimated from
      the frequency analysis) or to mispointing of the HGA (which can
      be estimated from spacecraft attitude data).  The remaining
      attenuation is believed to result from absorption by
      atmospheric constituents, especially sulfuric acid.  See
      [STEFFESETAL1994], [JENKINSETAL1994] and references cited
      therein for more information.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      Open loop data records (ODRs) contain 8-bit samples of receiver
      output.  Each block of (nominally) 4000 data samples is
      accompanied a 166 byte header.  The ODR is described by a
      Software Interface Specification (SIS), included as
      RSC11_11.TXT in the DOCUMENT directory of the data set archival
      volume.
 
      When 70-m antennas were available, two X-band (3.5 cm wave-
      length) open-loop receivers were used, one capturing right-
      circularly polarized signals and the other capturing left-
      circularly polarized signals.  These are identified in the data
      stream as Channels 1 and 3.  Two S-band open-loop receivers
      were also used, yielding right- and left-circularly polarized
      output on Channels 2 and 4, respectively.  When smaller
      antennas were used, no more than two receivers were used; the
      bands, polarizations, and channel assignments varied among
      experiments.
 
      Each ATDF data record contains 117 parameters, stored in
      records of 288 bytes at rates up to 10 per second.  The
      parameters include estimates of received signal strength and
      frequency as well as status information on components of the
      DSN system.  The ATDF is described by a Software Interface
      Specification (SIS), included as TRK_2_25.TXT in the DOCUMENT
      directory of each ROCC archival volume.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      Open loop data (ODRs) are not edited or otherwise processed
      before being incorporated into the ROCC RDA.  A 32-byte label
      at the beginning of each ODR tape is not included in the data
      file; it gives the software version of the data taking
      equipment and is saved instead in the PDS label that
      accompanies the data file.
 
      DSN Navigation Team performs editing on data during conversion
      from the Intermediate Data Record (IDR) to ATDF formats; this
      function serves mostly to remove anomalous (out of nominal
      range) values.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      Original Data Records (ODRs) were the primary data type for
      this raw data archive.  ODRs were generated at stations of the
      NASA Deep Space Network (DSN) and were distributed on 6250 bpi
      tape.  Those tapes have been copied to disk files, defined as
      PDS TABLE Objects, and archived on these CD-WO volumes.  ODRs
      are stored on CD-WO volumes in this archival data set in
      chronological order; ancillary data to support analysis
      accompany ODRs in the CALIB, GEOMETRY, and DOCUMENT
      directories.  The table FILELIST.TAB in the document directory
      shows relationships among ODR files and ancillary data.
 
      A nominal ODR contained 24000 records, each record having 166
      bytes of header data and 4000 bytes of 8-bit sample data.  For
      the carefully planned experiments, each of four receiver
      channels (X-RCP, S-RCP, X-LCP, and S-RCP) was sampled at 50000
      samples per second.  A single file represented 8 minutes of
      observing time.  For the ad hoc experiments (February-March
      1992, January 1993, and October 1994) channel assignments and
      sampling parameters varied.
 
      On MGN ROCC archival volumes ODR files have names of the form
      ydddhhmm.ODR where y gives the least significant digit of the
      year, ddd is the 3-digit day-of-year, hh is the 2-digit hour,
      and mm is the 2-digit minute on which data acquisition for the
      file began.
 
      Each ODR data file is accompanied by a full PDS detached label
      with name ydddhhmm.LBL which completely describes the contents
      of the ODR file.  The format and contents are also described in
      RSC11_11.TXT in the DOCUMENT directory of each archival volume.
 
      In two instances (1992-068T20:43 and 1992-070T21:48) two DSN
      stations (DSS 15 and DSS 45) began recording occultation data
      at the same ydddhhmm; the file with the slightly earlier start
      time (8 seconds in the first case and 2 in the second) has had
      its &apos;mm&apos; manually decremented by one so as to avoid duplicate
      file names.
 
      Archival Tracking Data Files (ATDFs or TDFs) are considered to
      be primary raw data for many radio science experiments.  In
      this case, they served a backup and ancillary role.  ATDFs are
      generated by the Radio Metric Data Conditioning Team in the
      DSN.  They were delivered either on computer-compatible tape or
      as electronic files.  They have been copied to disk, defined as
      PDS TABLE objects, and archived on these CD-WO volumes.
 
      A typical ATDF covered several days and had a volume of 35
      MBytes.  ATDF rates for these Magellan ROCC experiments were
      typically on the order of one sample every 60 seconds.  Each
      sample was of 117 items, including measurements of signal
      amplitude and frequency from closed loop receivers, and was
      stored as a single record of 288 bytes.  Sampling of the
      signals was limited to one polarization at S-band and one
      polarization at X-band.  Time resolution was far coarser than
      from the ODR and no information on signal phase was retained.
      The ATDF, from this perspective, provided low-resolution backup
      to the ODR.
 
      The ATDF also provided data on the uplink transmitting system,
      including constant and linear coefficients for a software
      driven oscillator that served as the uplink frequency
      reference.  This information is needed for analysis of the ODR,
      especially when the uplink signal was &apos;ramped&apos; -- used a
      linearly varying frequency.
 
      Each ATDF has a file name of the form ydddeeeX.TDF where y is
      the least significant digit of the year and ddd is the
      day-of-year for the first ATDF record.  The eee gives
      day-of-year for the last data record in the ATDF, and X is set
      to &apos;A&apos; unless there is more than one ATDF with ydddeee in the
      data set.  For the MGN ROCC raw data archive there were no
      duplicates of ydddeee among ATDFs.
 
      Each ATDF is accompanied by a full PDS detached label with name
      ydddeeeA.LBL which completely describes the contents of the
      ATDF.  The format and contents are also described in
      TRK_2_25.TXT in the DOCUMENT directory of each archival volume.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      For each ODR, there is a set of ancillary files needed for
      analysis.  These are stored in the CALIB and GEOMETRY
      directories, as appropriate.  A table FILELIST.TAB in the
      DOCUMENT directory shows relationships among ODRs and ancillary
      files.
 
 
      Uplink Frequency Data
      ---------------------
        The transmitted signal from the ground was used as the
        frequency reference for the spacecraft radio signal.  During
        early experiments the uplink was &apos;ramped&apos; -- the frequency
        varied linearly with time.  Coefficients for linear uplink
        frequency functions are stored in the ATDF (in items 112-114;
        see TRK_2_25.TXT in the DOCUMENT directory).  These were
        abstracted from the ATDF and stored in files of their own for
        the first set of experiments in 1991.  They are stored as
        tables with names TUNnnnnn.TAB in the CALIB directory on the
        first CD-WO volume.  Each TUNnnnnn.TAB file is accompanied by
        a detached PDS label with name TUNnnnnn.LBL.
 
        For later experiments, the user must obtain the uplink
        coefficients directly from the ATDF in the TDF directory.
        For experiments in 1994 ramping was discontinued, and a
        constant frequency was transmitted.  It is not known when the
        change occurred; users interested in working with data from
        1992 and 1993 should at least plan to obtained uplink
        coefficients (and times) from ATDFs.
 
 
      Downlink Frequency Files
      ------------------------
        Also, for the 1991 experiments (only), downlink frequencies
        were predicted at both S- and X-band.  These are stored as
        tables with names DSBnnnnn.TAB in the CALIB directory.  The
        files give offsets from the expected carrier frequency at
        S-band (B=S) and X-band (B=X) after Doppler effects from
        relative motion and effects of Earth&apos;s atmosphere are taken
        into account.  They do NOT include effects from the
        atmosphere of Venus, so subtracting the prediction from the
        observed frequency will give a first-order measure of the
        effects of the atmosphere in the frequency domain.  Each
        DSBnnnnn.TAB file is accompanied by a PDS detached label
        DSBnnnnn.LBL.  These prediction files appear only on the
        first CD-WO volume; users desiring them for experiments in
        1992-1994 must calculate their own.
 
 
      High-Gain Antenna (HGA) Radiation Pattern
      -----------------------------------------
        The radiation pattern of the high-gain antenna (HGA) is
        described in a PDS document with both ASCII and extended
        PostScript components in the CALIB directory.  The HGA
        pattern would not be needed if the HGA always pointed toward
        &apos;virtual&apos; Earth.  In ad hoc experiments, there was no limb
        track maneuver; and, when maneuvers were planned, they were
        simple linear offsets rather than true tracks of the image of
        Earth refracted through Venus&apos; atmosphere.  On 1994-221 the
        spacecraft executed its limb track maneuver two minutes
        early; so corrections based on the HGA patterns will be
        needed if the results are to be interpreted accurately.  The
        HGA calibration document is described in the detached PDS
        label HGA_XXX.LBL in the CALIB directory; it is included on
        all CD-WO volumes.
 
 
      Observing Geometry
      ------------------
        Files describing the observing geometry are stored in the
        GEOMETRY directory.  These include NAIF &apos;text&apos; format SPK
        files and NAIF &apos;transfer&apos; format ephemerides.  Files
        describing spacecraft attitude are also included in the
        GEOMETRY directory, but are described in the next section.
 
        NAIF (PDS Navigation and Ancillary Information) &apos;text&apos; format
        SPK files are available for all observations through
        1992-342.  These contain the positions of Magellan, Venus,
        Earth, and the Sun in data modules that can be used readily
        with NAIF Toolkit software.  Each &apos;text&apos; SPK file has a name
        ending with the extension &apos;TSP&apos;; each TSP data file is
        accompanied by a detached PDS minimal label having the same
        file name but ending with the &apos;LBL&apos; extension.
 
        NAIF &apos;transfer&apos; format ephemeris files are available for the
        remaining observations (1992-355 through 1994).  Files with
        names MGNyyddd.XSP contain the Magellan trajectory with
        respect to Venus beginning on year yy and day-of-year ddd.  A
        single file PEPH8996.XSP contains the positions of Earth,
        Venus, and the Sun from 1989 to 1996.  Each XSP file is
        accompanied by a detached PDS minimal label having the same
        file name, except for an &apos;LBL&apos; extension.
 
        Before using either &apos;text&apos; or &apos;transfer&apos; NAIF files, the user
        should convert ASCII carriage-return line-feed delimiters on
        each record to the default delimiter for text files on the
        local system, then use the NAIF utility SPACIT to convert the
        archival file to local binary.
 
        Information on acquisition, installation, and use of the NAIF
        software can be found in TK_FTP.TXT in the DOCUMENT
        directory.
 
 
      Spacecraft Attitude (Quaternions)
      ---------------------------------
        Data describing the attitude of the spacecraft during radio
        occultations is needed when the HGA was not pointed toward
        the image of Earth, as seen from the spacecraft.  Limb track
        maneuvers were planned and executed for several experiments
        -- to improve pointing during experiments; attitude data
        defines the accuracy to which the image of Earth remained on
        the HGA boresight.
 
        Attitude data are available in as many as five forms, though
        no more than three forms are included here for any single
        experiment.
 
        For the first set of experiments (1991), telemetry of
        quaternion values is available in PDS tables with file names
        of the form DRFnnnnn.TAB.  Filtered versions of the telemetry
        are available in files FILnnnnn.TAB.  Reconstructions of
        antenna pointing are in tables with file names HGAnnnnn.TAB.
        In each case a detached PDS label completely describes the
        format and content of the table.  One set of DRF, FIL, and
        HGA files is stored for each of the three Magellan orbits
        observed in 1991.  These files appear in the GEOMETRY
        directory, but only on the first CD-WO volume.
 
        For the remaining experiments during which a limb track
        maneuver was planned spacecraft attitude is described by
        either a table of quaternion values (QUAnnnnn.TAB file name),
        a text file of polynomial coefficients which can be used to
        generate quaternions (QCFnnnnn.TXT), or both.  The QUA*.TAB
        files are each accompanied by a detached PDS label with file
        name QUA*.LBL which completely describes the content and
        format of the associated table.  QCF*.TXT files are
        self-documenting.  In some QCF*.TXT files multiple sets of
        coefficients have been archived; in these cases the
        experiment investigator had not determined at the time of
        archiving which set had actually been executed on the
        spacecraft.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      SPK ephemeris files and quaternion files were produced for the
      J2000 inertial reference frame.  SPICE reader routines may be
      used to convert these to other coordinate systems.
 
      Other data types are not dependent on definition of a
      coordinate system.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      Software for parsing, reducing, and analyzing data such as
      these has been developed at Stanford University and elsewhere.
      The Stanford software has not been prepared for general
      distribution and is not included with the archival data set.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The archival data set is written on CD-WO media using the Young
      Minds CD Studio authoring system.  The CD-WO volumes conform to
      ISO 9660 standards.
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      At the time the raw data were archived relatively little
      analysis had been performed on the data, except for the 1991
      occultations (1991-10-05 and 1991-10-06) [STEFFESETAL1994],
      [JENKINSETAL1994], [HINSON&amp;JENKINS1995].
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was distributed for peer review panel
      prior to its acceptance by the Planetary Data System (PDS).
      The review was conducted in accordance with PDS procedures.
 
      Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data
      set, key elements of the archive were distributed for
      preliminary review.  These included electronic versions of
      example PDS labels, CATALOG files, and Software Interface
      Specifications.  These materials were distributed to PDS
      personnel, the experiment investigator, and others, as
      appropriate.  An earlier version of the first CD-WO volume
      (MG_2201, DATA_SET_ID = &apos;MGN-V-1-ROCC-V1.0&apos;) was distributed
      for review in February 1995.
 
      Data on the CD-WO volumes was checked using Stanford parsing
      and reduction software to ensure that it was both complete and
      an accurate replica of the data contained in the original tape
      files.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      The times covered by ODR tapes are given below.  Notes on
      presumed quality of the data follow each list of ODR times.
      Note that ODRs from 1992-355 and 1992-356 are included here for
      completeness; but those data were not in the the archive.
 
      DSS           START                 STOP
      ---     -----------------     -----------------
      43     1991-278T20:15:54     1991-278T20:23:54
      43     1991-278T20:23:54     1991-278T20:24:24
      43     1991-278T23:31:28     1991-278T23:39:27
      43     1991-278T23:39:28     1991-278T23:40:27
      43     1991-279T02:47:01     1991-279T02:55:01
      43     1991-279T02:55:01     1991-279T02:56:00
 
      No problems known with data above.
 
      DSS           START                 STOP
      ---     -----------------     -----------------
      65     1992-048T08:14:59     1992-048T08:37:00
      65     1992-048T11:32:31     1992-048T11:52:30
      61     1992-049T10:21:19     1992-049T10:41:19
      61     1992-049T13:36:54     1992-049T13:56:52
      61     1992-050T09:10:12     1992-050T09:30:13
      61     1992-050T12:25:48     1992-050T12:45:46
      61     1992-051T07:59:10     1992-051T08:19:10
      61     1992-051T11:14:46     1992-051T11:34:44
      65     1992-052T10:02:46     1992-052T10:23:46
      65     1992-052T13:18:23     1992-052T13:39:21
      45     1992-067T21:52:06     1992-067T22:12:02
      45     1992-068T01:07:58     1992-068T01:27:56
      45     1992-068T04:23:54     1992-068T04:43:52
      65     1992-068T11:32:39     1992-068T11:52:31
      65     1992-068T14:11:51     1992-068T14:31:43
      15     1992-068T17:27:42     1992-068T17:47:40
      45     1992-068T20:43:43     1992-068T21:03:39
      15     1992-068T20:43:51     1992-068T21:03:39
      45     1992-068T23:59:41     1992-069T00:19:39
      45     1992-069T03:15:43     1992-069T03:35:41
      65     1992-069T13:03:03     1992-069T13:25:01
      15     1992-069T16:20:02     1992-069T16:40:00
      15     1992-069T19:36:11     1992-069T19:56:09
      45     1992-069T22:52:25     1992-069T23:12:21
      45     1992-070T02:08:37     1992-070T02:28:35
      15     1992-070T15:14:25     1992-070T15:34:21
      15     1992-070T18:31:15     1992-070T18:51:13
      15     1992-070T21:48:46     1992-070T22:08:44
      45     1992-070T21:48:48     1992-070T22:08:44
      61     1992-071T10:38:08     1992-071T10:58:10
      61     1992-071T13:53:54     1992-071T14:13:45
      15     1992-071T14:09:58     1992-071T14:13:38
 
      No limb track maneuvers were planned, so penetration depth into
      atmosphere was limited.  No SPK file for 1992-052.  ODR files
      were not checked for anomalies prior to archiving.  DSS 61 used
      non-standard receiver filters (7500 Hz).  These data were
      typically collected using DSP mode 4; X-band samples were
      obtained using ADCs 2-4 (the samples from ADC 1 are redundant
      and should not be used).
 
      DSS           START                 STOP
      ---     -----------------     -----------------
      43     1992-342T03:21:45     1992-342T03:29:44
      43     1992-342T03:29:45     1992-342T03:37:44
      43     1992-342T03:37:45     1992-342T03:45:44
      43     1992-342T03:39:45     1992-342T03:37:44
      43     1992-342T03:45:45     1992-342T03:49:24
      43     1992-342T06:36:09     1992-342T06:44:08
      43     1992-342T06:44:09     1992-342T06:52:08
      43     1992-342T06:52:09     1992-342T07:00:08
      43     1992-342T07:00:09     1992-342T07:03:45
 
      Effect of atmosphere was not included in calculation of
      receiver tuning predictions; X-band signal drifts out of
      passband during observation periods.  Occultations were at
      apoapsis, so vertical resolution in the atmosphere was not as
      good as during 1991 experiments.
 
      DSS           START                 STOP
      ---     -----------------     -----------------
      14     1992-355T21:57:00     1992-355T22:04:59
      14     1992-355T22:05:00     1992-355T22:12:59
      14     1992-355T22:13:00     1992-355T22:20:59
      14     1992-355T22:29:00     1992-355T22:36:59
      14     1992-355T22:37:00     1992-355T22:44:59
      14     1992-355T22:45:00     1992-355T22:45:16
      14     1992-356T01:04:17     1992-356T01:12:16
      14     1992-356T01:12:17     1992-356T01:16:15
      14     1992-356T01:16:16     1992-356T01:24:15
      14     1992-356T01:24:16     1992-356T01:28:59
      14     1992-356T01:29:08     1992-356T01:37:07
      14     1992-356T01:37:08     1992-356T01:42:07
      14     1992-356T01:42:09     1992-356T01:50:10
      14     1992-356T01:50:11     1992-356T01:51:42
      14     1992-356T01:54:20     1992-356T01:59:37
 
      Recording system failed, and no quaternion files have been
      located.  Data corresponding to the ODR files above were NOT
      included in the archive.
 
      DSS           START                 STOP
      ---     -----------------     -----------------
      15     1993-013T20:31:30     1993-013T20:47:29
      15     1993-013T20:47:30     1993-013T21:03:29
      15     1993-013T21:03:30     1993-013T21:08:02
      15     1993-013T21:08:25     1993-013T21:24:24
      15     1993-013T21:24:25     1993-013T21:31:38
 
      No ATDF; but experiments were conducted with constant uplink
      frequencies in 1994, so uplink frequency rates MAY not be
      needed here.  No limb track maneuver means penetration depth in
      the atmosphere is not great.  ODRs were not reviewed before
      archiving, so their quality is unknown.
 
      DSS           START                 STOP
      ---     -----------------     -----------------
      14     1994-175T17:40:44     1994-175T17:51:39
      14     1994-175T18:17:41     1994-175T18:33:40
      14     1994-175T18:33:41     1994-175T18:34:22
      14     1994-175T19:13:39     1994-175T19:15:12
      14     1994-175T19:50:41     1994-175T20:01:39
      14     1994-175T20:46:41     1994-175T20:57:39
      14     1994-175T21:23:41     1994-175T21:34:39
      14     1994-175T22:20:01     1994-175T22:36:00
      14     1994-175T22:36:01     1994-175T22:36:35
      14     1994-175T22:56:39     1994-175T23:07:39
 
      Incorrect pointing of ground antenna (pointing was calculated
      for DSS 15, then used at DSS 14 without correcting for physical
      displacement between antennas; error was large enough that
      spacecraft was well off the S-band boresight and in the
      sidelobes at X-band).  Also, incorrect spacecraft polarization
      (and transmitter) was specified.  Incorrect entries in DSN
      keyword file meant ground sequencing was in error, including
      erroneous uplink transmit timing.  The last occultation may be
      OK, but the others are degraded.  By 1994 uplink transmissions
      did not use &apos;ramping&apos;; so the ATDF should not be required for
      details of uplink radio frequencies.
 
      DSS           START                 STOP
      ---     -----------------     -----------------
      43     1994-197T02:26:04     1994-197T02:37:59
      43     1994-197T03:59:35     1994-197T04:11:32
      43     1994-197T05:32:35     1994-197T05:44:32
 
      No known problems with the ODRs above.
 
      DSS           START                 STOP
      ---     -----------------     -----------------
      61     1994-221T13:37:09     1994-221T13:57:08
      61     1994-221T13:57:09     1994-221T14:16:13
      61     1994-221T15:10:11     1994-221T15:30:10
      61     1994-221T15:30:11     1994-221T15:49:02
      61     1994-221T16:43:10     1994-221T17:03:09
      61     1994-221T17:03:10     1994-221T17:22:01
      61     1994-221T18:16:13     1994-221T18:36:12
      61     1994-221T18:36:13     1994-221T18:55:01
      61     1994-221T19:49:10     1994-221T20:09:09
      61     1994-221T20:09:10     1994-221T20:28:01
 
      Spacecraft executed limb track maneuvers 2 minutes early.  DSS
      61 filters are non-standard.  Otherwise, no known problems with
      ODR data above.
 
      DSS           START                 STOP
      ---     -----------------     -----------------
      65     1994-274T12:55:41     1994-274T13:11:40
      65     1994-274T13:11:41     1994-274T13:20:17
      65     1994-274T13:23:47     1994-274T13:39:47
      65     1994-274T13:39:48     1994-274T13:55:47
      65     1994-274T13:55:48     1994-274T14:11:47
      65     1994-274T14:19:38     1994-274T14:34:40
      65     1994-274T16:42:57     1994-274T16:58:56
      65     1994-274T16:58:57     1994-274T17:14:56
      65     1994-274T17:14:57     1994-274T17:30:56
      65     1994-274T17:30:57     1994-274T17:33:36
      65     1994-274T17:34:09     1994-274T17:37:52
      15     1994-275T17:46:04     1994-275T18:02:03
      15     1994-275T18:02:04     1994-275T18:04:59
      15     1994-275T20:50:00     1994-275T21:05:59
      15     1994-275T21:06:00     1994-275T21:19:59
      15     1994-279T20:16:00     1994-279T20:31:59
      15     1994-279T20:32:00     1994-279T20:47:59
      15     1994-281T18:26:05     1994-281T18:42:04
      15     1994-281T18:42:05     1994-281T18:58:04
      15     1994-281T21:31:00     1994-281T21:46:59
      15     1994-281T21:47:00     1994-281T22:02:59
      61     1994-283T10:27:00     1994-283T10:46:38
      61     1994-283T10:46:58     1994-283T11:03:46
      61     1994-283T13:32:11     1994-283T13:52:10
      61     1994-283T13:52:11     1994-283T14:05:01
      61     1994-283T16:37:11     1994-283T16:57:10
      61     1994-283T16:57:11     1994-283T17:10:01
      42     1994-284T08:03:12     1994-284T08:19:11
      42     1994-284T08:19:12     1994-284T08:35:11
      42     1994-284T08:35:12     1994-284T08:38:03
      61     1994-284T11:05:28     1994-284T11:25:27
      61     1994-284T11:25:28     1994-284T11:43:04
      61     1994-284T14:06:56     1994-284T14:26:55
      61     1994-284T14:26:56     1994-284T14:43:07
      61     1994-284T15:42:10     1994-284T16:02:09
      61     1994-284T16:02:10     1994-284T16:15:31
      61     1994-284T17:14:10     1994-284T17:31:02
      42     1994-284T21:54:41     1994-284T22:10:40
      42     1994-284T22:10:41     1994-284T22:26:40
      42     1994-284T22:26:41     1994-284T22:30:03
      42     1994-284T23:27:10     1994-284T23:43:09
      42     1994-284T23:43:10     1994-284T23:59:09
      42     1994-284T23:59:10     1994-285T00:02:03
      42     1994-285T00:59:39     1994-285T01:15:38
      42     1994-285T01:15:39     1994-285T01:31:38
      42     1994-285T01:31:39     1994-285T01:34:33
      61     1994-285T09:55:28     1994-285T10:07:25
      61     1994-285T10:37:25     1994-285T10:57:24
      61     1994-285T10:57:25     1994-285T11:17:24
      61     1994-285T11:17:25     1994-285T11:37:24
 
      No limb track maneuvers, so atmospheric penetration expected to
      be limited.  DSS 61 used non-standard filters.  ODRs had not
      been checked for quality when archiving began; but no problems
      known a priori.  Spacecraft communications with Earth ended on
      1994-285.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      No ATDF is available for 1993-013.  No trajectory data are
      available for 1992-052.  Otherwise, the limitations in this
      data set follow from the quality of the execution, which is
      described above under Data Coverage and Quality.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>89-033B-03B</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

