<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dawn-a-grand-2-edr-vesta-counts-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DAWN GRAND RAW (EDR) VESTA COUNTS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.dawn_mission_to_vesta_and_ceres::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:grand.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.4_vesta::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dawn-a-grand-2-edr-vesta-counts-v1.0__browserp_dawn-a-grand-2-edr-vesta-counts-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Prettyman, T.H., W.C. Feldman, F.P. Ameduri, B.L. Barraclough, E.W. Cascio,
                   K.R. Fuller, H.O. Funsten, D.J. Lawrence, G.W. McKinney, C.T. Russell, S.A.
                   Soldner, S.A. Storms, C. Szeles, and R.L. Tokar, Gamma-ray and neutron
                   spectrometer for the Dawn mission to 1 Ceres and 4 Vesta, IEEE Trans. Nucl.
                   Sci., Volume 50, Issue 4, pp. 1190-1197, August 2003,
                   doi:10.1109/TNS.2003.815156
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PRETTYMANETAL2003B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Prettyman, T.H., W.C. Feldman, H.Y. McSween, Jr., R.D. Dingler, D.C. Enemark,
                   D.E. Patrick, S.A. Storms, J.S. Hendricks, J.P. Morgenthaler, K.M. Pitman, R.C.
                   Reedy, Dawn&apos;s Gamma Ray and Neutron Detector, Space Sci. Rev. (2011)
                   163:371-459, doi:10.1007/s11214-011-9862-0
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PRETTYMANETAL2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Prettyman, T.H., D.W. Mittlefehldt, N. Yamashita, D.J. Lawrence, A.W. Beck,
                   W.C. Feldman, T.J. McCoy, H.Y. McSween, M.J. Toplis, T.N. Titus, P. Tricarico,
                   R.C. Reedy, J.S. Hendricks, O. Forni, L. Le Corre, J.-Y. Li, H. Mizzon, V.
                   Reddy, C.A. Raymond, C.T. Russell, Elemental Mapping by Dawn Reveals Exogenic H
                   in Vesta&apos;s Regolith, Science (2012) 338(6104):242-246, DOI
                   10.1126/science.1225354
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PRETTYMANETAL2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DAWN-A-GRAND-2-EDR-VESTA-COUNTS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DAWN GRAND RAW (EDR) VESTA COUNTS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2011-05-03T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>THOMAS H. PRETTYMAN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Prettyman, T.H., DAWN GRAND RAW (EDR) VESTA APPROACH AND ORBITAL
            COUNTS V1.0, DAWN-A-GRAND-2-EDR-VESTA-COUNTS-V1.0. NASA Planetary
            Data System, 2011.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The GRaND Experimental Data Records (EDR) are a complete,
            time-ordered collection of state-of-health, gamma ray and neutron
            counting data, determined by reversible operations on the raw
            telemetry data.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The GRaND EDR are a time-ordered collection of gamma ray and
            neutron counting data and histograms acquired by GRaND during all
            phases of the Dawn mission. The dataset includes state-of-health
            data, such as temperature and voltage readings, needed for the
            analysis of the counting data. The EDR is an intermediate data
            product derived from the raw data records using reversible
            operations. All higher order data products are derived from the
            EDR. An automated pipeline is used to process the EDR from the
            raw data records.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Overview
  ========
 
The Dawn Mission&apos;s Gamma Ray and Neutron Detector (GRaND) is a nuclear
spectrometer that will collect data needed to map the elemental
composition of the surfaces of 4-Vesta and 1-Ceres [PRETTYMANETAL2003B,
PRETTYMANETAL2011, PRETTYMANETAL2012].  GRaND measures the spectrum of
planetary gamma rays and neutrons, which originate from cosmic ray
interactions and radioactive decay within the surface, while the spacecraft
(S/C) is in orbit around each body. The instrument, which is mounted on the
+Z deck of the S/C, consists of 21 sensors designed to separately measure
radiation originating from the surface of each asteroid and background
sources, including the space energetic particle environment and cosmic
ray interactions with the spacecraft.  The nuclear spectroscopy data
provided by GRaND will be analyzed to determine the abundance of major
rock forming elements, such as O, Fe, Ti, Si, Al, Mg, Ca, Cl and
radioactive elements, including K and Th, as well as light-elements such
as H, C, and N, which are constituents of ices and the products of
aqueous alteration of silicate minerals and ices.
 
The GRaND Experimental Data Records (EDR) are a time-ordered collection
of gamma ray and neutron counting data and histograms acquired by GRaND
during different phases of the Dawn Mission, including assembly-test-
and-launch- operations (ATLO), cruise, Mars Gravity Assist (MGA), and
science mapping at 4-Vesta and 1-Ceres.  The dataset also includes
state-of-health data (instrument settings, temperature and voltage
readings) needed for scientific analysis of the neutron and gamma ray
data. The EDR is an intermediate data product (Level 1A) that is derived
from Raw Data Records (Level 0) using reversible operations.  The Level
1A are the lowest level of GRaND data archived in the PDS, from which
all higher order data sets are derived.  To support timely delivery of
higher order products, the Level 1A data are processed using an
automated pipleline, which operates on Level 0 data when it is queried
by the DSC.
 
The data set consists primarily of ASCII tables, divided into three
functional categories: auxilliary information (AUX); gamma ray spectra
and event data (GAMMA); and neutron spectra and event data (NEUTRON).
Gamma ray and neutron event data are recorded in binary files.  Some of
the data in the ASCII files, which are human-readable, are repeated in
the binary files to aid in the verification of user-written routines.
 
The telemetry for GRaND consists of science and state-of-health data,
accumulated over consecutive time intervals to produce a time-series data
set. Each science data record includes scalers, histograms, and event data
accumulated over an interval specified by the commandable parameter
TELREADOUT, with units of seconds.  The state of health data include average
temperatures, voltages, and instrument state data acquired during time
intervals specified by the commandable parameter TELSOH (also in seconds).
Both intervals are adjusted, depending on the measurement conditions and
objectives for each mission phase.  During mapping, TELREADOUT will be set to
sub-sample spatial pixels defined on the surface of Vesta or Ceres. During
cruise, TELREADOUT was generally set to large values (e.g., 210s) to minimize
data volume.  TELSOH is generally set to subsample the science accumulation
interval, providing information needed to determine, for example, whether and
how many times the science scalers have rolled over.
 
GRaND has 23 scalers, which are described in the Paramters section.
Scalers are simply pulse counters. They accumulate counts over time.  The
value of the scaler registers are read out at the end of each science
accumuluation interval and then reset to zero to begin the next interval.
The same registers are read out at each state-of-health time step.  Because
the state-of-health data are acquired at a higher cadence than the science
data, the accumulation of counts can be monitored during each TELREADOUT
interval.  The 16-bit scalers roll over (return to zero) when they exceed
65535 counts.  Rollover can be detected and counted as a sawtooth pattern in
the state-of-health telemetry if TELSOH is set to be smaller than TELREADOUT.
For example, if a single reset is observed for a scaler in the state-of-health
telemetry, then the counts observed in the science telemetry need to be
increased by 65536. Properly accounting for rollover is particularly important
for determining dead time from the scaler counting data.
 
The data are downloaded regularly from the spacecraft by the Ground Data
System.  The UCLA Dawn Science Center (DSC) captures all of the payload
instrument telemetry frames as binary files after the data have been
cleaned up in post-pass processing to produce reconstructed Level-0
data.  The files are inventoried within the Dawn Science Database (DSDb)
and are retrieved by the GRaND team, which unscrambles, decompresses,
decodes, and formats the raw telemetry data into scientifically useful
data files.  The decompressed and decoded data, along with their
required PDS documentation, form the Level-1A EDR data sets.  The Level-
1a EDR data are determined by performing reversible operations on the
Level-1a data set, to produce counting data and spectral products useful
for mapping.
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
The EDR data are derived from Level 0 raw data queried by the DSC over
irregular time periods, roughly aligned with the mission phase
boundaries.  The DSC divides the Level 0 data into separate files
containing state of health and science data packets.  The Level 1a
pipeline operates on these files to produce the Level 1a archive.  The
directory structure for the Level 1a data is given by
 
   GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC    (top level directory)
      LEVEL1A_AUX         (directory containing auxiliary data)
      LEVEL1A_GAMMA       (directory containing gamma ray counting data)
      LEVEL1A_NEUTRON     (directory containing neutron counting data)
 
The top level directory name contains the SCET UTC dates for the first
and last science data records (Y1M1D1 and Y2M2D2, respectively), and the
creation date (YCMCDC) for the archive.  For example, for
GRD-L1A-090217-090218_090517, the first science data record was acquired
on 17- Feb-2009.  The last science data record was acquired on 18-Feb-
2009. The archive was created by the pipeline on 17-May-2009.
 
The LEVEL1A_AUX directory contains the following files derived from the
Level 0 state-of-health and science data:
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-STA.TAB - Instrument state file. The
     instrument state file contains the instrument settings, including
     the mode, power supply states, high voltage settings, the data
     accumulation interval, and coincidence windows.  The first record
     of the state-of-health file is recorded in the state file, stamped
     with SCET UTC.  Thereafter, rows are added only when the instrument
     settings change.
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-RDG.TAB - Instrument readings file.
     This file contains a time-ordered list of temperature and voltage
     readings averaged over each state-of-health accumulation interval
     (TELSOH), converted to physical units.
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-SOH-SCL.TAB - State of health scaler
     data. This file contains a time-ordered list of the scaler data
     recorded in the state-of-health telemetry.  The accumulation time
     for the scaler data is TELSOH.  Note that the scalers are set to zero
     the start of each science accumulation interval (TELREADOUT).  If the
     state-of-health accumulation interval is selected to subsample the
     science interval, then the state-of-health scalers can be used to
     detect and correct for rollover of the science scalers, such as the
     dead time counter.
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-SCI-SCL.TAB - Science scaler data.
     This file contains a time-ordered list of the scaler data recorded
     in the science telemetry.  The accumulation interval for the
     scalers is TELREADOUT.
 
     For each science and state of health record, values for 23 scalers
     are recorded in the -SCI-SCL.TAB and -SOH-SCL.TAB files,
     respectively.
 
     The scalers provide the following information:
 
     Index         Description
     ------------  -----------
     0             Dead time counts
     1             BGO overload events
     2             CZT overload events
     3             +Z phoswich overload events
     4             -Y BLP overload events
     5             +Y BLP overload events
     6             -Z phoswich overload events
     7             +Z phoswich CAT4 events
     8             -Y BLP CAT4 events
     9             +Y BLP CAT4 events
     10            -Z phoswich CAT4 events
     11            Early second interaction events
     12            Multiple-crystal CZT events
     13            Valid CZT events (CAT10)
     14            Coincidence BGO and CZT events (CAT7)
     15            Coincidence of three or more sensor elements
     16            Total events processed by GRaND
     17            Number of single CZT events (CAT10) in the
                   gamma ray event buffer
     18            Number of BGO-CZT coincidence events (CAT7) in the
                   gamma ray event buffer
     19            Number of events (CAT4) in the neutron event
                   buffer
     20            Total number of events allowed in the gamma
                   ray event buffer
     21            Number of single CZT events (CAT10) allowed in
                   the gamma ray event buffer
     22            Number of events allowed in the neutron event
                   buffer
 
     Note that indices 0 through 19 are for 16-bit counters, which are
     reset at the end of every science accumulation interval specified
     by TELREADOUT. If the state-of-health accumulation interval is
     adjusted to subsample the science accumulation interval (for
     example, TELREADOUT = n * TELSOH, where n is a whole number), then
     the scalers will monotonically increase during each acquisition
     interval, unless overflow occurs.  A rollover counter is not
     provided; however, for situations in which the counting rate is
     high or the accumulation intervals are large, the number of
     rollovers for individual scalers can be determined from the SOH
     scaler data if TELSOH is set to subsample the science accumulation
     interval.  In situations where the counting rate is changing,
     abrupt changes in the scaler values can also indicate that rollover
     has occurred.  Rollover is treated in production of the Level1b RDR
     data.
 
     Indices 20 through 21 are maximum values for the number of events
     that can be recorded in the event buffers.  The number of gamma ray
     and neutron events is commandable and can be adjusted.  The total
     number of gamma ray and neutron events must be less than 6677.
 
The LEVEL1A_GAMMA directory contains the following science data files:
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-BGO.TAB
     This file contains a time-ordered list of pulse height spectra
     (1024 channels with units of uncorrected counts/channel) acquired
     by the BGO sensor.
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-EMG.DAT
     This file contains gamma ray event data as a time series in a binary
     file. Each row of this file contains data from a science data record.
     Each science data record contains a list of 3876 events. Each event
     [e.g. i=0,...3875] is specified by ID_CZT[i], the index of the CZT
     sensor struck, CH_CZT[i], the pulse height (0-1023) recorded for
     ID_CZT[i], and CH_BGO[i], the pulse height (0-511) recorded for the BGO
     scintillator (see GRD_L1A-GAMMA_EVENTS.FMT).  If CH_BGO[i]=0, then the
     event was CAT7 (coincidence between the BGO and a single CZT sensor).
     Otherwise, the event was CAT10 (interaction with a single CZT sensor).
     See the instrument catalog and PRETTYMANETAL2011 for a detailed
     description of the event data and examples.  In addition, each row of
     the -EMG.DAT file includes the SCLK, and 23 scalers (SCALER_SCI).  These
     can be compared to values found in the ASCII format -SCI-SCL.TAB (e.g.
     for debugging programs that read the binary data).  The binary file can
     also be examined using NASAview and IDL routines accomanying this
     archive in EXTRAS.
 
The LEVEL1A_NEUTRON directory contains the following science data files:
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-PHOS_MZ.TAB
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-PHOS_PZ.TAB
     These files contain time ordered lists of the 256-channel CAT1
     pulse height spectra for the +Z and -Z phoswiches.  Note that the
     naming convention for the top, bottom, and side scintillators is
     determined by the instrument coordinate system.
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-BGO2_MZ.TAB
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-BGO2_PZ.TAB
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-BGO2_MY.TAB
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-BGO2_PY.TAB
     These files contain time ordered lists of the 64-channel CAT2 BGO
     pulse height spectra for coincidences with the BGO and the four BLP
     sensors.
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-BLP2_MZ.TAB
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-BLP2_PZ.TAB
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-BLP2_MY.TAB
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-BKP2_PY.TAB
     These files contain time ordered lists of the 64-channel CAT2 BLP
     pulse height spectra for coincidences with the BGO and the four BLP
     sensors.
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-EMN.DAT
     This file contains the fast neutron double pulse event data (CAT4) as a
     binary time series.  Each row of this file contains data from a science
     data record. Each science data record contains a list of 2880 events.
     Each event [e.g. i=0,...,2879] is specified by ID_FIRST[i], the index of
     the BLP scintillator that produced the first pulse (0=+Z phoswich;
     1=-Y BLP; 2=+Y BLP; 3=-Z phoswich), CH_FIRST[i], the amplitude of the
     first pulse (0-63), ID_SECOND[i], the index of the BLP scintillator that
     produced second pulse (0-3), CH_SECOND[i], the amplitude of the second
     pulse (0-63), and the time to second pulse (0-255), with units of 100 ns
     per data number.  See the instrument catalog and PRETTYMANETAL2011 for a
     detailed description of  the event data and examples.  In addition, each
     row of the -EMN.DAT file includes the SCLK, and 23 scalers (SCALER_SCI).
     These can be compared to values found in the ASCII format -SCI-SCL.TAB
     (e.g. for debugging programs that read the binary data).  The binary
     file can also be examined using NASAview and IDL routines accomanying
     this archive in EXTRAS.
 
  Processing
  ==========
 
The Level 1A data are automatically processed using a pipeline, which
operates on files queried by the DSC over selected time intervals.  Each
DSC query separates the GRaND data into files containing state-of-health
and science data records, in the order in which they were received on
the ground and with corrupted packets removed.  The state-of-health data
are further divided into real time telemetry data and playback data.
The science data are stored in a single raw data file.
 
The pipeline merges the state-of-health data from the playback and
realtime files to produce a time-ordered-list of records.  Selected data
are extracted to produce the Level 1A AUX files.  Internal temperature
readings are converted from data numbers (DN) to engineering units using
a linear function determined during ground calibration: T (degrees C) =
0.4354 DN - 0.4354. The high voltage readings for the high voltage power
supplies are reported in engineering units using the conversion V
(Volts) = 1500 DN/255.  The CZT differential bias voltage is converted
using V (Volts) = 0.405 DN.
 
The science data are decompressed, decoded, separated by functionality
and written as time-ordered ASCII tables and binary time series.  The
raw histograms (CAT1, CAT2, and CAT9) are represented as 8 bit numbers
which are decompressed and reported as 16 bit, unsigned integers.
 
The gamma ray event buffer can store up to 3876 events for each science
accumulation interval.  Each event is packed into 3 bytes, which contain
the ID of the CZT sensor, the CZT pulse amplitude, and the BGO pulse
amplitude.  The vales for each event are extracted and stored as a
binary time series.  When the gamma ray event buffer is not full, null
events are reported as zeros, such that each row of the Level 1A time
series contains 3876 events.
 
The neutron event buffer can store up to 2800 events for each science
data accumulation interval.  Each event is packed into 3 bytes, which
contain the BLP sensor ID and pulse amplitude for the first interaction,
the BLP sensor ID and pulse amplitude for the second interaction, and
the time between pulses.  The time between pulses has units of 100
nanoseconds/DN.  The vales for each event are extracted and stored as a
binary time series.  The pulse amplitudes are uncalibrated for Level 1A.
When the gamma ray event buffer is not full, null events are reported as
zeros, such that each row of the Level 1A time series contains 2800
events.
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
 
The Level 1A data include ancilliary data in the form of SCET UTC
strings reported in each row of the Level 1A data tables and time
series.  The UTC strings are determined from the spacecraft clock ticks
recorded in each state-of-health packet and for the first packet in each
science data record using NAIF SPICE (leap seconds kernel).  This
information is used in Level 1B processing to accurately determine the
mid-point of each science accumulation interval, which is needed for
mapping.
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
 
The instrument coordinate system (Fig. 1) determines the naming
convention of the sensors and orientation of the instrument relative to
the spacecraft. The use of MZ indicates a sensor on the -Z (zenith-
facing during mapping) side of GRaND;  PZ indicates the sensor is on the
+Z (spacecraft) side; MY indicates the sensor is on the -Y side
(inboard) side of the instrument; and PY indicates the sensor is on the
+Y side (outboard, towards the +Y solar panel) side of the instrument.
The phototube assembly, marked &apos;P&apos; on the diagram in Fig. 1 points along
the +X axis (towards the high gain antenna).
 
   .................
   . ooooooooooooo .
   . o           o .
   . o           o .
   . o    +Z     o .
   . o   (PZ)    o .
   . o           o .---&gt; +Y (PY)
   . ooo       ooo .
   .   P       P   .
   .   P       P   .
   .   PPPPPPPPP   .
   .               .
   .................
           |
           v
        +X (PX)
 
Figure 1. The coordinate system for GRaND is the same as that of the
S/C. For the diagram above, the observer is looking in the -Z (MZ)
direction and can see the outline of the phoswich assembly (o) on the +Z
side of GRaND. The phototubes are on the +X side and the scintillators
are on the -X side. During mapping at Vesta and Ceres, the planetary
surface is in the +Z direction.
 
  Software
  ========
 
Proprietary software is not needed in order to use the EDR data;
however, Interactive Data Language (IDL) functions are provided in the Extras
directory to read selected EDR data into a structures for analysis and
visualization.  The IDL functions are compatible with IDL Version 7.0 or
higher, distributed by Exelis Visual Information Solutions.  A document
illustrating the use of these functions is provided.
 
  Media/Format
  ============
 
The EDR label and data files are delivered by electronic transmission to
the PDS.  The neutron and gamma ray binary event data were written in
big endian IEEE binary format (MSB order).
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Review
  ======
 
The EDR will be reviewed internally by the Dawn Science Team prior to
submission to the PDS.  The PDS will also conduct an external peer
review of the EDR prior to releasing the data to the general public.
 
  Data Coverage/Quality
  =====================
 
The Level 1A EDR includes all of the available data acquired during flight.
The archive contains gaps in time when the instrument is off during cruise or
in STANDBY or ANNEAL mode for which science data are not acquired.
 
During ATLO, ICO, and EMC, state-of-health data were decimated by a
factor of 3 for storage in the virtual recorder on board the spacecraft.
Consequently, playback data contained every third state-of-health
packet.  Full sampling of GRaND housekeeping data was available
infrequently during the acquisition of real-time telemetry.  The
spacecraft flight software was modified to remove the decimation prior
to GRaND power on for Mars Gravity Assist (at UTC/ SCET 2009-
020/21:19:11), and, thereafter, housekeeping data volume was controlled
by the selection of TELSOH.  Consequently, fully-sampled housekeeping
data are available in the EDR following 20-Jan-2009.
 
GRaND&apos;s scalers do not have accompanying roll-over counters.  During
solar particle events or long accumulation times, it is possible that
one or more of the scalers can exceed the maximum number of counts
(65535), restarting at 0. In fact, the some scalers, such as the dead
time counter, can roll over multiple times.  The number of of times a
scaler has rolled over can be determined by watching for abrupt changes
in the science scaler data and by analyzing the state-of-health scaler
data when the state-of-health readout interval (TELSOH) is set to
subsample the science accumulation interval (TELREADOUT) (for example,
see Prettyman et al., 2011). Corrections for rollover, for example to
determine dead time, are made in the RDR (Level 1b) datasets.
 
Successive EDR directories contain short overlapping time periods, such that
a few science data records are repeated. Care should be taken to eliminate
repeated records when processing EDR from multiple directories. Gaps in the
EDR data set can occur due to missing packets (e.g. occultations) and for
periods of time when the instrument was off following spacecraft safing
events.  During Vesta encounter, the Dawn spacecraft entered safe mode
six times: on 27-Jun-2011 (VSA), 21-Sep-2011 (VSH), 4-Dec-2011 (VTL),
14-Jan-2012 (VSL), 21-Feb-2012 (VSL), and 8-Aug-2012 (VTC).  GRaND was not
powered back on following the last safe mode entry. Recovery of GRaND was
delayed due to anomalous conditions for the 21-Sep-2011 and 14-Jan-2012
events.   Recovery for the latter event required resetting the communications
link between GRaND and the spacecraft; however, GRaND was found in an
anomalous state following recovery from the 21-Sep-2011 event, which is
described here.
 
GRaND was powered on and configured for science data acquisition on
22-Sep-2011. It was discovered that following entry into NORMAL mode and
prior to application of high voltage, the BGO counting rate was about
80 hertz, with a sharp peak around channel 100.  During normal operations, no
counts would have been observed at this stage. At nominal high voltage
settings, the BGO pulse height spectrum was found to be noisy and the
spectrum was shifted and distorted (see EDRs in the 110922-110928 directory).
The behavior was stable and the instrument was allowed to operate at nominal
high voltages for about a week while the anomaly was investigated.
On 28-Sep-2011, GRaND was commanded into STANDBY mode, with all HV supplies
off and the low voltage supplies enabled.
 
The anomaly review panel concluded that it would do no harm to GRaND to cycle
power; however, the panel also suggested that GRaND remained powered off for
a few days in the event that the anomaly was caused by a damaged component,
which might recover with power removed.  The instrument was powered off on
30-Sep-2011 and powered on and configured on 4-Oct-2012.  The instrument was
found to be nominal upon entry into NORMAL mode with the +/-5V supply and
high voltage supply enabled.  Given the absence of the 80-Hz noise, the
decision was made to ramp up the high voltages for the BGO scintillator. This
was carried out on 5-Oct-2012, and the spectrum was found to be nominal.  The
high voltages for the remaining scintillators were ramped up the same day;
however, the high voltages for the CZT were not ramped up until 11-Oct-2011.
The system was fully configured and restored to nominal operations on
12-Oct-2011.
 
Although the root cause has not been identified, it was determined that the
abrupt removal of power from GRaND upon entry into safe mode was not likely
have caused catastrophic damage to analog components.  The analog or digital
circuitry appears to have an anomalous state that can be entered upon
application of power. Thus, the problem was mitigated by monitoring the event
counter on entry into NORMAL mode.  If anomalous counts are observed, the
instrument can be power cycled.  This operational measure was effectively
implemented during the recovery from the 21-Feb-2011 safing.
 
The BGO anomaly and recovery affects EDRs in directories with the following
date ranges:
 
110922-110928
111004-111006
111006-111011
111011-111016
 
For completeness, data corrupted (e.g. due to transmission errors) are not
excluded from the dataset; however, instances of corrupt data are rare,
restricted to the 120225-120303 directory (VSL), primarily on two days:
29-Feb-2012 and 1-Mar-2012.  User&apos;s should be cautious when processing data
in this directory.  Telemetry checksums are discarded in queries of instrument
data by the DSC.  Consequently, corrupt data can only be identified by
anomalies in scaler and spectral data (e.g. incongruous patterns in counts or
discontinuous pulse height spectra).  Corrupt data are partially excluded
from the EDR dataset by two mechanisms: 1) packet headers with incorrect SCLK
values or other invalid information recognized by the query software are
naturally excluded; 2) incomplete science data records (e.g. detected by gaps)
in the packet sequence counter) are discarded by the EDR processing code.
These result in gaps in the EDR science data.  Some unknown portion of the
records may be recognized as valid, yet still contain corrupted science data.
These are not exluded from the archive.
 
Some spectral data products contain artifacts, for example, abrupt increases
in counts for the highest channel or a nonphysical changes in counts
at high channels (e.g. for the CAT1 -Z sensor).  The former is likely from
events that do not exceed the overload threshold, but are not on scale.
These wind up in the last channel.  In addition, some distortion can occur
for large pulses processed by the analog pulse processing circuit.  This may
account for the roll-off observed for high channels for the -Z sensor (e.g.
above channel 230).
 
  Limitations
  ===========
 
The EDR is a low-level data product, which requires significant
processing prior to use in scientific analysis.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

