<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.phx-m-rac-3-radiometric-sci-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>PHOENIX MARS ROBOTIC ARM CAMERA 3 RADIOMETRIC SCI V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.phoenix::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.phx::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rac.phx::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.phx-m-rac-3-radiometric-sci-v1.0__browserp_phx-m-rac-3-radiometric-sci-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.phx-m-rac-3-radiometric-sci-v1.0__dvo_imaging_phx-m-rac-3-radiometric-sci-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.phx-m-rac-3-radiometric-sci-v1.0__pds.geo.phx.analysts_notebook::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Alexander, D., R. Deen, and P. Zamani, Phoenix Project Software Interface
                   Specification: Camera Experiment Data Record (EDR) and Reduced Data Record
                   (RDR) Data Products, Version 1.0, JPL D-33231, April 14, 2008.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ALEXANDERETAL2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Bos, B.J., P.H. Smith, R. Tanner, R. Reynolds, and R. Marcialis, Mars Surveyor
                   2001 Robotic Arm Camera (RAC) Calibration Report, University of Arizona,
                   415640-1200, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BOSETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Keller, H.U., W. Goetz, H. Hartwig, S.F. Hviid, R. Kramm, W.J. Markiewicz, C.
                   Shinohara, P.H. Smith, R. Tanner, P. Woida, R. Woida, B.J. Bos, and M.T.
                   Lemmon, The Phoenix Robotic Arm Camera, J. Geophys. Res., 113, E00A17,
                   doi:10.1029/2007JE003044, 2008.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KELLERETAL2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>PHX-M-RAC-3-RADIOMETRIC-SCI-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>PHOENIX MARS ROBOTIC ARM CAMERA 3 RADIOMETRIC SCI V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2008-12-23</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2008-05-25T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STUBBE HVIID</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Hviid, S., Phoenix Mars Robotic Arm Camera Radiometrically
            Corrected Sci RDR V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            PHX-M-RAC-3-RADIOMETRIC-SCI-V1.0, 2008.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Phoenix Mars Robotic Arm Camera Radiometrically Corrected Science
            Reduced Data Record, Version 1.0.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Robotic Arm Camera (RAC) experiment on the Mars Phoenix
            Lander consists of one instrument component plus command
            electronics. This RAC Imaging Science RDR data set contains
            radiometric data from the Robotic Arm Camera (RAC).
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    There are multiple methods of performing radiometric correction,
    distinguished by the RADIOMETRIC_CORRECTION_TYPE keyword. The most
    common are TAMCAL, RACCAL, MIPLRAD, MIPLRAD2, and MIPLRAD3.
 
    1. Radiance-calibrated RDRs (&apos;RAD&apos;, &apos;RAL&apos;)
 
    The non-linearized RDRs are generated from EDRs. They have all of the
    major instrumental/environmental calibrations applied, such as bias
    removal, dark current removal, electronic shutter smear effect removal,
    flat field correction, and bad pixel repair. Then they have been scaled
    to absolute radiance units using pre-flight radiometric calibration
    coefficients. The units on these files are (W/m^2/nm/sr).
 
    2. RACCAL Method (RAC Team)
 
    This refers to radiometric correction of RAC and OM instrument data only,
    performed by the RAC instrument team (MPS) using the RACCAL software
    suite. It is the most precise correction method applicable to RAC and OM
    data.
 
    The RAC/OM calibration steps performed by the RACSoft package are
    described below:
 
        1. The bad pixel step removal replaces a number of pixels marked
        bad because of dust grains on the CCD or hot electron production.
        The bad pixels are replaced by an interpolated value based on the
        surrounding pixels.
 
        2. The bias subtraction step subtracts the ADC digital offset
        from the image.
 
        3. The image is converted to DN/s
 
        4. The RAC and the OM uses an electronic shutter where the image
        data is fast clocked to a covered area of the CCD at the end of
        the exposure followed by a slower digitization of the image data.
        During the fast clocking each row experiences some additional light
        from other parts of the scene. The electronic shutter correction
        subtracts from row N the summed DN signal of row 0 to N-1 scaled
        by the time it takes to clock a row one step on the CCD.
 
        5. The dark current correction step subtracts an estimated mean value
        of dark current based on the temperature of the CCD. This simple
        scheme (as compared to the SSI) is used because the RAC and OM has
        very low dark current production under Mars conditions.
 
        6. The flatfield correction divide the image by the relevant
        flatfield for the given focus motor step (RAC).
 
        7. The OM calibration is finished after the flat field correction
        since good absolute calibration data is not available for the OM.
 
        8. The final step of the RAC calibration is to divide the image by
        the absolute calibration constant for the given focus motor step.
        The calibration constant is given by the ground absolute calibration
        at focus motor step 306 (near infinite focus) and a correction
        factor derived for the change in instantaneous field of view between
        focus step 306 and the active focus step.
 
  Processing
  ==========
    Phoenix RAC RDRs are considered CODMAC Level 3 (Calibrated Data equivalent
    to NASA Level 1-A), Level 4 (Resampled Data equivalent to NASA Level
    1-B), or Level 5 (Derived Data equivalent to NASA Level 1-C, 2 or 3).
    The RDRs are to be reconstructed from Level 2 edited data, and are
    to be assembled into complete images that may include radiometric
    and/or geometric correction.
 
    Phoenix RAC instrument EDRs and RDRs will be generated by JPL&apos;s
    Multimission Instrument Processing Laboratory (MIPL) as part of the
    OPGS subsystem of the Phoenix GDS. RDRs will also be generated by
    the RAC science instrument team at the SOC facility at the
    University of Arizona, as well as at its home institution, Max Planck
    Institute for Solar System Research.
 
    RDR data products will be generated by, but not limited to, MIPL
    using the Mars Suite of VICAR image processing software at JPL, and
    the RAC science instrument team using RACCAL software at
    the SOC facility at the University of Arizona and at the team&apos;s home
    institution at Max Planck Institute for Solar System Research. The
    RDRs produced will be &apos;processed&apos; data. The input will be one or more
    Camera EDR or RDR data products and the output will be formatted
    according to the data product SIS [ALEXANDERETAL2008]. Additional
    meta-data may be added by the software to the PDS label.
 
  Data
  ====
    RDR products generated by MIPL will have a VICAR label wrapped by a
    PDS label, and their structure can include the optional EOL label
    after the binary data. RDR products not generated by MIPL may
    contain only a PDS label. Or, RDR products conforming to a standard
    other than PDS, such as JPEG compressed or certain Terrain products,
    are acceptable without a PDS header during mission operations, but
    may not be archivable.
 
    The RDR data product is comprised of radiometrically decalibrated
    and/or camera model corrected and/or geometrically altered versions
    of the raw camera data, in both single and multi-frame (mosaic)
    form. Most RDR data products will have PDS labels, or if generated
    by MIPL (OPGS), dual PDS/VICAR labels. Non-labeled RDRs include JPEG
    compressed products and the Terrain products.
 
  Software
  ========
    The RACCal software pipeline was used to generate the RDR&apos;s included in
    this dataset.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    The data set will initially be delivered and kept online.  Upon
    Mission completion, the RAC Operations RDRs will be delivered to PDS
    on DVD.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
NULL
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

