<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.pvo-v-oetp-3-hireselectrons-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>PVO VENUS ELECT TEMP PROBE CALIB HIGH RES ELECTRONS VER 1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.pioneer_venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.pvo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:oetp.pvo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.pvo-v-oetp-3-hireselectrons-v1.0__browserp_pvo-v-oetp-3-hireselectrons-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Alexander, C.J., C.T. Russell, &apos;Solar Cycle Dependence of the Location of
                   the Venus Bow Shock, Geophys. Res. Lett., 12, 369, 1985.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ALEXANDERETAL1985</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Brace, L.H., W.T. Kasprzak, H.A. Taylor, Jr., R.F. Theis, C.T. Russell, A.
                   Barnes, J.D. Mihalov, and D.M. Hunten, &apos;The Ionotail of Venus: Its
                   Configuration and Evidence for Ion Escape, J. Geophys. Res., 92, 15, 1987.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BRACEETAL1987</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Brace, L.H., W.R. Hoegy, and R.F. Theis, &apos;Solar EUV Measurements at Venus
                   Based on Photoelectron Emission from the Pioneer Venus Langmuir Probe&apos;, J.
                   Geophys. Res., 93, 7282, 1988.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BRACEETAL1988</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Brace, L.H., R.F. Theis, and J.D. Mihalov, &apos;The Response of the Venus
                   Nightside Ionosphere and Ionotail to Solar EUV and Solar Wind Dynamic
                   Pressure&apos;, J. Geophys. Res., 95, 4075, 1990.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BRACEETAL1990</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Elphic, R.C., L.H. Brace, R.F. Theis, and C.T. Russell, &apos;Venus Dayside
                   Ionosphere Conditions: Effects of Magnetic Field and Solar EUV Flux&apos;,
                   Geophys. Res. Lett., 11, 124, 1984.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ELPHICETAL1984</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Krehbiel, J.P., L.H. Brace, J.R. Cutler, W.H. Pinkus, and R.B. Kaplan,
                   &apos;Pioneer Venus Orbiter Electron Temperature Probe&apos;, IEEE Transactions on
                   Geoscience and Remote Sensing, GE-18, 49, 1980.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KREHBIELETAL1980</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mahajan, K.K, W.T. Kasprzak, L.H. Brace, H.B. Niemann, and W.R. Hoegy,
                   Response of the Venus Exospheric Temperature Measured by Neutral Mass
                   Spectrometer to the Solar EUV Measured by Langmuir Probe on the Pioneer
                   Venus Orbiter, J. Geophys. Res., 95, 1091, 1990.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MAHAJANETAL1990</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Russell, C.T., E. Chou, J.G. Luhmann, P. Gazis, L.H. Brace,
                   and W.R. Hoegy, &apos;Solar and interplanetary control of the
                   location of the Venus bow shock&apos;, J. of Geophys. Res,
                   Vol. 93, No. A6, p. 5461, 1988.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.RUSSELLETAL1988</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Theis, R.F., L.H. Brace, K.H. Schatten, C.T. Russell, J.A. Slavin, J.A.
                   Wolf, &apos;The Venus Ionosphere as an Obstacle to the Solar Wind&apos;, Advances in
                   Space Research, 1, 47, 1980.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.THEISETAL1980</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Theis, R.F., L.H. Brace, R.C. Elphic, and H.G. Mayr, &apos;New Empirical Models
                   of the Electron Temperature and Density of the Venus Ionosphere, with
                   Applications to Transterminator Flow&apos;, J. Geophys. Res., 89, 1477, 1984.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.THEISETAL1984</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>PVO-V-OETP-3-HIRESELECTRONS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>PVO VENUS ELECT TEMP PROBE CALIB HIGH RES ELECTRONS VER 1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1993-10-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1978-12-05T13:31:29.898Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1992-10-07T20:11:28.102Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. ROBERT F. THEIS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            PVO VENUS ELECT TEMP PROBE CALIB HIGH RES ELECTRONS VER 1.0
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The High Resolution Ne File. These data are based on measurements
            of the electron saturation current or the ion saturation current
            taken from as many voltampere curves as the telemetry data rate
            permitted. Since Ne is assumed equal to Ni everywhere in the
            ionosphere, either can be used as a measure of Ne. The ion
            current is used at high densities (Ni &gt; 4x104cm-3) and the
            electron current is used at lower densities. Typically, 4 to 8
            high resolution density samples are obtained in the interval
            between recovered voltampere curves, although this ratio is bit
            rate dependent. This provides Ne and Ni measurements at much
            smaller intervals than is possible from the voltampere curves
            themselves. High resolution measurements are typically available
            at 2 to 8 second intervals depending upon the telemetry rate
            available to the OETP at the time.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The High Resolution Ne File.  These data are based on
      measurements of the electron saturation current or the ion
      saturation current taken from as many voltampere curves as the
      telemetry data rate permitted.  Since Ne is assumed equal to Ni
      everywhere in the ionosphere, either can be used as a measure
      of Ne.  The ion current is used at high densities (Ni &gt;
      4x104cm-3) and the electron current is used at lower densities.
      Typically, 4 to 8 high resolution density samples are obtained
      in the interval between recovered voltampere curves, although
      this ratio is bit rate dependent.  This provides Ne and Ni
      measurements at much smaller intervals than is possible from
      the voltampere curves themselves.  High resolution measurements
      are typically available at 2 to 8 second intervals depending
      upon the telemetry rate available to the OETP at the time.
 
      The High Resolution file provides measurements of Ne (or Ni)
      within 30 minutes either side of periapsis at somewhat higher
      resolution than is possible from the voltampere curves.
      However, these measurements are less accurate when the
      spacecraft is outside the ionosphere, where Ne is typically
      well below 100 cm-3.  In sunlight, spacecraft photoelectron
      densities at the radial probe location are of the order of
      30-50 cm-3.  In darkness, the Ne measurements can be made down
      to densities of about 2 cm-3 because the pe background is
      absent.  However, the measurements made in the Venus umbra are
      often degraded at low densities because of the presence of hot
      electrons that charge the spacecraft to potentials that lie
      beyond the range of the OETP sweep voltage.  This makes it
      impossible to drive the probe positive with respect to the
      plasma potential.  In addition, deBye shielding causes the
      probe to become enveloped in the ion sheath of the spacecraft
      at very low densities, further reducing its access to the
      ambient ionospheric plasma.  Empirically derived corrections
      for this effect have been applied to the high resolution data
      in order to provide at least a lower limit of Ne, but the
      errors could exceed a factor of 2 at densities below 10 cm-3.
      This correction does not allow Ne to be less than 2 cm-3.  When
      the electron current at maximum positive voltage is less than a
      certain very low value an Ne value of 2 cm-3 is entered in the
      High Resolution file simply to serve as an upper limit on Ne,
      and to show that data were actually being taken.
 
      In summary, the high resolution Ne measurements provide about a
      factor of 8 higher resolution than the UADS file whose
      resolution is limited by the recovery rate of raw voltampere
      curves.  Therefore the high resolution data better resolve such
      small scale features as the ionopause and the plasma clouds
      often found above the ionopause.  Also, the UADS densities
      often stop somewhere within the ionopause density gradient, so
      this feature can best be resolved using the High Resolution
      data.  However, certain artifacts have not been removed from
      the data, so one must be careful not of over-interpret them.
      (See section on accuracy).
 
    Unsupported Keywords
    ====================
      NATIVE_START_TIME = UNK
      NATIVE_STOP_TIME = UNK
      PROCESSING_LEVEL_ID = 3
      PRODUCER_INSTITUTION_NAME = &apos;GODDARD SPACE FLIGHT CENTER&apos;
      SOFTWARE_FLAG = N
      PROCESSING_START_TIME = UNK
      PROCESSING_STOP_TIME = UNK
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      In general, the high resolution Ne measurements have a lower
      absolute accuracy than the UADS (voltampere curve) measurements
      because factors such as the spacecraft potential and Te are not
      available to calculate Ne more precisely.  To reduce such
      errors in the high resolution data, they are normalized to the
      voltampere curve measurements.  This normalization is entirely
      different from the Ne-Ni normalization employed in deriving the
      UADS data.
 
      Another source of error in the High Resolution Ne measurements
      is the jump discontinuities that occur when the spacecraft
      passes from sunlight to shadow.  An abrupt change in spacecraft
      potential occurs at that point, and this changes the probe
      voltage which is referenced to the spacecraft.  The Ne
      measurements cannot easily be corrected for this change because
      they are not based on voltampere curves but measurements at a
      fixed positive potential.  Therefore a discontinuity may occur
      in Ne at the sunlight-shadow boundary if Ne is sufficiently low
      that spacecraft photoelectron emission affects the spacecraft
      potential.
 
      The precision of the high resolution data is probably somewhat
      better than that of the UADS data because the latter may suffer
      from the effects of volt ampere curve distortion due to small
      scale density variations and spin effects which do not show up
      in the single point samples used in the high resolution
      measurements.  This feature makes the high resolution data more
      valuable in resolving small scale, and small amplitude plasma
      structure.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>78-051A-01F</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XD-B3A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

