<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ody-m-mar-2-redr-raw-data-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ODYSSEY MARS MARIE REFORMATTED RAW DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.2001_mars_odyssey::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.ody::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mar.ody::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-mar-2-redr-raw-data-v1.0__browserp_ody-m-mar-2-redr-raw-data-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Zeitlin, C., F. Riman, S. Joy and M. Sharlow, MARIE Standard Products
                   Archive Volume Software Interface Specification (MARIE Archive Volume
                   SIS), Version 1.03 (draft document), Planetary Data System, September 11,
                   2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ZEITLINETAL2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>ODY-M-MAR-2-REDR-RAW-DATA-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ODYSSEY MARS MARIE REFORMATTED RAW DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2002-07-18</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2001-04-23</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. CARY ZEITLIN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Mars Odyssey MARIE raw (EDR) data (cruise, prime mission, etc.),
            edited and formatted as simple binary tables but otherwise
            unprocessed.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The MARIE (Martian Radiation Environment Experiment), aboard the
            2001 Mars Odyssey spacecraft, was launched on April 7, 2001, and
            arrived at Mars on October 24, 2001. Data were collected
            intermittently during the cruise phase, starting in late April
            and ending in late July. A problem with MARIE&apos;s onboard
            computer occurred in early August, and the instrument was turned
            off until early March, 2002, after Odyssey&apos;s mapping orbit
            had been established. Data have been collected from that time to
            the present without major interruption. Routine minor
            interruptions of up to 48 hours have occurred during the orbital
            phase when the instrument&apos;s data is erased from local
            storage (after having been downloaded). MARIE is oriented to
            point in the direction opposite Odyssey&apos;s velocity vector.
            Space radiation is for the most part isotropic, so the
            orientation of Odyssey is usually not critical and references to
            external coordinate systems are not a part of the data returned
            by MARIE. There is one exception to the statement that space
            radiation is isotropic: During the early stages of solar particle
            events, there can be directionality in the particle flux.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The MARIE (Martian Radiation Environment Experiment), aboard the
    2001 Mars Odyssey spacecraft, was launched on April 7, 2001, and
    arrived at Mars on October 24, 2001. Data were collected
    intermittently during the cruise phase, starting in late April and
    ending in late July. A problem with MARIE&apos;s onboard computer
    occurred in early August, and the instrument was turned off until
    early March, 2002, after Odyssey&apos;s mapping orbit had been
    established. Data have been collected from that time to the present
    without major interruption. Routine minor interruptions of up to 48
    hours have occurred during the orbital phase; the outages occur
    when the instrument&apos;s data is erased from local storage (after
    having been downloaded). MARIE is oriented to point in the
    direction opposite Odyssey&apos;s velocity vector. Space radiation is
    for the most part isotropic, so the orientation of Odyssey is
    usually not critical and references to external coordinate systems
    are not a part of the data returned by MARIE. There is one
    exception to the statement that space radiation is isotropic:
    During the early stages of solar particle events, there can be
    directionality in the particle flux.
 
    A manuscript containing a detailed description of MARIE is in
    preparation at the time of this writing (September 2002).
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The MARIE consists primarily of silicon detectors, of three
    different types: the A detectors, which are square in cross-section
    (25.4 mm on a side) and 1 mm in depth; the B detectors, circular,
    63.5 mm diameter and 5 mm thick; and the PSDs, or
    position-sensitive detectors. The PSDs are square double-sided
    strip detectors with 24 1-mm strips on each side (the strips on one
    side are orthogonal to those on the other side), and have a
    thickness of 0.3 mm. There are two A detectors, A1 and A2;
    sandwiched in between them are PSD1 and PSD2; behind A2, there are
    the B detectors, B1 through B4. Downstream of B4 is a circular
    piece of quartz, 10 mm thick, that radiates photons (Cerenkov
    radiation) generated by the passage of high-velocity particles
    through it. The Cerenkov photons are reflected by a 45-degree
    mirror into a photomultiplier tube that sits out of the path of
    particles that hit the detectors.
 
    The MARIE is triggered by a coincidence of hits in detectors A1 and
    A2. Once triggered, the data acquisition system records 12-bit
    digitized outputs that are proportional to the energies deposited
    in the A and B detectors. A two-byte data word is stored for each
    of these channels. The pulse height from the Cerenkov phototube is
    similarly digitized in 12 bits and stored.
 
    Readout of the PSDs is more complex. Each PSD has two orthogonal
    sides, referred to as columns and rows. The following description
    applies to each side of each detector. Onboard hardware analyzes
    the signals from each of the 24 strips and finds the two largest
    pulse heights. For each, the pulse height is digitized in 8 bits
    (256 channels) and stored, along with the strip number. The largest
    pulse height and position are referred to as &apos;event1&apos;, the
    second-largest as &apos;event2.&apos; The event2 data are usually noise.
    Four quantities are stored for each side of each detector, so that
    a total of sixteen words (thirty-two bytes) of PSD data are stored
    on each event. The eight-bit pulse heights are referred to as
    &apos;magnitudes&apos; (abbreviated to &apos;_Mag&apos; in the list below). The
    positions (listed as &apos;_Pos&apos; below) are valid only when in the range
    1 to 24.
 
    The full 72-byte data structure for each event is listed below.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    These are unprocessed raw data.  They have been reformatted into a
    binary or ASCII table structure.  Obviously bad records have been
    removed.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The primary data in the REDR data set are the event and count data.
    The event data files are characterized by file names that begin
    with EVN.  The count data have file names that begin with CNT.  The
    other data in the REDR data set are ancillary data.  These are
    comprised of four types:  board files (names beginning with BRD),
    detector files (DET), high voltage files (EXT), and power files
    (PWR).
 
    The event data and the count data are in binary format.  All of the
    other data types are in ASCII format.
 
    The six types of files in this dataset are described below, in this
    and the next section.
 
    --------------------
    Event Files (*.EVN):
    --------------------
 
    The principal (and normally largest) files in this data set are the
    event files.  Each record in an event file contains data pertaining
    to a specific particle detection event.  For this purpose, an
    &apos;event&apos; is considered to occur when a signal is detected by the
    A1 and A2 cards and is above threshold for both of these cards.  At
    the time a coincidence of A1 and A2 signals is detected, the
    digitizers for all detectors are polled, as is MARIE&apos;s internal
    clock, and the data are written to local storage. An event file is
    a binary table of events.
 
                     Table 1 - Event Data Format
    ____________________________________________________________________
    Column     - Data Type -Description
    ____________________________________________________________________
    TypeId     - byte      -Record type identifier, Identifiers are:
               -           -42 = Count data,  59 = Event data
               -           -91 = Engineering  107= Extended Eng
               -           -all others are invalid.
    InstID     - byte      -Instrument id number (MARIE = 1).
    RunId      - byte      -The run_Id is a number calculated using
               -           -the date and time of any change in the
               -           -instrument configuration. This value should
               -           -be constant in any data file.
    RecordId   - byte      -The recordId is a sequential record counter
               -           -that increments any time MARIE writes any
               -           -type of data record (event, count, etc.).
    Len        - Int2      -The length of the data record in bytes.
    CheckSum   - Int2      -Sum of the bytes in the record.
    Spare      - byte      -Unused byte
    Time       - real6     -6 byte floating point time tag - see
               -           -discussion
    EventsArray- Int2(23)  -A 23 element array of event data - see below
    FlagsArray - byte(11)  -An unused data array that is present in
               -           -order to keep the data format the same as it
               -           -is in a similar instrument operated by this
               -           -team.
 
    The 23 2-byte words of detector data are ordered as follows:
 
           A1, A2, B1, B2, B3, B4,  C1; ( for all, valid data in the
                                          lowest 12 bits )
           PSD1_Row_Event1_Mag;   ( valid data in the lowest 8 bits )
           PSD1_Row_Event1_Pos;   ( valid data in the range 1 to 24 )
           PSD1_Row_Event2_Mag;   ( valid data in the lowest 8 bits )
           PSD1_Row_Event2_Pos;   ( valid data in the range 1 to 24 )
           PSD1_Col_Event1_Mag;   ( valid data in the lowest 8 bits )
           PSD1_Col_Event1_Pos;   ( valid data in the range 1 to 24 )
           PSD1_Col_Event2_Mag;   ( valid data in the lowest 8 bits )
           PSD1_Col_Event2_Pos;   ( valid data in the range 1 to 24 )
           PSD2_Row_Event1_Mag;   ( valid data in the lowest 8 bits )
           PSD2_Row_Event1_Pos;   ( valid data in the range 1 to 24 )
           PSD2_Row_Event2_Mag;   ( valid data in the lowest 8 bits )
           PSD2_Row_Event2_Pos;   ( valid data in the range 1 to 24 )
           PSD2_Col_Event1_Mag;   ( valid data in the lowest 8 bits )
           PSD2_Col_Event1_Pos;   ( valid data in the range 1 to 24 )
           PSD2_Col_Event2_Mag;   ( valid data in the lowest 8 bits )
           PSD2_Col_Event2_Pos;   ( valid data in the range 1 to 24 )
 
    The first nine bytes are instrument and record identifiers,
    checksums, etc. Bytes 10-15 are the timestamp. Detector data begin
    at byte 16 and consist of 23 2-byte words. Bytes 62-72 are flags,
    the first seven of which are unused; the last four are the PSD
    status registers (one for each side of each PSD).
 
    --------------------
    Count Files (*.CNT):
    --------------------
 
    A count file is a binary file of count accumulations over one-minute
    periods. For this purpose, a &apos;count&apos; occurs when any card detects
    a signal that is above its threshold.  The record structure is
    outlined below.
 
                    Table 2 - Count Data Format
    ____________________________________________________________________
    Column     - Data Type -Description
    ____________________________________________________________________
    TypeId     - byte      -Record type identifier, Identifiers are:
               -           -42 = Count data,  59 = Event data
               -           -91 = Engineering  107= Extended Eng
               -           -all others are invalid.
    InstID     - byte      -Instrument id number (MARIE = 1).
    RunId      - byte      -The run_Id is a number calculated using
               -           -the date and time of any change in the
               -           -instrument configuration. This value should
               -           -be constant in any data file.
    RecordId   - byte      -The recordId is a sequential record counter
               -           -that increments any time MARIE writes any
               -           -type of data record (event, count, etc.).
    Len        - Int2      -The length of the data record in bytes.
    CheckSum   - Int2      -Sum of the bytes of the in the record.
    Time       - real6     -6 byte floating point time tag - see
               -           -discussion
    CntA1      - Int2      -Accumulated counts in detector A1
    CntA2      - Int2      -Accumulated counts in detector A2
    CntB1      - Int2      -Accumulated counts in detector B1
    CntB2      - Int2      -Accumulated counts in detector B2
    CntC       - Int2      -Accumulated counts in detector C
 
    ---------------------------
    Note on 6-byte real values:
    ---------------------------
 
    A few of the columns (specifically, the Time values) in the CNT
    and EVN files have the format of a 6-byte real number.  This format
    is summarized below.  Bits are numbered from left to right, starting
    with 0 as the high bit of the first byte read in order from the
    file. (Thus, for example, bit 8 will be the high bit of the byte
    that is second in file order.)
 
    Bits 0-7 are an exponent (e).
    Bit 40 is a sign bit (1 for sign = -1, 0 for sign = +1).
 
    The rest of the bits form a 39-bit real m (mantissa).
    To calculate this, start with m = 0 and x = 0.5, then run through
    the bits in the following order, each time adding x if the
    bit is 1 and then dividing x by 2 regardless of bit value:
    bits 41-47, 32-39, 24-31, 16-23, 8-15.
 
    The value of the real number is: sign * (1 + m) * 2**(e - 129).
 
    The real number represents the time in minutes on the Julian
    calendar that takes as its starting time 12 hours Universal Time
    (Greenwich mean noon) on noon of November 24, -4713.
 
    In the PDS labels for these data, the 6-byte reals are declared as
    character strings to avoid compatibility problems.  Hence these
    reals may be displayed as character strings by some software.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    The ancillary data for this dataset consist of the four types of
    instrument housekeeping data. Each of the ancillary file types are
    described below.
 
    -----------------------
    Detector Files(*.DET):
    -----------------------
 
    These are ASCII files describing the detector temperatures with a
    UTC Time Stamp followed by a Julian time.  The file heading lists
    the order of the boards as follows:
 
            Table 3 - Detector Temperature Data Format
    ____________________________________________________________________
    Column     - Data Type -Description
    ____________________________________________________________________
    UTC        - Char(19)  -UTC time tag, i.e.   10APR02  06:31:52.34
    ET         - F10.3     -Seconds since the J2000 epoch
    A1 temp    - F10.7     -Detector A1 temperature (degrees Celsius)
    A2 temp    - F10.7     -Detector A2 temperature (degrees Celsius)
    B1-2 temp  - F10.7     -Detector B1 temperature (degrees Celsius)
    B3-4 temp  - F10.7     -Detector B2 temperature (degrees Celsius)
    C temp     - F10.7     -Detector C  temperature (degrees Celsius)
    Power temp - F10.7     -Power card temperature (degrees Celsius)
    CPU temp   - F10.7     -CPU temperature (degrees Celsius)
    PSD1 temp  - F10.7     -PSD1 temperature (degrees Celsius)
    PSD2 temp  - F10.7     -PSD2 temperature (degrees Celsius)
 
    --------------------
    Board Files (*.BRD):
    --------------------
 
    These are text files describing the board temperatures with a UTC
    Time Stamp followed by a Julian time.  The file heading lists the
    order of the boards as follows:
 
            Table 4 - Board Temperatures Data Format
    ____________________________________________________________________
    Column     - Data Type -Description
    ____________________________________________________________________
    UTC        - Char(19)  -UTC time tag, i,e   10APR02  06:31:52.34
    ET         - F10.3     -Seconds since the J2000 epoch
    A1 temp    - F10.7     -A1 electronics temperature (degrees Celsius)
    A2 temp    - F10.7     -A2 electronics temperature (degrees Celsius)
    B1/2 temp  - F10.7     -B1 electronics temperature (degrees Celsius)
    B3/4 temp  - F10.7     -B2 electronics temperature (degrees Celsius)
    C temp     - F10.7     -C  electronics temperature (degrees Celsius)
    Power temp - F10.7     -Power card temperature (degrees Celsius)
    CPU temp   - F10.7     -CPU temperature (degrees Celsius)
    PSD1 temp  - F10.7     -PSD1 electronics temperature (degrees
    Celsius) PSD2 temp  - F10.7     -PSD2 electronics temperature
    (degrees Celsius)
 
    The BRD files differ from the DET files because each board comprises
    only a part of a detector, and has a separate thermistor that
    monitors the board&apos;s temperature.
 
    --------------------
    Power Files (*.PWR):
    --------------------
 
    The power files are text files describing the power consumption in
    mW, with a UTC Time Stamp followed by a Julian time.  The file
    heading lists the order of the boards as follows:
 
            Table 5 - Board Power Consumption Data Format
    ____________________________________________________________________
    Column     - Data Type -Description
    ____________________________________________________________________
    UTC        - Char(19)  -UTC time tag, i.e.   10APR02  06:31:52.34
    ET         - F10.3     -Seconds since the J2000 epoch
    A1 power   - F10.7     -A1 electronics power consumption (mW)
    A2 power   - F10.7     -A2 electronics power consumption (mW)
    B1/2 power - F10.7     -B1 electronics power consumption (mW)
    B3/4 power - F10.7     -B2 electronics power consumption (mW)
    C power    - F10.7     -C  electronics power consumption (mW)
    Power power- F10.7     -Power card power consumption (mW)
    CPU power  - F10.7     -CPU power consumption (mW)
    PSD1 power - F10.7     -PSD1 electronics power consumption (mW)
    PSD2 power - F10.7     -PSD2 electronics power consumption (mW)
 
    ---------------------------
    High Voltage Files (*.EXT):
    ---------------------------
 
    The high voltage files are text files describing the voltages
    (in volts) in each board, with a UTC Time Stamp followed by a Julian
    time.  The file heading lists the order of the boards as follows:
 
           Table 6 - Detector High Voltage Data Format
    ____________________________________________________________________
    Column     - Data Type -Description
    ____________________________________________________________________
    UTC        - Char(19)  -UTC time tag, i.e.   10APR02  06:31:52.34
    ET         - F10.3     -Seconds since the J2000 epoch
    A1 HV      - F10.7     -A1 detector high voltage (V)
    A2 HV      - F10.7     -A2 detector high voltage (V)
    B1-2 HV    - F10.7     -B1 detector high voltage (V)
    B3/4 HV    - F10.7     -B2 detector high voltage (V)
    C HV       - F10.7     -C  detector high voltage (V)
    Power HV   - F10.7     -Power card voltage minus battery voltage (V)
    spare      - F10.7     -spare column
    PSD1 +5V   - F10.7     -PSD1 detector voltage (V)
    PSD2 +5V   - F10.7     -PSD2 detector voltage (V)
 
    ----------------------------------------------
    Explanatory Notes on The Above File Summaries:
    ----------------------------------------------
 
    B1/2 is Detectors B1 &amp; B2 on the same board (One Temperature, 2
                                                 detector values)
    B3/4 is Detectors B3 &amp; B4 on the same board (One Temperature, 2
                                                 detector values)
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    MARIE&apos;s internal coordinate system is defined by the geometry of the
    detector. The PSDs have their own coordinate system in the sense
    that each strip (corresponding to a row or a column) is assigned a
    sequential number from 1 to 24. These values are not referenced to
    any other coordinate system, as the primary purpose of the PSDs is
    to calculate the angle at which incident particles traverse the
    silicon detectors. With valid hits in all rows and columns, the
    angle THETA with respect to the vertical (normal incidence) can be
    calculated as follows. We define
 
    DELTAr = PSD1_Row_Pos - PSD2_Row_Pos,
    DELTAc = PSD1_Col_Pos - PSD2_Col_Pos, and
    d = the distance between PSD1 and PSD2. Then
 
            tan(THETA) = [ (DELTAr**2 + DELTAc**2) / d**2 ]**1/2
 
    where ** indicates exponentiation.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    A version of the software the conversion of raw to reduced data is
    provided in the EXTRAS directory of the archive volume.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    Data are archived on recordable DVD (DVD-R) in UDF/ISO 9660 Bridge
    format with ISO 9660 level 2 compliance in the ISO partition.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
 
 
    Review
    ------
      These data have been reviewed by the instrument team and are of
      the highest quality that can be generated at this time. After
      submission to the PDS, these data underwent PDS peer review.
 
 
    Data Coverage/Quality
    ---------------------
      MARIE was on for parts of the 2001 Mars Odyssey cruise phase,
      starting in late April 2001 and ending in late July 2001. A
      problem with the onboard computer occurred in early August, and
      the instrument was turned off until mid-March, 2002, after
      Odyssey&apos;s mapping orbit had been established. Data have been
      collected from that time to the present without major
      interruption. Routine minor interruptions of up to 36 hours have
      been encountered during the orbital phase; the outages occur when
      the instrument&apos;s data is erased (after having been downloaded).
      Additional shorter outages of approximately 2 hours duration occur
      on a daily basis while data are downloaded.
 
      During processing of these data into RDR data, it was found that
      some of the time stamps may be out of chronological order or
      contain corrupt values of the year.  These problems do not affect
      the majority of the data records.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
 
    Geometric Acceptance
    --------------------
      MARIE&apos;s geometry is optimized for detecting particles coming into
      the detector (hitting A1 first) in a forward cone of half-angle
      approximately 30 degrees. The angle is defined with respect to the
      centerline of the silicon detectors. Particles incident at larger
      angles may hit one or more detectors, but will not satisfy the
      requirement of coincident hits in A1 and A2. Forward-going
      particles encounter minimal (but finite) mass before entering
      MARIE, and must have residual range sufficient to penetrate as far
      as A2. As of this writing (May 2002), best estimates of the
      material in front of MARIE lead to the prediction that the minimum
      free-space (i.e., before encountering any material) kinetic energy
      required for a proton to reach A2 is about 30 MeV. For helium-4
      ions, the minimum kinetic energy is 30 MeV/nucleon, and for
      heavier ions, the energy per nucleon increases as a function of
      the ion&apos;s charge and mass. MARIE can also be triggered by
      particles entering from the rear, provided they are sufficiently
      energetic to hit both A2 and A1. For a proton, this corresponds to
      a minimum energy of 72 MeV incident on B4. However, any such
      particle must pass through a considerable (currently unknown) mass
      in order to reach B4. (The mass in question is primarily due to
      Odyssey&apos;s oxidizer tank.)  Backward-going particles must therefore
      be far more energetic than their forward-going counterparts in
      order to trigger MARIE&apos;s readout.
 
      In the data, backward-going particles can, in some cases, be
      distinguished by the patterns of energy deposition they leave in
      the silicon detectors; for particular particle/energy
      combinations, these patterns may be quite distinct from those of
      forward-going particles of the same type and energy. In addition,
      the Cerenkov detector is directional, and no Cerenkov photons will
      be recorded for backwards-going particles.
 
 
    Saturation of Electronics
    -------------------------
      As of May 2002, all MARIE data have been taken with all silicon
      detectors operating at full depletion. The gains of the
      electronics combined with the limitations on input voltage into
      the analog-to-digital converters (ADCs) - are such that the A
      channels saturate at approximately 70 MeV energy deposited, while
      the B channels saturate at about 350 MeV energy deposited. Because
      deposited energy is a function of the charge (Z) squared of an
      incident heavy ion, this limits the detectable range of particle
      charges. In the present configuration, the largest usable signal
      corresponds to highly-energetic ions of charge 11. For more
      highly-charged particles, the signals are so large that the
      digitizer outputs go to full scale, and all resolution is lost.
      The Galactic Cosmic Radiation contains all elements up to uranium,
      though ions heavier than iron (charge 26) are rare. At present,
      and for the foreseeable future, ions with charge 12 and greater
      are detected by MARIE, but with no resolution.
 
 
    PSD Performance
    ---------------
      The PSD performance for sparsely-ionizing particles such as
      protons is known to be marginal. The detectors are thin
      (300 microm), so that signals are small and noise (which falls
      with increasing detector depth) is relatively large. The onboard
      algorithm for finding hits returns many 0 values (no hit found),
      many more values of 1 than is physically reasonable, and in the
      case of PSD1 columns, many more values of 24 than is physically
      reasonable. It is likely the case that the edge channels of the
      PSDs are nosier than those in the middle, and hence are often
      mistakenly identified by the onboard processing algorithm as
      having been hit. If the detectors were working optimally, all
      histograms of row and column positions would show broad
      distributions peaked in the middle. Only the distribution of hits
      in the PSD1 rows approximates the expected shape. One possible
      improvement would be to raise the software thresholds the
      hit-finding algorithm in the onboard firmware uses.  This would
      result in more &apos;0&apos; values (no hit found) but would reduce or
      eliminate erroneous positions from noise hits. At the time of this
      writing (September 2002), the instrument team is also
      investigating the possibility that some non-physical readings
      are caused by bit flips in the processing firmware. Some of
      these may be correctable in future processing.
 
 
    Cerenkov Detector Performance
    -----------------------------
      The Cerenkov detector performance is currently marginal. Signals
      are far smaller than expected, which suggests that the voltage on
      the photomultiplier tube is too low or possibly that the alignment
      of the 45 degree mirror is bad. Attempts to raise the phototube
      voltage failed due to a bug in the onboard control software. This
      may be corrected in the future when new control software is
      uploaded.
 
 
    Clock Issues and Time Tag Significance
    --------------------------------------
      Occasionally, MARIE&apos;s clock appears to jump backward by a fairly
      large interval (often on the order of minutes) from one event to
      the next. The source of this error is unknown. Usually, within the
      next few events, the clock jumps ahead to where one would expect
      it to be. Such jumps have been noted to occur up to 25 times in a
      file of 50,000 event records. As of this writing (September 2002),
      the instrument team is unable to diagnose or cure the problem. As
      few events are affected, and most users will likely be binning
      data in time bins on the order of many minutes or even hours,
      these do not present a serious problem.
 
      A second category of clock problems occurs when MARIE data is
      being downloaded to the spacecraft&apos;s data buffer at midnight.
      When this happens, the MARIE clock does not increment the day
      counter, and when data acquisition resumes, the clock is one day
      behind.  It remains in this state until the next data erase
      sequence (which typically occurs about once every 7 to 10 days,
      depending on solar activity), at which time MARIE&apos;s clock is
      synchronized to the Odyssey master clock and the problem is fixed
      (until the next time it occurs). For this reason, deliberate
      efforts have been made to avoid downloading MARIE data over
      midnight boundaries. While the problem has not been entirely
      eliminated, the frequency with which it occurs has decreased.
 
 
    Calibration Issues
    ------------------
      There are considerable uncertainties in the calibration constants
      that are used to convert raw pulse height readings to deposited
      energies. For the A1 and A2 detectors, we estimate the
      uncertainties to be +- 20%. For the B detectors, we estimate the
      uncertainties to be +- 15%. These are uncertainties in the
      absolute scale of deposited energy; they are not expected to vary
      significantly within a particular data set, but they may show
      long-term variations. As of this writing (Dec. 2002), further
      work to determine these constants with greater precision is in
      progress, using stopping protons from Solar Particle Events.
      Periodic monitoring of the constants will be needed to look for,
      and correct, any drifts in amplifier gains.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

