<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.co-e-sw-j-s-mag-4-summ-1secavg-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CASSINI ORBITER MAG CALIBRATED SUMMARY 1 SEC AVERAGES V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mag.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.saturn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:plasma_stream.solar_wind::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.co-e-sw-j-s-mag-4-summ-1secavg-v1.0__browserp_co-e-sw-j-s-mag-4-summ-1secavg-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CO-E/SW/J/S-MAG-4-SUMM-1SECAVG-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CASSINI ORBITER MAG CALIBRATED SUMMARY 1 SEC AVERAGES V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-01-25</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2000-01-20T02:28:30Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-03-31T23:59:58.5Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JOSEPH N. MAFI</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Dougherty, M.K., S. Kellock, A.P. Slootweg, N. Achilleos, S.P.
            Joy, and J.N. Mafi, CASSINI ORBITER MAG CALIBRATED SUMMARY 1 SEC
            AVERAGES V1.0, CO-E/SW/J/S-MAG-4-SUMM-1SECAVG-V1.0, NASA
            Planetary Data System, 2013
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains calibrated 1 second averaged Cassini
            magnetometer data, for the entire Cassini mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains calibrated 1 second averaged Cassini
            magnetometer data, for the entire Cassini mission. These data are
            provided in Kronographic (KRTP, KSO, KSM) coordinates at Saturn,
            Geographic coordinates (GSE, GSM) for the Earth flyby,
            Jovigraphic coordinates for the Jupiter flyby, and RTN
            coordinates for the entire mission. These data were calibrated
            and converted to physical coordinates from the Cassini MAG Raw
            Data Set (CO-E/SW/J/S-MAG-2-REDR-RAW-DATA-V1.0), by the Cassini
            MAG team at Imperial College. The data averaged to 1 second at
            the PDS-PPI node at UCLA.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
      This data set contains magnetic-field data acquired during the
      cruise and tour phases of the Cassini mission to Saturn.
      On 16 August, 1999 two days before the spacecraft commenced Earth
      swingby, the magnetometer boom was unfurled into its extended
      position; a  configuration it maintained for the remainder of the
      mission.  Magnetic-field data acquired prior to boom deployment are
      limited and are significantly affected by spacecraft noise. These
      data are of no scientific value and, consequently, do not form part
      of this data set.
 
      Cassini carried two magnetometers: a fluxgate magnetometer (FGM)
      and a vector-helium magnetometer capable of operating in both
      vector and scalar mode (V/SHM). This data set contains calibrated,
      and averaged magnetic-field data recorded by the FGM instrument.
      The data are provided in both 1 second. The 1 second averaged data
      files span 1 quarter of year prior to arrival at Saturn, and 1 Saturn
      orbit following arrival at Saturn. The data are provided in RTN
      coordinates throughout the mission. After arrival at Saturn, the
      Saturn-centered KRTP, KSO, and KSM coordinates are also provided.
      Earth-centered, and Jupiter-centered coordinates are provided for
      the flybys of those two planets. All data files are ASCII.
 
      These data were calibrated, and rotated into geophysical coordinates
      by the Cassini MAG team at Imperial College (IC), and provided to
      the PDS/PPI node via the Cassini MAG team Co-I at UCLA. In other
      words these data use the same calibration as the data routinely
      delivered to the Cassini MAG team. Averaging for the 1 second data
      was performed at the PDS-PPI Node.
 
 
      Processing
      ==========
 
 
      Coordinate Systems
      ==================
      The coordinate systems in which the data are provided in vary by
      mission phase, and are designed to support both solar wind and
      planetary magnetospheric studies.
 
 
      Solar Wind Coordinates
      ----------------------
 
         Radial-Tangential-Normal Coordinates (RTN)
         ------------------------------------------
         RTN coordinates consist of R (radial component, Sun to the
         spacecraft), T (tangential component, parallel to the Solar
         Equatorial plane and perpendicular to R), and N (normal component,
         completes right handed set).
 
      Saturn-Centered Coordinates
      ---------------------------
 
         Kronocentric body-fixed, J2000 spherical Coordinates (KRTP)
         -----------------------------------------------------------
         KRTP magnetic field vector components form the standard right-handed
         spherical triad (R, Theta, Phi) for a planet-centered system.
         Namely, R is radial (along the line from the center of Saturn to the
         center of the spacecraft), and positive away from Saturn. Phi, the
         azimuthal component, is parallel to the Kronographic equator (Omega
         x R) and positive in the direction of corotation. Theta, the
         &apos;southward&apos; component, completes the right-handed set.
 
         Kronocentric Solar Magnetospheric Coordinates (KSM)
         ---------------------------------------------------
         KSM is a cartesian Saturn-center coordinate system where X points
         from Saturn to the Sun, the X-Z plane contains Saturn&apos;s centered
         magnetic dipole axis, M, and Y completes right handed set.
 
         Kronocentric Solar Orbital Coordinates (KSO)
         --------------------------------------------
         KSO is a cartesian Saturn-centered coordinate system where X points
         from Saturn to the Sun, Z is parallel to Saturn&apos;s orbital plane
         upward normal, and Y completes the right handed set.
 
      Earth-Centered Coordinates
      --------------------------
 
      Jupiter-Centered Coordinates
      ----------------------------
 
         Jovicentric Body-Fixed (IAU_JUPITER) Coordinates (J3)
         -----------------------------------------------------
         J3 is a body-fixed Jovicentric cartesian coordinate system
         consistent with the IAU 1997 definition of the System 3 prime
         meridian where X is in the Jovian equatorial plane, along S3
         1997 Prime Meridian, Z is parallel to the Jovian spin axis,
         and Y completes right-handed set.
 
         Jovicentric Body-Fixed Magnetospheric Coordinates (JMXYZ)
         ---------------------------------------------------------
         JMAG XYZ is a body-fixed Jovicentric cartesian coordinate system
         where X is in the plane containing Z and the S3 1997 Prime Meridian,
         Z is the Jupiter magnetic dipole, and Y completes right handed set.
 
 
      SPICE
      =====
      The data product labels associated with the data set include a list of
      the SPICE kernels that were used in calibrating the associated data,
      and coverting them to physical coordinates. While the SPICE kernels
      used are not part of this data set, these kernels are archived at the
      PDS-NAIF node on the volume cosp_1000. Note that the SPICE kernels
      listed in each of the product labels may be uniquely identified by
      their file name.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      Product Versions
      ================
      PRODUCT_VERSION_ID 1 data were calibrated at the PDS/PPI node at
      UCLA using software (CAL02), and calibration data provided by the
      Cassini MAG team. The process used the same calibration data that
      was provided with the Raw Magnetometer data archive (Data Set ID:
      CO-E/SW/J/S-MAG-2-REDR-RAW-DATA-V1.0). The data were then rotated
      into geophysical coordinates using MAG team additonal MAG team
      provided code (TRANSCAL) and spice kernels obtained from NAIF.
      The data were then averaged, and reformatted to ASCII using code
      developed at PDS/PPI.
 
      PRODUCT_VERSION_ID 2 data were calibrated, and rotated into
      geophysical coordinates by the Cassini MAG team at Imperial
      College, and provided to the PDS/PPI node via the MAG team Co-I at
      UCLA. Averaging to 1 second was performed at PDS/PPI (UCLA). The
      data were then reformatted at PDS/PPI to match the format used for
      the version 1 data.
 
      PRODUCT_VERSION_ID 3 have followed the same path as the version 2
      data, however, the data have been recalibrated.
 
      PRODUCT_VERSION_ID 4 data were processed following the same
      procedure that was followed for the version 2 data. However,
      previously undetected mis-time tagged data which were present in
      the full-resolution data were removed prior to averaging the data
      to 1 second. More details on the timing errors are provided in the
      confidence level note (below).
 
      PRODUCT_VERSION_ID 5 data were processed following the same
      procedure that was followed for the version 4 data, including the
      removal of mis-timed data before averaging. In addition, version 5
      products have been modified to satisfy liens set in the PDS peer
      review. Including a change in record formatting, and changes to
      the PDS labels.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

