<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ear-e-rebelxt-7-image-mars-analog-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>EARTH BASED CANON REBEL XT LVL IMAGES OF MARS ANALOGS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:unk.unk::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-e-rebelxt-7-image-mars-analog-v1.0__browserp_ear-e-rebelxt-7-image-mars-analog-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-e-rebelxt-7-image-mars-analog-v1.0__browser_ear-e-rebelxt-7-image-mars-analog-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-e-rebelxt-7-image-mars-analog-v1.0__dvo_ear-e-rebelxt-7-image-mars-analog-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Yingst, R.A. and K.R. Kuhlman, A Mars-oriented image library of handlens-scale
                   features and textures: The 1996 Skeidararsandur Joklhlaup example, GSA Spec.
                   Pap., 2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.YINGST-KUHLMAN2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Yingst, R.A., M.E. Schmidt, and R.C.F. Lentz, Understanding Mars at the
                   microscale by imaging terrestrial analogs: The handlens atlas, Lunar Planet.
                   Sci. Conf.., 38th, Abs. 1130, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.YINGSTETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Yingst, R.A., M.E. Schmidt and R.C.F. Lentz, The handlens atlas: A terrestrial
                   image library of microscale structures as analogues for Mars, GSA Abstracts &amp;
                   Programs, Abs. 149187, 2008.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.YINGSTETAL2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Yingst, R.A., M.E. Schmidt, and R.C.F. Lentz, Observations of a potential Mars
                   analog at the microscale using rover-inspired methods: A 10-sol observation of
                   Fort Rock tuff ring, J. Geophys. Res., 114, E06004, doi:10.1029/2008JE003223,
                   2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.YINGSTETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>EAR-E-REBELXT-7-IMAGE-MARS-ANALOG-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>EARTH BASED CANON REBEL XT LVL IMAGES OF MARS ANALOGS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2009-11-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2006-08-21T23:32:42Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2009-04-20T13:33:23Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>R. AILEEN YINGST</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Yingst, R.A., Mars analog handlens-scale image database,
            EAR-E-REBELXT-7-IMAGE-MARS-ANALOG-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2009.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains JPEG images of potential martian analog
            materials taken at 10 micrometers/pixel, approximately the scale
            of a geologist&apos;s handlens, along with a table of associated
            measurements and other information about each sample.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Collection of hand-lens-scale images of Mars-analog materials and
            associated measurements.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This dataset represents a library of images of potential martian analog
    features and materials, taken at 10 micrometer/pixel resolution,
    approximately at the scale of a geologist&apos;s handlens. The purpose of this
    library is twofold: (1) to characterize some important martian analogs;
    and (2) to provide a convenient tool for the community to access those
    data for comparison.
 
    The library consists of 271 images at 10 micrometer/pixel taken in situ at
    eleven locations: Skeidararsandur, Iceland; Lanai Lookout, Hawaii;
    Tantalus Formation (Koko Crater), Hawaii; Kau Desert, Hawaii; Kilauea Iki
    and Halemaumau Crater, Hawaii; Deschutes Formation, Crooked River Gorge,
    Oregon; Fort Rock Tuff Ring, Oregon; Hole-in-the-Ground Maar, Oregon; Lava
    Butte, Oregon and Big Obsidian Flow, Oregon.  Materials in each image are
    described by the following characteristics:  grain size range and average;
    grain roundness range; grain sphericity range; grain texture, sorting,
    fabric, orientation and packing; sedimentary structure; and a list of
    prominent grain colors. The library is searchable by any of these
    characteristics. Ancillary data include geologic context data and context
    images of all sample locations at centimeter- and meter-scale resolution.
    The latitude, longitude and elevation of each sampling location, where
    known, are also recorded.
 
    For more detailed information regarding the purpose and scope of the
    library, please see [YINGSTETAL2008] and [YINGST&amp;KUHLMAN2009] as listed in
    the REF.CAT document.
 
 
  Data Acquisition
  ================
 
    Images were collected in situ at field sites in nine regions:
    Skeidararsandur, Iceland; Lanai Lookout, Hawaii; Keanakakoi Ash Beds,
    Hawaii; Kilauea Iki, Hawaii; Deschutes Formation, Crooked River Gorge,
    Oregon; Fort Rock Tuff Ring, Oregon; Hole-in-the-Ground Maar, Oregon; Lava
    Butte, Oregon and Big Obsidian Flow, Oregon. Formations of interest were
    imaged for context at meter- to centimeter-scale, then features identified
    as most analogous to specific martian features were imaged at ~10
    micrometer/pixel.
 
    Because of the set-up time required, a large number of image stacks of
    each individual feature could not be produced. Instead, the goal was to
    summarize as completely as possible the unique or diagnostic microscale
    details of each feature or unit, which necessitated sacrificing depth of
    imaging for overall imaging coverage. Additionally, rather than attempt to
    model the variations of illumination that occur under natural lighting,
    images were acquired under the artificial illumination of a light ring.
    Where stability of the camera could not be achieved otherwise, the camera
    was mounted on a tripod prior to acquiring images.
 
    Materials imaged at 10 micrometer/pixel (handlens-scale) were
    characterized for grain size, roundness, sphericity, texture, color,
    sorting, fabric, orientation and packing. Any sedimentary structure was
    also described.
 
    For more detailed information regarding the instruments used in data
    acquisition, please see [YINGSTETAL2007], as noted in the REF.CAT
    document, as well as the summary in the INSTRUMENT.CAT document.
 
  Data Organization
  =================
 
    All images in this data set are found in the DATA subdirectory. Primary
    image data products have file names beginning with IMG_. Most primary
    images have associated meter-scale and centimeter-scale context images,
    whose names begin with MIMG_ and CIMG_ respectively. Many primary images
    also have associated ancillary image files, whose names begin with AIMG_.
 
    Each primary image, context image, and ancillary image is described by
    a detached PDS label in a separate file with the same name,
    extension LBL. PDS labels are text files written in a keyword=value
    format. The PDS label for a given primary image includes references to
    its context images and ancillary images.
 
    Each primary image is associated with description files found in the
    DOCUMENT directory. The primary image&apos;s PDS label includes pointers to
    these description files.
 
    The file INDEX.TAB in the INDEX directory is a table of all primary images
    in the archive. It includes a great deal of information about each image,
    including sample characteristics, location, and related context images,
    ancillary images, and descriptions. This table is suitable for loading
    into a spreadsheet or data base program (such as Microsoft Excel) for
    searching.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Review
    ======
 
     This data set is subject to PDS peer review. PDS accepts only those
     data sets that have passed a peer review with all liens resolved.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

