<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mex-m-mrs-5-occ-9101-v2.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MARS EXPRESS MARS MRS 5 OCCULTATION 9101 V2.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_express::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mex::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mrs.mex::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mex-m-mrs-5-occ-9101-v2.0__browserp_geo_mex-m-mrs-5-occ-9101-v2.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.psa::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Fjeldbo, G., A.J. Kliore, and V.R. Eshleman, The Neutral Atmosphere of Venus as
                   Studied with the Mariner V Radio Occultation Data, Astron. J., 76, 123-140,
                   1971.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FJELDBOETAL1971</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MEX-M-MRS-5-OCC-9101-V2.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MARS EXPRESS MARS MRS 5 OCCULTATION 9101 V2.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2009-12-08</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-05-18T15:26:42.558Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2007-05-14T23:16:38.750Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>MARTIN PAETZOLD</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            M. Paetzold, Mars Express MaRS Level 5 data, Experimental Data
            acquired from COMMISSIONING, PRIME MISSION, EXTENDED MISSION 1,
            Version V2.0, MEXMRS_HSD_9101_V2.0, ESA Planetary Science
            Archive, 2009.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Example Mars Express radio Occultation temperature-pressure
            profiles and electron density profiles from 2004-2007.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            A sampling of Mars neutral atmosphere temperature-pressure
            profiles and ionospheric electron density profiles derived from
            Mars Express radio occultation data collected during the first
            three years of orbital operations (2004-2007). The data are
            presented as ASCII tables.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
Data Set Overview
================
This data set contains neutral atmosphere temperature-pressure
profiles and ionospheric electron density profiles derived from 12
Mars Express radio occultations spread over the first three years of
orbital operations (2004-2007).
The data set was created as a prototype for future data sets
containing a larger number of profiles.
 
 
PARAMETERS
==========
The neutral atmosphere profiles are ASCII tables containing values of
pressure, temperature, and number density (with uncertainties) as a
function of radius from the Mars center of mass, geopotential height
relative to a reference model, latitude, longitude, and time. Pressure
 and temperature are derived using an inversion procedure; the results
for three starting conditions are included.
 
The ionospheric profiles are ASCII tables giving electron number
density (and uncertainty), refractivity, and signal level as a
function of radius, latitude, longitude, and time.
 
 
PROCESSING
==========
Measurements of radio signal frequency/phase collected during an
occultation were corrected for known Doppler effects such as motion of
the spacecraft and ground receiving station, for drift of the
frequency reference, and for effects of the intervening medium (such
as Earth?s atmosphere and ionosphere).  The residual frequency shifts
are presumed to result from refractive bending by the atmosphere of
Mars. Variation of the bending angle, ray asymptote, and refractivity
of the neutral atmosphere are related by an Abel transform, which can
be inverted [FJELDBOETAL1971] using knowledge of the spacecraft
trajectory.  If hydrostatic equilibrium and a mean molecular weight
for the atmosphere (primarily CO2) are assumed, number density,
pressure, and temperature can be derived from the refractivity profile
of the neutral atmosphere.  For the ionosphere, the procedures are
similar but assumptions such as hydrostatic equilibrium do not apply,
so the details are more complicated. See also ESA publication
ESA-SP-1291 for details.
 
 
DATA
====
The data set comprises 12 neutral atmosphere temperature-pressure
profiles and 12 ionospheric electron density profiles derived from
Mars Express radio occultation measurements collected in 2004-2007.
These are example profiles created to test analysis and archiving
procedures, anticipating more profiles in future data sets.
 
Profiles are stored in the DATA directory.  Under the DATA heading are
 subdirectories OCC_ATMO and OCC_IONO, into which the neutral
atmosphere and ionospheric profiles are divided.  Under these two
headings are directories which organize the data by year (2004, 2005,
2006, and 2007).  Under the yearly headings are directories with names
 DOY_ddd_ooo_yyyy, where ddd is the day of year, ooo is the orbit
number for the measurements, and yyyy is the year.
 
Each directory DOY_ddd_ooo_yyyy contains an ASCII table
(extension *.TAB) which contains the temperature-pressure or electron
density file.  A companion PDS label (same file name, but *.LBL
extension) describes the format and content of the table.  A third
file with extension *.TXT gives supplementary information about the
occultation itself and some of the initial parameters used in the
inversion process. A fourth file is the label for the file with the
supplementary information.
 
The dataset, volume, directory, and file naming conventions are
described in MEX_MRS_RIU_IS_3050.PDF in the DOCUMENT directory of this
archive.
 
 
 
 
 
 
Coordinate Systems
==================
 
Latitudes and longitudes are given in areo centric (east) longitude
and areo centric (north) latitude. As rotation rate for Mars the
following value was used: Omega = 7.088218081*10**-5 s**-1.
 
Software
========
Since these are ASCII files containing high level science results,
no software is needed to display or process these data, and none is
included in the archive.
 
 
 
Documents
=========
 
     The DOCUMENT directory contains files that provide documentation
     and supplementary information to assist in understanding
     and using the data products in the volume.
 
  MEX-MRS-RIU-IS-3050.PDF/ASC         File naming convention for
                                       higher Science Products
  MEX-MRS-RIU-IS-3050 _APP.ASC        File naming convention for
                                       higher Science Products
                                       Appendix, PDS Example labels
  M00SUMML03_OC1_040930000_05.TAB/LBL   Additional information about
                                         first occultation season
 
  M00SUMML03_OC2_043430000_05.TAB/LBL   Additional information about
                                         second occultation season
 
  M00SUMML03_OC3_052000000_05.TAB/LBL   Additional information about
                                         third occultation season
  M00SUMML03_OC7_071150000_05.TAB/LBL   Additional information about
                                         seventh occultation season
 
  MARS_OPS_LOGBOOK_04.PDF               Operations logbook 2004
 
  MARS_OPS_LOGBOOK_05.PDF               Operations logbook 2005
 
  MARS_OPS_LOGBOOK_06.PDF               Operations logbook 2006
 
  MARS_OPS_LOGBOOK_07.PDF               Operations logbook 2007
 
  MEX-MRS-IGM-MA-3008.PDF            MaRS Users Manual.
 
 
 
Media/Format
============
      The archival data are written to hard discs for distribution.
 
 
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
Overview
========
      Data in this archival data set have been processed as part of
      prototyping effort to test analysis and archiving procedures for
      reduced data from Mars Express radio occultation experiments.
      In general, this is a good data set.
 
 
 
Review
======
      This archival data set was reviewed by the MEX Radio Science
      Team prior to submission to the Planetary Science Archive (PSA).
 
 
Data Coverage and Quality
=========================
The products in this data set were derived from the following Mars
Express ingress radio occultations with the spacecraft in &apos;two-way&apos;
mode:
 
                          Year  Day of Year  Orbit
                          ----  -----------  -----
                          2004       139       414
                          2004       180       559
                          2004       181       564
                          2004       183       570
                          2004       355      1184
                          2004       362      1212
                          2005       234      2061
                          2005       268      2182
                          2006       025      2619
                          2006       084      2829
                          2007       118      4253
                          2007       134      4312
 
In &apos;two-way&apos; mode, the spacecraft radio system uses a signal
transmitted from the ground as its frequency reference when radiating
its own signal.  The frequencies of the &apos;uplink&apos; and &apos;downlink&apos; differ
by about 10 percent so there is no interference.  The two-way mode
provides better frequency stability on the downlink than can be
achieved using the spacecraft&apos;s on-board oscillator, yielding more
accurate atmospheric profiles.  However, the fact that both the uplink
 and downlink pass through the atmosphere of Mars complicates the
analysis since refractive bending occurs during each passage and the
raypaths are at slightly different altitudes.
 
During an egress occultation, the spacecraft&apos;s radio system must find
and lock onto the uplink signal before transmitting &apos;coherently&apos; back
to Earth.  The &apos;lock-up&apos; time can be several seconds, during which the
 raypath is traversing a significant fraction of the atmosphere. The
uplink signal reaching the spacecraft is also somewhat unstable
because of perturbations introduced by the atmosphere of Mars.  For
these reasons, only ingress occultations were collected by the Mars
Express Radio Science Team.
 
 
 
 
Limitations
===========
 
      The limitations in this data set follow from the quality of
      the execution, which is described above under Data Coverage
      and Quality.
 
 
ACRONYMS
========
DSN             Deep Space Network
ESA             European Space Agency
IFMS            Intermediate Frequency Modulation System
JPL             Jet Propulsion Laboratory
MEX             Mars Express
NNO             New Norcia Station (Perth)
PDS             Planetary Data System
PSA             Planetary Science Archive
RSR             Radio Science Receiver
S/C             Spacecraft
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

