<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dawn-a-fc2-3-rdr-vesta-images-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DAWN FC2 CALIBRATED VESTA IMAGES V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.dawn_mission_to_vesta_and_ceres::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:fc2.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.4_vesta::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dawn-a-fc2-3-rdr-vesta-images-v1.0__browserp_dawn-a-fc2-3-rdr-vesta-images-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Schroeder, S.E., and P. Gutierrez-Marques, Calibration Pipeline, MPS Report
                   DA-FC-MPAE-RP-272, Issue 2, Rev. a, 20 July 2011.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SCHROEDER-GUTIER2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DAWN-A-FC2-3-RDR-VESTA-IMAGES-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DAWN FC2 CALIBRATED VESTA IMAGES V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2013-08-12</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2011-05-03T10:49:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2012-08-26T14:52:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>PABLO GUTIERREZ-MARQUES</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Nathues, A., H. Sierks, P. Gutierrez-Marques, S. Schroeder, T.
            Maue, I. Buettner, M. Richards, U. Chistensen, U. Keller, DAWN
            FC2 CALIBRATED VESTA IMAGES V1.0,
            DAWN-A-FC2-3-RDR-VESTA-IMAGES-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2011.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Reduced data records for Framing Camera 2 on Dawn during the
            Vesta Encounter Phases
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== Framing Camera 2 is one of two identical units
            flying on Dawn spacecraft. This dataset includes the Reduced Data
            Record (RDR) version of all available images acquired during the
            Vesta Encounter (Approach, Survey, Transfer to HAMO, HAMO,
            Transfer to LAMO, LAMO, Transfer to HAMO2, HAMO-2, and Transfer
            to Ceres). In addition to the imagery, anciliary information is
            stored within the image headers, as well as a detailed account of
            all the reference files used for the calibration. Calibration
            files needed for further processing are archived as a separate
            data set.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Dataset overview
    ================
      Framing Camera 2 is one of two identical units flying on Dawn
      spacecraft. This dataset includes the Reduced Data Record (RDR) version
      of all available images acquired during the Vesta Encounter (Approach,
      Survey, Transfer to HAMO, HAMO, Transfer to LAMO, LAMO, Transfer to
      HAMO2, HAMO-2, and Transfer to Ceres). In addition to the imagery,
      anciliary information is stored within the image headers, as well as a
      detailed account of all the reference files used for the calibration.
      Calibration files needed for further processing are archived as a
      separate data set. The images in this dataset have been radiometrically
      calibrated by means of fully reversible procedures, transforming the
      value of the pixels from digital units to applicable engineering units
      without modification of the geometry.
 
      For more information on the contents and organization of the volume
      set refer to the aareadme.txt file located in the root directory of
      the data volumes.
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      Compression: FC images may optionally be compressed by wavelet
      transformation.
 
      Wavelet compression: Images may be integer or floating point wavelet
      transform-compressed in the DPU. The integer approach produces lossless
      compression, while the floating point can induce distortions of +/-1 DN.
      The encoding of the wavelets ensures that any length of the data
      starting at the beginning can be decoded, thus allowing to compress
      further by discarding the trailing part.
 
      Windowing: In order to manage downlink resources, up to 10 portions
      of the image can be selected in the DPU and downlinked as subframes.
      The subframes are allowed to overlap. During EDR construction each
      subframe is stored separately and also mosaicked into the original
      image.
 
      Exposure Control: The exposure time of FC images is set
      by command for each image.
 
      Pointing: The Framing Cameras are fix mounted onto the Dawn Instrument
      deck, with the nominal alignment of the optical axis with the +Z axis of
      the spacecraft. Deviations from the nominal are documented in the
      calibration data.
 
      Filter selection: The FC has 8 filters at its disposal, numbered from F1
      to F8. F1 is a broadband (clear) filter, sensitive in the wavelength
      interval from 400 to 1100 nm peaking at 700 nm. The narrow-band color
      filters are of the interference type, and have wavelengths ranging from
      430 to 980 nm.
 
    Processing
    ==========
      An FC image downlinked by the spacecraft unpacks into a succession of
      one or more compressed image subframes with an attached PDS headers
      containing housekeeping items that include full status of the instrument
      hardware, software configuration, temperature, voltage and current
      readings.
 
      The data in one EDR consists of one or more reconstructed image frames,
      with the accompanying header translated into text format in the label.
      The dimensions and location (pixel coordinates) of each frame are
      included for proper further processing. Each frame is formatted into
      one file (suffix *.IMG), with an attached label.
 
      Subframes are retained as separate entities and also are reassembled
      into their original coordinates in the &apos;summary&apos; image. Parts of the
      reconstructed image not included in the subframes are given a value
      of zero.
 
      The label contains all relevant housekeeping information in calibrated
      form (e.g. degrees Celsius, volts, or amperes).
 
      The calibration process is divided into several steps that aim to remove
      the effect of different source of noise: conversion from 16-bit integer
      to 32-bit floating point, read-out bias, dark current, read-out smear,
      flat field non-uniformity, correction of under-sensitive pixels,
      exposure normalization, radiometric calibration.
 
      For more detailed informatin on the calibration process, please refer to
      [SCHROEDER&amp;GUTIER2011].
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Exposure times
    ==============
      Due to an idiosyncracy of the proximity electronics, that takes
      approximately 193 milliseconds from the commanding of the image
      acquisition to the actual start of the exposure, the images report the
      commanding time and the end of exposure. This results in a difference of
      193 milliseconds between the usual calculation of exposure time
      (STOP_TIME - START_TIME) and the reported EXPOSURE_DURATION, which is
      always shorter than the difference of the other two.
 
    Data Coverage
    =============
      The following table provides a list of major image losses and anomalies
      which affect FC science data coverage.
 
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------
                      Start
      Phase/Obs       Date     Description
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------
      VSA/OpNav #11   11/179   All images from were lost due to a spacecraft
                               safing.
 
      VSA/RC3         11/205   16 images were 0 ms exposures and are not
                               included in the L-1B data set.
 
      VSA/RC3B        11/205   16 images were 0 ms exposures and are not
                               included in the L-1B data set.
 
      VSH/Cycle 1/    11/276   104 images were tranmitted in raw format due
      Orbit 9                  to an overflow in the number of images in
                               camera memory.
 
      VSH/Cycle 1/    11/277   68 images were tranmitted in raw format due
      Orbit 10                 to an overflow in the number of images in
                               camera memory.
 
      VSH/Cycle 2/    11/278   All FC images from orbit 1 were lost due to a
      Orbit 1                  delay in uploading science command sequences.
 
      VTL/OpNav #2             Observation cancelled as the spacecraft was on
                               the night side of Vesta at the scheduled time.
 
      VTL/OpNav #3             Observation cancelled as the spacecraft was on
                               the night side of Vesta at the scheduled time.
 
      VSL/Cycle 1     11/347   131 images lost due to a spacecraft safing.
 
      VSL/Cycle 6     12/014   All images lost due a spacecraft safing.
 
      VSL/Cycle 11    12/049   40 images lost due to a spacecraft safing.
 
      VSL/Cycle 13    12/063   252 images lost due to a spacecraft safing.
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------
 
      Data Quality
      ============
 
      The following table contains a list of known corrupted images. These
      images have been omitted from the RDR data set.
 
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------
      Corrupted Images
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------
      Phase/Obs       Image #   Notes
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------
      VSA/MoonSrch    0002889   image double exposed
      VH2/Cyc3/Orb9   0028659
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

