<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.di-c-spice-6-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DEEP IMPACT SPICE KERNELS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_impact::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dii::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.dii::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.9p-tempel_1_1867_g1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.di-c-spice-6-v1.0__browserp_di-c-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.di-c-spice-6-v1.0__browser_di-c-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.di-c-spice-6-v1.0__browser_wgc_di-c-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.naif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DI-C-SPICE-6-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DEEP IMPACT SPICE KERNELS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2006-03-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2005-01-12T19:22:28Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2009-01-15T00:03:56Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>BORIS V. SEMENOV</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Semenov, B.V., and C.H. Acton, DEEP IMPACT SPICE KERNELS V1.0,
            DI-C-SPICE-6-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2006.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Navigation and ancillary data in the form of SPICE System kernel
            files for the Deep Impact Flyby and Impactor spacecraft.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set includes the complete set of Deep Impact SPICE data
            files (``kernel files&apos;&apos;), which can be accessed using
            SPICE software. The SPICE data contains geometric and other
            ancillary information needed to recover the full value of the
            science instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide
            spacecraft and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting
            alignments, spacecraft orientation, spacecraft sequences of
            events, and data needed for relevant time conversions.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
 
      This data set includes the complete set of Deep Impact (DI) SPICE
      data files (``kernel files&apos;&apos;), which can be accessed using SPICE
      software. The SPICE data contains geometric and other ancillary
      information needed to recover the full value of the science
      instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft
      and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments,
      spacecraft orientation, spacecraft sequences of events, and data
      needed for relevant time conversions.
 
 
      Data Types (SPICE kernel types)
      ===============================
 
      SPK kernels contain ephemerides for spacecraft, planets,
      satellites, comets and asteroids as well as for moving or fixed
      spacecraft and instrument structures. They provide position and
      velocity, given in a Cartesian reference frame. SPK files are
      located under the ``data/spk&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      PCK kernels contain certain physical, dynamical and
      cartographic constants for target bodies, such as size and shape
      specifications, and the orientation of the spin axis and prime
      meridian. PCK files are located under the ``data/pck&apos;&apos; directory
      of this data set.
 
      IK kernels (Instrument description kernels) give descriptive and
      operational data peculiar to a particular scientific instrument,
      such as internal timing relative to the spacecraft clock and
      field-of-view model parameters. IK files are located under the
      ``data/ik&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      CK kernels describe pointing, containing a transformation
      traditionally called the C-matrix which is used to determine
      time-tagged pointing (orientation) angles for a spacecraft
      structure upon which science instruments are mounted. CK files
      are located under the ``data/ck&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      EK (Events) kernels are derived from the integrated sequence of
      events used to produce actual spacecraft commands. EK files are
      located under the ``data/ek&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      LSK (Leapseconds) kernels contain the leapseconds and the values
      of other constants required to perform a transformation between
      Universal Time Coordinated (UTC) and Ephemeris time (ET). LSK
      files are located under the ``data/lsk&apos;&apos; directory of this data
      set.
 
      SCLK (Spacecraft Clock) kernels contain on-board clock calibration
      data required to perform a mapping between Ephemeris time (ET)
      and spacecraft on-board time (SCLK.) SCLK files are located under
      the ``data/sclk&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      FK (Frame Definitions) kernels contain information required to
      define reference frames, sources of frame orientation data and
      inter-connections between these frames and other frames supported
      within the SPICE system. This includes mounting alignment
      information for each instrument. FK files are located under
      the ``data/fk&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
 
      Kernel File Details
      ===================
 
      A brief overview of the different types of Deep Impact kernels
      included in this data set is provided in the
      CONFIDENCE_LEVEL_NOTE section of this file while details specific
      to individual files are found in the ``*info.txt&apos;&apos; files in the
      corresponding data directory. The most detailed description of
      the data in each file is provided in metadata included inside the
      file -- in the description area of text kernels or in the comment
      area of binary kernels.
 
 
      Software
      ========
 
      The SPICE Toolkit contains software modules needed to read
      SPICE kernel files. SPICELIB software is highly documented
      via internal headers. Additional documentation is available
      in separate ASCII text files called Required Reading files.
      For example, the S- and P- Kernel (SPK) Required Reading File,
      named SPK.REQ, describes use of the SPK kernel file readers
      and contains sample programs.
 
      The latest SPICE Toolkit for a variety of computer platforms such
      as PC, Mac, SUN, etc. is available at the NAIF Node of PDS
      electronically (via anonymous FTP and WWW servers). Refer to
      information in ``software/softinfo.txt&apos;&apos; for details regarding
      obtaining this software. Each version of the Toolkit is also
      archived at the NASA National Space Science Data Center.
 
 
      Loading Kernel Files into a SPICE-based Application
      ===================================================
 
      The easiest way to make data from a collection of SPICE kernels
      available to a SPICE-based application is to list these kernels
      in a meta-kernel and load it into the program using the high
      level SPICE data loader routine FURNSH. This data set provides
      such meta-kernel(s) under the ``extras/mk&apos;&apos; directory. For more
      information about the Stardust meta-kernel(s), see the file
      ``extras/mk/mkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      This data set contains SPICE kernel files created during mission
      operations and after mission data reconstruction and analysis.
      Some general information about this collection follows here,
      but the prospective user is also referred to extensive
      descriptions about each file that are stored inside each kernel
      file. These metadata provide detailed information regarding
      the information source from which the data were derived, the
      type of processing applied to the source data, applicability
      of the data, etc. Metadata are located in the ``comment area&apos;&apos;
      for binary kernel types (SPK, CK, ESQ), accessible using either
      the COMMNT or SPACIT utility program found in the NAIF Toolkit.
      Metadata are located after ``\begintext&apos;&apos; markers within the
      text kernel types (PCK, IK, FK, LSK, SCLK), accessible by
      using any available text file display tool such as a word
      processor, text editor, or the unix ``more&apos;&apos; or ``cat&apos;&apos;
      commands.
 
      In some cases data accuracy information does not exist because
      could not be estimated even after mission completion.
 
      Where there are questions about data accuracy or ``confidence&apos;&apos;
      not addressed herein the reader is invited to examine subsequent
      SPICE archive releases associated with this data set (if such
      exist), or to contact the NAIF node of the Planetary Data System
      for possible further information.
 
 
      SPK Files
      =========
 
      The SP-Kernel files included in this data set provide different
      versions of the trajectory of the Deep Impact Flyby (DIF) and
      Deep Impact Impactor (DII) spacecraft and ephemeris data for the
      mission target comet Tempel 1. Some of these SPKs also include
      ephemeris data for planets, the Sun, and a possible extended
      mission target comet Boethin.
 
      One version of the DIF and DII trajectories provided in this data
      set (dif_preenc174_nav_v1, dii_preenc174_nav_v1) was generated by
      merging regular orbit determination solutions based on radio
      tracking and far approach optical navigation data produced by the
      DI Navigation team, JPL during operations. This solution covers
      the whole primary mission, from launch to the beginning of
      August 2005, and extends four years past it, to January 2009.
      While this solution does not provide accurate trajectory for
      the close encounter because the encounter portion of it is based
      on predicted data generated pre-encounter, it provides sufficient
      coverage and accuracy for processing data taken at all other
      times during the mission.
 
      Another version of the DIF and DII trajectories provided in this
      data set was generated as the result of post-encounter processing
      of the close approach optical navigation data by Dan Kubitschek
      and Nick Mastrodemos of the DI Navigation Team, JPL. This
      solution covers only the two day period around the Tempel 1
      encounter. While this solution provides much better accuracy
      for processing of the close encounter data, it was found to be
      inadequate for some applications because the spacecraft position
      provided in it was referenced to the impact site rather than the
      comet Tempel 1 center. Two SPKs files of this kind provide
      early (di_finalenc_nav_v1.bsp) and final (di_finalenc_nav_v3.bsp)
      versions of this solution with the earlier version being archived
      only because it was used in processing image data in
      November/December 2005.
 
      The last version of the DIF and DII trajectories provided in this
      data set (di_finalenc_nav_v3_to06048.bsp) was generated by
      adjusting the final close approach optical navigation solution
      mentioned above by Brian Carcich of the DI Science Data Center,
      Cornell University. This solution also covers only the two day
      period around the Tempel 1 encounter. The adjustment was done by
      incorporating the offset between the impact site and the comet
      center determined from the final optical navigation solution
      SPK (v3) and the latest Tempel 1 shape model provided by
      Peter Thomas. This solution was used to process the PDS archive
      images in February 2006.
 
      This data set also includes a separate, long-spanning SPK
      (di_tempel1_ssd_v1.bsp) providing the latest ephemeris data for
      comet Tempel 1 produced using all DI mission data by the Solar
      System Dynamics Group, JPL. The ``original&apos;&apos; and ``adjusted&apos;&apos;
      close approach solutions mentioned are consistent with and
      incorporate a portion of this file.
 
      Additional information about SPK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/spk/spkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      CK Files
      ========
 
      C-kernel files included in this data set provide the orientation of
      the DIF and DII spacecraft buses and the DIF high gain antenna
      (HGA). Most of these CK files were produced from engineering
      telemetry downlinked from the spacecraft. As is often the case
      with spacecraft engineering telemetry-based measurements,
      considerable uncertainty exists as to the accuracy of such
      measurements, and, data quality (accuracy and completeness) can
      vary significantly.
 
      DIF Spacecraft Bus CK files
      ---------------------------
 
      Two kinds of the DIF spacecraft bus orientation CK files are
      included in this data set. The first kind, based on the low rate
      (1/8 Hz), provides coverage for the whole primary mission while
      the second kind, based on the high rate telemetry (5 Hz) provides
      coverage only for a short period in February 2005 and the for
      about 50 minutes around closest approach to Tempel 1. Both types
      of files need to be loaded to provide most complete coverage with
      the high rate CKs, providing superior attitude, loaded last so
      that data from them is accessed first. Also, while the low rate
      CK covers the whole mission, its coverage contains numerous gaps
      ranging from minutes to hours and, in some cases, even days. Due
      to these gaps this CK does not provide attitude data for about
      20% of the DIF images, particularly those taken during some cruise
      calibration sequences and far approach. This lack of attitude can
      be alleviated to some extent by modifying interpolation intervals
      in the file by using the CKSPANIT program (as was done for
      processing of the images for archiving in PDS in February 2006 -
      see comments below on &apos;gap-filler CK files&apos;.)
 
      The first archived versions of both the low rate and the high
      rate CKs had problems with internal time tags. The tags in the
      low rate CKs were ``compressed&apos;&apos; to the start of each second due
      to discrepancy in interpretation of the fractional SCLK part,
      causing timing error of up to 50 milliseconds and the end of each
      second (see additional information about this in the ``SCLK
      Files&apos;&apos; section below.) The tags in the high rate CKs were
      truncated by up to 2 milliseconds, introducing attitude errors of
      almost 20 microradians during the fastest spacecraft turn rates
      in the ~100 second interval before the closest approach to Tempel
      1 (at other times attitude errors due to this truncation were
      negligible). These problems were fixed in the version 2 of these
      CKs.
 
      The accuracy of the DIF spacecraft bus orientation determined
      on-board varied significantly, from 50 micro-radians (~5 MRI
      pixels) at the times when the attitude was determined based on
      the star tracker measurements to a few hundreds of micro-radians
      (tens of MRI pixels) for the periods when the attitude was
      determined by propagating ACS gyro data without any star tracker
      updates for extended periods of time. For this reason, the actual
      nucleus center position in the images is different from the
      center position computed using the CK files provided in this data
      set by as many as 20-30 MRI pixels for a number of the early
      pre-encounter and post-encounter look-back images. Some of this
      discrepancy may also be attributed to fact that the linear
      interpolation done by the Type 3 CK readers between the rather
      sparse, 1/8th Hz attitude points stored in the low-rate CK
      file does not adequately represent the actual orientation between
      the points.
 
      A number of times during the mission the ACS system was reset due
      to a safe mode entry or an update to the flight software. At the
      time of each reset the attitude quaternion computed by the ACS
      software was re-initialized (in some cases to an identity
      quaternion, in other cases to a random quaternion) and for a
      period of time following the reset, until the ACS was able to
      re-estimated the actual orientation from the star tracker data,
      the attitude data sent down in the channelized telemetry was
      bogus. This table lists the times and reasons of the ACS resets
      during the mission:
 
         2005 JAN 12 19:25:30.858  post-launch safe mode
         2005 JAN 12 19:29:44.578  post-launch safe mode
         2005 JAN 12 19:33:37.578  post-launch safe mode
         2005 JAN 12 19:37:18.578  post-launch safe mode
         2005 JAN 12 19:45:05.007  post-launch safe mode
         2005 JAN 20 06:59:48.398  solar flare induced safe mode
         2005 FEB 09 21:32:48.264  flight s/w 6.3.0 update
         2005 MAR 16 08:28:18.000  SCU-A reset safe mode
         2005 APR 12 23:27:45.377  flight s/w 7.0.0 update
         2005 JUN 06 04:12:39.808  flight s/w 7.0.0 update
 
      DII Spacecraft Bus CK Files
      ---------------------------
 
      Two kinds of the DII spacecraft bus orientation CK files are
      included in this data set. The first kind provides DII attitude
      prior to its separation from DIF. This attitude -- constant with
      respect to DIF -- was determined as the result of processing
      instrument geometric calibration data. The second kind, based on
      telemetry, provides attitude from separation through impact. The
      coverage of this CK contains a number of gaps. Due to these gaps
      this CK does not provide attitude data for some of the
      post-separation DII images. This lack of coverage can be
      alleviated by modifying the interpolation intervals in the file by
      using the CKSPANIT program (as was done for processing of the
      images for archiving in PDS in February 2006.) It is important to
      note that during image archive preparation Science Data Center
      team observed a bias (of up to 20 ITS pixels, decreasing to zero
      at closer to the impact time) in image pointing solutions done
      using this CK. No explanation was found for and no correction was
      done to this bias at that time.
 
      DIF HGA CK Files
      ----------------
 
      Two kinds of the DIF HGA orientation CK files are included in
      this data set. The first kind is based on the measured HGA gimbal
      angles provided in telemetry (``V-channels&apos;&apos;) while the second
      kind is based on the commanded HGA gimbal angles provided in
      telemetry (``B-channels&apos;&apos;). These files should be loaded together
      to provide the most complete coverage with the file based on
      measured angles loaded last (to be accessed first.) Even when
      loaded together, the combined coverage provided by the files is
      full of gaps, which can be alleviated by modifying the
      interpolation interval information by using the CKSPANIT program.
 
      Additional information about CK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/ck/ckinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      PCK Files
      =========
 
      PCK files provide size, shape and orientation data for ``target&apos;&apos;
      bodies such as planets, satellites, comets and asteroids. A
      description of these data items and reference to their source is
      provided inside the PCK file, which is a simple text file that
      can be viewed using any word processor, text editor or text
      display utility.
 
      This data set contains generic PCK file based on the official
      IAU/IAG/COSPAR values accepted in 2000 and PCK file for DI
      mission target -- Tempel 1 -- providing constants determined
      after the encounter. The PCK file for Tempel 1 contains both
      rotation and shape/size data derived by the DI science team
      during post encounter data analysis.
 
      Additional information about PCK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/pck/pckinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      FK Files
      ========
 
      Frames kernel files provide specifications for how one reference
      frame is defined relative to another frame. The DI FK provided in
      this data set contains a complete set of frame definitions for
      the both spacecraft, their structures such as antennas, and all
      of their science instruments. Comments in the FK file provide
      the frame definitions, a description of the frame relationships,
      the source of and accuracy of the mounting alignment information,
      etc. The instrument frame definitions provided in the file
      incorporate the latest mounting alignment data available at the
      end of the mission.
 
      Additional information about FK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/fk/fkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      IK Files
      ========
 
      Instrument kernel files provide specifications for the optical
      and physical instrument parameters and -- where applicable --
      field-of-view size, shape and orientation for the named
      instrument. Metadata describing these estimates are provided in
      each IK file included in this archive. While a majority of the of
      parameters included in the IK files archived in this data set
      are based on the nominal instrument data, the files incorporate
      the latest version of optical distortion model derived by the DI
      optical navigation team.
 
      Additional information about IK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/ik/ikinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      SCLK Files
      ==========
 
      Spacecraft Clock kernel files provide a tabulation of data needed
      to convert time measurements between ephemeris time (ET) and
      spacecraft clock time (SCLK). A SPICE SCLK file is made from a
      similar file -- SCLK/SCET or SCLKvSCET file -- produced by
      another mission entity. Each newly made SCLK file fully replaces
      the previous SCLK file.
 
      This data set includes SCLK kernels providing the correlation
      between the DIF spacecraft primary (SCU-A) on-board clock, DIF
      spacecraft secondary (SCU-B) on-board clock, and DII spacecraft
      on-board clock. Two SCLK kernels -- the ``official&apos;&apos; version and
      ``science&apos;&apos; version -- are available for the DIF primary clock and
      DII clock while only one SCLK kernel -- ``official&apos;&apos; version --
      is available for the DIF secondary clock.
 
      The main difference between the ``official&apos;&apos; versions of the SCLK
      kernels and the ``science&apos;&apos; versions is that ``official&apos;&apos; versions
      are based on the latest time correlations that were used by the
      project during mission operations while the ``science&apos;&apos; versions
      contain updated correlations that were used to process science
      data for archiving in PDS.
 
      The correlation updates for the DIF primary clock and for the DII
      clock were done for two different reasons. The DIF correlation was
      updated to eliminate ``artificial&apos;&apos; data points introduced by the
      tool-set that created source SCLKvSCET file and to adjust clock
      rates in order to connect actual data points in a continuous
      fashion. The DII correlation, on the other hand, was updated to
      simply enforce consistency between the DIF primary clock and the
      DII clock based on the SCLK times of the impact determined from
      the image data (DII SCLK = 1/173727875.105 +/-300ms per Dennis
      Wellnitz and DIF SCLK = 1/173727702.218 +/-25ms per image
      number 064 of ExpID 9000910) and DIF/DII trajectory solutions
      based on close approach optical navigation data (time of impact
      for DII trajectory at 2005-185T05:44:34.2 UTC).
 
      The ``science&apos;&apos; versions of the SCLKs and trajectory solutions
      based close approach optical navigation data were created in the
      following sequence:
 
        - correlation from ``official&apos;&apos; DIF primary clock SCLK kernel
          was modified to get ``science&apos;&apos; DIF primary clock SCLK kernel
 
        - ``science&apos;&apos; DIF primary clock SCLK kernel and ``official&apos;&apos;
          DII SCLK kernels were used to process close approach optical
          navigation images to generate trajectory solution
 
        - UTC of impact (2005-185T05:44:34.2) was determined by
          converting DIF SCLK of impact determined from DIF images
          (1/173727702.218) to UTC using ``science&apos;&apos; version of DIF
          primary clock SCLK kernel
 
        - correlation from ``official&apos;&apos; DII SCLK kernel
          was modified so that UTC mentioned above matched DII SCLK
          of impact determined from DII images (1/173727875.105)
 
        - DII trajectory was shifted so that impact happened at the
          UTC mentioned above.
 
      Because of the tight coupling between the SPK and SCLK kernels,
      the ``science&apos;&apos; SCLK must be used for encounter image processing.
 
      Unfortunately, the absolute accuracy of both ``official&apos;&apos; and
      ``science&apos;&apos; correlations is no better than 1 second as was
      determined by a DI Time Issues Working Group that included Ball
      and JPL engineers and members of the DI science team. This group
      was put together at the end 2005 with the goal to improve DIF and
      DII time correlation knowledge. The group concluded that getting
      improvement was not possible without substantial effort due a
      number of factors among which were the lack of correlation data
      during the last ten days before encounter, big changes in the
      thermal conditions and strong temperature dependency of the clock
      oscillators, and errors in the production of the time correlation
      packets.
 
      Note that the clock format defined by both ``official&apos;&apos; and
      ``science&apos;&apos; SCLK kernels (seconds with fractional seconds given
      as a count of 1/256 second ticks) does not match the format of
      on-board time tags in mission telemetry (seconds with fractional
      seconds given as top 8 or 16 or full 20 bits of a count of
      micro-seconds). For details on this discrepancy and the algorithm
      to fix it see ``sclk140.txt&apos;&apos; provided in Deep Impact and EPOXI
      documentation set (DI-C-HRII/HRIV/MRI/ITS-6-DOC-SET-V3.0).
 
      While all science images sent to the ground contained SCLK time
      in the headers (spacecraft primary, SCU-A, SCLK for DIF
      and main SCLK for DII), optical- and auto-navigation image
      headers contain a different time. This time was so a called
      on-board Ephemeris Time (ET) that optical/auto navigation
      on-board software used internally to perform autonomous
      trajectory and attitude solutions. This on-board ET was computed
      from on-board clock by adding a constant delta to it to make it
      synchronous with the actual ET to the extent possible. Since the
      on-board clock was drifting throughout the mission, the delta had
      to be changed a number of times. The table below shows the delta,
      in seconds, that must be subtracted from the on-board ET to get
      corresponding SCLK (spacecraft primary, SCU-A, SCLK for
      DIF and main SCLK for DII) and the time when a particular
      delta had been uplinked and took effect in the on-board software
      (shown as UTC and on-board ET):
 
        DIF:
 
          Delta    Applicability Start UTC  Apl. Start on-board ET
          -------  -----------------------  ----------------------
           64.184  2005-014T02:50:20.1133   158943084.297
          160.176  2005-083T11:14:00.1992   164934912.535
          177.161  2005-103T02:14:28.7695   166630537.301
          268.794  2005-157T04:17:00.0000   171303535.833
          237.978  2005-175T03:58:33.1251   172857585.892
 
        DII:
 
          Delta    Applicability Start UTC  Apl. Start on-board ET
          -------  -----------------------  ----------------------
           64.184  2005-014T02:50:20.1133   158943084.297
 
      Additional information about SCLK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/sclk/sclkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      LSK Files
      =========
 
      Leapseconds kernel files provide a tabulation of ``leapseconds&apos;&apos;
      and some other terms used in converting time measurements between
      ephemeris time (ET) and Universal Time (UTC). ``Spacecraft Event
      Time&apos;&apos; (SCET) is the commonly used name for UTC events measured
      at the spacecraft.
 
      Metadata describing how the LSK data are obtained or computed is
      contained inside the LSK text file. The time conversion provided
      by SPICE LSK files is accurate to approximately 0.000030 seconds.
 
      Additional information about LSK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/lsk/lskinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      EK Files
      ========
 
      Two Events kernel (EK) files are included in this archive: DIF
      Sequence EK and DIF Command Dictionary EK.
 
      DIF Sequence EK contains a summary of the commands sent to the
      spacecraft during the mission as well as instrument state
      (status) summaries as modeled by the sequence generation tools.
      This file was created from integrated sequence Predicted Events
      File (PEF) provided by Steve Wissler, DI Mission Operations
      Systems Engineer as the end of the primary mission. While
      significant effort was made to collect all necessary information
      for producing complete PEF file, command logs for some periods
      have not been available and the commands for these periods are
      missing from the EK. Also, because the PEF file was the result
      of sequence modeling process the EK records have times different
      from the actual command execution times (although very close in
      most cases).
 
      DIF Command Dictionary EK is based on the last version of the
      command dictionary available at the end of the primary mission.
 
      Additional information about EK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/ek/ekinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      Kernel Files Not Included In This Data Set
      ===========================================
 
      A number of kernel files used to process image data archived in
      PDS and mentioned in the image labels were not included in this
      data set because they either were superseded by the files
      provided in this archive, or were known to contain incorrect or
      out-of-date information, or could be easily re-created from the
      data provided in this archive using utility program(s) available
      from NAIF. Among such files are:
 
        - predicted SPK files:
 
            spk_bet_050112_101_impactor.bsp
            spk_bet_050112_101_flyby.bsp
            spk_od023.bsp
            dif_ort11_dss_merged.bsp
            spk_diipredict_2005177_175028.bsp
 
          These SPKs were used for processing of the images for
          archiving in PDS during November/December 2005. They
          contained earlier versions of the spacecraft trajectory and
          comet ephemerides and were superseded by the SPKs included
          in this data set.
 
        - predicted CK files:
 
            dii_attached_v10.bc
            launch_bet050112_101_20050102t205819_att.bc
            dif_rec_ck_ort11_merged.bc
            dii_predict_2005177_175028.bc
 
          These CKs were used for processing of the images for
          archiving in PDS during November/December 2005. They
          contained predicted attitude data for DII and DIF spacecraft.
          The main purpose of using these files was to provide ``some&apos;&apos;
          orientation data for under 20% of the images, for which
          actual orientation data was not available in the
          reconstructed CKs provided in this archive. While they served
          this gap-filler purpose, the data provided by them was
          incorrect in most/all cases due to differences between
          planned and actual pointing profiles, timing issues, etc. For
          this reason they were not included into this data set.
 
        - nominal Tempel 1 PCK file:
 
            di_tempel1_v00.tpc
 
          This PCK was used for processing of the images for archiving
          in PDS during November/December 2005. It contained nominal,
          placeholder shape/size and rotation constants for comet Tempel
          1. It was superseded by comet PCK ``di_tempel1_v01.tpc&apos;&apos;
          provided in this data set. For the record, the nominal
          constants provided in that PCK were:
 
            BODY1000093_POLE_RA   = (   0.0    0.0              0.0 )
            BODY1000093_POLE_DEC  = ( +90.0    0.0              0.0 )
            BODY1000093_PM        = (   0.0  205.7142857142857  0.0 )
            BODY1000093_RADII     = (   3.1    2.1              2.1 )
 
        - star position SPK and PCK files:
 
            naifstarnames_2005321_v01.tpc
            stars_2005321_v01.bsp
 
          These SPK and PCK were used in the Science Data Center image
          processing pipeline to provide access via SPICE interfaces
          to positions of a few stars used for instrument calibration
          during the mission. While these kernels successfully served
          their purpose, they were not fully compliant with official
          NAIF practices. This reason they were not included into this
          data set. On the other hand, recognizing the importance of
          this data, it was decided to include the star positions
          stored in these files into this data set&apos;s documentation for
          the reference. The table below provides these positions.
          Each line contains J2000 RA (hours, arc-minutes,
          arc-seconds), J2000 DEC (degrees, arc-minutes, arc-seconds)
          and name.
 
            10,24,23.71,-74,1,53.8,PRETEND I CAR HD90589
            0,25,45.07,-77,15,15.3,BET HYI HD2151
            10,2,42,-60,7,0,NGC3114
            6,23,57.11,-52,41,44.4,CANOPUS HD45348
            1,37,42.85,-57,14,12.3,ACHERNAR HD10144
            21,7,6,42,14,0,NGC7027
            19,41,48.95,50,31,30.2,16 CYG A HD186408
            7,33,27.32,-50,35,3.3,HD60753
            18,36,56.34,38,47,1.3,VEGA HD172167
            0,24,5.22,-72,4,57.9,47 TUC NGC104
            6,45,08.92,-16,42,58.0,SIRIUS HD48915
            9,11,16.72,-62,19,1.1,I CAR HD79447
            11,5,33,-58,43,48,NGC3532
            18,51,6,-6,16,0,M11
            10,36,16.079,-58,16,38.20,HD92044
            08,40,36,-53,02,0,OMI VEL CLUSTER IC2391
 
        - ``gap-filler&apos;&apos; CK files
 
            dii_predict_050703_050704.bc
            dif_predict_050112_050809.bc
 
          These CKs were used for processing of the images for
          archiving in PDS during February to fulfill the same purpose
          as the predicted CKs mentioned above -- to provide ``some&apos;&apos;
          orientation data for under 20% of the images, for which
          actual orientation data was not available in the
          reconstructed CKs. Unlike the other predicted CKs these two
          kernels did not provide truly predicted orientation. Instead
          they stored the same data as the reconstructed CKs but
          allowed interpolation across gaps of any size between actual
          attitude data points. These files were not included in this
          data set because they were created -- and can be recreated at
          any time -- from the reconstructed CKs provided in this data
          set using CKSPANIT application with the tolerance of 44236800
          ticks (= 2 days).
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>PSCM-00027</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

