<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dif-cal-hrii-hriv-mri-6-epoxi-temps-v2.1</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>EPOXI HRII/HRIV/MRI INSTRUMENT TEMPERATURES V2.1</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.epoxi::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:hrii.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dif-cal-hrii-hriv-mri-6-epoxi-temps-v2.1__browserp_dif-cal-hrii-hriv-mri-6-epoxi-temps-v2.1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hampton, D.L., J.W. Baer, M.A. Huisjen, C.C. Varner, A. Delamere, D.D.
                   Wellnitz, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, and K.P. Klaasen, An Overview of the Instrument Suite
                   for the Deep Impact Mission, Space Science Reviews, 117, 43-93, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3390-8.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAMPTONETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., M.F. A&apos;Hearn, M. Baca, A. Delamere, M. Desnoyer, T. Farnham, O.
                   Groussin, D. Hampton, S. Ipatov, J. Li, C. Lisse, N. Mastrodemos, S.
                   McLaughlin, J. Sunshine, P. Thomas, and D. Wellnitz, Deep Impact Instrument
                   Calibration, Rev. Sci. Instrum., 79, 091301, 2008, doi:10.1063/1.2972112.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., M. A&apos;Hearn, S. Besse, D. Bodewits, B. Carcich, T. Farnham, L.
                   Feaga, O. Groussin, D. Hampton, M. Huisjen, M.S. Kelley, S. McLaughlin, F.
                   Merlin, S. Protopapa, J. Sunshine, P. Thomas, and D. Wellnitz, EPOXI Instrument
                   Calibration, Icarus, 225(1), 643-680, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.icarus.2013.03.024.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV/MRI-6-EPOXI-TEMPS-V2.1</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>EPOXI HRII/HRIV/MRI INSTRUMENT TEMPERATURES V2.1</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2013-02-11</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2007-10-04T03:30:00.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2011-02-06T23:55:58.390Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STEPHANIE MCLAUGHLIN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Carcich, B., D. Hampton, and S. McLaughlin, EPOXI HRII/HRIV/MRI
            INSTRUMENT TEMPERATURES V2.1,
            DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV/MRI-6-EPOXI-TEMPS-V2.1, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2013.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw temperature measurements for EPOXI from 17 Dec 2007 to 31 Dec
            2008 from multiple sensors located in the HRII, HRIV, and MRI
            instruments and on the HRI and MRI telescopes, instrument
            platform, and solar wings of the Deep Impact flyby spacecraft
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset contains the raw and smoothed (averaged) instrument
            thermal telemetry for the entire EPOXI mission, from 04 October
            2007 through 06 February 2011. Measurements were collected by 59
            thermal sensors located in the HRII, HRIV, and MRI instruments,
            on the instrument platform, and on the solar wings of the Deep
            Impact flyby spacecraft. Version 2.1 corrects a typo in a column
            description in 5 data labels.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This dataset contains the raw and smoothed (averaged) instrument
    thermal telemetry for the entire EPOXI mission, from 04 October 2007
    through 06 February 2011.  Measurements were collected by 59 thermal
    sensors located in the HRII, HRIV, and MRI instruments, on the
    instrument platform, and on the solar wings of the Deep Impact flyby
    spacecraft.  Version 2.1 corrects a typo in a column description
    in 5 data labels, hri_raw_i_temps_*.lbl.
 
 
  Temperature Sensors
  ===================
    The raw and smoothed temperatures provided in this dataset are
    from two independent types of sensors:
 
      1)  One set is part of the spacecraft thermal subsystem
          which continuously control the thermal environment via
          the spacecraft telemetry stream, and
 
      2)  The other set records the measurements embedded in the
          science data image headers by the software on-board the
          spacecraft.
 
    The spacecraft thermal subsystem are placed on active operating
    components and in critical locations on the HRI and MRI telescopes and
    in the HRII infrared spectrometer, the HRIV CCD, and the MRI CCD, as
    well as on the instrument platform and the two solar wings of the
    flyby spacecraft.  All of these sensors, except those on the
    instrument platform and solar wings, are connected to side A or B of
    the flyby spacecraft&apos;s Thermal Interface Board (TIB).  The sensors are
    used to monitor the thermal environment and, with the instrument
    heaters, provided a closed-loop temperature control via the telemetry
    stream. Measurements are recorded in the telemetry at various rates
    throughout the mission, from about once every minute to several times
    every hour whether the instruments were turned on or off.
 
    The instrument thermal sensors are also placed on active operating
    components and in critical locations on the HRI and MRI telescopes and
    in the HRII infrared spectrometer, the HRIV CCD, and the MRI CCD
    instruments, sometimes in close proximity to sensors connected to the
    spacecraft thermal subsystem.  However most of the instruments sensors
    only record measurements when an instrument is turned on. Measurements
    are recorded in the science image headers and in the telemetry at
    various rates throughout the mission, from about once every minute to
    several times every hour.
 
    The Pictorial Atlas of Deep Impact and EPOXI) Instrument Thermal
    Telemetry document included in this dataset illustrates the location
    of the thermal telemetry points (sensors) are located.  The thermal
    design of the instruments is described by Hampton, et al. (2005)
    [HAMPTONETAL2005].  The Deep Impact instrument calibration paper by
    Klaasen, et al. (2008) [KLAASENETAL2006] and the EPOXI instrument
    calibration paper by Klaasen, et al. (2011) describe how various
    temperatures affect the calibration of the HRII, HRIV, and MRI
    instruments.  A draft of the Deep Impact document and summary of EPOXI
    document are included in this dataset.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    Raw thermal measurements received in the original telemetry stream
    from the flyby spacecraft were extracted, grouped by type (&apos;T&apos; for the
    spacecraft thermal subsystem and &apos;I&apos; for the instrument sensors) and
    year of data acquisition, then formatted into fixed-width ASCII tables
    with filenames of {HRI,MRI}_RAW_{T,I}_YYYY.TAB and placed in the
    DATA/RAW/ path of this dataset.  Each sensor measurement is provided
    as both raw data numbers and in the engineering unit (kelvin or
    degrees Celsius).  No corrections or conversions were applied to the
    raw values.
 
    The tools used to extract the measurements from the engineering
    telemetry have been run in a mode called &apos;report on change only with
    channel clear&apos;, such that for each sensor the tools excluded
    subsequent contiguous measurements that are the same as the previous
    measurement.
 
    The raw thermal measurements were smoothed by averaging all
    measurements for each sensor within a 20-minute interval.  The
    resulting averages were also grouped by type (&apos;T&apos; for the spacecraft
    thermal subsystem and &apos;I&apos; for the instrument sensors) and year of data
    acquisition, formatted into fixed-width ASCII tables with filenames of
    {HRI,MRI}_SMOOTH_{T,I}_YYYY.TAB and placed in the DATA/SMOOTH/ path of
    this dataset.  Each raw averaged temperature is provided in the
    engineering unit (kelvin or degrees Celsius), and a count of the
    values used to compute that average is included.  No corrections or
    conversions were applied to the values.
 
    This dataset contains raw and smoothed temperatures for these sensors
    which are illustrated in the Pictorial Atlas of Deep Impact &amp; EPOXI
    Instrument Thermal Telemetry:
 
    Spacecraft Thermal Subsystem, HRI &apos;T&apos; Sensors
    ---------------------------------------------
         S/C    AMMOS*
      Sensor# : Telem# : Sensor Description
        TS104 : T-0276 : HRI tele. barrel at center (first sensor)
        TS102 : T-0287 : HRI SIM bench at prisms (first sensor
        TS103 : T-0296 : HRI CCD plate assembly (first sensor)
        TS118 : T-0298 : HRI beam splitter
        TS131 : T-0302 : HRI primary mirror
        TS107 : T-0303 : HRI pre-amp box
        TS134 : T-0305 : HRI IR detector cooler (secondary radiator)
        TS114 : T-0306 : HRI IR focal plane array (primary radiator)
        TS116 : T-0327 : HRI electronics box
        TS110 : T-1777 : HRI tele. barrel at center (second sensor)
        TS108 : T-1792 : HRI SIM bench at prisms (second sensor)
        TS109 : T-1793 : HRI CCD plate assembly (second sensor)
        TS115 : T-1804 : HRI SIM bench at rear flexure
        TS135 : T-1806 : HRI telescope barrel baffle extension
          n/a : T-0339 : Panel underneath the instrument platform**
          TS1 : T-0275 : Back side of solar array wing 1, -Z direction**
          TS3 : T-0280 : Back side of solar array wing 1, +Z direction**
          TS2 : T-1776 : Back side of solar array wing 2, -Z direction**
          TS4 : T-1781 : Back side of solar array wing 2, +Z direction**
 
            * AMMOS Advanced Multi-Mission Operations System
           ** Not shown in the Pictorial Atlas
 
    Spacecraft Thermal Subsystem, MRI &apos;T&apos; Sensors
    ---------------------------------------------
         S/C
      Sensor# : AMMOS# : Sensor Description
        TS132 : T-0277 : MRI optical bench at primary mirror
        TS106 : T-0284 : MRI CCD plate assembly (first sensor)
        TS105 : T-0299 : MRI telescope box at center bottom
        TS133 : T-1778 : MRI telescope box extension
        TS112 : T-1797 : MRI CCD plate assembly (second sensor)
        TS111 : T-1800 : MRI primary mirror
        TS113 : T-1805 : MRI pre-amp box
        TS117 : T-1819 : MRI electronics box
 
    Instrument, HRI &apos;I&apos; Sensors
    ---------------------------
         Instr
        Sensor# : AMMOS# : Sensor Description
            n/a : I-0221 : HRI instrument controller board
            n/a : I-0223 : HRI CCD signal processing board
            n/a : I-0225 : HRI IR signal processing board
            n/a : I-0227 : HRI mechanism and telemetry board
            n/a : I-0229 : HRI low voltage power supply board
      AD590PAMP : I-0231 : HRI pre-amp box
           PTS1 : I-0233 : HRI CCD plate assembly
           PTS2 : I-0235 : SIM bench at prism (close to prism #1)
           PTS3 : I-0237 : HRI primary mirror
           PTS4 : I-0239 : HRI secondary mirror;
           PTS5 : I-0241 : HRI SIM cover at motor bracket
           PTS6 : I-0243 : HRI SIM cover at the rear flexure
           PTS7 : I-0245 : HRI telescope barrel at primary mirror
           PTS8 : I-0247 : HRI telescope barrel baffle extension at 2nd mirror
           PTS9 : I-0249 : HRI SIM bench at motor bracket
          PTS10 : I-0251 : HRI CCD filter wheel and shutter motor bracket
            n/a : I-0342 : On-chip IR focal plane array
 
    Instrument, MRI &apos;I&apos; Sensors
    --------------------------
         Instr
        Sensor# : AMMOS# : Sensor Description
            n/a : I-1221 : MRI instrument controller board
            n/a : I-1223 : MRI CCD signal processing board
            n/a : I-1227 : MRI mechanism and telemetry board
            n/a : I-1229 : MRI low voltage power supply board
      AD590PAMP : I-1231 : MRI pre-amp box
          PTS12 : I-1233 : MRI CCD plate assembly
          PTS12 : I-1235 : MRI optical bench at rear flexure
          PTS13 : I-1237 : MRI primary mirror
          PTS14 : I-1239 : MRI secondary mirror;
          PTS15 : I-1241 : MRI cover top plate
          PTS16 : I-1243 : MRI side panel radiator
          PTS17 : I-1245 : MRI telescope box top at primary mirror
          PTS18 : I-1247 : MRI telescope box top at secondary mirror
          PTS19 : I-1249 : MRI telescope box bottom at secondary mirror
          PTS20 : I-1251 : MRI CCD filter wheel and shutter motor bracket
 
  Media Format
  ============
    This data set is released in electronic format.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  The EPOXI science team uses the smoothed temperatures to monitor and
  understand the thermal environment and its effects on the science image
  data.  For example the HRII spectrometer is known to be very sensitive
  to temperature fluctuations.
 
  Please note the HRI IR Spectral Imaging Module (SIM) bench temperatures
  recorded by the spacecraft thermal subsystem are known to be one to two
  degrees different, but more realistic, than the measurements collected
  by the instruments and recorded in the science data image headers.
  Because the HRII spectrometer is thermally sensitive, the calibration
  the calibration pipeline uses smoothed temperatures from the thermal
  telemetry when reducing IR data.  See the Deep Impact instrument
  calibration paper by Klaasen, et al. (2008) [KLAASENETAL2006] for more
  information.
 
  Version 2.0 of this dataset was peer reviewed and certified for
  scientific use on 15 August 2011.  The label corrections for this
  version 2.1 were internally checked by PDS-SBN before archiving.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SUPERSEDED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

