<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dif-cal-hrii-2-ground-tv1-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DEEP IMPACT PREFLIGHT THERMAL-VACUUM 1 HRII DATA</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_impact::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:hrii.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dif-cal-hrii-2-ground-tv1-v1.0__browserp_dif-cal-hrii-2-ground-tv1-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   A&apos;Hearn, M.F., M.J.S. Belton, A. Delamere, and W.H. Blume, Deep Impact: A
                   Large-Scale Active Experiment on a Cometary Nucleus, Space Science Reviews,
                   117, 1-21, 2005, doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3387-3.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.AHEARNETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hampton, D.L., J.W. Baer, M.A. Huisjen, C.C. Varner, A. Delamere, D.D.
                   Wellnitz, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, and K.P. Klaasen, An Overview of the Instrument Suite
                   for the Deep Impact Mission, Space Science Reviews, 117, 43-93, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3390-8.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAMPTONETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., B. Carcich, G. Carcich, E.J. Grayzeck, and S. McLaughlin, Deep
                   Impact: The Anticipated Flight Data, Space Science Reviews, 117, 335-372, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3385-5.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DIF-CAL-HRII-2-GROUND-TV1-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DEEP IMPACT PREFLIGHT THERMAL-VACUUM 1 HRII DATA</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2004-10-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2002-06-27T09:53:16Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2002-07-02T13:52:14Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STEPHANIE MCLAUGHLIN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Hampton, D.L., D.D. Wellnitz, and S.A. McLaughlin, DEEP IMPACT
            PREFLIGHT THERMAL-VACUUM 1 HRII DATA,
            DIF-CAL-HRII-2-GROUND-TV1-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Infrared spectral image data acquired by the High Resolution
            Instrument&apos;s Infrared Spectrometer (HRII) during the first
            preflight thermal-vacuum test (TV1) of the Deep Impact
            instruments.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains 2-dimensional spectral images acquired by
            the High Resolution Instrument&apos;s Infrared Spectrometer
            (HRII) during the the first preflight thermal-vacuum test (TV1)
            of the Deep Impact instruments.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  This data set description was provided by Stephanie McLaughlin and
  Dennis Wellnitz (University of Maryland), who participated in
  the ground calibration tests of the Deep Impact instruments.
 
 
Data Set Overview
=================
 
  This data set contains 2-dimensional spectral images acquired by the
  High Resolution Instrument&apos;s Infrared Spectrometer (HRII) during the
  the first preflight thermal-vacuum test (TV1) for Deep Impact.
  TV1 was considered a dry run in preparation for the full, second
  thermal-vacuum test (TV2) of the HRII instrument.  The experiments
  performed during TV1 were designed by the Ball Aerospace team with
  input from the project&apos;s science team.  TV1 was conducted by Don Hampton
  and Jeff Van Cleve of Ball Aerospace.  Several science team members
  were present at all times to assist with the experiments and perform
  real-time analysis of the data.
 
  The main objectives of the TV1 were to:
 
    - Perform tests at the 3 nominal operating temperatures of optical
      bench:  128K, 135K, and 141K.
    - Determine best focus at 128K.
    - Measure the minimum and maximum wavelengths of the focal plane
      array (FPA).
    - Determine alignment of a spectral image on the FPA.
    - Determine the spatial and spectral dispersion of the FPA.
    - Obtain flat fields from various blackbody sources for preliminary
      measurements of the response of the FPA at different wavelengths.
    - Determine the non-linearity of the FPA.
    - Activate the internal stimulator to be used as an in-flight
      calibrator.
    - Check for stray light.
 
  To meet these objectives, the HRII was tested in the Ball 8
  thermal-vacuum chamber; its shroud was cooled with liquid nitrogen
  and its instrument plate was cooled with liquid helium.  The
  High Resolution telescope was simulated by an optical bench that
  was setup outside the chamber and oriented such that light
  produced by a source would enter the chamber&apos;s window and
  illuminate the FPA.  Various types of emission, absorption, and
  black body sources were employed to test the FPA.
 
  Daily tests are summarized in the following chart.  Since TV1 was
  a dry run, temperature logs were not created for the HRII&apos;s
  optical bench and FPA.  Instead, these temperatures were simply
  recorded at the beginning of each test day.
 
                 FPA     IR Opt.
    Date/(DOY)  Temp(K)  Bench(K)    Tests
    ----------  -------  -------  ---------------------------------
    2002-06-27  120-113    155    First light on flight FPA with EM
    (178)                         electronics; CO2 and H20 asborp-
                                  tion lines visible; blackbody
                                  radiation of room visible at
                                  longer wavelengths
.
    2002-06-28   90-88   125-123  At colder temperatures, signal
    (179)                         visible across entire array;
                                  Check test telescope boresight;
                                  Tungsten source
 
    2002-06-29    ~92     ~128    Focus test; Internal stimulator;
    (180)                         Argon source; Darks
 
    2002-06-30    ~92     ~128    Best focus achieved; Argon and
    (181)                         Krypton sources; CO2 and H20
                                  absorption lines; Darks; Various
                                  blackbody sources for flats
 
    2002-07-01    ~99     ~135    Argon and Krypton sources; Darks;
    (182)                         Various blackbody sources for
                                  flats; Tungsten source
 
    2002-07-02   ~105     ~141    Argon and Krypton sources; Darks;
    (183)                         Various blackbody sources for
                                  flats; M filter for long wave-
                                  length cutoff; Stray light;
                                  Internal stimulator
 
  For more information about the mission, the HRII instrument,
  and the anticipated HRII flight data, see A&apos;Hearn, et al. (2005)
  [AHEARNETAL2005], Hampton, et al. (2005) [HAMPTONETAL2005], and
  Klaasen, et al. (2005) [KLAASENETAL2005].
 
 
Parameters
==========
 
  The image data are in units of raw data numbers.  For TV1, all
  seven of the HRII&apos;s image modes were tested:
 
    Image  MinExp  X-Size  Y-Size  #Images
    Mode#  (sec)   (pix)   (pix)    Output  Binning  Comments
    -----  ------  ------  ------  -------  -------  ----------------------
      1     2.862    512     256       1      2x2
      2     1.432    512     128       1      2x2
      3     0.717    512      64       1      2x2
      4     2.861   1024     512       1      1x1
      5     2.865    512     256       1      2x2
      6     1.432   1024     512       2      1x1    Reset then data frame
      7     2.864   1024     512       1      1x1    Memory check mode
 
  In this table, MinExp is the frame-to-frame minimum exposure times,
  X-Size is spectral dimension and Y-Size is spatial dimension of the
  FPA.  For all image modes except 6, the reset frame is automatically
  subtracted, on-chip, from the data frame and the result is output.
  For more information about the image modes, see Hampton, et al. (2005)
  [HAMPTONETAL2005].
 
 
Data
====
 
  The data are in the form of FITS files with attached FITS headers
  and detached PDS labels. One data files contains one HRII
  2-dimensional image.  The fastest-varying axis (X) is the spectral
  dimension and slowest-varying axis (Y) is the spatial dimension
  along the spectrometer&apos;s slit.  TV1 data filenames have this format:
  Iyymmdd_hhmmss_sss_xn.FIT where the &apos;yymmdd_hhmmss_sss&apos; string the date,
  time and subseconds stamp provided by the ground-support computer
  when it stored the original data file.  The clock on the ground-support
  computer was set to local Mountain time.  The &apos;x&apos; string&apos; is valued
  with &apos;B&apos; for HRII data and the &apos;n&apos; string is only used for image
  mode 6 (see the last paragraph in this section).
 
  For TV1, the ground-support computer stored data files in a native
  image format, called &apos;IMG&apos;.  The raw data numbers were 14-bit and
  and left justified.  A 100-byte image header was prepended to each
  data array.  The &apos;IMG&apos; data were converted to FITS at the Deep Impact
  Science Data Center (SDC) at Cornell University, using algorithms
  developed by Ball Aerospace for testing of the instruments and to
  allow real-time analysis of data during thermal-vacuum tests.
  During the conversion, raw data numbers were right justified to
  give the actual, true data numbers.  Data in the 100-byte image header
  are captured in the FITS header.
 
  For HRII image mode 6, the ground-support computer stored a
  3-dimensional data file:  the first slice was the reset frame and
  the second slice was the data frame.  To avoid mixing product types
  in this data archive for one instrument, the SDC split the reset
  and read frames into two separate files, with the reset frame
  receiving a filename suffix of &apos;1&apos; and the data frame receiving a
  suffix of &apos;2&apos;.  This split was also required for TV2 HRII mode 6.
  However, by TV4, the ground-support computer was changed so that
  each read and data frame were written to separate 2-dimensional
  &apos;IMG&apos; files.
 
  Also, HRII spectral images have reference rows and columns that
  border the edges on the image array.  These areas are not exposed
  to light and are simply read out.  The number of rows and columns
  varies between the types of image modes.
 
         .
Ancillary Data
==============
 
  The DOCUMENT directory provides an image log recorded during TV1.
  The log contains an entry for each image acquired during TV1 and
  includes image parameters such as mode and experiment type.  The
  log includes a brief description of each type of experiment performed
  during TV1 and a summary of experiments performed on each test date.
 
  The DOCUMENT directory also provides daily reports written by the
  test leaders and distributed to the test team and the science
  team.  The reports describe in detail the test activities as well
  problems and successes encountered during TV1.
 
  The DOCUMENT directory includes the local PDS data dictionary used
  to produce the labels.
 
 
Media/Format
============
 
  This data set is released as a logical data volume.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    1) The time stamp in the FITS filename can vary by several
       tens of seconds of the actual time the image was acquired.
 
    2) TV1 was designed as a test run of the calibration procedures
      and processes to be used for the full thermal-vacuum test
      of the HRII instrument during August and September 2002
      (called TV2).  The data from TV1 have some noise because
      the FPA was only cooled to about 88K, the highest of the nominal
      operating temperatures for the instrument.  Also, during TV1,
      existing procedures were refined as testing was performed.
      The Deep Impact science team and Ball Aerospace engineers
      used these data to perform only a preliminary calibration
      of the HRII instrument.  These data were reviewed internally
      by the Deep Impact project before release to the planetary
      community.
 
    3) Instrument temperatures were not rigorously recorded for TV1.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

