<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dawn-m-grand-2-edr-mars-counts-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DAWN GRAND RAW (EDR) MARS FLYBY COUNTS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.dawn_mission_to_vesta_and_ceres::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:grand.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dawn-m-grand-2-edr-mars-counts-v1.0__browserp_dawn-m-grand-2-edr-mars-counts-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Prettyman, T.H., W.C. Feldman, F.P. Ameduri, B.L. Barraclough, E.W. Cascio,
                   K.R. Fuller, H.O. Funsten, D.J. Lawrence, G.W. McKinney, C.T. Russell, S.A.
                   Soldner, S.A. Storms, C. Szeles, and R.L. Tokar, Gamma-ray and neutron
                   spectrometer for the Dawn mission to 1 Ceres and 4 Vesta, IEEE Trans. Nucl.
                   Sci., Volume 50, Issue 4, pp. 1190-1197, August 2003, DOI
                   10.1109/TNS.2003.815156
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PRETTYMANETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DAWN-M-GRAND-2-EDR-MARS-COUNTS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DAWN GRAND RAW (EDR) MARS FLYBY COUNTS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2007-12-17T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2009-03-27T14:23:52Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>THOMAS H. PRETTYMAN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Prettyman, T.H., DAWN GRAND RAW (EDR) MARS FLYBY COUNTS V1.0.
            DAWN-M-GRAND-2-EDR-MARS-COUNTS-V1.0. NASA Planetary Data System,
            2009.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The GRaND Experimental Data Records (EDR) are a complete,
            time-ordered collection of state-of-health, gamma ray and neutron
            counting data, determined by reversible operations on the raw
            telemetry data.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The GRaND EDR are a time-ordered collection of gamma ray and
            neutron counting data and histograms acquired by GRaND during all
            phases of the Dawn mission. The dataset includes state-of-health
            data, such as temperature and voltage readings, needed for the
            analysis of the counting data. The EDR is an intermediate data
            product derived from the raw data records using reversible
            operations. All higher order data products are derived from the
            EDR. An automated pipeline is used to process the EDR from the
            raw data records.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Overview
  ========
 
The Dawn Mission&apos;s Gamma Ray and Neutron Detector (GRaND) is a nuclear
spectrometer that will collect data needed to map the elemental composition
of the surfaces of 4-Vesta and 1-Ceres [PRETTYMANETAL2003].  GRaND measures
the spectrum of planetary gamma rays and neutrons, which originate from
cosmic ray interactions and radioactive decay within the surface, while the
spacecraft (S/C) is in orbit around each body. The instrument, which is mounted
on the +Z deck of the S/C, consists of 21 sensors designed to separately
measure radiation originating from the surface of each asteroid and background
sources, including the space energetic particle environment and cosmic ray
interactions with the spacecraft.  The nuclear spectroscopy data provided
by GRaND will be analyzed to determine the abundance of major rock forming
elements, such as O, Fe, Ti, Si, Al, Mg, Ca, Cl and radioactive elements,
including K and Th, as well as light-elements such as H, C, and N, which are
constituents of ices and the products of aqueous alteration of silicate
minerals and ices.
 
The GRaND Experimental Data Records (EDR) are a time-ordered collection of
gamma ray and neutron counting data and histograms acquired by GRaND during
different phases of the Dawn Mission, including assembly-test-and-launch-
operations (ATLO), cruise, Mars Gravity Assist (MGA), and science mapping
at 4-Vesta and 1-Ceres.  The dataset also includes state-of-health data
(instrument settings, temperature and voltage readings) needed for
scientific analysis of the neutron and gamma ray data. The EDR is an
intermediate data product (Level 1A) that is derived from Raw Data Records
(Level 0) using reversible operations.  The Level 1A are the lowest level
of GRaND data archived in the PDS, from which all higher order data sets are
derived.  To support timely delivery of higher order products, the Level 1A
data are processed using an automated pipleline, which operates on Level 0
data when it is queried by the DSC.
 
The data set consists primarily of ASCII tables, divided into three
functional categories: auxilliary information (AUX); gamma ray spectra and
event data (GAMMA); and neutron spectra and event data (NEUTRON).  Gamma ray
and neutron event data are recorded in binary files.  Some of the data in the
ASCII files, which are human-readable, are repeated in the binary files to
aid in the verification of user-written routines.
 
The telemetry for GRaND consists of science and state-of-health data,
accumulated over time intervals, which are commandable. Each science data
record includes scalers, histograms, and event data accumulated over an
interval specified by the commandable parameter TELREADOUT (s).  The state of
health data include average temperatures, voltages, and instrument state data
acquired during time intervals specified by the commandable parameter
TELSOH (s).  Both intervals are adjustable, depending on the measurement
conditions and objectives for each mission phase.  During mapping, TELREADOUT
will be set to sub-sample spatial pixels defined on the surface of Vesta or
Ceres.  During cruise, TELREADOUT was generally set to large values (e.g.,
210s) to minimize data volume.  TELSOH is generally set to subsample the
science accumulation interval, providing information needed to determine
whether and how many times the science scalers have rolled over and information
needed to precisely determine the start time of the science acquisition
interval.
 
The data are downloaded regularly from the spacecraft by the Ground Data
System.  The UCLA Dawn Science Center (DSC) captures all of the payload
instrument telemetry frames as binary files after the data have been cleaned
up in post-pass processing to produce reconstructed Level-0 data.  The files
are inventoried within the Dawn Science Database (DSDb) and are retrieved by
the GRaND team, which unscrambles, decompresses, decodes, and formats the raw
telemetry data into scientifically useful data files.  The decompressed and
decoded data, along with their required PDS documentation, form the Level-1A
EDR data sets.  The Level-1a EDR data are determined by performing reversible
operations on the Level-1a data set, to produce counting data and spectral
products useful for mapping.
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
The EDR data are derived from Level 0 raw data queried by the DSC over irregular
time periods, generally determined by the pattern of downlinks from the
spacecraft.  The DSC divides the Level 0 data into separate files containing
state of health and science data packets.  The Level 1a pipeline operates on
these files to produce the Level 1a archive.  The directory structure for the
Level 1a data is given by
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC    (top level directory)
        LEVEL1A_AUX             (directory containing auxiliary data)
        LEVEL1A_GAMMA           (directory containing gamma ray counting data)
        LEVEL1A_NEUTRON         (directory containing neutron counting data)
 
The top level directory name contains the SCET UTC dates for the first and
last science data records (Y1M1D1 and Y2M2D2, respectively), and the creation
date (YCMCDC) for the archive.  For example, for GRD-L1A-090217-090218_090517,
the first science data record was acquired on 17-Feb-2009.  The last science
data record was acquired on 18-Feb-2009.  The archive was created by the
pipeline on 17-May-2009.
 
The LEVEL1A_AUX directory contains the following files derived from the
Level 0 state-of-health and science data:
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-STA.TAB - Instrument state file.
     The instrument state file contains the instrument settings, including
     the mode, power supply states, high voltage settings, the data
     accumulation interval, and coincidence windows.  The first record of the
     state-of-health file is recorded in the state file, stamped with SCET
     UTC.  Thereafter, rows are added only when the instrument settings
     change.
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-RDG.TAB - Instrument readings file.
     This file contains a time-ordered list of temperature and voltage
     readings averaged over each state-of-health accumulation interval
     (TELSOH), converted to physical units.
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-SOH-SCL.TAB - State of health scaler data.
     This file contains a time-ordered list of the scaler data recorded in
     the state-of-health telemetry.  The accumulation time for the scaler
     data is TELSOH.  Note that the scalers are reset at the end of each
     science accumulation interval (TELREADOUT).  If the state-of-health
     accumulation interval is selected to subsample the science interval,
     then the state-of-health scalers can be used to detect and correct for
     rollover of the science scalers, such as the dead time counter.
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-SCI-SCL.TAB - Science scaler data.
     This file contains a time-ordered list of the scaler data recorded in
     the science telemetry.  The accumulation interval for the scalers is
     TELREADOUT.
 
     For each science and state of health record, the values for 23 scalers
     are recorded in the Level1a dataset in the variables SCALER_SCI and
     SCALER_SOH.
 
     The scalers provide the following information:
 
     Index         Description
     ------------  -----------
     0             Dead time counts
     1             BGO overload events
     2             CZT overload events
     3             +Z phoswich overload events
     4             -Y BLP overload events
     5             +Y BLP overload events
     6             -Z phoswich overload events
     7             +Z phoswich CAT4 events
     8             -Y BLP CAT4 events
     9             +Y BLP CAT4 events
     10            -Z phoswich CAT4 events
     11            Early second interaction events
     12            Multiple-crystal CZT events
     13            Valid CZT events (CAT10)
     14            Coincidence BGO and CZT events (CAT7)
     15            Coincidence of three or more sensor elements
     16            Total events processed by GRaND
     17            Number of single CZT events (CAT10) in the
                   gamma ray event buffer
     18            Number of BGO-CZT coincidence events (CAT7) in the
                   gamma ray event buffer
     19            Number of events (CAT4) in the neutron event
                   buffer
     20            Total number of events allowed in the gamma
                   ray event buffer
     21            Number of single CZT events (CAT10) allowed in
                   the gamma ray event buffer
     22            Number of events allowed in the neutron event
                   buffer
 
     Note that indices 0 through 19 are for 16-bit counters, which are reset
     at the end of every science accumulation interval specified by TELREADOUT.
     If the state-of-health accumulation interval is adjusted to subsample the
     science accumulation interval (for example, TELREADOUT = n * TELSOH, where
     n is a whole number), then the scalers will monotonically increase during
     each acquisition interval, unless overflow occurs.  A rollover counter
     is not provided; however, for situations in which the counting rate is
     high or the accumulation intervals are large, the number of rollovers
     for individual scalers can be determined from the SOH scaler data if
     TELSOH is set to subsample the science accumulation interval.  In
     situations where the counting rate is changing, abrupt changes in the
     scaler varues can also indicate that rollover has occurred.  Rollover is
     treated in production of the Level1b RDR data.
 
     Indices 20 through 21 are maximum values for the number of events that
     can be recorded in the event buffers.  The number of gamma ray and
     neutron events is commandable and can be adjusted.  The total number of
     gamma ray and neutron events must be less than 6677.
 
The LEVEL1A_GAMMA directory contains the following science data files:
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-BGO.TAB
     This file contains a time-ordered list of pulse height spectra (1024
     channels with units of uncorrected counts/channel) acquired by the BGO
     sensor.
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-EMG.DAT
     This file contains gamma ray event data as a binary time series.
 
The LEVEL1A_NEUTRON directory contains the following science data files:
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-PHOS_MZ.TAB
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-PHOS_PZ.TAB
     These files contain time ordered lists of the 256-channel CAT1 pulse
     height spectra for the +Z and -Z phoswiches.  Note that the naming
     convention for the top, bottom, and side scintillators is determined by
     the instrument coordinate system.
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-BGO2_MZ.TAB
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-BGO2_PZ.TAB
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-BGO2_MY.TAB
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-BGO2_PY.TAB
     These files contain time ordered lists of the 64-channel CAT2 BGO pulse
     height spectra for coincidences with the BGO and the four BLP sensors.
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-BLP2_MZ.TAB
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-BLP2_PZ.TAB
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-BLP2_MY.TAB
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-BKP2_PY.TAB
     These files contain time ordered lists of the 64-channel CAT2 BLP pulse
     height spectra for coincidences with the BGO and the four BLP sensors.
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-EMN.DAT
     This file contains the neutron event data as a binary time series.
 
  Processing
  ==========
 
The Level 1A data are automatically processed using a pipeline, which
operates on files queried by the DSC over selected time intervals.  Each DSC
query separates the GRaND data into files containing state-of-health and
science data records, in the order in which they were received on the ground
and with corrupted packets removed.  The state-of-health data are further
divided into real time telemetry data and playback data.  The science data
are stored in a single raw data file.
 
The pipeline merges the state-of-health data from the playback and realtime
files to produce a time-ordered-list of records.  Selected data are extracted
to produce the Level 1A AUX files.  Internal temperature readings are
converted from data numbers (DN) to engineering units using a linear function
determined during ground calibration: T (degrees C) = 0.4354 DN - 0.4354.
The high voltage readings for the high voltage power supplies are reported
in engineering units using the conversion V (Volts) = 1500 DN/255.  The
CZT differential bias voltage is converted using V (Volts) = 0.405 DN.
 
The science data are decompressed, decoded, separated by functionality
and written as time-ordered ASCII tables and binary time series.  The
raw histograms (CAT1, CAT2, and CAT9) are represented as 8 bit numbers which
are decompressed and reported as 16 bit, unsigned integers.
 
The gamma ray event buffer can store up to 3876 events for each science
accumulation interval.  Each event is packed into 3 bytes, which
contain the ID of the CZT sensor, the CZT pulse amplitude, and the BGO pulse
amplitude.  The vales for each event are extracted and stored as a binary
time series.  When the gamma ray event buffer is not full, null events are
reported as zeros, such that each row of the Level 1A time series contains
3876 events.
 
The neutron event buffer can store up to 2800 events for each science data
accumulation interval.  Each event is packed into 3 bytes, which are
contain the BLP sensor ID and pulse amplitude for the first
interaction, the BLP sensor ID and pulse amplitude for the second interaction,
and the time between pulses.  The time between pulses has units of
100 nanoseconds/DN.  The vales for each event are extracted and stored as a
binary time series.  The pulse amplitudes are uncalibrated for Level 1A.
When the gamma ray event buffer is not full, null events are reported as
zeros, such that each row of the Level 1A time series contains 2800 events.
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
 
The Level 1A data include ancilliary data in the form of SCET UTC strings
reported in each row of the Level 1A data tables and time series.  The UTC
strings are determined from the spacecraft clock ticks recorded in each
state-of-health packet and for the first packet in each science data record
using NAIF SPICE (leap seconds kernel).  This information is used in Level 1B
processing to accurately determine the mid-point of each science accumulation
interval, which is needed for mapping.
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
 
The instrument coordinate system (Fig. 1) determines the naming convention of
the sensors and orientation of the instrument relative to the spacecraft.
The use of MZ indicates a sensor on the -Z (zenith-facing during mapping)
side of GRaND;  PZ indicates the sensor is on the +Z (spacecraft) side; MY
indicates the sensor is on the -Y side (inboard) side of the instrument; and
PY indicates the sensor is on the +Y side (outboard, towards the +Y solar
panel) side of the instrument.  The phototube assembly, marked &apos;P&apos; on the
diagram in Fig. 1 points along the +X axis (towards the high gain antenna).
 
   .................
   . ooooooooooooo .
   . o           o .
   . o           o .
   . o    +Z     o .
   . o   (PZ)    o .
   . o           o .---&gt; +Y (PY)
   . ooo       ooo .
   .   P       P   .
   .   P       P   .
   .   PPPPPPPPP   .
   .               .
   .................
           |
           v
        +X (PX)
 
Figure 1. The coordinate system for GRaND is the same as that of the S/C.
For the diagram above, the observer is looking in the -Z (MZ) direction and
can see the outline of the phoswich assembly (o) on the +Z side of GRaND.
The phototubes are on the +X side and the scintillators are on the -X side.
During mapping at Vesta and Ceres, the planetary surface is in the +Z
direction.
 
  Software
  ========
 
Proprietary software is not needed in order to use the EDR data; however, an
Interactive Data Language (IDL) functions (GRD_READ_L1A_SOH.PRO and
GRD_READ_L1A_SCIENCE.PRO) are provided to read selected EDR data into a
structure for analysis and visualization.  The IDL functions are compatible
with IDL Version 7.0, distributed by ITT Visual Information Solutions,
Boulder, CO (2008).  The documentation is included at the beginning of the
functions.
 
  Media/Format
  ============
 
The EDR label and data files are delivered by electronic transmission to the
PDS.  The neutron and gamma ray binary event data were written in big endian
IEEE binary format (MSB order).
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Review
  ======
 
The EDR will be reviewed internally by the Dawn Science Team prior to
submission to the PDS.  The PDS will also conduct an external peer review
of the EDR prior to releasing the data to the general public.
 
  Data Coverage/Quality
  =====================
 
With the exception of corrupted packets, the Level 1A EDR includes all of the
available data acquired during flight.  The archive contains gaps in time
when the instrument is off during cruise or in STANDBY or ANNEAL mode for
which science data are not acquired.
 
During ATLO, ICO, and EMC, state-of-health data were decimated by a factor of 3
for storage in the virtual recorder on board the spacecraft.  Consequently,
playback data contained every third state-of-health packet.  Full sampling of
GRaND housekeeping data was available infrequently during the acquisition of
real-time telemetry.  The spacecraft flight software was modified to
remove the decimation prior to GRaND power on for Mars Gravity Assist (TBD),
and, thereafter, housekeeping data volume was controlled by the selection of
TELSOH.  Consequently, fully-sampled housekeeping data are available in the
EDR following TBD.
 
  Safe-mode Event
  ===============
 
While Dawn successfully completed its gravity assist at Mars, the spacecraft
entered safe-mode shortly following closest approach. At that time, all of the
instruments were shut down. All planned activities which had not been executed
did not occur. Any data from activities which had taken place, but which had
not yet been dumped out of instrument memory and into the spacecraft virtual
recorder were lost. GRaND returned data through shortly after closest
approach. FC2 returned 6 lit images of Mars. VIR returned no data for the Mars
flyby.
 
  Limitations
  ===========
 
The EDR is a low-level data product, which requires significant processing
prior to use in scientific analysis.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

