<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mer2-m-mi-4-linearized-ops-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MER 2 MARS MICROSCOPIC IMAGER LINEARIZED RDR OPS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_exploration_rover::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mer2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mi.mer2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer2-m-mi-4-linearized-ops-v1.0__browserp_mer2-m-mi-4-linearized-ops-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer2-m-mi-4-linearized-ops-v1.0__browser_geo_analysts_notebook::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer2-m-mi-4-linearized-ops-v1.0__dvo_imaging_mer2-m-mi-4-linearized-ops-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mars Exploration Rover Mission, Camera Software Interface Specification, 2003
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CAMSIS2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Herkenhoff, K.E., et al., The Athena Microscopic Imager Investigation, Journal
                   of Geophysical Research, July 2, 2003.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HERKENHOFFETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MER2-M-MI-4-LINEARIZED-OPS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MER 2 MARS MICROSCOPIC IMAGER LINEARIZED RDR OPS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2004-08-03</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-01-05T05:37:43.593Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JUSTIN MAKI</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Maki, Justin, MER 2 Mars Microscopic Imager RDR Linearized Ops
            V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            MER2-M-MI-4-LINEARIZED-OPS-V1.0, 2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Mars Exploration Rover 2 Microscopic Imager Linearized Operations
            Reduced Data Record, Version 1.0
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>not applicable</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    EDRs and single-frame RDRs are described by a camera model. This
    model, represented by a set of vectors and numbers, permit a point
    in space to be traced into the image plane, and vice-versa.
 
    EDR camera models are derived by acquiring images of a calibration
    target with known geometry at a fixed azimuth/elevation. The vectors
    representing the model are derived from analysis of this imagery.
    These vectors are then translated and rotated based on the actual
    pointing of the camera to represent the conditions of each specific
    image. The results are the camera model for the EDR.
 
    The Navcam and Pancam use a CAHVOR model, while the Hazcams use a
    more general CAHVORE model. Neither are linear and involve some
    complex calculations to transform line/sample points in the image
    plane to XYZ positions in the scene. To simplify this, the images
    are warped, or reprojected, such that they can be described by a
    linear CAHV model. This linearization process has several benefits:
 
    1) It removes geometric distortions inherent in the camera
       instruments, with the result that straight lines in the scene are
       straight in the image.
 
    2) It aligns the images for stereo viewing. Matching points are on
       the same image line in both left and right images, and both left
       and right models point in the same direction.
 
    3) It facilitates correlation, allowing the use of 1-D correlators.
 
    4) It simplifies the math involved in using the camera model.
 
    However, it also introduces some artifacts in terms of scale change
    and/or omitted data (see the references). The linearized CAHV camera
    model is derived from the EDR camera model by considering both the
    left and right eye models and constructing a pair of matched linear
    CAHV models that conform to the above criteria.
 
    The image is then projected, or warped, from the CAHVOR/CAHVORE
    model to the CAHV model. This involves projecting each pixel through
    the EDR camera model into space, intersecting it with a surface
    (which matters only for Hazcams and is a sphere centered on the
    camera), and projecting the pixel back through the CAHV model into
    the output image.
 
    C - The 3D position of the entrance pupil
 
    A - A unit vector normal to the image plane pointing outward
       (towards C)
 
    H - A vector pointing roughly rightward in the image; it is a
        composite of the orientation of the CCD rows, the horizontal
        scale, the horizontal center
 
    V - A vector pointing roughtly downward in the image; it is a
        composite of the orientation of the CCD columns, the vertical
        scale, the vertical center, and A.
 
    If P is a point in the scene then the corresponding image locations
    x and y can be computed from:
 
    x = (P-C)H
        ------
        (P-C)A
 
 
    y = (P-C)V
        ------
        (P-C)A
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    This Operations RDR is produced by OPGS/MIPL using the Mars Suite of
    VICAR image processing software.
 
    Single-frame RDRs are described by a camera model. This model,
    represented by a set of vectors and numbers, permit a point in space
    to be traced into the image plane, and vice-versa.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    1 band, 16-bit signed integer, dual PDS/VICAR (OPGS) binary file.
 
    The RDR data product is comprised of radiometrically decalibrated
    and/or camera model corrected and/or geometrically altered versions
    of the raw camera data, in both single and multi-frame (mosaic)
    form. Most RDR data products will have PDS labels, or if generated
    by MIPL (OPGS), dual PDS/VICAR labels. Non-labeled RDRs include the
    Terrain products (Mesh and Wedge).
 
    The following is a list of the types of Linearized files along with
    the Product Type Identifier, which is an element in the formal RDR
    file name:
 
    Data Product       Linearized
    ------------       ----------
    Full frame EDR        FFL
    Sub-frame EDR         SFL
    Downsampled EDR       DNL
    Thumbnail EDR         THN
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The MIPL Mars Program Suite was used to generate these RDRs.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    The data set will initially be delivered and kept online.  Upon
    Mission completion, the Microscopic Imager Operations RDRs will be
    delivered to PDS on DVD.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
NULL
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

