<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.arcb-nrao-l-rtls-gbt-4-5-70cm-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ARECIBO/NRAO MOON RTLS/GBT 4/5 70CM V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.arcb::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.nrao::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:gbt.nrao::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rtls.arcb::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.arcb-nrao-l-rtls-gbt-4-5-70cm-v1.0__browserp_geo_arcb-nrao-l-rtls-gbt-4-5-70cm-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.arcb-nrao-l-rtls-gbt-4-5-70cm-v1.0__dvo_geo_arcb-nrao-l-rtls-gbt-4-5-70cm-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Campbell, B.A., D.B. Campbell, J.L. Margot, R.R. Ghent, M. Nolan, J. Chandler,
                   L.M. Carter, and N. Stacy, Focused 70-cm wavelength radar mapping of the Moon,
                   IEEE Transactions on Geoscience and Remote Sensing, 2006, submitted.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CAMPBELLETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>ARCB/NRAO-L-RTLS/GBT-4/5-70CM-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ARECIBO/NRAO MOON RTLS/GBT 4/5 70CM V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2007-07-18</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2006-01-01</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>BRUCE A. CAMPBELL</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Campbell, B.A., and J. Ward, Dual- Polarization Calibrated Radar
            Map of the Moon, ARCB/NRAO-L-RTLS/GBT-4/5-70CM-V1.0, NASA
            Planetary Data System, 2007.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This dataset contains a dual-polarization calibrated radar map of
            the moon collected at a wavelength of 70 cm.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Radar backscatter power from the lunar surface was collected at a
            wavelength of 70 cm, using the 305 m Radio Telescope at Arecibo
            to transmit and the NRAO&apos;s 105 m Robert C. Byrd Green Bank
            Telescope to receive.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    The data products in the DATA directory are organized into folders based
    on NASA data processing level. Data in the &apos;level1&apos; folder correspond to
    NASA Level 1B, or PDS Level 4 Resampled Data. According to the PDS
    Standards Reference, these are &apos;data that have been resampled in time or
    space domains in such a way that the original edited data cannot be
    reconstructed.&apos; Data in the &apos;level2&apos; folder correspond to NASA Level 2, or
    PDS Level 5 Derived Data. According to the PDS Standards Reference, these
    are &apos;derived results, as maps, reports, graphics, etc.&apos;
 
    The &apos;level1&apos; and &apos;level2&apos; folders contain 80 and 100 image files,
    respectively. Each image has an accompanying detached PDS label. The
    &apos;level1&apos; data set consists of 4 image files for each of 20 lunar &apos;quads.&apos;
    The images are named as follows: xxxx_dep_level1.img (depolarized map),
    xxxx_pol_level1.img (polarized map), xxxx_beam_level1.img (map of beam
    angle in radians), and xxxx_inc_level1.img (map of incidence angle in
    radians), where xxxx is an abbreviation of the FEATURE_NAME (named for a
    prominent feature within each image &apos;quad&apos;) listed in the PDS label. The
    &apos;level2&apos; data set consists of 5 image files for each of the 20 lunar
    &apos;quads.&apos; The naming convention is the same as that of &apos;level1&apos; for the
    &apos;dep&apos;, &apos;pol&apos;, &apos;beam&apos;, and &apos;inc&apos; maps, however the &apos;level2&apos; data set also
    includes a circular polarization ratio image, xxxx_rat_level2.img. North is
    at the top of the frame in all of these images.
 
    Level 1:
    For the polarized (&apos;pol&apos;) and depolarized (&apos;dep&apos;) maps, the floating
    point values represent the relative backscatter power from the lunar
    surface at a radar wavelength of 70 cm (430 MHz frequency). &apos;Polarized&apos;
    refers to energy scattered from the lunar surface in the opposite circular
    polarization sense to that transmitted (the behavior expected of a flat,
    mirror-like reflecting surface). &apos;Depolarized&apos; refers to reflected energy
    with the same sense of circular polarization (the behavior expected from a
    surface with abundant wavelength-scale objects that randomize the reflected
    polarization).
 
    The data were collected by transmitting a circular polarized signal from
    the Arecibo Observatory, and receiving the lunar echoes at the Robert C.
    Byrd Green Bank Telescope in West Virginia. The transmitted signal was a
    series of 3 microsecond pulses separated by 15 ms to allow for the full
    possible range of echo time delays over the Moon&apos;s surface. No pulse
    compression techniques (for example, Barker coding or a chirped signal)
    were used. A patch focusing method was used to correct for time-varying
    Doppler changes at lunar surface points distant from the radar pointing
    target. Multiple independent integration periods (looks) were added
    together to reduce radar speckle.
 
    Image power values were normalized to the effective scattering area that
    contributes to each pixel (based on a reference spherical shape) and to the
    thermal background noise measured at the Green Bank Telescope. Results are
    thus proportional to the backscatter coefficient, but have not been
    calibrated for the transmitted power, variation in antenna gain across the
    scene, or the absolute power represented by the Green Bank Telescope
    thermal noise. Ratios between the two circular polarization channels are
    well calibrated. The stated location of the sub-radar point and the
    apparent Doppler angle and center-to-limb bandwidth (Hz) at 430 MHz are
    approximate values at the center of the multi-look observing period.
 
    The incidence angle value for each pixel represents the angle (in
    radians) between a vector from the Moon&apos;s center of mass (COM) to the
    surface location and the vector from the COM that passes through the
    sub-radar point. Values near the radar-visible limb of the Moon thus
    approach 90 degrees. This angle is often used to correct a radar
    backscatter image for variations in brightness due to the &apos;scattering law&apos;
    of the surface.
 
    The beam angle value for each pixel represents the angle (in radians)
    between a vector from the observer to the surface location and the vector
    from the observer to the radar pointing target given for each &apos;quad.&apos; This
    angle may be used to correct for the decrease in incident power and
    receiving antenna sensitivity with offset from the pointing target.
 
    Level 2:
    The Level 2 images and ancillary data (incidence and beam angle) have
    been warped to match the Clementine basemap, adjusted for the average net
    Arecibo-GBT beam pattern, and calibrated to our best estimate of absolute
    backscatter coefficient (&apos;sigma zero&apos;). These maps are also normalized to
    the average lunar power scattering behavior (set to unity, or zero dB, at
    zero incidence angle), given for the polarized and depolarized channels by:
 
    Pol = 10^([-1.4372 P + 0.02545 P^2 - 0.000168 P^3]/10)
    Dep = cos(P),
 
    where P is the incidence angle in degrees.
 
    In addition to the &apos;pol&apos; and &apos;dep&apos; images, the archive also includes
    &apos;rat&apos;, &apos;beam&apos;, and &apos;inc&apos; images. The &apos;rat&apos; image files, found only in the
    &apos;level2&apos; data set, are circular polarization ratio images formed by
    averaging &apos;valid&apos; pixels in a 5x5 grid and dividing the averaged &apos;dep&apos; data
    by the averaged &apos;pol&apos; data. No other normalization is performed, so the
    polarization ratio images have a strong decrease toward the center of the
    Moon (lower incidence angle). Values of unity and greater are typical of
    rough surfaces, particularly at high incidence angles where the diffuse
    scattering component dominates the echo. The other image files (&apos;beam&apos; and
    &apos;inc&apos;) display the beam angle and incidence angle, respectively, in radians
    for each pixel. These co-registered maps, in floating point format, will
    allow a user to reverse the applied calibration steps if desired.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Known Problems =
 
    (a) The individual radar looks are combined with a second-order rubbersheet
    transform that compensates for minor variations in the apparent origin of
    the radar coordinate system. The edges of a Level 1 map may thus have
    pixels that do not reflect a sum of data values from every look. These
    low-quality border areas are less than 10 pixels in extent. The edges of
    each Level 2 quad are &apos;trimmed&apos; of these pixels, so the maps can be more
    readily mosaicked.
 
    (b) Separate quad maps may have spatial offsets of order 4 km with respect
    to the Clementine image base, but it is unknown to what degree these
    offsets are due to errors in the lunar radar ephemeris or the Clementine
    lunar reference grid.
 
    (c) There is considerable uncertainty (up to a factor of 2) in the absolute
    transmitted power at Arecibo. This translates into up to 3 dB of offset
    between mosaicked Level 2 image products. Good-quality mosaics may be
    obtained by a simple multiplicative shift between images, but the absolute
    backscatter coefficient must be regarded as uncertain by this 3 dB factor.
    The polarization ratios are much better calibrated, and are accurate to at
    least the 10% level.
 
    (d) Delay-Doppler radar images of a planet have a north-south ambiguity
    about the line on the plane of the sky (the &apos;Doppler equator&apos;)
    perpendicular to the apparent spin axis. This means that some observations,
    particularly those collected for areas near the center of the Moon, may
    have blurred bright patches associated with echoes from rugged features in
    the undesired hemisphere. In general, these are only visible in quads near
    the center of the Moon (for example, with the bright crater Tycho appearing
    as a blurred patch near the crater Copernicus). Careful mosaicking of
    overlapping coverage can avoid these unwanted contributions.
 
    (e) The polarized (opposite-sense circular) data for &apos;quads&apos; &apos;Canon&apos; and
    &apos;Faraday&apos; suffered from saturation of the analog/digital converter at low
    incidence angles (closer to the center of the Moon). This led to an
    apparent reduction in echo power with decreasing incidence angle. The error
    was corrected in an approximate sense by comparison of the overlap between
    these two &apos;quads&apos; and other data collected without saturation effects. The
    polarization ratio values for incidence angles less than 45 degrees for
    these two &apos;quads&apos; should be treated as only approximate.
 
    This data set underwent external peer review from April to July 2007.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

