<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mgs-m-rss-5-eds-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MGS RS: IONOSPHERIC ELECTRON DENSITY PROFILES V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_global_surveyor::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mgs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.mgs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-rss-5-eds-v1.0__browserp_mgs-m-rss-5-eds-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Clancy, R.T., B.J. Sandor, M.J. Wolff, P.R. Christensen, M.D. Smith, J.C.
                   Pearl, B.J. Conrath, and R.J. Wilson, An Intercomparison of Ground-Based
                   Millimeter, MGS TES, and Viking Atmospheric Temperature Measurements: Seasonal
                   and Interannual Variability of Temperatures and Dust Loading in the Global Mars
                   Atmosphere, Journal of Geophysical Research, 105, 9553-9571, 2000.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CLANCYETAL2000</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Davies, M.E., V.K. Abalakin, A. Brahic, M. Bursa, B.H. Chovitz, J.H. Lieske,
                   P.K. Seidelmann, A.T. Sinclair, and Y.S. Tjuflin, Report of the IAU/IAG/COSPAR
                   Working Group on Cartographic Coordinates and Rotational Elements of the
                   Planets and Satellites: 1991, Celestial Mechanics and Dynamical Astronomy, 53,
                   377-397, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DAVIESETAL1992B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Fjeldbo, G., A.J. Kliore, and V.R. Eshleman, The Neutral Atmosphere of Venus as
                   Studied with the Mariner V Radio Occultation Data, Astron. J., 76, 123-140,
                   1971.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FJELDBOETAL1971</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hinson, D.P., R.A. Simpson, J.D. Twicken, G.L. Tyler, and F.M. Flasar, Initial
                   Results from Radio Occultation Measurements with Mars Global Surveyor, Journal
                   of Geophysical Research, 104, 26997-27012, 1999.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HINSONETAL1999</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hinson, D.P., G.L. Tyler, J.L. Hollingsworth, and R.J. Wilson, Radio
                   Occultation Measurements of Forced Atmospheric Waves on Mars, Journal of
                   Geophysical Research, 106, 1463-1480, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HINSONETAL2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hinson, D.P., M.D. Smith, and B.J. Conrath, Comparison of Atmospheric
                   Temperatures Obtained through Infrared Sounding and Radio Occultation by Mars
                   Global Surveyor, Journal of Geophysical Research, 109, E12002,
                   doi:10.1029/2004JE002344, 2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HINSONETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Konopliv, A.S., and W.L. Sjogren, The JPL Mars Gravity Field, Mars50C, Based
                   upon Viking and Mariner 9 Doppler Tracking Data, Jet Propulsion Laboratory
                   Publication 95-5, Pasadena, CA., 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KONOPLIV-SJOGREN1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tyler, G.L., G. Balmino, D.P. Hinson, W.L. Sjogren, D.E. Smith, R. Woo, S.W.
                   Asmar, M.J. Connally, C.L. Hamilton, and R.A. Simpson, Radio Science
                   Investigations with Mars Observer, Journal of Geophysical Research, 97,
                   7759-7779, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TYLERETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tyler, G.L., G. Balmino, D.P. Hinson, W.L. Sjogren, D.E. Smith, R.A. Simpson,
                   S.W. Asmar, P. Priest, and J.D. Twicken, Radio science observations with Mars
                   Global Surveyor: Orbit insertion through one Mars year in mapping orbit,
                   Journal of Geophysical Research, 106, 23327-23348, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TYLERETAL2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MGS-M-RSS-5-EDS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MGS RS: IONOSPHERIC ELECTRON DENSITY PROFILES V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2008-05-31</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1998-12-24T03:47:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2005-06-09T23:52:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID P. HINSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Hinson, D.P., Mars Global Surveyor Radio Occultation Profiles of
            the Ionosphere - Reorganized, MGS-M-RSS-5-EDS-V1.0, NASA
            Planetary Data System, 2008.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Mars Global Surveyor radio occultation ionospheric electron
            density profiles - reorganized onto one volume.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains 5600 ionospheric electron density profiles
            (EDS files) derived from Mars Global Surveyor (MGS) radio
            occultation data. The profiles were previously archived in the
            MGS-M-RSS-5-SDP-V1.0 data set along with other reduced data
            products from the MGS Radio Science Team (RST). Here they have
            been pulled from the original 38 volumes and reorganized in
            chronological order on a single volume. The profiles themselves
            have not been modified, and the labels have been edited only to
            conform with the requirements of the new data set. This set of
            profiles is accompanied by a single occultation summary file
            which lists key characteristics of each experiment.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      MGS radio occultation experiments were conducted using a 3.6-cm
      wavelength radio signal transmitted by the spacecraft and received
      on Earth.  In principle this &apos;downlink&apos; configuration allows
      atmospheric structure to be sampled twice per orbit. Occultation
      entry and exit generally occurred in the northern and southern
      hemispheres, respectively, and the latitude of the measurements
      drifted gradually in response to changes in the observing geometry.
      However, far more experiments were performed at occultation
      entry than exit, owing to a problem with one of the gimbals used
      to point the spacecraft high-gain antenna (HGA).  This resulted
      in particularly dense coverage at latitudes of 60-80 deg in the
      northern hemisphere. The coverage in longitude of the data set
      is fairly dense and uniform with few exceptions.
 
      EDS files are stored as ASCII tables, preceded by a header record
      which contains supplementary information as described below.
      The headers from each individual file have been collected in a
      single occultation summary file, which may be useful for scanning
      the data set, identifying profiles of particular interest, and
      reviewing the coverage in latitude, season, and solar zenith
      angle.
 
      David Hinson at Stanford University created all EDS files and the
      occultation summary file.
 
      For more information about these data, see [TYLERETAL1992],
      [HINSONETAL1999], [HINSONETAL2001], and [TYLERETAL2001].
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      Each EDS file contains a table of electron number density versus
      radius from Mars&apos; center of mass.  The file also specifies the
      altitude of each sample relative to the equipotential surface, or
      areoid, whose mean equatorial radius is 3,396,000 m.  Each profile
      extends in altitude from about 90 km to 200 km with a sample
      spacing of about 1 km.  A header record prepended to each table
      provides information about observing times, experiment geometry,
      and files used in the data processing.
 
      The radius of the reference areoid at a given latitude and
      longitude is computed using a spherical harmonic model of the
      gravity field, with an additional centrifugal term that arises
      from the rotation of Mars.  Note that different spherical harmonic
      models were used in defining the altitude scale for the experiments
      conducted in 1998 (GGM50A02.SHA) and those conducted in 1999-2006
      (JGM75C01.SHA).  See [KONOPLIV&amp;SJOGREN1995] for a definition
      of how the coefficients in these models are normalized.  The
      spherical harmonic models can be found in PDS data set
      MGS-M-RSS-5-SDP-V1.0.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The MGS radio occultation experiments were optimized for sounding
      the neutral atmosphere, but electron density profiles were also
      obtained from a limited subset of observations.  The retrieval
      algorithm involves no a priori assumptions about the shape of
      the electron density profile, the peak density, or the altitude
      of the peak, but the electron density is assumed to be zero at
      altitudes below about 90 km and above about 250 km.  The typical
      uncertainty in the MGS electron density profiles is several
      thousand per cubic centimeter.  At this level of sensitivity,
      reliable profiles could be obtained over an altitude range of
      about 90-200 km for experiments in which the solar zenith angle
      was less than about 90 degrees.
 
      Electron density profiles are derived from raw receiver output
      in several steps.
 
      First, deterministic sources of frequency change are identified
      and removed coherently. These included motion of the spacecraft,
      motion of the Earth receiving station, drift of the UltraStable
      Oscillator (USO), and relativistic effects associated with
      gravity fields of solar system bodies.  This leaves the carrier
      signal at a known frequency except for phase drift associated
      with passage of the radio ray through Mars&apos; atmosphere and/or
      ionosphere.  Drift associated with passage through solar plasma
      or the Earth&apos;s atmosphere or ionosphere is assumed to be
      negligible over the time of a Mars occultation (approximately
      two minutes).
 
      Second, using an accurate reconstruction of the spacecraft
      trajectory, the phase of the signal versus time is converted
      into a measure of refraction angle versus impact parameter --
      the perpendicular distance between the incoming raypath and the
      center of curvature of the atmosphere.
 
      Third, the index of refraction versus radius is obtained using
      an Abel inversion [FJELDBOETAL1971].  At ionospheric heights, the
      refractive index is determined predominantly by free electrons,
      and there is a simple linear relationship between refractive
      index and electron number density.  An electron density profile
      is obtained by applying this linear transformation to the
      refractive index profile, using coefficients that depend on the
      measurement frequency (8423 MHz).
 
 
    Data
    ====
      Data are stored on a single volume in the EDS directory
      in subdirectories in the order they were collected.  Twelve
      subdirectories have been defined with names of the form
      yyyy_ddd  where  yyyy  is the year and  ddd  is the day-of-year
      of the first profile in each directory.  Directory boundaries
      have been chosen so that collections have common characteristics,
      such as similar Ls values, or are easily separated by periods
      when there was little MGS RST activity, such as solar conjunction
      or spacecraft anomalies when no data were collected.  When these
      criteria allowed more than 1000 profiles in a directory,
      arbitrary boundaries were added.  The largest directory
      contains only 877 profiles.  The directories and their
      boundaries are summarized below.
 
      Electron density profiles are stored with file names of
      the form  ydddhmmC.EDS  where  y  is the least significant
      digit of the year,  ddd  is the three-digit day number,
      h  is a one-character string denoting the hour, and  mm  is
      a two-character string denoting the minute in which data
      acquisition began.  h  is  &apos;A&apos; if the hour was  00,  &apos;B&apos;
      if the hour was  01, ... and &apos;X&apos; if the hour was 23.  In
      most cases  mm  is the two-digit minute; but when data were
      collected from two sources and the start time was in the
      same minute, the second digit in  mm  was changed to a
      letter in the second file name (minute  00  becomes  0A,  01
      becomes  0B,  etc.).  C  is a single character
      indicating the version of the file, starting with &apos;A&apos;.
 
      An occultation summary file is stored in the OCS directory.
      Its file name is 812506AA.OCS where 812 indicates that the
      first occultation was from December 1998 and 506 indicates that
      the last occultation was from June 2005. &apos;AA&apos; is a two
      character string which indicates that this is the first version
      of the file.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      OCCLOG.TAB in the DOCUMENT directory provides single-line
      summaries for each observation opportunity.  Parameters listed
      mostly relate to settings of and quick-look results from data
      acquisition.  See detached PDS label OCCLOG.LBL for details.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      MGS RST SDP files use a Mars centered body-fixed coordinate
      system with positive east longitude.
 
      Gravity models generally use the IAU 1991 [DAVIESETAL1992B]
      coordinate frame.  Variations are noted in the labels of
      specific gravity products.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      None.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The archival data set was written on CD-WO media using the
      Sun Ultra-60/PlexWriter system.  The CD-WO volumes conform
      to ISO 9660 standards.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this archive have been reduced as part of mission data
      analysis activities of the MGS Radio Science Team.  Products
      of questionable validity have been flagged or omitted.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was reviewed by the MGS Radio Science
      Team prior to submission to the Planetary Data System (PDS).
 
      All of the profiles had been in the public domain as elements
      of the MGS-M-RSS-5-SDP-V1.0 data set for as much as seven years
      before this reorganized data set was compiled.
 
    Data Coverage
    ==============
 
      The following table describes the directories that contain
      the profiles.  Each directory is represented by one row.  The
      first two columns list the year and day-of-year of the first
      and last profiles in each directory, respectively.  The first
      column is also the directory name.  The third and fourth
      columns provide the same information in standard calendar
      format.  The fifth and sixth columns give the number of the
      Martian year (MY, as defined by [CLANCYETAL2000]) and the
      approximate areocentric longitude of the Sun (Ls, in degrees)
      of the first and last profiles in each directory, respectively.
      The last column specifies the number of profiles in each
      directory.  Blank rows denote major gaps between measurements
      in different Martian years.
 
       Start     End       Start       End      Start   End
      yyyy_ddd yyyy_ddd  yyyy-mm-dd yyyy-mm-dd  MY/Ls  MY/Ls   Number
      -------- --------  ---------- ----------  ------ ------  ------
      1998_358 1998_365  1998-12-24 1998-12-31  24/074 24/077    32
      1999_068 1999_086  1999-03-09 1999-03-27  24/108 24/116    43
      1999_126 1999_149  1999-05-06 1999-05-29  24/135 24/146   220
 
      2000_306 2001_031  2000-11-01 2001-01-31  25/070 25/111   732
      2001_032 2001_157  2001-02-01 2001-06-06  25/111 25/174   840
 
      2002_305 2002_365  2002-11-01 2002-12-31  26/089 26/116   526
      2003_001 2003_080  2003-01-01 2003-03-21  26/116 26/156   650
      2003_081 2003_155  2003-03-22 2003-06-04  26/156 26/197   630
      2003_173 2003_183  2003-06-22 2003-07-02  26/208 26/214    76
 
      2004_328 2004_357  2004-11-23 2004-12-22  27/119 27/133   270
      2004_361 2005_090  2004-12-26 2005-03-31  27/135 27/185   877
      2005_091 2005_160  2005-04-01 2005-06-09  27/185 27/227   704
 
 
      MGS radio occultation experiments were capable of sounding
      the lower neutral atmosphere under a wide range of conditions,
      but reliable electron density profiles could be obtained only
      when the solar zenith angle was less than about 90 degrees
      at the location of the measurement.  For this reason the MGS
      mission produced far fewer electron density profiles (5600)
      than profiles of the neutral atmosphere (21243).
 
      Coverage of the ionosphere was limited by other factors.
      This is particularly true during the pre-mapping phases of
      the mission, which extended into early 1999.  Prior to the
      start of the mapping phase, the spacecraft frequently
      conducted special maneuvers for aerobraking and temperature
      control, and scientific observations were constrained by
      numerous other operational issues.  The following discussion
      summarizes the most significant gaps in coverage that occurred
      during the mapping phase of the mission.
 
      Low Solar Zenith Angles
      -----------------------
        Because the orbit of Mars is outside the orbit of Earth,
        occultations tend to take place near the terminator.
        Scientists interested in studying convection in the
        neutral atmosphere or peak electron densities in the
        ionosphere will find relatively few observations near
        local noon except where the occultation point is at polar
        latitudes.
 
      Solar Conjunction
      ------------------
        The noise level of the radio occultation measurements
        increased dramatically near solar conjunction.  This
        prevented retrieval of profiles in the following intervals:
        2000_153 - 2000_213
        2002_197 - 2002_250
        2004_204 - 2004_283
        2006_263 - 2006_277
 
      Beta Supplement
      ----------------
        The range of motion of one of the gimbals that controls
        pointing of the spacecraft HGA was severely restricted
        until late in the mission, when the obstruction vanished
        for reasons unknown. During the extended intervals when
        the failed gimbal prevented normal operations, the
        spacecraft was configured in a &apos;beta supplement&apos; mode
        that restored most of its functionality. This had no
        effect on measurements at occultation entry (northern
        hemisphere) but experiments could not be conducted
        routinely at occultation exit (southern hemisphere) when
        the spacecraft was in the beta supplement mode:
        2000_039 - 2001_171
        2002_073 - 2003_253
        2004_204 - 2005_251
 
      Spacecraft Anomalies and Emergencies
      --------------------------------------
        The spacecraft occasionally stopped collecting scientific
        data for periods of several days in response to problems
        with flight software or hardware.  This prevented
        occultation experiments from being conducted in the
        following intervals:
        2001_123 - 2001_129
        2002_059 - 2002_065
        2002_092 - 2002_100
        2003_162 - 2003_168
        2004_358 - 2004_360
        2005_239 - 2005_251
        2005_256 - 2005_261
 
 
    Data Quality
    =============
 
      Each profile includes uncertainties on the estimates of
      electron number density.  This is the best source of
      information about data quality.  Some obvious trends are
      apparent in the error bars, such as a general increase
      in the noise level when the spacecraft was close to solar
      conjunction.  Data quality can vary significantly between
      successive experiments, and sometimes from one DSN complex
      to another, and these variations are reflected in the
      error bars.
 
      Some error sources are difficult to quantify, and their
      effects are therefore not included in the formal
      uncertainties. As a general rule, diametric occultations
      yield more reliable results than grazing occultations.
      (The header of each profile includes several parameters,
      such as the &apos;angle from diametric&apos;, that characterize
      the experiment geometry.)
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The limitations in this data set follow from the quality of
      the execution, which is described above under Data Coverage
      and Quality.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

