<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.pvo-v-onms-4-ionmaxcountrate-12sec-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>PVO VENUS ONMS BROWSE SUPRTHRML ION MAX COUNT RATE 12S V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.pioneer_venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.pvo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:onms.pvo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.pvo-v-onms-4-ionmaxcountrate-12sec-v1.0__browserp_pvo-v-onms-4-ionmaxcountrate-12sec-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Guenther, Y.P., &apos;Pioneer Venus Neutral Mass Spectrometer,&apos; NASA/Goddard
                   Space Flight Center Summer Institute on Atmospheric Science, Laboratory for
                   Planetary Atmospheres, Code 910, 1989.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GUENTHER1989</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kasprzak, W.T., H.B. Niemann and P. Mahaffy, Observations of Energetic Ions
                   on the Nightside of Venus, Journal of Geophysical Research, vol. 32,
                   291-298, 1987.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KASPRZAKETAL1987</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Niemann, H.B. and W.T. Kasprzak, Comparative Neutral Composition
                   Instrumentation and New Results, Advances in Space Research, vol. 2,
                   261-270, 1983.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NIEMANN-KASPRZAK1983</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Niemann, H.B., J.R.Booth, J.E. Cooley, R.E. Hartle, W.T. Kasprzak,
                   N.W.Spencer, S.H. Way, D.M. Hunten and G.R. Carignan, Pioneer Venus
                   Orbiter Neutral Gas Mass Spectrometer, IEEE Trans. on Geoscience and
                   Remote Sensing, vol. GE-18 (1), 60-65, 1980.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NIEMANNETAL1980B</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>PVO-V-ONMS-4-IONMAXCOUNTRATE-12SEC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>PVO VENUS ONMS BROWSE SUPRTHRML ION MAX COUNT RATE 12S V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1993-03-31</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1978-12-05T15:06:31.820Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1992-10-07T19:50:28.680Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. WAYNE KASPRZAK</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>TBD</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains PVO Neutral Mass Spectrometer superthermal
            ion data. Each record contains the maximum count rate per second
            in a 12 second period beginning with the time of the first data
            point for a given mass number.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains PVO Neutral Mass Spectrometer superthermal
            ion data. Each record contains the maximum count rate per second
            in a 12 second period beginning with the time of the first data
            point for a given mass number.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
       Dataset Overview
       ================
       This data set represents the maximum count rate per second in a
       12 second period beginning with the time of the first data point
       for a given mass number. Although species other than O+ cannot be
       reduced to to a flux and direction it is possible to estimate the
       approximate flux from the maximum count rate per second occurring
       within one spin period (about 12 seconds). The maximum count rate
       can be approximately converted to a flux using:
 
       [4.E7 (particles/cm**2/sec)]/[1.E4 (counts/sec)].
 
       This sensitivity is for O+. At higher mass numbers the sensitivity
       is less, being about a factor of 2.5 lower for Ar+.
 
       The instrument has detected superthermal, energetic
       or fast ions whose energy exceeds 36 eV in the spacecraft
       frame of reference.  These ions were observed in early orbits
       during measurements of the neutral density near periapsis, have
       an erratic and unpredictable signature, and occur at too high an
       altitude to be due to the neutral atmosphere. When the altitude
       of periapsis increased above the point where sensible neutral
       density measurements could be made, the instrument was configured
       specifically to detect superthermal ions.  In general, for orbit
       numbers 1 to 645, data were taken from the RPA mode.  The gas
       background signal with the filament on is about a factor of 10
       less in this mode than in non-RPA mode, resulting in a lower
       detection threshold. For orbit numbers above 923, the instrument
       was deliberately configured with the filament off and non-RPA
       mode data was used. For mass 16 the RPA voltage is about +3.8
       volts.
 
       The superthermal ion species regularly monitored include: He+, N+,
       O+, (N+ +  CO+), and CO2+. Because of the paucity of data at other
       mass numbers only mass 16 (atomic oxygen) has been reduced to a
       flux and number density. As part of the reduction process the
       angle in the ecliptic plane of the apparent ion flow in spacecraft
       reference frame has been deduced. The flux values are estimated
       in the spacecraft reference frame relative to spacecraft ground.
       The density is computed from the flux by dividing it by a speed
       corresponding to 40 eV. No correction has been applied to the
       angle, density or flux in order to remove the effect of spacecraft
       velocity.
 
       Data Processing and Sampling
       ============================
       The data reduction process has been described in literature
       [KASPRZAKETAL1987]. The method used to reduce the data assumes
       cylindrical symmetry of the ion source.  In actual fact, the
       source is asymmetrical in its angular response [GUENTHER1989].
       This can introduce as much as a factor of 2 scatter in the data.
       No simple solution has been found for modeling this asymmetry
       since the actual ion drift vector is unknown. The minimum energy
       of an ion detectable by the ONMS in this ion mode is 35.9 eV.
       The maximum transmission is assumed to occur about 10 V above
       this value.  On the nightside of Venus the spacecraft potential
       is negative and the most probable ion energy is near 40 eV.
 
 
       The dataset contains the following columns:
 
       Column    Description &lt;units&gt;
       ________________________________________________________________
       YEAR      YY=2 digit year (e.g. 78 for 1978)
       DOY       DDD=3 digit day of year (e.g. 053)
       UT        Universal time represented as the
                 number of milliseconds since
                 1966-01-01T00:00:00Z stored as a double
                 precision floating point number.
       ORBIT     Orbit number
       TFP       Time from periapsis (sec)
       MASS      Mass number -
                    4 for He+
                   12 for C+
                   14 for N+
                   16 for O+
                   28 for N2+ and/or CO+
                   30 for NO+
                   32 for O2+
                   44 for CO2+
       PULSE     Maximum count rate/sec in 12 second interval
       VALT      Altitude (km)
       VLAT      Venus Latitude (deg N)
       VLST      Local solar time (hr)
       VSZA      Solar zenith angle (deg)
 
 
       References:
       ===========
       Niemann, H.B., J.R.  Booth, J.E.  Cooley, R.E. Hartle, W.T.
       Kasprzak, N.W.  Spencer, S.H.  Way, D.M.  Hunten and G.R.
       Carignan, Pioneer Venus Orbiter Neutral Gas Mass Spectrometer,
       IEEE Trans. on Geoscience and Remote Sensing, vol. GE-18 (1),
       60-65, 1980b.
 
       Niemann, H.B. and W.T. Kasprzak, Comparative Neutral Composition
       Instrumentation and New Results, Advances in Space Research, vol.
       2, 261-270, 1983.
 
 
       Kasprzak, W.T., H.B.  Niemann and P.  Mahaffy, Observations of
       Energetic Ions on the Nightside of Venus, Journal of Geophysical
       Research, vol. 32, 291-298, 1987.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
       In order to fit the data a minimum of 30 points were required
       in 36 seconds. In addition, the maximum to minimum count ratio was
       required to be factor of 3 or greater in order to insure that
       there was a definitive spin modulation.  The center 12 seconds of
       data is divided by the fitting function to derive the equivalent
       flux for that point. The center of the new fitting interval is
       adjusted so that it is centered on the expected signal maximum
       predicted from the previous interval fit. As a result of this
       method of fitting, discontinuities may exist near minimum angle of
       attack where one 12 second interval adjoins the next interval.
 
       See [KASPRZAKETAL1987].
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>1978-051A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>78-051A-11H</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XD-B3A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

