<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.sdu-c-d-dfmi-2-3-next-tempel1-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>STARDUST 9P/TEMPEL 1 DFMI 2/3 NEXT V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.next::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.sdu::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:dfmi.sdu::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.9p-tempel_1_1867_g1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:unk.unk::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.sdu-c-d-dfmi-2-3-next-tempel1-v1.0__browserp_sdu-c-d-dfmi-2-3-next-tempel1-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Economou, T.E., S.F. Green, B.C. Clark, D.E. Brownlee, more authors TBD (2011),
                   Title TBD, Icarus (tentative), in press, Volume TBD, Issue TBD, Date TBD, Pages
                   TBD.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ECONOMOUETAL2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Green, S.F., J.A.M. McDonnell, N. McBride, M.T.S.H. Colwell, A.J. Tuzzolino,
                   T.E. Economou, P. Tsou, B.C. Clark, and D.E. Brownlee (2004), The dust mass
                   distribution of comet 81P/Wild 2, J. Geophys. Res., 109, E12S04,
                   doi:10.1029/2004JE002318, preprint available at
                   http://oro.open.ac.uk/5378/1/2004_Green_et_al_JGR_109_E12S04_pre-print.pdf
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GREENETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Semenov, B.V., A.R. Cheuvront, K.V. Gilliland, and C.H. Acton, STARDUST WILD 2
                   ENCOUNTER DYNAMIC SCIENCE EXPERIMENT DATA, SDU-C-DYNSCI-2-WILD2-V1.0, NASA
                   Planetary Data System, 2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SEMENOVETAL2004C</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tuzzolino, A.J., T.E. Economou, R.B. McKibben, J.A. Simpson, J.A.M. McDonnell,
                   M.J. Burchell, B.A.M. Vaughan, P. Tsou, M.S. Hanner, B.C. Clark, and D.E.
                   Brownlee, Dust Flux Monitor Instrument for the Stardust mission to comet Wild
                   2, J. Geophys. Res., 108, (E10), 8115, 2003, doi:10.1029/2003JE002086.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TUZZOLINOETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Veverka, J., K. Klaasen, M. A&apos;Hearn, M. Belton, D. Brownlee, S. Chesley, B.
                   Clark, T. Economou, R. Farquhar, S. Green, A. Harris, O. Groussin, J. Kissel,
                   J.-Y. Li, K. Meech, J. Melosh, J. Richardson, P. Schultz, J. Silen, J.
                   Sunshine, P. Thomas, S., Bhaskaran, D. Bodewits, B. Carcich, A. Cheuvront, T.
                   Farnham, S. Sackett, D. Wellnitz, and A. Wolf, Return to Comet Tempel 1:
                   Results from Stardust-NExT, Icarus (tentative), 2011, in press, preprint
                   included in all Stardust-NExT PDS data sets.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.VEVERKAETAL2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>SDU-C/D-DFMI-2/3-NEXT-TEMPEL1-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>STARDUST 9P/TEMPEL 1 DFMI 2/3 NEXT V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2011-08-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2007-01-25</start_time>
        <stop_time>2011-03-01</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STARDUST DATA MANAGEMENT AND ARCHIVE TEAM</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Economou, T., S.F. Green, B.V. Semenov, STARDUST 9P/TEMPEL 1 DFMI
            2/3 NEXT V1.0, SDU-C/D-DFMI-2/3-NEXT-TEMPEL1-V1.0, NASA Planetary
            Data System, 2011.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            EDR/RDR data collected by the STARDUST Dust Flux Monitor
            Instrument (DFMI) during the Stardust-NExT mission
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains Level 2/3 (EDR/RDR) data collected by the
            Dust Flux Monitor Instrument (DFMI) during the Stardust-NExT
            mission from January, 2007, through cruise, approach to and
            encounter with comet 9P/Tempel 1, and up to end of mission in
            March, 2011. The Tempel 1 encounter data span a ~40 minute
            period. The RDR data convert the EDR (raw) sensor data, from the
            entire comet encounter, to dust fluences at each of twelve mass
            thresholds.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    This description was written by B. Carcich with support from the
    Stardust-NExT operations and science teams.
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
 
      This data set contains Level 2 (EDR) and 3 (RDR) data collected by
      the Dust Flux Monitor Instrument (DFMI) during the Stardust-NExT
      mission from January, 2007, through cruise, approach to and encounter
      with comet 9P/Tempel 1, and up to end of mission in March, 2011.
      The Tempel 1 encounter data span a ~40 minute period.  The RDR data
      convert the EDR (raw) sensor data, from the entire comet encounter,
      to dust fluences at each of twelve mass thresholds.
 
      These data record dust impact and other events which resulted from
      interstellar particles, the encounter with particles surrounding
      Tempel 1, instrument commands such as automated calibrations, and an
      instrument anomaly, which generated false positive events, that was
      known to occur after the DFMI has been powered on for over thirty
      minutes.
 
 
    Data Collection Periods
    =======================
 
      The only DFMI science data were taken at encounter with 9P/Tempel 1.
      Throughout the Stardust-NExT mission the DFMI was powered on
      infrequently because of the power supply anomaly that typically
      occurred when it was on for longer than about thirty minutes.  Except
      for the ENCOUNTER period, the DFMI was mainly turned on two minutes
      at a time for calibration and checkout to assess instrument health.
      The forty-nine minutes of operation on 2008-12-10 was a checkout
      exercise to determine if the anomaly was still an issue; the anomaly
      appeared less than nineteen minutes after power-on.  At encounter,
      the anomaly appeared at about 2011-02-15T04:44:00, twenty-seven
      minutes after power on and five minutes after closest approach; data
      after that point are suspect as science data.
 
      The periods when the DFMI was powered on, as well as the model and
      the times when the anomaly started, if present, are as follows:
 
           Mode:  CRUISE
          Start:  2007-01-25T20:37:37.997
        Anomaly:  N/A
           Stop:  2007-01-25T20:39:20.294
       Duration:  ~2 minutes
 
           Mode:  CRUISE
          Start:  2008-12-10T18:48:03.661
        Anomaly:  2008-12-10T19:06:45.462
           Stop:  2008-12-10T19:36:49.184
       Duration:  ~49 minutes
 
           Mode:  CRUISE
          Start:  2010-06-29T15:48:49.910
        Anomaly:  N/A
           Stop:  2010-06-29T15:50:32.210
       Duration:  ~2 minutes
 
           Mode:  CRUISE
          Start:  2011-02-02T17:12:08.805
        Anomaly:  N/A
           Stop:  2011-02-02T17:13:51.106
       Duration:  ~2 minutes
 
           Mode:  ENCOUNTER
          Start:  2011-02-15T04:17:16.415
        Anomaly:  2011-02-15T04:44:28.003
           Stop:  2011-02-15T04:57:12.315
       Duration:  ~40 minutes
 
           Mode:  CRUISE
          Start:  2011-03-01T22:10:53.654
        Anomaly:  2011-03-01T22:42:50.531
           Stop:  2011-03-01T23:00:53.542
       Duration:  ~50 minutes
 
 
    Data Calibration
    ================
 
      This data set contains one PDS TABLE of calibrated data for the
      encounter with comet 9P/Tempel 1.  The table lists fluence, mass
      threshold and uncertainties for each of the DFMI threshold circuits.
 
      There are no calibrated data corresponding to the non-ENCOUNTER
      CRUISE mode raw data.
 
 
      Calibration sources
      -------------------
 
        The calibrations for this instrument were derived from laboratory
        and pre-launch testing.  The stability of the instrument was
        monitored in-flight by injecting a known signal to the electronics
        and monitoring the digital counters.
 
 
      Calibration process
      -------------------
 
        This data set includes documents (see /DOCUMENT/DOCINFO.TXT) along
        with references to published papers detailing the calibration of
        the two types of sensors in DFMI.  A summary of the calibration
        process follows.
 
        There are several aspects to DFMI calibration.
 
        One aspect is converting raw counter data, which incremented
        between time samples, into a number of impacts.  This is roughly a
        straightforward one-for-one operation for the PVDF sensors, with a
        possible correction for counter overflow.  However, it is more
        complex for the acoustic sensors, where the counters indicate the
        fraction of time decaying oscillating signals, each generated by a
        single impact, exceeded each of two different threshold voltages.
        Another issue is that the incremental counts over two or more
        contiguous time periods may need to be combined to properly
        understand the data.  This data set includes a spreadsheet where
        this accounting is performed and a document where the process is
        explained.  See /DOCUMENT/AC/AC.LBL, especially AC_PROCESS.* and
        AC_T1_CT2IMP*.*.
 
        A second aspect is determining the mass threshold, with
        uncertainties, that applies to each of the threshold circuits.
        For the PVDF sensors this involved scaling ground-based laboratory
        data to the Tempel 1 encounter speed (10.9km/s); see
        [ECONOMOUETAL2011] for details.  For the acoustic sensor, see
        /DOCUMENT/AC/AC.LBL, especially AC_PROCESS.*.
 
        A third aspect is calculating fluence (impacts m^-2).  Again this
        is fairly straightforward for the PVDF sensor:  divide the number
        of impacts for each threshold by the area of the corresponding PVDF
        sensor (0.02m^2 or 0.002m^2).  For the acoustic sensor the fluence
        calculation is complicated by the large extent of the shield which
        means the impact of a small particle near the piezoelectric sensors
        cannot be distinguished from that of a larger particle farther
        away.  This can be resolved if the mass distribution of the
        impacting particle population is known, so a distribution is
        assumed to calculate the fluences.  The resulting fluences are then
        checked against the assumed distribution to see if they are
        consistent, and if not then these steps are repeated until the
        process converges.  This approach is implemented via a correlation
        between a &apos;mass distribution index&apos; and an &apos;effective&apos; area of the
        acoustic surface that is a function of that index.  The index is
        the exponent of a power law distribution; see /DOCUMENT/AC/AC.LBL,
        especially AC_DFMI.*, as well as [TUZZOLINOETAL2003],
        [GREENETAL2004] and [ECONOMOUETAL2011].
 
 
    Data Product Type and Format Overview
    =====================================
 
      DFMI data files provided in this archive are divided into two main
      categories:  raw (EDR); calibrated (RDR).  The raw data are further
      divided by target, INTERSTELLAR PARTICLES and 9P/TEMPEL 1 (1867 G1),
      which also corresponds to DFMI mode, CRUISE and ENCOUNTER,
      respectively.
 
      Two further types of ancillary data have been provided at the request
      of the peer reviewers to aid in interpreting the 9P/Tempel encounter
      flyby DFMI events:
 
        1) The PVDF data are &apos;unrolled&apos; to remove the effect of counter
           rollover, where the recorded raw value decreased (reset to zero)
           as event counts increased, although no rollover occurred as a
           result of dust impact events i.e. all PVDF rollovers occurred
           only after the power supply anomaly began to cause false
           positive impact events.  The count rates have also been
           calculated in the data product containing these unrolled counts.
 
        2) Thruster firing events during the encounter flyby with 9P/Tempel
           1 have been supplied to allow assessment of the possibility that
           thruster activity could have caused false positive impact
           events.
 
      The data files provide data as ASCII-formatted comma-separated-values
      (CSVs).  In the EDR data, each row represents a single sample in
      time.  In the RDR data, each row represents an accumulated fluence
      for the duration of the Tempel 1 encounter for one threshold.  There
      are no RDR data corresponding to the non-ENCOUNTER CRUISE mode EDR
      data.  Refer to the data labels (*.LBL) for the meaning of each CSV
      in a row.
 
      See &apos;Parameters - Sampling interval&apos; below for details of what times
      may be represented in each EDR row.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      Each parameter is stored as one ASCII CSV in a row.  Refer to the
      data labels (*.LBL) for the format and location of the data file
      parameters.
 
      EDR data
      --------
 
        EDR data contain the time-cumulative raw counter values with
        rollover.  As noted above, for PVDF sensors these counters are
        roughly 1:1 with actual impacts, and for acoustic sensors the
        relationship is more complicated.  The PVDF sensor counters are
        16-bit and roll over (reset to zero) after 65,535 counts; the
        acoustic sensors roll over after 255 counts.  The PVDF counters are
        also threshold-cumulative i.e. each nominal impact is only counted
        once in one of the threshold counters and an impact detected and
        counted by one of the higher thresholds does not register as an
        impact in any lower threshold.
 
        EDR data also contain synoptic data at each time the counters are
        read.  The synoptic data include UTC time at the spacecraft, DFMI
        configuration, DFMI temperatures, a sync byte, spacecraft position
        and velocity relative to some or all of Earth, Sun, and comet
        9P/Tempel 1.  Refer to the EDR data labels for further detail.
 
 
      RDR Data
      --------
 
        The calibrated data for the ENCOUNTER contain the particle mass
        corresponding to each voltage threshold, an equivalent spherical
        particle diameter, the fluence of the particles above each
        threshold, and uncertainties for mass and fluence.
 
        There are no RDR data corresponding to the non-ENCOUNTER CRUISE
        mode EDR data.
 
 
      Sampling Intervals
      ------------------
 
        In CRUISE mode, the DFMI updates counter values up to ten times per
        second, but only when some of the counters change.  ENCOUNTER mode
        is almost identical, except that updates are sent at least once per
        second even if no changes occur.  EDR data contain data sampled at
        these intervals.
 
        RDR ENCOUNTER data contain fluences (cumulative impacts) for the
        duration of the encounter up to before the start of the anomaly.
 
        There are no RDR data corresponding to the non-ENCOUNTER CRUISE
        mode EDR data.
 
 
      Thruster firings
      ----------------
 
        The thruster firing data have been extracted from a Small Forces
        File, available from JPL/NAIF (http://naif.jpl.nasa.gov/) and as
        described in the Stardust Wild 2 Encounter Dynamic Science
        Experiment Data set [SEMENOVETAL2004C].
 
 
    Data Processing
    ===============
 
      The Stardust DFMI instrument output consisted of a variety of binary
      data blocks.  On board the spacecraft these blocks were packetized by
      the spacecraft&apos;s flight software and downlinked within packets in the
      spacecraft telemetry stream.
 
      A suite of software -- developed and run by the Stardust Data
      Management and Archive Team (DMA) -- retrieved packets with DFMI data
      from the Telemetry Data Server(s)(TDS) used by the Stardust Project,
      stripped off ground system and spacecraft packet headers, and placed
      the binary data in a binary collection file.  For readability, the
      binary data were also converted to ASCII text, combined with
      ancillary information such as spacecraft, comet, Sun and Earth
      relative positions, and stored as comma-separated values (CSVs) in
      the EDR data files in this archive.
 
      The ENCOUNTER RDR data were extracted from the last of a series of
      calibration spreadsheet workbooks, which are archived with this data
      set in the /DOCUMENT/ directory.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
 
      Each data file includes a number of derived geometry parameters.
      These parameters were computed using the following SPICE kernels
      archived in the Stardust SPICE data set, SDU-C-SPICE-6-V1.0:
 
        Kernel Type   File Name
        ------------  ------------------------
        LSK           naif0009.tls
 
        PCK           pck00009.tpc
 
        SCLK          sdu_sclkscet_00186.tsc
 
        FK            sdu_v20.tf
 
        SPKs          sdu_tempel1_ssd_s154.bsp&apos;
                      sdu_isp000.bsp&apos;
                      sdu_l_1999.bsp&apos;
                      sdu_l_2000.bsp&apos;
                      sdu_l_2001.bsp&apos;
                      sdu_l_2002.bsp&apos;
                      sdu_l_2003_w2.bsp&apos;
                      sdu_l_2004.bsp&apos;
                      sdu_l_2005_return.bsp&apos;
                      sdu_l_2006.bsp&apos;
                      sdu_l_2007.bsp&apos;
                      sdu_l_2008.bsp&apos;
                      sdu_l_2009.bsp&apos;
                      sdu_l_2010.bsp&apos;
                      sdu_l_2011_t1.bsp&apos;
 
        CKs           sdu_sc_rec_1999_v2.bc
                      sdu_sc_rec_2000_v2.bc
                      sdu_sc_rec_2001_v2.bc
                      sdu_sc_rec_2002_v2.bc
                      sdu_sc_rec_2003_w2_v2.bc
                      sdu_sc_rec_w2_opnav.bc
                      sdu_sc_rec_2004_v2.bc&apos;
                      sdu_sc_rec_2005_v2.bc&apos;
                      sdu_sc_rec_next.bc&apos;
 
 
        ------------  ------------------------
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
 
      The geometry items provided in the files are relative to the J2000
reference frame. Refer to the specification of the geometry table columns to
see which parameters are defined in which frame.
 
      The J2000 reference frame is defined as follows:
 
        -  +Z axis is along Earth Mean Equator North at the J2000 epoch
           (2000 JAN 01 12:00 ET);
 
        -  +X axis is along the vernal Equinox at the J2000 epoch;
 
        -  +Y completes the right hand frame;
 
      The Stardust reference frame is defined as follows:
 
        -  +X axis is along the longer side of the spacecraft bus and
           points from the aerogel capsule side towards the dust shield
           side;
 
        -  +Z is perpendicular to the deployed solar arrays surface and
           points along the HGA pointing direction;
 
        -  +Y completes the right hand frame;
 
        -  the origin of this frame is at the center of the launch
           vehicle interface ring attached to the shield side of the
           spacecraft bus.
 
      This diagram illustrates the spacecraft reference frame and DFMI
      mounting with respect to it:
 
 
 
        Solar Array           Whipple
          Shield       +Z .-. Shield
            .-.          ^| |
            | |==========|====o===============o===============
            `-&apos;          || |-------------------.          Solar
  ------&gt; ------&gt;        || |&lt;--DFMI sensors are|          Array
   Nominal               || | .-----.  on the   |
   Incoming      &lt;-------o| | |      &apos;  Whipple |
   Particle    +X        +Y   .CIDA_/    Shield |
   direction              | |  `. `.            |
   during                 | |--- `. `.---- -----&apos;
   Encounter              | |      `. `
                          `-&apos;        `.&apos;`.
                                        .&apos;
 
 
 
      As seen on the diagram DFMI is located on the +X side of the
      spacecraft bus. The DFMI target plane is parallel to the
      spacecraft YZ plane, and the particles are coming in from the
      +X direction.
 
 
    Software
    ========
 
      The data in this data set are in standard PDS format -- ASCII text
      files with comma-delimited columns -- and, therefore, can be viewed
      by PDS-provided programs or loaded into commercial programs that
      support comma-delimited formats. For this reason no special
      processing software is included in this data set.
 
 
    Contact Information
    ===================
 
      For any questions regarding the data in this archive, contact:
 
        Dr. Thanasis Economou, DU, PVDF sensors
        Dr. Simon Green, Stardust DASS, acoustic sensors.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      The mass vs. fluence calibrated data table provides positive and
      negative uncertainties for the derived parameters.
 
      All telemetry data produced by the DFMI instrument contained a
      checksum that were validated upon ground receipt.
 
      During the processing of the data in preparation for delivery
      with this volume, the structure of each data packet was verified.
      This verification included detection of both the sync word and
      the length of each packet, which assured that all packets were
      complete and not damaged.  The fundamental validity of the data has
      been inferred by the DFMI Science Lead and DFMI Science team members
      by plotting and subsequent review of the data.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

