<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mgn-v-rss-5-losapdr-l2-v1.13</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MGN V RSS LINE OF SIGHT ACCELERATION PROFILES V1.13</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.magellan::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mgn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.mgn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgn-v-rss-5-losapdr-l2-v1.13__browserp_geo_mgn-v-rss-5-losapdr-l2-v1.13::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgn-v-rss-5-losapdr-l2-v1.13__dvo_geo_mgn-v-rss-5-losapdr-l2-v1.13::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Special issue, The Geophysics of Venus, Icarus, 112, 1-295, 1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ICARUSMGN1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Konopliv, A.S., and W.L. Sjogren, Venus Gravity Handbook, Jet Propulsion
                   Laboratory Publication 96-2, January 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KONOPLIV-SJOGREN1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Archival Tracking Data File Data Record (ATDFDR), Magellan Software
                   Interface Specification: DSN Document 820-13, Rev. A, TRK-2-25, Jet
                   Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, 1986.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MGN-ATDFDR1986</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Navigation Constants File Data Record (NCFDR), Magellan Software Interface
                   Specification: NAV-103, Rev. A, Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA,
                   1991.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MGN-NCFDR1991</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Orbit Data File Data Record (ODFDR), Magellan Software Interface
                   Specification: DSN Document 820-13, Rev. A, TRK-2-18, Jet Propulsion
                   Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, 1988.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MGN-ODFDR1988</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Small Forces File Data Record (SFFDR), Magellan Software Interface
                   Specification: SES-121, Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, 1987.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MGN-SFFDR1987</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Moyer, T.D., Mathematical Formulation of the Double-Precision Orbit
                   Determination Program (DPODP), TR 32-1527, Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena,
                   CA, 1971.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MOYER1971</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Moyer, T.D., Changes to the ODP and the ODE for processing X-Band Uplink
                   Data, EM-314-430, Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, 1987.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MOYER1987</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Planetary Data System Standards Reference, Jet Propulsion Laboratory Document
                   D-7669, Part 2, 20 November 1992
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PDSSR1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MGN-V-RSS-5-LOSAPDR-L2-V1.13</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MGN V RSS LINE OF SIGHT ACCELERATION PROFILES V1.13</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1997-01-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1992-09-15</start_time>
        <stop_time>1994-10-12</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>WILLIAM L. SJOGREN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Sjogren, W. L., MGN V RSS LINE OF SIGHT ACCELERATION PROFILES
            V1.13, MGN-V-RSS-5-LOSAPDR-L2-V1.13, NASA Planetary Data System,
            1997
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Magellan Line of Sight Acceleration Profile Data Record
            (LOSAPDR) archive (V1.13) contains results from processing of
            radio tracking data during Cycles 4, 5, and 6 of the Magellan
            spacecraft.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Line of Sight Acceleration Profile Data Records (LOSAPDR) consist
            of data from Doppler tracking of the orbiting spacecraft. The
            relative motion of the spacecraft and the earth-based radio
            receiver is measured very precisely, and known motions are
            removed a priori (i.e. earth rotation, planetary motions,
            spacecraft orbital motion, solar pressure, drag), leaving small
            velocity changes caused by variations in the mass distribution of
            the planet. The residual Doppler frequency shifts are linearly
            proportional to the component of velocity in the Earth direction.
            Numerical differentiation of these velocity residuals with
            respect to time produces line-of-sight (LOS) gravity. These
            measures are accelerations at spacecraft altitude which can be
            modeled for geophysical interpretation. For information on
            Magellan gravity investigations see papers in [ICARUSMGN1994].
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      Line of Sight Acceleration Profile Data Records (LOSAPDR)
      consist of data from Doppler tracking of the orbiting
      spacecraft.  The relative motion of the spacecraft and the
      earth-based radio receiver is measured very precisely, and
      known motions are removed a priori (i.e.  earth rotation,
      planetary motions, spacecraft orbital motion, solar pressure,
      drag), leaving small velocity changes caused by variations in
      the mass distribution of the planet.  The residual Doppler
      frequency shifts are linearly proportional to the component of
      velocity in the Earth direction.  Numerical differentiation of
      these velocity residuals with respect to time produces
      line-of-sight (LOS) gravity.  These measures are accelerations
      at spacecraft altitude which can be modeled for geophysical
      interpretation.  For information on Magellan gravity
      investigations see papers in [ICARUSMGN1994].
 
      Note:  JPL documents describing the Magellan gravity experiment,
             including the acquisition, processing, and quality of
             the LOSAPDR data, are available from the PDS
             Geosciences Node, Washington University, St. Louis, MO.
             [KONOPLIV&amp;SJOGREN1996] provides the most detailed
             description of the Magellan gravity experiment.
 
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      Users of these data should be aware of particular events and
      tracking station operations to properly reduce the complex
      motions inherent in the Doppler signals.
 
      Many of the spacecraft parameters can be found in the
      Navigation Constants Document, [MGN-NCFDR1991].  There is a
      small force record, [MGN-SFFDR1987], which lists the times and
      duration of the momentum dumps.  There were several maneuvers
      and their times and durations are given in the Maneuver Profile
      Listing (MPL) data product.  The spacecraft orientations are
      all listed in the Spacecraft Attitude During Hide Maneuver
      Listing (SADHML) data product.
 
      On every orbit the spacecraft orientation changed with the high
      gain antenna pointing at Venus or at the Earth or some other
      direction to keep the spacecraft temperature within safe
      bounds.  The transmitter ramp rates and initiation times are
      listed in the ODFDR (Orbit Data File Data Record) and ATDFDR
      (Archival Tracking Data File Data Record) [MGN-ODFDR1988;
      MGN-ATDFDR1986].  The equations to incorporate the ramp data as
      well as the complete theoretical Doppler observable are given
      in [MOYER1971; MOYER1987].
 
      Note:  All the ancillary data and information to process and
             interpret the Doppler data are located at the PDS
             Geosciences Node, Washington University St. Louis, MO.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The raw X-Band uplink/downlink Doppler observations have been
      fit with a model which accounts for theoretical motions and
      other signal effects.  The difference between the observed or
      measured Doppler and the theoretical model are Doppler
      residuals.  These are small systematic variations and are
      attributed to unmodeled gravity field perturbations.
 
      The Doppler residuals are then spline fitted and analytically
      differentiated to produce line-of-sight (LOS) accelerations.
      The spacecraft position in orbit at each acceleration point is
      noted at a specific altitude, latitude and longitude.
 
      All the Doppler residuals are two-way (round trip), where the
      Doppler shift is the shift between the outgoing and returned
      frequency.  The Doppler residuals can be converted into
      velocity residuals of the spacecraft relative to Earth using:
 
           (Doppler residual * c) / (2 * frequency),
 
      where c is the velocity of light, 2.997925E11 mm/sec, and the
      frequency is 8.43E09 Hz, which reduces to 1 Hz Doppler being
      equivalent to 17.78 mm/sec (range-rate).
 
      The LOS data during cycle 4 (Sept.  92 - May 93), cycle 5 (Aug.
      93 - April 94) and cycle 6 (April 94 - Oct.  94) have been
      produced using a 120th degree and order spherical harmonic
      model (MGN120P) of the Venusian gravity field, which causes the
      Doppler residuals to be much smaller and thus the LOS
      accelerations to be also small (i.e.  on the order of a few
      milligals as compared to 50-80 milligals with the GM only
      model, which has only a central term and without any spherical
      harmonic coefficients).
 
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      N/A
 
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      The coordinates extracted from the JPL ODP (Orbit Determination
      Program) and given in the data files for the spacecraft
      position and velocity are: space-fixed cartesian,
      Venus-centered, referenced to the Venus true equator and prime
      meridian at the epoch time given.
 
 
 
    Software
    ========
      N/A
 
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The Cycle 4, 5 and 6 LOSAPDR dataset will be available
      electronically via the World-Wide Web and anonymous FTP
      transfer.  The archive will also be delivered to the National
      Space Sciences Data Center (NSSDC) using compact disk write
      once (CD-WO) media.  Formats will be based on standards
      established by the Planetary Data System (PDS).
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      The Doppler residuals were differentiated to produce LOS
      acceleration profiles.  These LOS profiles however have
      distortions in them due to viewing geometry, variations in
      spacecraft altitude and the least squares reduction process.
      With the high degree and order spherical harmonics, similar
      profiles can be generated that are free from most of the above
      effects, but may suffer from loss of high frequency components
      that remain in the raw data.  The LOS data should be used for
      refinements when small features are important to the analyst,
      but otherwise the gravity field as defined by the harmonics is
      the most valid.
 
 
 
    Review
    ======
      The LOSAPDR archive will be reviewed by PDS and planetary
      scientists familiar with the dataset, prior to release to the
      planetary community.
 
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      There were 990 LOSAPDRs for cycle 4 (orbits 5827-7615) produced
      at JPL and then validated and archived at the Planetary Data
      System&apos;s Geophysics Subnode at Washington University, St.
      Louis, MO.  There was 360 degrees of longitude coverage with
      periapsis altitude near 180 km.
 
      During cycle 5, the coverage was redundant and there was a gap
      in the longitude coverage.  Some profiles were acquired across
      apoapsis (550 km altitude) while others were across periapsis.
      There were 1679 LOSAPDRs produced at JPL and then validated at
      the Geophysics Subnode for cycles 5 and 6 combined.  There were
      736 LOSAPDRs for cycle 5 (orbits 8606-12248) and 943 for cycle
      6 (orbits 12250-14992).
 
 
 
      January 17 to January 24, 1992
      ------------------------------
        There was a week of Doppler periapsis data during January
        (17-24) 1992 when there was battery recharging.  The data
        were at S-Band from the medium gain antenna and periapsis was
        at 280 km.
 
 
 
      April 22 to May 16, 1992
      ------------------------
        From April 22 to May 16, 1992 (23 days) with periapsis at 261
        km there were sixteen orbits of X-Band periapsis data
        acquired.
 
 
 
      August 1990 to September 1992
      -----------------------------
        Other than these two prior blocks of data, all Doppler
        gravity data from August 1990 to September 1992 were taken
        when spacecraft altitudes were well above 2000 km.
 
 
 
      September 15, 1992 to May 24, 1993
      ----------------------------------
        The first block of high quality and high resolution gravity
        data were acquired.  Periapsis was lowered to 180 km and
        coverage across periapsis was obtained continuously for 360
        degrees of longitude.  Periapsis latitude remained
        essentially constant at 10 degrees N latitude and good
        resolution was maintained within +/- 30 degrees (i.e.  40
        degrees N to 20 degrees S where spacecraft altitudes reached
        ~450 km).  There were only a few days where no data were
        obtained, but in general excellent data coverage was
        maintained providing at least two orbits per day and much of
        the time 4 to 5 orbits per day.  All of these were X-Band
        uplink and downlink having a noise level of 0.1 mm/sec.  In
        addition there were also two or more orbits with S-Band
        coverage each day.
 
 
 
      May 1993 to August 6, 1993
      --------------------------
        The MGN spacecraft successfully completed an aerobraking
        sequence that nearly circularized its orbit.  This new orbit
        provided high resolution data in the high latitude regions
        which previously had poor gravity model determination.  The
        orbit had a periapsis altitude of 180 km and an apoapsis of
        550 km and provided ~300 - 400 km altitudes over the high
        latitude regions.  The orbital period changed from 195
        minutes to 94 minutes, so there were approximately fifteen
        orbits per day.
 
        Because of operational sequencing of the onboard computers
        and the necessity to orient the spacecraft for thermal
        conditions, the first good coherent X-Band data were acquired
        on Aug 19, 1993.  There were some short S-Band data blocks
        starting on August 6, 1993.  The data during aerobraking are
        on ODF and ATDF files, but were not used for any of the
        gravity experiment reductions.  The Doppler data acquired
        during aerobraking were all S-Band at relatively high
        altitudes.  There were no data near periapsis since the
        spacecraft was oriented with its high gain antenna pointed
        along the spacecraft velocity vector and not toward the
        earth.
 
        The daily coverage in this orbit was excellent with data for
        several orbits every day.  However orbital geometry of the
        Earth and Venus have made the coverage redundant for some
        longitudes and none existent for others.
 
 
 
      January 6 to January 26, 1994
      -----------------------------
        There was a solar conjunction on January 16, 1994 and as a
        result data from January 6, 1994 to January 26, 1994 are very
        noisy and essentially non-usable for gravity extraction.  The
        data immediately after solar conjunction have low altitude
        passes over Maxwell Montes and provides the very best
        information for this unique feature.
 
 
 
      June 22 to July 14, 1994
      ------------------------
        During this period (orbits 13298-13635), the Doppler radio
        tracking on each orbit of Magellan was cut short due to
        inadvertent spacecraft event sequencing of the thermal
        control where the spacecraft was turned-off of earth-pointing
        (loss of radio contact) earlier than it should have been.
        This was corrected in the next up-load to the spacecraft,
        making the arcs about another 10 minutes longer.
 
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      N/A
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>89-033B-02G</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

