<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dif-c-hrii-3-4-9p-encounter-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DEEP IMPACT 9P/TEMPEL ENCOUNTER - REDUCED HRII SPECTRA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_impact::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:hrii.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.9p-tempel_1_1867_g1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dif-c-hrii-3-4-9p-encounter-v1.0__browserp_dif-c-hrii-3-4-9p-encounter-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   A&apos;Hearn, M.F., M.J.S. Belton, W.A. Delamere, J. Kissel, K.P. Klaasen, L.A.
                   McFadden, K.J. Meech, H.J. Melosh, P.H. Schultz, J.M. Sunshine, P.C. Thomas, J.
                   Veverka, D.K. Yeomans, M.W. Baca, I. Busko, C.J. Crockett, S.M. Collins, M.
                   Desnoyer, C.A. Eberhardy, C.M. Ernst, T.L. Farnham, L. Feaga, O. Groussin, D.
                   Hampton, S.I. Ipatov, J.-Y. Li, D. Lindler, C.M. Lisse, N. Mastrodemos, W.M.
                   Owen, J.E. Richardson, D.D. Wellnitz, and R.L. White, Deep Impact: Excavating
                   Comet Tempel 1, Science, 310, 258-264, 2005, doi:10.1126/science.1118923.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.AHEARNETAL2005A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   A&apos;Hearn, M.F., M.J.S. Belton, A. Delamere, and W.H. Blume, Deep Impact: A
                   Large-Scale Active Experiment on a Cometary Nucleus, Space Science Reviews,
                   117, 1-21, 2005, doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3387-3.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.AHEARNETAL2005B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hampton, D.L., J.W. Baer, M.A. Huisjen, C.C. Varner, A. Delamere, D.D.
                   Wellnitz, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, and K.P. Klaasen, An Overview of the Instrument Suite
                   for the Deep Impact Mission, Space Science Reviews, 117, 43-93, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3390-8.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAMPTONETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., B. Carcich, G. Carcich, E.J. Grayzeck, and S. McLaughlin, Deep
                   Impact: The Anticipated Flight Data, Space Science Reviews, 117, 335-372, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3385-5.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., M.F. A&apos;Hearn, M. Baca, A. Delamere, M. Desnoyer, T. Farnham, O.
                   Groussin, D. Hampton, S. Ipatov, J. Li, C. Lisse, N. Mastrodemos, S.
                   McLaughlin, J. Sunshine, P. Thomas, and D. Wellnitz, Deep Impact Instrument
                   Calibration, Rev. Sci. Instrum., 79, 091301, 2008, doi:10.1063/1.2972112.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DIF-C-HRII-3/4-9P-ENCOUNTER-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DEEP IMPACT 9P/TEMPEL ENCOUNTER - REDUCED HRII SPECTRA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2005-12-31</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2005-06-20T21:08:55.414Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2005-07-06T18:17:45.267Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STEPHANIE MCLAUGHLIN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            McLaughlin, S. A., B. Carcich, T. McCarthy, M. Desnoyer, and K.P.
            Klaasen, DEEP IMPACT 9P/TEMPEL ENCOUNTER - REDUCED HRII SPECTRA
            V1.0, DIF-C-HRII-3/4-9P-ENCOUNTER-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2005.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Reduced spectral images of comet 9P/Tempel 1 acquired by the Deep
            Impact High Resolution Instrument Infrared Spectrometer during
            the encounter phase of the mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains reduced spectral images of 9P/Tempel 1
            acquired by the Deep Impact High Resolution Instrument Infrared
            Spectrometer during the encounter phase of the mission.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set contains reduced spectral images of comet 9P/Tempel 1
    acquired by the Deep Impact High Resolution Instrument Infrared
    Spectrometer (HRII) during the encounter phase of the mission.
    Spectra taken before June 20, 2005, are not included in this data set
    because the spectrometer was not pointing at the target.
 
    The 9P/Tempel 1 spectra are described in &apos;Deep Impact:  The
    Anticipated Flight Data&apos; by Klaasen, et al. (2005) [KLAASENTAL2005].
    For more details about the spectra taken around impact, refer to the
    HRII encounter data summary document which provides a log of the
    exposures taken from 28 hours before impact through lookback.  Also,
    refer to the HRII encounter pointing summary document which describes
    the pointing and scan direction for exposures taken at encounter.
 
    A list of the reduced spectra in this data sets is provided here:
 
        Mid-Obs          Exposure IDs
         Date     DOY  Minimum  Maximum  Mission Activity
      ----------  ---  -------  -------  --------------------------
      2005-06-20  171 6002005  6002005  Daily comet imaging
      2005-06-21  172 6002100  6002105  Daily comet imaging
      2005-06-22  173 6002200  6002205  Daily comet imaging
      2005-06-23  174 6002300  6002305  Daily comet imaging
      2005-06-24  175 6002400  6002405  Daily comet imaging
      2005-06-25  176 6002500  6002504  Daily comet imaging
      2005-06-26  177 6002600  6002603  Daily comet imaging
      2005-06-27  178 8000000  8000004  Continuous comet imaging
      2005-06-28  179 8000005  8100004  Continuous comet imaging
      2005-06-29  180 8100005  8300000  Continuous comet imaging
      2005-06-30  181 8400000  8400005  Continuous comet imaging
      2005-07-01  182 8400006  8500009  Continuous comet imaging
      2005-07-02  183 8500009  8800003  Continuous comet imaging
      2005-07-03  184 9000000  9000021  Continuous comet imaging
      2005-07-04  185 9000022  9000029  Continuous comet imaging
                      9000030  9000039  Pre-impact scans
                      9000040  9000068  Impact imaging
                      9010000  9070002  Lookback imaging
      2005-07-05  186 9080000  9110002  Lookback imaging
      2005-07-06  187 9120000  9150002  Lookback imaging
 
 
    Essential Reading
    -----------------
      The following documents, located on the Deep Impact Documentation
      volume, DIDOC_1000, are essential for the understanding and
      interpretation of this data set:
 
      ANTICIPATED_FLIGHT_DATA.*       : Anticipated flight data by Klaasen,
                                        et al. (2005) [KLAASENTAL2005]
      HRII_ENCOUNTER_DATA_SUMMARY.*   : Image log from 28 hours before
                                        impact through lookback
      HRII_ENCOUNTER_POINTING_SUMM.*  : Pointing and scan directions for
                                        encounter data from June 20 through
                                        July 6
      HRII_CALIBRATION_LIMITATIONS.*  : Discusses known deficiencies in
                                        the IR calibration process that
                                        reduced the spectral images
      CALIBRATION_DOC.*               : Instrument calibration by Klaasen,
                                        et al. (2006) [KLAASENETAL2006]
      CALIBRATION_SOFTWARE/AADICAL.LBL: Calibration pipeline IDL software
                                        provided as documentation
      INFLIGHT_CALIBRATION_SUMMARY.*  : Summary of in-flight calibrations
      INSTRUMENTS_HAMPTON.*           : Instrument paper by Hampton, et al.
                                        (2005) [HAMPTONETAL2005]
      MISSION_OVERVIEW_AHEARN.*       : Mission overview by A&apos;Hearn, et al.
                                        (2005) [AHEARNETAL2005B]
      SCLK_CORRELATION.*              : Discussion of the discrepancy
                                        between the spacecraft clocks and
                                        UTC
      AIDC_FLIGHT_HRII.*              : Description of the data set and
                                        definitions of label keywords
 
      Initial results from the encounter and impact were presented in
      &apos;Deep Impact: Excavating Comet Tempel 1&apos; by by A&apos;Hearn, et al.
      (2005) [AHEARNETAL2005A].
 
 
    Related Data Sets
    -----------------
      The following PDS data sets are related to this one:
 
      DIF-CAL-HRII-2-9P-CRUISE-V1.0           : Raw HRII cruise calibrations
      DIF-C-HRII-2-9P-ENCOUNTER-V1.0          : Raw HRII encounter data
      DIF-CAL-HRII-2-GROUND-TV1-V1.0          : HRII pre-flight calib data
      DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV-2-GROUND-TV2-V1.0     : HRII pre-flight calib data
      DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV/MRI-2-GROUND-TV4-V1.0 : HRII pre-flight calib data
      DI-C-SPICE-6-V1.0                       : SPICE kernels
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The reduced, two-dimensional FITS spectra in this data set were
    generated by the Deep Impact calibration pipeline, maintained by the
    project&apos;s Science Data Center (SDC) at Cornell University.  The
    pipeline performed the following reduction steps to produce the
    spectra in this data set:
 
      - Calibration of temperatures and voltages in the FITS headers
      - Decompression of compressed images
      - Correction for uneven bit weighting due to analog-to-digital
        (ADC) conversion (a unit correction)
      - Linearization of raw data numbers
      - Subtraction of dark noise
      - Removal of electronic cross-talk removal (a unit correction)
      - Normalization of quadrant gains (a unit correction)
      - Application of a flat field (a unit correction)
      - Conversion of data numbers to units of radiance for an absolute,
        radiometric calibration
 
    The resulting spectra were provided in physical units of radiance,
    Watts/(meter**2 steradian micron).  These spectra, designated by the
    pneumonic &apos;&apos;RADREV&apos;&apos;, were not cleaned and are considered reversible
    because the calibration steps can be removed to get back to the
    original, raw data numbers.  The data were not cleaned for cosmic
    rays because the automated routine could not handle all cases as
    of this archive.
 
    During the calibration process, the pipeline updated the
    pixel-by-pixel image quality map, the first FITS extension, to
    identify the following types of pixels:
 
      - Pixels where the raw value was saturated
      - Pixels where the analog-to-digital converter was saturated
      - Pixels that were ultra-compressed and thus contain very little
        information
      - Pixels considered bad as indicated by bad pixel maps
 
    The pipeline also created FITS image extensions for a spectral
    registration (wavelength) map, a spectral resolution (bandwidth) map,
    and a signal-to-noise ratio map.  The calibration steps and files used
    to reduce each raw spectral image are listed in the
    PROCESSING_HISTORY_TEXT keyword in the PDS data label.
 
    The reduced spectra were the best available data as of November
    2005. There are known deficiencies for these spectra which are
    discussed in the HRII calibration limitations document.  For a
    detailed discussion of the calibration pipeline used to reduce these
    data, see the instrument calibration document by Klaasen, et al.
    (2006) [KLAASENETAL2006].
 
    Applied Coherent Technology Corporation in Herndon, VA, produced the
    PDS data labels by extracting parameters from the FITS headers.
 
 
  Data
  ====
 
    Spectral Images
    ---------------
      The two-dimensional, infrared spectral images in this data set are
      in FITS format.  The primary data array contains the spectral image,
      with the fastest varying axis corresponding to increasing
      wavelengths (1.05 to 4.8 microns) and the slowest varying axis
      providing the spatial dimension.  Each FITS file includes four image
      extensions that are pixel-by-pixel maps providing additional
      information about the primary image:
 
        - The first extension uses one byte of eight, bit flags to
          describe the quality of each pixel in the primary image.
          The PDS data labels define the purpose of each bit.
 
        - The second extension provides the spectral registration or
          wavelength for each pixel in the primary image.  Each image
          requires a specific wavelength map because the wavelength
          changed with temperature.
 
        - The third extension provided the spectral resolution or
          bandwidth for each pixel in the primary image.  Each image
          requires a specific spectral resolution map because the
          bandwidth changed with temperature.
 
        - The fourth extension provides a signal-to-noise ratio for
          each pixel in the primary image.
 
      Each spectral image FITS file is accompanied by a detached PDS
      label.  For more information about the FITS primary image and the
      extensions, refer to the instrument calibration document.
 
 
    Compression
    -----------
      The calibration pipeline used one of four lossy lookup tables to
      decompress raw spectral images that were compressed onboard the
      spacecraft.  For information about data compression, see the Deep
      Impact instruments document by Hampton, et al. (2005)
      [HAMPTONETAL2005] or the instrument calibration paper by Klaasen,
      et al. (2006) [KLAASENETAL2006].
 
 
    True-Sky &apos;&apos;As Seen By Observer&apos;&apos; Display
    ----------------------------------------
      A true-sky view is achieved by displaying the image using the
      standard FITS convention:  the fastest-varying axis (samples)
      increasing to the right in the display window and the slowest-
      varying axis increasing to the top.  This convention is also
      defined in the PDS data labels:
 
        SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION = RIGHT
        LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION   = UP
 
      The direction to Celestial North and Ecliptic North, measured
      clockwise from the top of the displayed image, is provided in PDS
      labels by CELESTIAL_NORTH_CLOCK_ANGLE and
      SOLAR_NORTH_POLE_CLOCK_ANGLE, both of which assume the correct
      display defined by SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION and
      LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION.
 
      Using this convention to display an approach image of Tempel 1,
      ecliptic North is toward the right and the Sun is down.  After
      impact, the Flyby spacecraft came out of shield mode and turned
      around to lookback at the comet.  For lookback images, ecliptic
      North is toward the left, and the Sun is down.
 
 
    IR Slit Location
    ----------------
      For a comparison of the relative locations of the IR slit with
      respect to the fields of view of the Medium Resolution Instrument
      CCD (MRI) and the High Resolution Instrument CCD (HRI), see the
      relative boresight alignments section of the instrument calibration
      document.
 
 
    Timing for Spectra
    ------------------
      It is important to note that the readout order of the IR detector
      affects the timing of the spectra.  When a HRII spectral image is
      displayed using the true-sky convention, the wavelength increases
      horizontally to the right and the spatial or along-slit direction is
      vertical.  In this orientation, the IR detector was read out from
      the left and right edges and toward the center and starting with the
      first row at the bottom and ending with the last row at the top of
      the display.  Since the detector was reset and read out on a
      pixel-by-pixel basis, the read out order affects the time at which
      each pixel was exposed, although each pixel had the same exposure
      duration.  For more information about the timing of the spectra, see
      the IR focal plane and quadrant nomenclature sections of the
      instrument calibration document.
 
 
    Spectral Scans
    --------------
      Nearly all exposures of Tempel 1 during encounter were scans across
      the nucleus or the coma, and these are identified in the HRII
      encounter pointing summary document.  To make scans, the spacecraft
      was slewed while the IR detector recorded data.  To work with
      spectral scans, it is recommended that all frames for one exposure
      ID be stacked into a three-dimensional cube.  Then, a
      spatial-spatial map can be produced for a specific wavelength by
      selecting the appropriate spectral column from the image cube.
      Spectral wavelengths are provided by the second FITS extension, the
      spectral registration (wavelength) map.
 
      Several exposures from encounter were stares, where the spectrometer
      was pointed at a specific target location for the duration of the
      exposure.  Exposure IDs that were stares are also identified in the
      HRII encounter pointing summary document.
 
 
    File Naming Convention
    ----------------------
      The naming convention for the data labels and FITS files is
      HIcccccccccc_iiiiiii_nnn_RR.LBL or FIT where cccccccccc is the
      spacecraft clock count at the mid-point of the observation and
      iiiiiii is the exposure ID (OBSERVATION_ID in data labels).  Up to
      999 individual images could be commanded for one exposure ID.
      Spectral scans often had 32 or more frames for one specific
      exposure.  Therefore, nnn in the file name provides the sequentially
      increasing frame number within an exposure ID and corresponds to
      IMAGE_NUMBER in the data labels.  For example, if 32 frames were
      commanded for a scan with an exposure ID of 9009001, the first FITS
      file name would be HIcccccccccc_9009001_001_RR.FIT and the last
      would be HIcccccccccc_9009001_032_RR.FIT.  Finally, RR identifies
      the reduction level, RADREV:  reversible data in units of radiance.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
    Data Units
    ----------
      Reduced &apos;&apos;RADREV&apos;&apos; data are in units of radiance, W/(m**2 steradian
      micron).  The data are reversible and are not cleaned.
 
 
    Imaging Modes
    ------------
      For a description of the imaging modes, please see the Deep Impact
      instrument paper by Hampton, et al. (2005) [HAMPTONETAL2005].
 
 
    Time-Related Keywords
    ---------------------
      All time-related keywords in the data labels, except
      EARTH_RECEIVED_TIME, are based on the clock on board the flyby
      spacecraft.  EARTH_RECEIVED_TIME provides the UTC when an
      Earth-based observer should have been able to see an event recorded
      by the instrument.
 
      The TIME_FROM_IMPACT_VALUE keyword in the data labels was based on
      the estimated impact time at the flyby spacecraft of UTC
      05:44:35.821 on 4 Jul 2005, as published by A&apos;Hearn, et al. (2005)
      [AHEARNETAL2005A].
 
 
    Geometry-Related Keywords
    -------------------------
      The SDC attempted to calculate geometric parameters relating to the
      target only when it was within several fields of view of the
      instrument boresight.  When these parameters could not be
      calculated, the corresponding keywords in the PDS data labels were
      set to a value of unknown (UNK).
 
      Geometric parameters were computed using the best SPICE kernels
      available at the time of calibration and the results were stored in
      the FITS header.  For impact images, geometric parameters such as
      the target-to-spacecraft distance were computed with respect to the
      impact site, not the center of the comet.
 
      Geometric parameters provided in the data labels were computed at
      the epoch specified by MID_IMAGE_TIME, except for the target-to-sun
      and earth-observer-to-target parameters.  Target-to-sun values were
      calculated for the time when the light left the sun while
      earth-observer-to-target were calculated for the time when the light
      left the target.
 
      Geometry-related parameters in the PDS data labels are uncertain at
      a level of a few seconds because of a known 2-second discrepancy
      between the clocks on board the flyby and impactor spacecraft and
      between in-situ data and ground-based observations.  The Deep Impact
      project generated self-consistent SPICE kernels, outside of NAIF, to
      help account for the discrepancy.  The November 2005 version of
      these kernels was used to calculate the image times and geometric
      information in PDS data labels.  After further analysis of the
      timing problem in early 2006, improved self-consistent SPICE kernels
      were generated by the Deep Impact project.  The improved kernels
      were included in the DI SPICE data set.  For more information about
      this discrepancy, please see the spacecraft clock correlation
      document included on the Deep Impact document volume.
 
      The SPICE kernels used to calculated the geometric parameters are
      provided by the SPICE_FILE_NAME keyword in the PDS data labels. The
      kernels are listed in the order they were loaded into memory for
      processing.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    Geometric parameters included in the data labels were computed using
    the November 2005 version of the SPICE data.  These were the best
    available data at the time of image creation.  Since image creation,
    some SPICE kernels were improved, and these were archived in the Deep
    Impact SPICE data set.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    Earth Mean Equator and Vernal Equinox of J2000 (EME J2000) was the
    inertial reference system used to specify observational geometry
    parameters in the data labels.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    As noted above, the geometry-related parameters in the PDS data
    labels are uncertain at a level of a few seconds because of a known
    2-second discrepancy between the clocks on board the flyby and
    impactor spacecraft and between in-situ data and ground-based
    observations.  For more information about this discrepancy, please
    see the spacecraft clock correlation document included on the Deep
    Impact documentation volume.
 
    The FITS files in this data set were reviewed internally by the Deep
    Impact project and were used extensively by the science team to
    calibrate the instruments.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    This data set passed a PDS peer review that took place on April 5,
    2006.  Reviewers stated these data should be archived pending
    resolution of the liens produced during the review.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    There are no gaps in this data set.  All raw, Tempel 1 spectral
    images were successfully reduced and included in this data set.
 
    Horizontal striping through some images indicates missing data.  The
    image quality map extension identifies where pixels are missing.  If
    the second most-significant bit of a pixel in the image quality map is
    turned on, then data for the corresponding image pixel is missing.
    For more information, refer to the notes about image quality map in
    the PDS data label or to the instrument calibration document.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
 
    Known Deficiencies for the IR Calibration
    -----------------------------------------
      There are known deficiencies with the version of the IR calibration
      pipeline that reduced these data.  For example, the dark subtraction
      process was not robust.  A better method was implemented in early
      2006, after these data were delivered to SBN for a peer review,
      which improved the calibration of the anti-saturation filter by
      about 10%. The project plans to archive these improved data into PDS
      as version 2.0 of this data set.  This and other deficiencies are
      described in the HRII calibration limitations document.  Given the
      known deficiencies of the reduced spectra in this data set, the most
      reliably calibrated pixels are those outside the anti-saturation
      filter from 2.0 to 4.8 microns.
 
 
    HRI Telescope Focus
    -------------------
      Early images of stars using the HRI visible CCD indicated the HRI
      telescope was out of focus.  However, this focus problem did not
      affect the HRII instrument.  For more details, please see the
      instrument calibration paper by Klaasen, et al. (2006)
      [KLAASENETAL2006].
 
 
    Displaying Images
    -----------------
      Flight software overwrote the first 50 uncompressed (or 100
      compressed) pixels of first quadrant read out from the instrument
      with an image header.  These header pixels were included in the
      reduced FITS images.  Since the values in these pixels vary
      dramatically, it is recommended that the values of the MINIMUM and
      MAXIMUM keywords in the PDS data label (or the MINPVAL and MAXPVAL
      in the FITS header) be used to scale an image for display because
      these values exclude the header bytes as well as the reference rows
      and columns located around the edge of the spectral image.  The
      location of the header pixels in a displayed FITS image depends on
      the readout order of the instrument, as discussed in the quadrant
      nomenclature section of the Deep Impact instrument calibration
      document.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SUPERSEDED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

