<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.sdu-c-spice-6-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>STARDUST SPICE KERNELS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.next::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.stardust::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.sdu::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.sdu::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.5535_annefrank::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.81p-wild_2_1978_a2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.9p-tempel_1_1867_g1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.sdu-c-spice-6-v1.0__browserp_sdu-c-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.sdu-c-spice-6-v1.0__browser_sdu-c-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.sdu-c-spice-6-v1.0__browser_wgc_sdu-c-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.naif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>SDU-C-SPICE-6-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>STARDUST SPICE KERNELS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2003-02-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1999-02-07T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2011-05-01T00:00:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>BORIS V. SEMENOV</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Semenov, B.V., L.S. Elson, and C.H. Acton, STARDUST SPICE KERNELS
            V1.0, SDU-C-SPICE-6-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Navigation and ancillary data in the form of SPICE System kernel
            files for the Stardust spacecraft.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set includes the complete set of Stardust SPICE data
            files (``kernel files&apos;), which can be accessed using SPICE
            software. The SPICE data contains geometric and other ancillary
            information needed to recover the full value of science
            instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft
            and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments,
            spacecraft orientation, spacecraft sequences of events, and data
            needed for relevant time conversions.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
 
      This data set includes the complete set of Stardust SPICE data
      files (``kernel files&apos;) for the primary (Stardust) and extended
      (NEXT) missions. These kernels files can be accessed using SPICE
      software. The SPICE data contains geometric and other ancillary
      information needed to recover the full value of science
      instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft
      and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments,
      spacecraft orientation, spacecraft sequences of events, and data
      needed for relevant time conversions.
 
 
      Data Types (SPICE kernel types)
      ===============================
 
      SPK kernels contain ephemerides for spacecraft, planets,
      satellites, comets and asteroids as well as for moving or fixed
      spacecraft and instrument structures. They provide position and
      velocity, given in a Cartesian reference frame. SPK files are
      located under the ``data/spk&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      PCK kernels contain certain physical, dynamical and
      cartographic constants for target bodies, such as size and shape
      specifications, and orientation of the spin axis and prime
      meridian. PCK files are located under the ``data/pck&apos; directory
      of this data set.
 
      IK kernels (Instrument description kernels) give descriptive and
      operational data peculiar to a particular scientific instrument,
      such as internal timing relative to the spacecraft clock and
      field-of-view model parameters. IK files are located under the
      ``data/ik&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      CK kernels describe pointing, containing a transformation
      traditionally called the C-matrix which is used to determine
      time-tagged pointing (orientation) angles for a spacecraft
      structure upon which science instruments are mounted. CK files
      are located under the ``data/ck&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      EK (Events) kernels are derived from the integrated sequence of
      events used to produce actual spacecraft commands. EK files are
      located under the ``data/ek&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      LSK (Leapseconds) kernels contain the leapseconds and the values
      of other constants required to perform a transformation between
      Universal Time Coordinated (UTC) and Ephemeris time (ET). LSK
      files are located under the ``data/lsk&apos; directory of this data
      set.
 
      SCLK (Spacecraft Clock) kernels contain on-board clock calibration
      data required to perform a mapping between Ephemeris time (ET)
      and spacecraft on-board time (SCLK.) SCLK files are located under
      the ``data/sclk&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      FK (Frame Definitions) kernels contain information required to
      define reference frames, sources of frame orientation data and
      inter-connections between these frames and other frames supported
      within the SPICE system. This includes mounting alignment
      information for each instrument. FK files are located under
      the ``data/fk&apos; directory of this data set.
 
 
      Kernel File Details
      ===================
 
      A brief overview of the different types of Stardust kernels
      included in this data set is provided in the
      CONFIDENCE_LEVEL_NOTE section of this file while details specific
      to individual files are found in the ``*info.txt&apos; files in the
      corresponding data directory. The most detailed description of
      the data in each file is provided in metadata included inside the
      file -- in the description area of text kernels or in the comment
      area of binary kernels.
 
 
      Software
      ========
 
      The SPICE Toolkit contains software modules needed to read
      SPICE kernel files. SPICELIB software is highly documented
      via internal headers. Additional documentation is available
      in separate ASCII text files called Required Reading files.
      For example, the S- and P- Kernel (SPK) Required Reading File,
      named SPK.REQ, describes use of the SPK kernel file readers
      and contains sample programs.
 
      The latest SPICE Toolkit for a variety of computer platforms such
      as PC, Mac, SUN, etc. is available at the NAIF Node of PDS
      electronically (via anonymous FTP and WWW servers). Refer to
      information in ``software/softinfo.txt&apos; for details regarding
      obtaining this software. Each version of the Toolkit is also
      archived at the NASA National Space Science Data Center.
 
 
      Loading Kernel Files into a SPICE-based Application
      ===================================================
 
      The easiest way to make data from a collection of SPICE kernels
      available to a SPICE-based application is to list these kernels
      in a meta-kernel and load it into the program using the high
      level SPICE data loader routine FURNSH. This data set provides
      such meta-kernel(s) under the ``extras/mk&apos; directory. For more
      information about the Stardust meta-kernel(s), see the file
      ``extras/mk/mkinfo.txt&apos;.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      This volume contains SPICE kernel files created during mission
      operations and after mission data reconstruction and analysis.
      Some general information about this collection follows here,
      but the prospective user is also referred to extensive
      descriptions about each file that are stored inside each kernel
      file. These metadata provide detailed information regarding
      the information source from which the data were derived, the
      type of processing applied to the source data, applicability
      of the data, etc. Metadata are located in the ``comment area&apos;
      for binary kernel types (SPK, CK, ESQ), accessible using either
      the COMMNT or SPACIT utility program found in the NAIF Toolkit.
      Metadata are located after ``\begintext&apos; markers within the
      text kernel types (PCK, IK, FK, LSK, SCLK), accessible by
      using any available text file display tool such as a word
      processor, text editor, or the unix ``more&apos; or ``cat&apos;
      commands.
 
      In some cases data accuracy information does not exist, or
      may be estimated after mission completion.
 
      Where there are questions about data accuracy or ``confidence&apos;
      not addressed herein the reader is invited to examine subsequent
      SPICE archive releases associated with this data set (if such
      exist), or to contact the NAIF node of the Planetary Data System
      for possible further information.
 
 
      SPK Files
      =========
 
      Majority of the SP-Kernel files included in this data set provide
      the trajectory of the Stardust spacecraft. These files also
      include ephemeris data for the primary mission targets -- Wild 2
      and Annefrank -- and the NEXT mission target -- Tempel 1 -- along
      with ephemeris data for Earth, Moon, and Sun. The spacecraft
      trajectory stored in these SPKs was determined by the Stardust
      Navigation (NAV) and Optical Navigation (OPNAV) teams, both from
      JPL.
 
      According to the NAV Team post-Annefrank flyby trajectory release
      the converged B-plane solution -- B.R (b-plane radial), B.T
      (b-plane transversal), and CLTOF (closest approach time, ET) --
      were -1249.9km (-+ 4km), 2813.4km (-+ 8.5km), and 2-nov-2002
      04:51:20.8 (-+ 0.8sec). The flyby distance was 3078.5km (-+9km).
 
      For the Wild 2 encounter the most accurate spacecraft trajectory
      relative to Wild 2 was computed by the OPNAV team by fitting the
      NAVCAM image data. Based on this solution the closest approach
      time and distance for the encounter are 2004-01-02T19:21:32 UTC
      and 236.5 km. This solution is provided in a separate SPK file,
      covering just the two hour period around the encounter. While it,
      when used together with the adjusted spacecraft attitude CK file,
      provides the best geometry for processing of the image data, it
      does not provide an accurate representation of the heliocentric
      location of the spacecraft. The boundary discontinuity between
      this image-based solution and the primary radio navigation
      solution, which is more accurate in an absolute sense, is about
      440 km.
 
      For the Tempel 1 encounter the most accurate spacecraft
      trajectory relative to Tempel 1 was also computed by the OPNAV
      team by fitting the NAVCAM image data. Based on this solution the
      closest approach time and distance for the encounter are
      2011-02-15T04:39:12.417 UTC and 182.0 km. This solution was
      combined with the longer arc solution based on radio tracking
      data and delivered in the SPK covering the first four months of
      2011.
 
      One additional SP-Kernel file included in this data set provides
      locations of the spacecraft&apos;s center of gravity and antennas with
      respect to the spacecraft reference frame origin. This file is
      included in the data set because it may be useful for the future
      radio science analysis.
 
      Additional information about SPK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/spk/spkinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      CK Files
      ========
 
      C-kernel files included in this data set provide orientation of
      the spacecraft bus, Navigation Camera instrument, and dust
      collector grid. The former two kinds of CK files are produced
      from engineering telemetry downlinked from the spacecraft. As is
      often the case with spacecraft engineering telemetry-based
      measurements, considerable uncertainty exists as to the accuracy
      of such measurements, and, data quality (accuracy and
      completeness) can vary significantly. The latter kind of CK files
      is produced from commanded collector angle data.
 
      Spacecraft Bus CK Files
      -----------------------
 
      These CK files containing the orientation of the spacecraft bus
      (``the spacecraft&apos;) are provided to support interpretation of
      data obtained by all science experiments. The spacecraft
      orientation CK file included in this data set were produced from
      the merged stream of orientation quaternions computed on-board
      and sent down in channelized telemetry, small forces packets, and
      NAVCAM image headers.
 
      The fact that the NAVCAM instrument could successfully point to
      and track the desired targets (Annefrank, Wild 2, star fields,
      etc.) and that the targets were found close to the expected
      location in the images indicates that the accuracy of orientation
      information sent down from the spacecraft was within the mission
      requirements. At the same time it should be mentioned that at the
      time of this archive release there are no known reports assessing
      accuracy of the spacecraft orientation provided in these CK
      files.
 
      For the Wild 2 encounter the most accurate spacecraft orientation
      was computed by the OPNAV team by fitting the NAVCAM image data.
      This attitude solution is provided in a separate CK file,
      covering just the 45 minute period around the encounter. When
      used together with the OPNAV-determined spacecraft trajectory SPK
      file, this solution provides the best geometry for processing of
      the close encounter data, predicting the Wild 2 center position
      in the NAVCAM images to within five to twenty pixels of the
      actual, seen position (for the unadjusted, telemetry-based
      spacecraft attitude CK this difference is tens of pixels.)
 
      For the Tempel 1 encounter the most accurate spacecraft
      orientation was computed by the OPNAV team by fitting the NAVCAM
      image data. This attitude solution is provided in a separate CK
      file, covering just 72 short intervals between to the exposure
      start and stop times of the 72 encounter images. When used
      together with the OPNAV-determined spacecraft trajectory SPK
      file, this solution provides the best geometry for processing of
      the close encounter data.
 
      Navigation Camera CK Files
      --------------------------
 
      These CK files containing orientation of the NAVCAM instrument
      relative to the spacecraft bus are provided to support the NAVCAM
      image analysis. The orientation data in these files are comprised
      of a number of individual transformations implementing the NAVCAM
      pointing model defined and described in the Stardust Frames
      Kernel (FK) file. Some of these transformations have been computed
      from the NAVCAM mirror angle data contained in the image headers,
      others -- using the OPNAV team pointing correction tables
      provided in the NAVCAM IK file.
 
      The original, type 1, NAVCAM CK files contain discrete data points
      corresponding to the exact times when the images were taken and
      cannot be used to compute the camera view direction for any other
      times. To get these exact times users interested in computing
      NAVCAM orientation using these CKs must start with SCLK values
      provided in the SPACECRAFT_CLOCK_START_COUNT keywords in the
      NAVCAM image labels and convert these SCLKs to other time
      system(s) to access SPICE data. Starting with UTC times from the
      NAVCAM labels will result in a small round off and the pointing
      will not be found.
 
      The type 2 NAVCAM CK files prepared for the archive contain the
      same orientation as the original type 1 CKs but that orientation
      covers small windows, from exposure start minus 1 SCLK tick to
      exposure stop plus 1 SCLK tick, allowing computing NAVCAM
      orientation at any time within the image exposures and making
      these CKs more usable with high-level SPICE APIs. The mirror
      orientation stored in these files is constant during each of the
      exposure windows.
 
      While OPNAV Team invested substantial effort in solving for
      correction to be applied to the ideal NAVCAM pointing model in
      order to estimate actual camera orientation, the correction that
      had been derived prior to the Annefrank flyby and used to compute
      orientation data for the NAVCAM CK files did not work well for
      all image sequences. Even with correction applied, computed
      pointing estimate had been off by as much as few tens of pixels
      for some of the images.
 
      Dust Collector CK File
      ----------------------
 
      This file contains commanded orientation of the collector,
      computed from commanded collector position angles, because no
      direct indicators of the actual collector orientation were
      available in the spacecraft engineering telemetry. It covers both
      ISP collection period and the Wild 2 encounter.
 
      Caution on Using CK Files
      -------------------------
 
      While not a data accuracy issue, the CK user is nevertheless
      cautioned to understand and properly use the data found and
      tolerance arguments that are inputs to the CK reader provided
      in the SPICE Toolkit. Descriptions about how to read CK files
      are found in the CK reader routine headers (top of the source
      code files) and in the ``CK Required Reading&apos; document; these
      are contained in each SPICE Toolkit package.
 
      Additional information about CK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/ck/ckinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      PCK Files
      =========
 
      PCK files provide size, shape and orientation data for ``target&apos;
      bodies such as planets, satellites, comets and asteroids. A
      description of these data items and reference to their source is
      provided inside the PCK file, which is a simple text file that
      can be viewed using any word processor, text editor or text
      display utility.
 
      This data set contains generic PCK files based on the official
      IAU/IAG/COSPAR values accepted in 1994 and 2006  and PCK files
      for Stardust mission targets -- Wild 2 and Annefrank, -- and NEXT
      mission target -- Tempel 1 -- that provide constants determined
      after the encounters. While the PCK files for Wild 2 and Tempel 1
      contains both rotation and shape data, the file for Annefrank
      contains only the shape data because orientation of the asteroid
      was not determined from the flyby data.
 
      Additional information about PCK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/pck/pckinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      FK Files
      ========
 
      Frames kernel files provide specifications for how one reference
      frame is defined relative to another frame. The Stardust FK
      provided in this data set contains a complete set of frame
      definitions for the spacecraft, its structures such as antennas,
      and all of its science instruments. Meta information provided in
      the comments included in this file consists of the frame
      definitions, description of the frame relationships, source of
      and accuracy of the mounting alignment information, etc.
 
      Additional information about FK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/fk/fkinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      IK Files
      ========
 
      Instrument kernel files provide specifications for the optical
      and physical instrument parameters and -- where applicable --
      field-of-view size, shape and orientation for the named
      instrument. Metadata describing these estimates are provided in
      each IK file included in this archive.
 
      Additional information about IK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/ik/ikinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      SCLK Files
      ==========
 
      Spacecraft Clock kernel files provide a tabulation of data
      needed for converting time measurements between ephemeris time
      (ET) and spacecraft clock time (SCLK). A SPICE SCLK file is
      made from a similar file -- SCLK/SCET file, or SCLKvSCET
      file -- produced by another mission entity. Each newly made SCLK
      file fully replaces the previous SCLK file.
 
      For Stardust the time correlation accuracy provided in SCLK/SCET
      files is informally reported by the Lockheed Martin spacecraft
      team to be better than 20 milliseconds. (NAIF has not attempted
      to obtain or produce an independent corroboration of these LMA
      estimates.) The SPICE SCLK file has essentially the same accuracy
      as the SCLK/SCET file.
 
      SPICE software does not prohibit an SCLK file from being used
      for time conversions occurring for ``future times&apos; (or more
      accurately, for epochs that occur later than the epoch of the
      last telemetry data used in producing the last correlation
      coefficients found in the SCLK file). Such ``predict&apos; time
      conversions are likely to be inaccurate (changed somewhat)
      once the epoch of interest has been passed.
 
      Additional information about SCLK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/sclk/sclkinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      LSK Files
      =========
 
      Leapseconds kernel files provide a tabulation of ``leapseconds&apos;
      and some other terms used in converting time measurements
      between ephemeris time (ET) and Universal Time (UTC). ``Spacecraft
      Event Time&apos; (SCET) is the commonly used name for UTC events
      measured at the spacecraft.
 
      Metadata describing how the LSK data are obtained or computed
      is contained inside the LSK text file. The time conversion
      provided by SPICE LSK files is accurate to approximately
      0.000030 seconds.
 
      Additional information about LSK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/lsk/lskinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      EK Files
      ========
 
      Two kinds of Events kernel (EK) files for the primary mission are
      included in this archive: Experimenter&apos;s Notebook EKs and
      Sequence EKs. No EK files were made during the NEXT mission.
 
      Experimenter&apos;s Notebook EKs kernels are a digital analog to
      the traditional paper laboratory notebook. Hence Experimenter&apos;s
      Notebook entries represent truth only as seen by the author
      of the notes--there is no attempt made to independently validate
      any aspect of Experimenter&apos;s Notebook information.
 
      Sequence EKs comprise a summary of the commands sent to the
      spacecraft as well as instrument state (status) summaries as
      modeled by the sequence generation tools. This data set includes
      Sequence EKs created from integrated sequence Predicted Events
      Files (PEFs) produced by the Stardust spacecraft team, LMA. As
      seen from the source product name these files contain predicted
      information -- background sequences, as should have executed by
      the spacecraft. Because of that the EK records have times
      different from the actual command execution times (although very
      close in most cases.) These EKs are also missing any commands
      that were not part of the background sequences (real-time
      commands).
 
      Additional information about EK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/ek/ekinfo.txt&apos;.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>PSCM-00033</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

