<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mgn-v-rss-5-occ-prof-abs-h2so4-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MAGELLAN V RSS 5 OCCULTATION PROFILE ABS H2SO4 VOLMIX V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.magellan::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mgn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.mgn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgn-v-rss-5-occ-prof-abs-h2so4-v1.0__browserp_mgn-v-rss-5-occ-prof-abs-h2so4-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Davies, M.E., et al., The rotation period, direction of the North Pole, and
                   geodetic control network of Venus, J. Geophys. Res., 97 (E8), pp. 13141-13151,
                   1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DAVIESETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Fjeldbo, G., and V.R. Eshleman, The Atmosphere of Mars Analyzed By Integral
                   Inversion of the Mariner IV Occultation Data, Planet. Space Sci., 16, pp.
                   1035-1059, 1968.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FJELDBO-ESHLEMAN1968</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Jenkins, J.M., and P.G. Steffes, Results for 13-cm absorptivity and H2SO4
                   abundance profiles from the season 10 (1986) Pioneer Venus Orbiter radio
                   occultation experiment, Icarus, 90, 129-138, 1991.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JENKINS-STEFFES1991</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Jenkins, J.M., Variations in the 13 cm Opacity below the Main Cloud Layer
                   in the Atmosphere of Venus inferred from Pioneer-Venus Radio Occultation
                   Studies 1978-1992, Ph.D. dissertation, Georgia Institute of Technology,
                   1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JENKINS1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Jenkins, J.M., P.G. Steffes, D.P. Hinson, J.D. Twicken, and G.L. Tyler, Radio
                   Occultation Studies of the Venus Atmosphere with the Magellan Spacecraft: 2.
                   Results from the October 1991 Experiments, Icarus, 110, 79-94, 1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JENKINSETAL1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lipa, B., and G.L. Tyler, Statistical and computational uncertainties in
                   atmospheric profiles from radio occultation: Mariner 10 at Venus, Icarus,
                   39, pp. 192-208, 1979.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LIPA-TYLER1979</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Steffes, P.G., J.M. Jenkins, R.S. Austin, S.W. Asmar, D.T. Lyons, E.H. Seale,
                   and G.L. Tyler, Radio Occultation Studies of the Venus Atmosphere with the
                   Magellan Spacecraft: 1. Experimental Description and Performance, Icarus, 110,
                   71-78, 1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.STEFFESETAL1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MGN-V-RSS-5-OCC-PROF-ABS-H2SO4-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MAGELLAN V RSS 5 OCCULTATION PROFILE ABS H2SO4 VOLMIX V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1996-06-27</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1991-10-05</start_time>
        <stop_time>1991-10-06</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JON JENKINS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            MAGELLAN OCCULTATION PROFILE ABS H2SO4 VOLMIX
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set includes vertical profiles of 13-cm and 3.6-cm
            absorptivity and abundance of sulfuric acid vapor (H2SO4). The
            data set is composed of the following parameter fields (listed as
            the field name followed by a description).
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      This data set includes vertical profiles of 13-cm and 3.6-cm
      absorptivity and abundance of sulfuric acid vapor (H2SO4).  The
      data set is composed of the following parameter fields (listed
      as the field name followed by a description).
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      WAVELENGTH - radio carrier wavelength (X-band or S-band).
 
      ORBIT_NUMBER - orbit number (3212, 3213, or 3214).
 
      ERT - Earth received time of the observation (UT).
 
      ALTITUDE - altitude above 6052 km, km.  (Note that this
      reference surface is one km higher than the 6051 km Venus
      radius adopted by the MGN project).
 
      ABSORPTIVITY - absorptivity, dB/km.
 
      ABSORP_DEV - absorptivity standard deviation, dB/km.
 
      H2SO4_VOLMIX - H2SO4 vapor volume mixing ratio, ppm.
 
      H2SO4_VM_DEV - H2SO4 vapor volume mixing ratio standard
      deviation, ppm.
 
      LATITUDE - latitude at the proximate point (the deepest level
      of the atmosphere probed by the radio beam), deg (North is
      positive).  See DAVIESETAL1992 for a discussion of the Venus
      cartographic coordinate system.
 
      LONGITUDE - east longitude (Venus body-fixed) at the proximate
      point (the deepest level of the atmosphere probed by the radio
      beam), deg.  See DAVIESETAL1992 for a discussion of the Venus
      cartographic coordinate system.
 
      ZENITH_ANGLE - solar zenith angle at the proximate point (the
      deepest level of the atmosphere probed by the radio beam), deg.
 
      LOCAL_TIME - local time at the proximate point (the deepest
      level of the atmosphere probed by the radio beam), hours (1/24
      local day).
 
 
      Data were obtained from dual-frequency ingress radio
      occultation experiments using the Magellan orbiter on three
      consecutive orbits (#3212 - #3214) on October 5 and 6, 1991.
      The radio signals probed a region of the atmosphere near 65
      degrees N latitude, reaching as low as 35 km altitude at X-band
      (3.6 cm wavelength or 8.426 GHz frequency) and below 34 km
      altitude at S-band (13 cm wavelength or 2.298 GHz frequency)
      above a mean planetary radius of 6052 km.  (Note that this
      reference surface is one km higher than the 6051 km Venus
      radius adopted by the MGN project).
 
      A full description of the spacecraft performance and the design
      of the experiment is discussed in [STEFFESETAL1994].  Data
      processing and results are discussed in [JENKINSETAL1994].
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The raw data sets consisted of open-loop recordings of the
      13-cm and 3.6-cm carrier signals received at DSN Station 43 at
      Tidbinbilla (near Canberra), Australia, along with spacecraft
      trajectory and planetary ephemerides information, supplied by
      JPL Navigation and the Magellan Project, and reconstructions of
      the actual limb-tracking maneuvers executed by the spacecraft,
      supplied by Martin Marietta Corporation.  The open-loop
      recordings contained four channels digitized at 8-bits and
      sampled at 50 kHz: right hand and left hand circular
      polarization (RCP and LCP) at 13 cm and 3.6 cm.  The receiver
      bandwidths were 20 kHz prior to sampling.  Since Magellan
      transmits in linear polarization at 13 cm, the 13-cm RCP and
      LCP signals each contained half the power received at the
      ground station, but were not in phase with one another.  At 3.6
      cm, Magellan transmits in RCP, so that the 3.6-cm signal of
      primary interest was the RCP channel.
 
      Obtaining atmospheric profiles from the raw data sets required
      several steps.  Most of these are routine and well-documented
      in the literature (e.g.  [FJELDBO&amp;ESHLEMAN1968];
      [LIPA&amp;TYLER1979]; [JENKINS&amp;STEFFES1991]; and [JENKINS1992]).
      First, the open loop recordings were processed to obtain
      time-series of frequency and power (log intensity) for each
      channel.  The frequency time-series were used to determine the
      13-cm and 3.6-cm refractivity profiles, from which the
      temperature, pressure and density profiles were derived.  The
      power time-series, in conjunction with the frequency
      time-series, were used to derive 13-cm and 3.6-cm absorptivity
      profiles, which were combined with the temperature/pressure
      profiles to obtain abundance profiles of H2SO4 vapor.  These
      steps are described in more detail in [JENKINSETAL1994].
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      These experiments probed the neutral atmosphere at altitudes
      between 33 and 100 km.  The experiment geometry was nearly
      identical for all three occultations.  The angle between the
      spacecraft orbit plane and the direction to Earth at the time
      of the measurements was about 28 degrees, so that the
      occultations were nondiametric.  Hence the ray paths sliced
      obliquely through the atmosphere.  In traversing the range of
      altitudes given above, the proximate point (point of closest
      approach to Venus along the ray path) sampled latitudes from 68
      to 56 degrees N, longitudes from 128 to 139 degrees E, and
      solar zenith angles from 109 to 114 degrees.  See
      [DAVIESETAL1992] for a discussion of the Venus cartographic
      coordinate system.  The direction along the ray path near the
      proximate point nearly coincided with the local east-west
      direction on Venus (it varied between 280 and 290 degrees from
      North during each experiment).  As the atmosphere of Venus
      rotates about 10 degrees during each 3.25 hour orbit of the
      spacecraft, these data made it possible to investigate
      short-term variations and to place constraints on the zonal
      variability in the Venus atmosphere.
 
      These signals probe deeper than any previous radio occultation
      profiles of Venus, and with lower uncertainties.  Error bars
      were placed on all derived parameters using the standard
      propagation of errors.  Numerical simulations with analytical
      models for the Venus atmosphere were conducted to validate the
      processing and to confirm the magnitude of the error bars
      placed on the profiles.
 
      Abundance profiles inferred from the 13-cm absorptivity
      profiles are more reliable than the ones derived from the 3.6
      cm measurements.  This is due to the additional problems
      associated with correcting for antenna pointing errors at 3.6
      cm, and the lower uncertainties in the expression for H2SO4
      vapor absorptivity at 13 cm developed from laboratory
      measurements.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The low uncertainties in the absorptivity profiles are due to
      the capabilities of the Magellan spacecraft (in particular, a
      high effective isotropic radiated power or EIRP), as well as to
      the application of new signal processing methods.  However, the
      magnitudes of the errors within 2 km of the base and the top of
      each of these profiles are understated by the standard
      propagation of errors.  The error bars outside of the 2 km
      margins have been estimated conservatively.  The stated
      uncertainties in absorptivity include an inflation factor (in
      the range of 30 to 50) designed to account for power
      fluctuations caused by small-scale refractive irregularities.
 
 
    PDS Peer Review
    ===============
      The peer review of these data began in December 1994 and was
      concluded on January 17, 1995.  The data and accompanying
      documentation were accepted for archival and distribution by
      the PDS.  The peer-review committee included:
 
        Jon Jenkins
        Ron Joyner
        Marc Kolodner
        Steve Lee
        Dick Simpson
        Paul Steffes
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>89-033B-03C</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

