<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.go-j-pws-2-edr-waveform-80khz-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GO JUPITER PWS EDITED EDR 80KHZ WAVEFORM RECEIVER V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.galileo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:pws.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:plasma_cloud.io_plasma_torus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.amalthea::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.callisto::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.europa::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.ganymede::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.io::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-j-pws-2-edr-waveform-80khz-v1.0__browserp_go-j-pws-2-edr-waveform-80khz-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GO-J-PWS-2-EDR-WAVEFORM-80KHZ-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GO JUPITER PWS EDITED EDR 80KHZ WAVEFORM RECEIVER V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1997-01-02</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1995-12-07T15:21Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2002-11-06T06:35Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. WILLIAM S. KURTH</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Gurnett, D.A., Kurth, W.S., Granroth, L.J., GO JUPITER PWS EDITED
            EDR 80KHZ WAVEFORM RECEIVER V1.0,
            GO-J-PWS-2-EDR-WAVEFORM-80KHZ-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            1997
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set includes 80 kHz wideband waveform measurements from
            the Galileo plasma wave receiver obtained during Jupiter orbital
            operations. Data were acquired near perijove, satellite
            encounters, and other selected intervals.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set includes wideband waveform measurements from the
            Galileo plasma wave receiver obtained during Jupiter orbital
            operations. These data were obtained during selected observation
            periods near perijove, satellite encounters and other select
            times. These measurements are electric waveforms obtained by
            rapidly sampling the potential at the input to the receiver from
            the electric dipole antenna. The sample rates are 201,600/s,
            25,200/s, or 3,150/s taken through bandpass filters of 80, 10, or
            1 kHz, respectively.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
    This data set includes wideband waveform measurements from the
    Galileo plasma wave receiver obtained during Jupiter orbital
    operations. These data were obtained during selected observation
    periods near perijove, satellite encounters and other select times.
    These measurements are electric waveforms obtained by rapidly
    sampling the potential at the input to the receiver from the
    electric dipole antenna.  The sample rates are 201,600/s, 25,200/s,
    or 3,150/s taken through bandpass filters of 80, 10, or 1 kHz,
    respectively.  Each sample is a 4-bit measurement after an automatic
    gain control (AGC) amplifier designed to keep the signal amplitude
    in a range commensurate with the optimal analog-to-digital converter
    dynamic range with a time constant of about 500 msec.  As such, the
    measurements are not absolutely calibrated, although it is possible
    to determine the approximate AGC gain from a digital performance
    parameter available every 2.667 seconds, assuming the signal
    amplitude does not vary appreciably over the 2.667 second interval.
    Alternately, the sweep frequency receiver (low rate) portion of the
    instrument can be used to determine the absolute amplitude of waves.
    In many cases, the waveform data are used without any calibration
    for the purposes of identifying characteristic frequencies of the
    plasma via resonances or cutoffs, observing discrete emissions such
    as chorus or whistlers, or looking at the detailed form of the
    waveforms.
 
    In general, the waveform samples are not continuous over long time
    periods due to the limited telemetry capability of the Galileo data
    system and limits on the bandwidth available to the PWS instrument.
    Instead, sequences of contiguous samples are collected for up to
    about 67 msec followed by a gap.  The number of consecutive samples
    between gaps is determined by the telemetry format and the bandwidth
    (instrument mode).  Details of the timing, number of consecutive
    samples in a series, and the effective duty cycle are described in
    the inst.cat, rowpfx.fmt, and edrhdr.fmt files included with the
    data set.
 
    The data are formatted in files covering no more than 1 RIM (60.667
    s) each up to 91 data records, with a record containing 10 or 80
    blocks of contiguous waveform samples.  The data in any one file are
    from only a single combination of instrument mode (waveform) and
    telemetry format, however, the antenna can change within a file;
    this is noted in the record header information, but is only updated
    every 2.667 sec, hence, may not be accurate less than 2.667 seconds
    after a real antenna change. Since the instrument mode information
    is also updated only once per 2.667 seconds, the last data in a
    record (less than 2.667 seconds) may actually be in a different
    mode.
 
    The typical uses of the waveform data are to (1) display the
    waveform of plasma wave and other signals such as dust impacts, and
    (2) as highly detailed (in time and frequency) spectra through the
    use of Fourier transforms.  To avoid artifacts, we suggest not
    transforming over the gaps but limiting the input to the Fourier
    transform to a single contiguous series of samples.  Spectra from
    individual waveform series can be stacked in order to generate
    frequency-time dynamic spectrograms.
 
    This data set is highly discontinuous in time. Because of the severe
    limitations in the downlink capability of the Galileo spacecraft,
    LPW rate data were recorded only for targeted observations. Most
    of these data were acquired near the Galilean moons, although
    selected observations were made in various locations around the
    magnetosphere. Table 1 below provides a listing of the start and
    stop times of the recorded data segments. Even within these time.
    intervals, the data are discontinuous. Data are acquired by using
    both the electric field and magnetic field antennas. The PDS labels
    provided contain information about which antenna was used to
    to generate the data in each file. All 80 kHz observations were
    recorded in the LPW tape format with the instrument configured
    into the PWH5 data format.
 
     ----------------------------------------------------------
                               TABLE  1
     ----------------------------------------------------------
                  Start                   Telemetry   PWS
     Orb Obs-ID*  Date         Time Range    mode    format
     ----------------------------------------------------------
     J00   IO   1995/12/07   14:52 - 18:26   LPW      PWH5
     J00   PJOV 1995/12/07   23:22 - 01:25   LPW      PWH5
     G01   GAN  1996/06/27   06:09 - 06:52   LPW      PWH5
     G02   GAN  1996/09/06   18:32 - 19:27   LPW      PWH5
     C03   CALL 1996/11/04   13:14 - 14:00   LPW      PWH5
     E04   EUR  1996/12/19   06:35 - 07:24   LPW      PWH5
     E06   EUR  1997/02/20   16:37 - 21:47   LPW      PWH5
     G07   PSX  1997/03/30   19:38 - 20:25   LPW      PWH5
     C09   CALL 1997/06/28   13:55 - 24:51   LPW      PWH5
     C21   PJOV 1999/07/02   01:48 - 01:51   LPW      PWH5
 
     * The ID element is derived from the SEF identifier for the
        recorded observation. The recording identifiers translate to:
            IO, GAN, EUR, CALL - satellites
            PSX  - plasma sheet crossing
            TAR  - trans-auroral region
            QRS  - quarter rotation survey
            DSK  - dusk side of orbit C9
            DAWN - dawn side of orbit C9
            APJ  - apojove
            TOR  - Io torus
            EQX  - magnetic equator crossing
            PJOV - perijove
            RAMP - outer torus
        These designations were defined by the sequence team.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
    This data set includes all available wideband waveform data within
    the interval of time covered.  Original UDRs contained inaccuracies
    in the instrument status and Spacecraft Event Time (SCET).  Each
    file contains a corrected SCET in the attached PDS label and binary
    EDR header, and corrected instrument status information in the
    record headers.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

