<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.gp-j-dwe-3-entry-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GALILEO PROBE DOPPLER WIND EXPERIMENT DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.galileo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.gp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:dwe.gp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.gp-j-dwe-3-entry-v1.0__browserp_gp-j-dwe-3-entry-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Atkinson, D.H., J.B. Pollack, and A. Seif, Galileo Doppler measurements of the
                   deep zonal winds at Jupiter, Science, 272, 842-843, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ATKINSONETAL1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Davies, M.E., M. Abalakin, J.H. Lieske, P.K. Seidelman, A.T. Sinclair, A.M
                   Sinzi, B.A. Smith, and Y.S. Tjuflin, Report of the IAU Working Group on
                   Cartographic Coordinates and Rotational Elements of the Planets and
                   Satellites, Celestial Mechanics and Dynamical Astronomy 29, 309-321, 1983.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DAVIESETAL1983</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.RIDDLE-WARWICK1976</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GP-J-DWE-3-ENTRY-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GALILEO PROBE DOPPLER WIND EXPERIMENT DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1996-12-08</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1995-12-07T21:05:44Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1995-12-07T23:35:44Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID ATKINSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            GALILEO PROBE DOPPLER WIND EXPERIMENT DATA V1.0
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            A total of seven data sets are used to derive the wind profile.
            These include two trajectory data files (probe and orbiter),
            three frequency data files including the &apos;quicklook&apos;
            data set comprising 1/2 resolution frequency data from the
            orbiter CDS, and two data files containing the full tape recorder
            (SDR) data. Additionally, the probe descent trajectory data are
            supplemented with probe descent velocity/altitude/pressure/time
            data from the Atmospheric Structure Instrument. Finally, the
            Jovian atmospheric structure, based on measurements by the
            Atmospheric Structure Instrument, is included.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    A total of seven data sets are used to derive the wind profile.
    These include two trajectory data files (probe and orbiter),
    three frequency data files including the &apos;quicklook&apos; data set
    comprising 1/2 resolution frequency data from the orbiter CDS,
    and two data files containing the full tape recorder (SDR) data.
    Additionally, the probe descent trajectory data are supplemented
    with probe descent velocity/altitude/pressure/time data from the
    Atmospheric Structure Instrument.  Finally, the Jovian
    atmospheric structure, based on measurements by the Atmospheric
    Structure Instrument, is included in ASI4ATM.TAB.
 
 
    Reference Times
    ---------------
      time of entry (UT): 22:04:43.752
      time of Minor Frame Zero (UT at the probe): 22:07:30.265
      time of Minor Frame Zero (UT at the orbiter): 22:07:30.965
      time of Lock (UT at the orbiter): 22:08:30.693
      time of Loss of Lock (UT at the orbiter): 23:06:09
      time between entry and Minor Frame Zero at the probe: 166.513
      seconds
      time between entry and lock at the orbiter: 226.941 seconds
      time between Minor Frame Zero and lock at the orbiter: 59.728
      seconds
      time between entry and loss of lock at the orbiter: 3,685.25
      seconds
      total data (total time of lock): 57 minutes, 38.31 seconds =
      3,458.31 seconds
      Total data points (frequencies): 5,015 out of a possible 5,174
      total missing frequencies: 5,174 - 5,015 = 159
 
      Note 1:
 
      Minor Frame Zero is the start time of the first minor frame of
      data in probe descent mode.  This is the probe mission
      reference time.  It differs between the probe and orbiter due
      to the propagation time between the probe and orbiter of about
      0.7 seconds.  The use of one time or the other (relative to the
      probe or the orbiter) depends on whether the instantaneous
      times of each frequency measurement and the trajectory
      parameters are referenced to times at the probe or the orbiter.
 
      Since the probe/orbiter trajectories, as well as the winds, are
      referenced to times at the probe, Minor Frame Zero at the probe
      is used rather than at the orbiter.
 
      Note 2:
 
      Lock is the time (UT) at which the orbiter locks onto the probe
      signal and starts recording probe science data.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    Data files:
 
    CRS (Orbiter trajectory, ASCII): orbtrtrj.tab
    PSTF (Probe trajectory, ASCII): probetrj.tab
    CDS (Tape Recorder, half resolution frequency, ASCII): rsf0117a.adj
    SDR (Probe frequency data, ASCII): sdr0530a.tab
    SDR (Probe frequency data, ASCII): radio.tab
    ASI (Probe trajectory data from ASI, ASCII): asi2ref.tab
    Atmospheric Structure Data (ASCII): asi4atm.tab
 
    Frequency data:
 
    The frequency data sets come in two different forms.  The
    &apos;Quick-Look&apos; data are half-resolution and comprise probe radio
    link frequencies stored in the orbiter CDS every 4/3 seconds.
    These data files, designated as rsf (radio science frequencies)
    are described in more detail below.
 
    The System Data Record (SDR) data are from the tape recorder with
    a sampling frequency of 1.5 Hz (one sample every 2/3 seconds).
    The SDR data are described below.
 
    The probe and orbiter data files (PSTF and CRS, respectively)
    provide the probe and orbiter trajectories in time from entry.
    The PSTF file lists the probe position and velocity as a function
    of time from probe entry (defined to be the time of probe
    altitude equal to 450 km above the one bar reference surface).
    The probe descent trajectory is given in x,y,z,xdot,ydot,zdot in
    EME50 coordinates (defined below).
 
    The orbiter trajectory is also listed as x,y,z,xdot,ydot,zdot in
    EME50 coordinates as a function of time past 1950 in ephemeris
    time.
 
 
    CRS - Orbiter Trajectory Data File, ASCII
    -----------------------------------------
      The orbiter trajectory, provided by the Galileo Navigation team
      at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory, is contained in a data file
      called a CRS file.  The CRS data set provides the EME50
      coordinates (x,y,z;xdot,ydot,zdot) of the center of Jupiter in
      an orbiter-centered system.  The CRS file also provides
      auxiliary data such as GM, and the equatorial and polar radii
      for Jupiter.  The times for the orbiter trajectory are given in
      year, day, hour, minute, second, and millisecond past 1950 in
      ephemeris time.
 
      The orbiter trajectory is converted from the
      spacecraft-centered EME50 coordinates to a Jupiter-centered
      JPPM (Jupiter Pole and Prime Meridian) frame.  To make this
      conversion, the unit vectors in the direction of Jupiter&apos;s
      rotation axis (x_pole,y_pole,z_pole) and prime meridian
      (x_pm,y_pm,z_pm) in EME50 coordinates must be known.  These are
      provided in the probe trajectory file PSTF.
 
 
    PSTF - Probe Trajectory Data File, ASCII
    ----------------------------------------
      The Probe System Trajectory File (PSTF) provides the nominal
      descent profile of the probe from entry to the end of the
      descent mission.  The PSTF file is generated by the ATMINT
      program, a key element of JPL&apos;s RLINK program set.
 
      The PSTF file is an ASCII file that contains 1) a header
      containing run identification information; 2) a listing of
      major program parameter values, including a table of probe
      aerodynamic coefficients, and 3) a descent trajectory profile
      which lists the probe&apos;s inertial and atmosphere relative motion
      in Jupiter&apos;s atmosphere as a function of time after entry.  At
      the time of parachute deployment the profile is interrupted by
      a second aerodynamic characteristics table.  This is followed
      by a listing of the probe positional and velocity vectors, the
      unit vectors in the vertical, west, and north directions at the
      probe, and the probe altitude relative to the one bar level,
      all as a function of time (seconds after entry).  The probe
      position and velocity components are given in Jupiter-centered
      EME50 coordinates.
 
      Auxiliary data supplied in the PSTF file include 1) the probe
      entry time both in year, day of year, hour, minutes, and
      seconds in ephemeris time, and the number of seconds past 1950
      again in ephemeris time; 2) the unit vectors in the direction
      of Jupiter&apos;s pole (z-axis), and the intersection between the
      prime meridian and Jupiter&apos;s equator (y-axis) in EME50
      coordinates; 3) the atmosphere model (nominal Orton III); 4)
      Gravitational parameters (GM, J_2, J_4); 5) the polar and
      equatorial radii; 6) the planetary flattening; and 7) the
      system III rotation period of Jupiter.  An x-axis is generated
      by standard techniques to complete the right-handed coordinate
      system.  It should be noted that, although the probe entry time
      is provided in the PSTF file, for purposes of the wind
      retrieval the entry time is input separately, and can therefore
      be altered without the need for regenerating an entirely new
      PSTF data set.
 
      The PSTF file used (PSTF-OD126\_1s) provides the probe descent
      trajectory in 1 second increments and includes the effect of
      the late parachute deployment.  Once the probe trajectory is
      converted from the Jupiter-centered EME50 coordinates to the
      JPPM reference frame, the probe positions and velocities are
      generated as a function of time after entry in a radius,
      latitude, longitude coordinate system.
 
 
    CDS (RSF) Frequency Data, ASCII
    -------------------------------
      Due to the failure of the high gain antenna to deploy and
      concerns about the possible failure of the orbiter tape
      recorder, the probe data were stored in the memory of the
      orbiter Command and Data Subsystem as a backup.  The CDS data
      stored in the CDS were at half resolution (every other time
      point) and therefore provided a frequency measurement every 4/3
      seconds.  The CDS data are an ASCII file of NCO frequency vs.
      time from lock and were used for the early wind analysis.
 
      The CDS (half-resolution) data are contained within the data
      file rsf0117a.adj.  The &apos;adj&apos; indicates that the data set is
      adjusted by removal of spurious frequency measurements and
      missing data.
 
      The first several lines of rsf0117a.adj are given below:
 
            0.000  95:341:22: 8:30.693  1  30 96 C8  432029.71
            1.333  95:341:22: 8:32. 26  1  30 96 75  432018.45
            2.667  95:341:22: 8:33.360  1  30 96 1B  432006.24
            4.000  95:341:22: 8:34.693  1  30 95 BE  431993.62
            5.333  95:341:22: 8:36. 26  1  30 95 68  431981.95
 
      Column one gives the time after lock (seconds) and the last
      column gives the NCO frequency in Hz.
 
 
    SDR Frequency Data (Tape Recorder)
    ----------------------------------
      There are two SDR data sets presented in this archive.  The
      first, designated sdr0530a.tab, is the probe frequency raw data
      as an ASCII data file.  This file has several data outages of
      varying lengths, and several individual missing frequency
      measurements.  Many of these missing measurements were filled
      in using the CDS data set.
 
      Including housekeeping and radioscience, the probe data were
      stored on the orbiter tape recorder for later playback to the
      ground.  The probe signal frequency, measured every 2/3
      seconds, as well as the other probe science and engineering
      data measured throughout the probe mission, was delivered in
      the form of binary System Data Records.
 
      The data file sdr0530a.tab is an ASCII file that was converted
      from binary for further analysis.  Although the probe signal
      frequencies were measured every 2/3 seconds, some gaps existed
      in the data due to corrupted data, DSN outages, and possibly
      several bad spots on the tape recorder tape.  Many of these
      gaps were filled by the CDS data.  Out of 5,174 possible
      frequency measurements there are only 159 missing points, none
      consecutive.
 
      The SDR (tape-recorder) data are contained within data file
      radio.tab and include (where necessary) half-resolution data
      from the CDS file rsf0117a.adj to fill gaps in the data, and
      corrections for the timing errors.  radio.tab is an ASCII file
      that lists NCO frequency vs.  time from lock (seconds).
 
      The first several lines of radio.tab are given below.  The
      columns are time from lock (seconds) and NCO frequency (Hz):
 
            .000       432029.712
            .667       432024.013
           1.334       432018.451
           2.000       432012.481
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    Data from the probe Atmospheric Structure Instrument are used to
    supplement the Doppler wind analysis.  Of primary importance are
    the probe descent velocity, and radius/altitude (above/below the
    one bar reference surface at the given latitude) vs.
    pressure/time.  These data are included in the file asi2ref.tab.
    The first several lines of asi2ref.tab are provided below.  The
    columns are
 
       column 1: time from minor frame zero (seconds)
       column 2: unused
       column 3: probe altitude (km above 1 bar)
       column 4: probe radial velocity (m/s)
       column 5: unused
       column 6: unused
       column 7: unused
       column 8: Probe latitude (planet-centered)
       column 9: Probe longitude at initial time point only
       column 10: unused
       column 11: unused
       column 12: unused
 
  30.1600  0.0  16.000 98.747  0.0  0.0  0.0  6.41 359.468 0.0  0.0  0.0
  50.4700  0.0  14.031 95.168  0.0  0.0  0.0  6.41   0.0   0.0  0.0  0.0
  71.1400  0.0  12.098 91.866  0.0  0.0  0.0  6.41   0.0   0.0  0.0  0.0
  91.2600  0.0  10.281 88.709  0.0  0.0  0.0  6.41   0.0   0.0  0.0  0.0
  112.200  0.0  8.4539 85.822  0.0  0.0  0.0  6.41   0.0   0.0  0.0  0.0
  134.400  0.0  6.5777 83.206  0.0  0.0  0.0  6.41   0.0   0.0  0.0  0.0
  157.460  0.0  4.6867 80.797  0.0  0.0  0.0  6.41   0.0   0.0  0.0  0.0
 
    The initial time point is 30.60 seconds after Minor Frame Zero,
    and the final time point is 3,422.44 seconds after Minor Frame
    Zero.
 
    Note: The total data used in the Doppler Wind Analysis is limited
    by the duration of the ASI data.  Therefore, although the total
    time of lock is 3,458.31 seconds, only 3,361.33 seconds of data
    are used for the wind retrieval due to the lack of ASI data
    beyond 3,422.44 seconds after Minor Frame Zero.
 
 
  Other Data Sets Provided
  ========================
    FRED.TAB
 
    This ASCII file contains the frequency residuals for the Galileo
    Probe Doppler Wind Experiment prior to the wind measurements.
    The columns are
 
      Time from Entry in seconds
      Pressure at probe location (bar)
      Frequency Residuals before the wind retrieval (Hz)
 
    This file contains 5043 rows.  The initial time point is
    1995-12-07 22:08:31 (UT), corresponding to the initial Time from
    Entry of 227.3333 seconds.  The final time point is 23:04:32
    (UT), corresponding to Time from Entry of 3,588.6667 seconds.
 
    Note: the total time in this file (5043 time points) is
    3,588.6667 - 227.3333 seconds = 3,361.33 seconds.  This is less
    than the total time of lock provided above (3,458.31 seconds) and
    is due to the fact that data from the Atmospheric Structure
    Instrument was used to generate the probe descent profile
    (asi2ref.tab).  Therefore, the total data are limited not by the
    time of loss of lock, but by the time at which the data provided
    by the ASI instrument team ended.
 
    The first several rows are shown below:
 
     227.3333      0.5648        0.0000
     228.0000      0.5664        0.3178
     228.6667      0.5680        0.4498
     229.3333      0.5696        0.2558
 
    RESID.TAB
 
    This ASCII file contains data for the Galileo Probe Doppler Wind
    Experiment, including time from entry, time from link lock,
    altitude, pressure, and frequency residuals after the wind
    retrieval.  The columns are
 
      Time from entry (seconds)
      Time from link lock (seconds)
      Altitude above 1 bar (km)
      Pressure at probe location (bar)
      Frequency Residuals after the wind retrieval (Hz)
 
    This file contains 5043 rows.  The initial time point is
    1995-12-07 22:08:31 (UT), corresponding to the initial Time from
    Entry of 227.3333 seconds.  The final time point is 23:04:32
    (UT), corresponding to Time from Entry of 3,588.6667 seconds.
 
    Note: the total time in this file (5043 time points) is
    3,588.6667 - 227.3333 seconds = 3,361.33 seconds.  This is less
    than the total time of lock provided above (3,458.31 seconds) and
    is due to the fact that data from the Atmospheric Structure
    Instrument was used to generate the probe descent profile
    (asi2ref.tab).  Therefore, the total data are limited not by the
    time of loss of lock, but by the time at which the data provided
    by the ASI instrument team ended.
 
    The first several rows are shown below:
 
     227.3330       0.392330       13.3990      0.5648       0.00000
     228.0000        1.05900       13.3380      0.5664       0.37720
     228.6670        1.72567       13.2770      0.5680       0.56510
     229.3330        2.39233       13.2160      0.5696       0.42640
 
    WIND.TAB
 
    This ASCII file contains wind data from the Galileo Probe Doppler
    Wind Experiment, including time from entry, time from lock,
    temperature, pressure and wind.  The columns are
 
      Time from entry (seconds)
      Time from link lock (seconds)
      Temperature (K)
      Pressure at probe location (bar)
      Wind (m/s)
 
    This file contains 5043 rows.  The initial time point is
    1995-12-07 22:08:31 (UT), corresponding to the initial Time from
    Entry of 227.3333 seconds.  The final time point is 23:04:32
    (UT), corresponding to Time from Entry of 3,588.6667 seconds.
 
    Note: the total time in this file (5043 time points) is
    3,588.6667 - 227.3333 seconds = 3,361.33 seconds.  This is less
    than the total time of lock provided above (3,458.31 seconds) and
    is due to the fact that data from the Atmospheric Structure
    Instrument was used to generate the probe descent profile
    (asi2ref.tab).  Therefore, the total data are limited not by the
    time of loss of lock, but by the time at which the data provided
    by the ASI instrument team ended.
 
    The first several rows are shown below:
 
     227.3330        0.39200      138.1107      0.5648      86.54214
     228.0000        1.05900      138.2380      0.5664      86.52588
     228.6670        1.72600      138.3654      0.5680      86.51108
     229.3330        2.39200      138.4927      0.5696      86.49774
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
 
    EME50 - Earth Mean Equator and Equinox of 1950 Coordinates
    ----------------------------------------------------------
      The EME50 coordinate system is an inertial (non-rotating)
      cartesian coordinate frame.  It is defined by the Earth&apos;s mean
      equator, Earth&apos;s vernal equinox, and Earth&apos;s rotation axis.
      The positive x-axis is directed towards the Earth&apos;s mean vernal
      equinox of date; the z-axis is aligned with Earth&apos;s mean
      rotation axis, and the y-axis is made to complete the
      right-handed coordinate frame.  The epoch is 1950 (December 21,
      1949 at 22:09:07 UT).
 
 
    Planetographic/Planetocentric Latitudes
    ---------------------------------------
      Planetographic/planetocentric latitudes are measured north
      (positive) and south (negative) of the equator.  The
      planetographic latitude of a point on the reference surface is
      the angle between the equatorial plane and the normal to the
      surface at that point.  The planetocentric latitude of a point
      is the angle between the line connecting the point to the
      center of mass and the equator [DAVIESETAL1983].
 
 
    System III Longitudes
    ---------------------
      The Jupiter System III longitudes are defined by the rotation
      of Jovian decimetric and decametric radio noise, presumably
      co-rotating with Jupiter&apos;s magnetic field and core.
      [RIDDLE&amp;WARWICK1976].
 
 
    JPPM - Jupiter Pole and Prime Meridian Coordinates
    --------------------------------------------------
      The Jupiter Pole/Prime Meridian system is an inertial cartesian
      coordinate system centered on Jupiter&apos;s center.  The z-axis is
      along Jupiter&apos;s rotation axis, the y-axis is defined by the
      unit vector through the intersection of the system III (1965)
      Prime Meridian and the Jovian equator in EME50 at the epoch of
      probe entry, and the x-axis completes the right-handed
      coordinate system.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    -------------------------
      There are several locations where frequency data points are
      missing.  Several gaps existed due to tape recorder (SDR)
      problems, corrupted data, and DSN outages.  Most of these gaps
      were filled with CDS data.  Out of the maximum possible number
      of frequency measurements of 5,174 covering the period of lock
      (3,458.31 seconds), 5,015 were obtained.  None of the missing
      points are consecutive so the largest gap is 4/3 second.
 
      At approximately 10 locations in the frequency profile, a null
      frequency measurement is observed.  This is due to a timing
      mismatch between the RRH and the orbiter.  Occasionally the
      orbiter will look for a frequency in an RRH buffer before the
      frequency has been placed in the buffer.  The null
      measurements, resulting from a sampling period that is slightly
      longer than 2/3 seconds, occur approximately every 340 seconds.
      A portion of the SDR frequency data with the null measurement
      is shown below:
 
 REC1.DAT  RRH DATA --11/20/92-- PLL MODE ONLY
    HHMMSS.SSS  SFM  SFI  SFL  FREQC    FREQ(Hz)    FTIME (SEC) RS FREQ
                                                                 (Hz)
295 155339 798  048  098  242  3171058. 430229.321  196.667  430229.3209
296 160019 767  048  098  199  3171015. 430223.487  197.334  430223.4870
297 160659 731  048  098  157  3170973. 430217.789  198.000  430217.7887
298 161339 701  048  098  113  3170929. 430211.819  198.667  430211.8190
299 162019 670  048  098  068  3170884. 430205.714  199.334  430205.7137
300 162659 634  048  098  017  3170833. 430198.794  200.000  430198.7944
301 163339 599  000  000  000        0.       .000  200.667        .0000
301 164019 567  048  097  221  3170781. 430191.739  201.334  430191.7393
302 164659 530  048  097  176  3170736. 430185.634  202.000  430185.6340
303 165339 495  048  097  127  3170687. 430178.986  202.667  430178.9860
 
      A simple method of treating this discontinuity is to remove the
      null frequency and recalculate the times.  For example, the
      first point above is 196.667 seconds, the last is at 202.667
      seconds.  In this interval there are 9 valid frequency
      measurements.  While the frequencies are unchanged, the
      corresponding times for each of the nine frequencies (for this
      example) are 196.667 + (n-1)*delta t where n=1,2,3,...9 and
      delta t is (202.667-196.667)/(n-1) = 0.75 seconds.  This
      results in the listed frequencies (not including the null
      measurement) at times 196.667, 197.417, 198.167, 198.917,
      199.667, 200.417, 201.167, 201.917, 202.667.  The choice of 9
      points is arbitrary.  This averaging of n measurements over n+1
      time points results in a shift in the apparent time of each
      frequency measurement of a fraction of a second.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

