<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.vg2-n-pls-5-rdr-elemagsphere-96sec-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>VG2 NEP PLS DERIVED RDR ELECTRON MAGNETOSPHERE 96SEC V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.comet_sl9-jupiter_collision::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.voyager::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vg2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:pls.vg2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.neptune::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vg2-n-pls-5-rdr-elemagsphere-96sec-v1.0__browserp_vg2-n-pls-5-rdr-elemagsphere-96sec-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Belcher, J.W., et al, Plasma Observations at Neptune:
                   Initial results from Voyager 2, Science, 246, 1478-1483,
                   1989.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BELCHERETAL1991</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Zhang, M., J.D. Richardson, and E.C. Sittler, Jr.,
                   Voyager 2 Electron Observations in the magnetosphere
                   of Neptune, J. Geophys. Res., in press, 1991.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ZHANGETAL1991A</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>VG2-N-PLS-5-RDR-ELEMAGSPHERE-96SEC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>VG2 NEP PLS DERIVED RDR ELECTRON MAGNETOSPHERE 96SEC V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1991-07-22</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1989-08-24T14:38:00.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1989-08-25T09:23:00.000Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JOHN D. RICHARDSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            VG2 NEP PLS DERIVED RDR ELECTRON MAGNETOSPHERE 96SEC V1.0
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The electron spectra are fit using several isotropic Maxwellian
            distribution functions to find electron parameters. The
            spacecraft charge may seriously affect the density measurements.
            The temperature of each component is, however, independent of the
            spacecraft potential. To obtain the best estimate of the electron
            density, the encounter period is divided into four regions and
            four different analysis methods are used.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The electron spectra are fit using several isotropic Maxwellian
      distribution functions to find electron parameters.  The
      spacecraft charge may seriously affect the density
      measurements.  The temperature of each component is, however,
      independent of the spacecraft potential.  To obtain the best
      estimate of the electron density, the encounter period is
      divided into four regions and four different analysis methods
      are used.
 
      In the time period from 1989-08-24T14:38:04.130 (236.60977) to
      1989-08-24T19:45:17.571 (236.82312), when the spacecraft is in
      the inbound magnetosheath and is probably positively charged, a
      program written by Sittler (1987) is used to derive the
      electron density and temperature.  The spacecraft potential is
      calculated using Scudder&apos;s (1981) return current-spacecraft
      potential relation.  Estimates of the formal errors are not
      performed in Sittler&apos;s program.  Since the electrons are hot in
      this region, we are confident of the results.
 
      In the time periods from 1989-08-24T22:46:35.334 (236.94902) to
      1989-08-24T23:32:12.481 (236.98070) and from
      1989-08-25T08:09:47.233 (237.34013) to 1989-08-25T09:23:24.001
      (237.39125), when the spacecraft is in hot plasma regions, all
      the electron parameters are derived from fits to the electron
      spectra.  Again, we are confident of the results.
 
      In the regions where a cold electron component is present in
      the spectra (1989-08-24T23:35:23.424 (236.98291) to
      1989-08-25T00:35:23.712 (237.02458) and from
      1989-08-25T04:33:48.095 (237.19014) to 1989-08-25T08:02:35.233
      (237.33513), the spacecraft is negatively charged and the
      density calculation is seriously affected by spacecraft
      charging.  The total ion density from the PLS ion measurements
      and the condition of charge neutrality are used to estimate the
      spacecraft potential.  The true density of each electron
      component is equal to d0*exp(-Vsc/T), where d0 is the density
      from the fits assuming a zero spacecraft potential, Vsc is the
      spacecraft potential and T is the temperature of that
      component.  Uncertainties in the electron density should thus
      mainly determined by the ion density calculation.  However,
      electron temperature calculations are not affected by the
      spacecraft charging, so they are quite accurate.
 
      In the time period from 1989-08-25T00:45:47.520 (237.03180) to
      1989-08-25T02:42:02.592 (237.11253), the cold component is
      below the threshold the PLS measurement.  A temperature of 3 eV
      is assumed for the cold component.  The spacecraft potential is
      not available, so is set equal to zero.  The parameters of the
      hot electron components are obtained directly from the fits.
      The cold electron density is then set equal to the total ion
      density minus the hot electron density.  In this region the
      results have large error bars.
 
      In the region near closest approach (1989-08-25T04:11:23.712
      (237.17458) to 1989-08-25T04:25:34.752 (237.18443), where the
      loss-cone effect is prominent, the density of each component is
      equal to d0*ditot/detot, where d0 is the density of the
      component calculated from the fits, ditot is the total ion
      density, detot is the total electron density from the fits.
 
      Zhang, M., J. D.  Richardson, and E. C.  Sittler, Jr., Voyager
      2 electron observations in the Magnetosphere of Neptune, J.
      Geophys.  Res., in press, 1991.
 
      J. W.  Belcher, H. S.  Bridge, et al., Plasma Observations Near
      Neptune: Initial Results from Voyager 2, Science, 246,
      1478-1483, 1989.
 
      Scudder, J.  D., E. C.  Sittler, Jr.  and H. S.  Bridge, A
      survey of the plasma electron environment of Jupiter: a view
      from Voyager, J. Geophys.  Res., 86, 8319-8342, 1981.
 
      Sittler, E.  C., Jr., K. W.  Ogilvie and R. S.  Selesnick,
      Survey of electrons in the Uranian magnetosphere: Voyager 2
      observations, J. Geophys.  Res., 92, 15,263-15,281, 1987.
 
      Processing Level Id            : 5
      Software Flag                  : Y
      Processing Stop Time           : UNK
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;ELECTRON DENSITY&apos;
      -------------------------------------
        A derived parameter equaling the number of electrons per unit
        volume over a specified range of electron energy.  Different
        forms of electron density are derived distinguished by method
        of derivation (Maxwellian fit, method of moments) or by the
        some selection criteria (ie., hot electron and cold electron
        density).  In general, if more than one electron component is
        analyzed, either by moment or fit, a total density will be
        provided which is the sum of the electron densities.  If the
        electron do not have a Maxwellian distribution the actual
        distribution can be represented as the sum of several
        Maxwellians, in which case the density of each Maxwellian is
        given.
 
        Data Set Parameter Name        : ELECTRON DENSITY
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : CM**-3
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : UNK
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : UNK
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : UNK
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : UNK
        Noise Level                    : UNK
 
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;ELECTRON TEMPERATURE&apos;
      -----------------------------------------
        A derived parameter giving an indication of the mean
        energy/electron, assuming the shape of the electron energy
        spectrum to be Maxwellian (i.e.highest entropy shape).  Given
        that the electron energy spectrum is not exactly Maxwellian,
        the electron temperature can be defined integrally (whereby
        the mean energy obtained by integrating under the actual
        electron energy spectrum is set equal to the integral under a
        Maxwellian, where the temperature is a free parameter for
        which to solve), or differentially (whereby the slopes of the
        actually electron energy spectrum at various energies are
        matched to the slopes of a corresponding Maxwellian).  The
        temperature parameter is often qualified with a range of
        applicable energies.  temperatures can be angularly
        anisotropic.  If the electrons do not have a Maxwellian
        distribution the actual distribution can be represented as
        the sum of several Maxwellians, each with a separate
        temperature.
 
        Data Set Parameter Name        : ELECTRON TEMPERATURE
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : CM**-3
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : UNK
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : UNK
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : UNK
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : UNK
        Noise Level                    : UNK
 
 
    Source Instrument Parameters
    ============================
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : ELECTRON DENSITY
      Instrument Parameter Name       : ELECTRON RATE
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : ELECTRON DENSITY
      Instrument Parameter Name       : ELECTRON CURRENT
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : ELECTRON TEMPERATURE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : ELECTRON RATE
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : ELECTRON TEMPERATURE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : ELECTRON CURRENT
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      Processing History
      ------------------
        Source Data Set ID          : N/A
        Software                    : UNK
        Product Data Set ID         :
                             VG2-N-PLS-5-RDR-ELEMAGSPHERE-96SEC-V1.0
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      The electron parameters are reliable except near closest
      approach where the electrons are cold.  In the time period
      between 237.03180 and 237.11253, the cold component is below
      the threshold the PLS measurement.  A temperature of 3 eV is
      assumed for the cold component.  The spacecraft potential is
      not determined and is set equal to zero.  The parameters of the
      hot electron components are obtained directly from the fits and
      are reliable.  The cold electron density is set equal to the
      total ion density minus the hot electron density.  In this
      region the results have large error bars.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XM-11A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

