<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ody-m-grs-5-and-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 5 AND V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.2001_mars_odyssey::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.ody::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:grs.ody::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-grs-5-and-v1.0__browserp_geo_ody-m-grs-5-and-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-grs-5-and-v1.0__dvo_geo_ody-m-grs-5-and-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-grs-5-and-v1.0__pds.ua.grs_web_site::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Boynton, W. V., W. C. Feldman, I. Mitrofanov, L. G. Evans, R. C. Reedy, S.
                   W. Squyres, R. Starr, I. Trombka, C. d&apos;Uston, J. R. Arnold, P. A. J.
                   Englert, A. E. Metzger, H. Wanke, J. Bruckner, D. M. Drake, C. Shinohara,
                   C. Fellows, D. K. Hamara, K. Harshman, The Mars Odyssey gamma-ray
                   spectrometer instrument suite, Space Sci. Rev., 110 (1-2): 37-83, 2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BOYNTONETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Feldman, W.C., T.H. Prettyman, R. L. Tokar, W.V. Boynton, R. C. Byrd, K.R.
                   Fuller, O. Gasnault, J.L. Longmire, R.H. Olsher, S.A. Storms, and G.W.
                   Thornton, Fast neutron flux spectrum aboard Mars Odyssey during cruise, J.
                   Geophys. Res. - Space Physics, v. 107(#A6) p. 1083, 2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FELDMANETAL2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Planetary Data System Standards Reference, JPL Document D-7669, Part 2, Jet
                   Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PDSSR2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Prettyman, T. H., W. C. Feldman, M. T. Mellon, G. W. McKinney, W. V.
                   Boynton, S. Karunatillae, D. J. Lawrence, S. Maurice, A. E. Metzger, J. R.
                   Murphy, S. W. Squyres, R. D. Starr, R. L. Tokar, and the 2001 Mars Odyssey
                   Gamma Ray Spectrometer Science Team, Composition and structure of the
                   Martian surface in the high southern latitudes from neutron spectroscopy,
                   J. Geophys. Res. - Planets, submitted 2003.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PRETTYMANETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Seidelmann, P.K., V.K. Abalakin, M. Bursa, M.E. Davies, C. de Bergh, J.H.
                   Lieske, J. Oberst, J.L. Simon, E.M. Standish, P. Stooke, and P.C. Thomas,
                   Report of the IAU/IAG working group on cartographic coordinates and rotational
                   elements of the planets and satellites: 2000, Celestial Mechanics and Dynamical
                   Astronomy, 82, 83-111, 2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SEIDELMANNETAL2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>ODY-M-GRS-5-AND-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 5 AND V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2004-07-08</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2002-02-19T00:00:00.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2004-01-06T00:00:00.000Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>WILLIAM BOYNTON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Boynton, W.V., Mars 2001 Odyssey Gamma Ray Spectrometer Averaged
            Neutron Data V1.0, ODY-M-GRS-5-AND-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2003.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Averaged neutron data from the Neutron Spectrometer in the
            Odyssey GRS instrument suite.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 5 AND data set is a table of
            neutron data from the NS sub-system of the Mars Odyssey Gamma-Ray
            Spectrometer that have been averaged (AND) over 5-degree latitude
            by 5-degree longitude spatial grids and 15-degrees of aerocentric
            solar longitude (Ls). The AND are an intermediate data product.
            These data are calculated from the derived neutron data (DND) and
            result in maps of thermal,epithermal, and fast neutron counting
            rates.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The Mars Odyssey Gamma-Ray Spectrometer (GRS) is a suite of
    three instruments working together to collect data that will
    permit the mapping of elemental concentrations on the surface
    of Mars. The suite of three instruments, the gamma sensor head
    (GS), the neutron spectrometer (NS) and the high-energy neutron
    detector (HEND), are a complimentary set of instruments in that
    the neutron instruments have better counting statistics and
    sample to a greater depth than the GS, but the GS determines
    the abundance of many more elements. A full description of the
    Mars Odyssey Gamma-Ray Spectrometer instrument can be found in
    [BOYNTONETAL2004].
 
    The ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 5 AND data set is a table
    of neutron data from the NS sub-system of the Mars Odyssey
    Gamma-Ray Spectrometer that have been averaged (AND) over 5-
    degree latitude by 5-degree longitude spatial grids and 15-
    degrees of aerocentric solar longitude (Ls). The AND are an
    intermediate data product. These data are calculated from the
    derived neutron data (DND) and result in maps of thermal,
    epithermal, and fast neutron counting rates.
 
    The GRS collects a new spectrum (pixel) approximately every 20
    seconds, 360 times per orbit. Approximately 4200 neutron
    measurements are expected to be received every day. The data
    are downloaded from the spacecraft by the Jet Propulsion
    Laboratory (JPL) into the Telemetry Data System (TDS). The TDS
    sends data to a process that translates data packets and
    examines instrument health via messages. Data are output to a
    spooler that passes it to the University of Arizona (UA)
    database ingest process. The ingest process inputs raw data
    into the UA database. Neutron data are processed by Los Alamos
    National Laboratory through a number of programs to yield the
    DND from which the AND are determined.
 
    The AND is intended to be the second intermediate data product
    available for the NS portion of the GRS data. This data should
    be useful to those scientists who are experienced in neutron
    spectroscopy.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The averaged neutron data set (AND) is composed of a single
    data type. The objective of compiling the AND is to create a
    table of neutron counting data from the DND time series. Each
    AND product data file will contain a table of neutron counting
    rates (counts per second) averaged over 5-degree latitude by
    5-degree longitude spatial grids and 15-degrees of Ls, the
    number of 20-second collection intervals that have been
    averaged, and the standard deviation in counts per second of
    the counting rate for each average. Each spatial grid
    corresponds to one row in the table. The first 72 rows in the
    table are the data for the 5 degree latitude band centered at
    87.5 degrees north latitude, the second 72 rows are the data
    for the band centered at 82.5 degrees north latitude, et
    cetera. Within each latitude band, longitude increases eastward
    from the cell centered at 2.5 degrees east longitude to the
    cell centered at 357.5 degrees  east longitude. AND data files
    will be labeled by the beginning and ending Ls values.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The products of the neutron data reduction algorithms are a
    time-series data set (DND), corrected for variations in the
    instrument response and the cosmic ray background, that
    can be used to produce thermal, epithermal, and fast neutron
    global maps of Mars. Tables of temporally and spatially
    averaged counting rates (AND) are also provided. The AND data
    set consists of maps of thermal, epithermal, and fast neutron
    counting rates averaged over 15-degree Ls intervals. The maps
    are 5-degree cylindrical projections. In addition to the
    counting rates, maps of the number of measurements binned in
    each pixel and the standard deviation of the pixel counting
    rates are provided.
 
    A summary of these algorithms adapted from Appendix A of
    PRETTYMANETAL2004] is provided here. See [Neutron
    Spectrometer Processing V.1.1] for details of the neutron data
    reduction process. See [FELDMANETAL2002] and [BOYNTONETAL2004] for
    details of the neutron spectrometer design and operation.
 
    The neutron spectrometer consists of a block of boron-loaded
    plastic that is diagonally segmented into four optically
    decoupled prisms that are viewed by separate photomultiplier
    tubes. During mapping, two of the prisms are aligned along the
    axis of motion of the spacecraft: Prism 2 (P2) faces in the
    forward direction and Prism 4 (P4) faces opposite to the
    direction of motion. The remaining two prisms are oriented
    along the nadir axis: Prism 1 (P1) faces downward towards Mars
    and Prism 3 (P3) faces upwards towards the spacecraft. P1 is
    covered with cadmium foil, which absorbs neutrons below roughly
    0.5 eV. Consequently, P1 is sensitive to epithermal neutrons.
 
    Raw (EDR) neutron data, including spectra, histogram, and
    events arrays, are processed through several automated programs
    to yield normalized neutron counting rates for all four of the
    NS prisms, from which thermal, epithermal, and fast neutron
    counting rates are determined.
 
    The first step in the neutron processing is the determination
    of the 10B(n,alpha) peak centroid and the after-pulse
    threshold of each prism averaged over a course time window 720
    collection intervals in length. This information is used
    subsequently by algorithms that determine the area of the
    10B(n, alpha) peak for each prism for each 19.75s interval The
    10B(n,alpha) peak centroid is determined using double pulse
    events (Category-2 events), which are primarily a result of
    interactions of fast neutrons with the spectrometer. Fast
    neutrons are identified by the detection of a characteristic
    double pulse. The light output caused by proton recoils
    produced by the prompt interaction of a fast neutron and the
    hydrogen in the plastic provides a measure of the energy of
    the incident neutron. A second pulse of light corresponding to
    the absorption of the neutron at low energy by 10B follows a
    delay in which the neutron is slowing down in the plastic, but
    does not produce light. This double-pulse signature occurs for
    neutrons above approximately 700 keV.
 
    Category-2 event mode data (EDR EVENTS_ARRAY) are accumulated
    over a coarse time window containing 720 19.75s intervals. The
    overload counts (EDR GCR_CNT) are monitored and events are
    discarded for intervals for which the overload counts exceed a
    user-defined threshold, currently set at 7000. For each time
    window, the second event spectrum is constructed from the
    accumulated event-mode data. If the number of accepted
    intervals is less than 360, then the time window is not
    analyzed and the window is assigned the results for centroid
    and threshold from the analysis of the previous window.
 
    The second event spectrum acquired for each window is analyzed
    by simultaneously fitting two normal distributions (one for the
    10B peak and one for the after-pulse peak) and a constant
    background (to represent the continuum) to the data. The
    fitting algorithm minimizes the sum of the squares of the
    difference between the model and the data weighted by the
    statistical uncertainty in the counting data i.e., a weighted
    least squares fit to the data. The weighted least squares fit
    yields the peak centroids, the highest of which is taken as the
    10B peak, the full width at half maximum, and the after-pulse
    threshold, which is taken to be the channel for which the model
    is minimum between the two centroids. For a more complete
    description see Neutron Spectrometer Processing V1.1 in the
    documents directory that accompanies this release. The peak
    centroid determined by this process is used subsequently to
    make gain corrections in the next processing step, which is
    evaluation of the Category 1 single event spectrum.
 
    Thermal and epithermal neutrons are detected through the
    10B(n,alpha)7Li* reaction, which produces a distinct peak in
    the pulse-height spectrum caused by the deposition of the
    recoil energy of the reaction products in the scintillator.
    This peak corresponds to an equivalent electron energy of 93
    keV. For each prism, the net counting rate for this peak was
    determined from the Category-1 pulse-height spectrum, a
    spectrum of single-interaction events that is recorded every
    19.75 s. During this measurement interval, the spacecraft
    traverses approximately one degree of arc length (roughly 60
    km). Determination of peak areas for each prism from the
    Category-1 spectra involved several steps summarized here:
 
    1) A correction was applied to each spectrum to remove
    artifacts of the differential nonlinearity of the analog to
    digital converter from the spectrum.
 
    2) The spectra were corrected in gain so that the 93 keV peak
       always fell in Channel 11. Implementation of this step
       required knowledge of the original peak location determined
       from the second interaction spectrum. The gain correction
       enabled the same region of interest (range of energy) to be
       used for the peak and background for all spectra.
 
    3) For each prism, selected channels surrounding the peak
       above and below were fitted to a power law.  The power law was
       determined for spectra in a sliding window 5 x 19.75 s in
       length. The length of the window was selected empirically to
       minimize the uncertainty in the background parameters because
       of statistical variations in counting rate while avoiding the
       introduction of bias resulting from integration over surface
       features.
 
    4) The peak areas (counts in the peaks for each prism) were
       determined for each 19.75 s spectrum by subtracting the
       background predicted by the power law from the total counts in
       the peak region of interest.
 
    The thermal-neutron counting rate was determined by subtracting
    the peak area for the backward-looking prism (P4) from that of
    the forward-looking prism (P2). During the mapping phase, the
    spacecraft traveled in a circular polar orbit at an average
    altitude of 400 km and speed of 3380 meters per second. A
    significant portion of the population of thermal neutrons at
    orbital altitudes had speeds much less than that of the
    spacecraft and the flux of low-energy neutrons incident on the
    exposed face of P2 was much higher than that of P4. If the
    return of neutrons from the spacecraft is neglected, both
    prisms should receive the same contribution from epithermal
    neutrons. Consequently, subtraction of P4 from P2 yielded a
    response that was representative of the thermal-neutron
    population. The epithermal-neutron counting rate was taken to
    be the counting rate for P1, which was shielded from thermal
    neutrons by a Cd foil. Note that based on an analysis of cruise
    data, the cosmic-ray-induced background for Category-1 counting
    rates for P1, P2, and P4 was found to be consistent with zero.
 
    For fast neutrons, two data products are provided in the raw
    data set: Event-mode data for which the magnitude of the first
    pulse, time to the second pulse, and magnitude of the second
    pulse of a selected number of events (84 per 19.75 s
    acquisition period) were recorded; and histogram data for which
    first pulses with magnitude above a preset, fixed threshold
    were binned into histograms for early and late time windows.
    The late time interval (nominally chosen to be between 20 and
    25 microseconds) was selected so that it is well beyond the
    die-away time of neutrons in the spectrometer and thus contains
    accidental events only. The early time interval (nominally
    chosen to be between 0.4 and 5.4 microseconds) was selected so
    that it is sensitive to neutrons slowing down in the
    spectrometer. Subtraction of the late from early time
    histograms yields a pulse-height spectrum that is sensitive to
    the energy spectrum of fast neutrons.
 
    The fast-neutron counting rate was taken to be the first two
    channels of the histogram spectrum for P1, which is primarily
    sensitive to neutrons coming directly from Mars. The lower
    channels were selected because they give the greatest count
    rates and are also least susceptible to contamination by
    after-pulsing. However, because considerable drift in gain
    occurred, the threshold selected for after-pulse suppression
    used to construct the histogram data was not always effective.
    During times of high gain, the threshold was too low and
    after-pulsing events contaminated the histogram spectrum.
    Variations caused by shifts in gain were corrected using the
    BellyBand algorithm described below.
 
    Neutron counting rates are sensitive to a number of factors
    unrelated to the surface and atmosphere of Mars. These
    include, for example, instrument drift and variations in the
    galactic cosmic-ray flux. To eliminate these variations from
    our data set, we developed an algorithm to adjust our
    time-series counting data so that counting rates at equatorial
    latitudes did not change with time and were equal to the
    average counting rates observed over a normalization interval,
    which was arbitrarily selected to be from LS equals 329 degrees
    to LS equals 131 degrees. The region between latitudes plus to
    minus 30 degrees (the belly band) was used for normalization.
    Minor variations in counting rate due to seasonal changes in
    atmospheric mass were initially ignored, but were later
    restored to the time series.
 
    The belly-band normalization algorithm removes gain and offset
    variations caused by a number of effects, including variations
    in the galactic cosmic-ray background and errors in the
    Category 1 background subtraction algorithm, with a linear
    correction (CAT1_PRISMX_NORM_SLOPE, CAT1_PRISMX_NORM_OFFSET)
    However, the normalization algorithm also removes variations
    that would otherwise be present as a result of seasonal changes
    in atmospheric mass at the equator. To restore the effect of
    atmospheric mass, we combined maps of atmospheric mass at
    equatorial latitudes (derived from the ARC-GCM) with
    expressions for counting rate as a function of atmospheric
    thickness [PRETTYMANETAL2004] to determine the relative
    variation of belly-band-averaged neutron-counting rates
    as a function of time. The normalized counting rates were
    then multiplied by the relative variation to restore the
    atmospheric effect. Use of pressures from the ARC-GCM is
    justified because the ARC-GCM fits the Viking 1 and 2
    landing-site pressure data that are representative of
    equatorial to midlatitude pressure variations and were found
    to be reproducible year after year. This procedure was applied
    to the fast and epithermal counting data that show the largest
    effect. Thermal neutrons vary negligibly with atmospheric mass
    when the water abundance of the surface is less than about 15
    percent, which is representative of the belly band. The fast
    neutrons, which have the largest variation, show a 5 percent
    peak-to-peak variation in counting rate over an entire Martian
    year. Therefore, the correction is relatively minor.
 
    Averaged neutron counting rates are produced from the derived
    (background subtracted, normalized) neutron counting rates. A
    summing algorithm is used to bin and combine thermal,
    epithermal, and fast neutron counting data both spatially and
    temporally. The spatial constraint is variable, but will be set
    at 5-degrees latitude by 5-degrees longitude bins for the AND
    records. In order to be grouped within a particular 5-degree
    bin, the latitude and longitude must be greater than or equal
    to the lower limit and less than the upper limit. The thermal
    data are assigned latitudes and longitudes that are shifted by
    4.5 degrees along the spacecraft trajectory from the
    sub-satellite point. Similarly, the epithermal data are
    assigned locations that are shifted by 1 degree along the
    trajectory. The temporal constraint on the AND product is
    variable, but will be constrained for the PDS to be 15-degrees
    of Mars Ls. The 15-degree periods are called seasons by the GRS
    Team.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The AND data set is composed of a 24 data tables per Mars year.
    Each data table will contain 2592 rows of data.
 
 
    Averaged Neutron Data
    ---------------------
      Averaged Neutron Data are composed of the averaged neutron
      data and the associated timing, and spatial information for
      each 5-degree latitude by 5-degree longitude spatial and
      15-degree Ls temporal interval. The averaged neutron data
      consists of 11 columns of data that are output from the AND
      processing for each spatial and temporal cell. The timing and
      spatial data provided with the AND includes center points of
      the spatial cell  and the beginning and ending times that
      data was averaged over.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    None at this time.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
   The coordinate system used for all GRS data is a Mars
   aerocentric system following the IAU convention
   [SEIDELMANNETAL2002], with east longitudes from 0 to 360.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    A library of source code to parse the AND data product files
    is included in the software directory. This library allows a
    programmer to build applications that display or manipulate
    AND data. This source is written in the Java language, and
    requires version 1.3 of the Java Runtime Environment (JRE) or
    Java Software Development Kit (SDK).
 
    Documentation for the code is located in the software directory
    in the file GRS_CODE_DOC.ZIP. The contents of this file are
    described in the label GRS_CODE_DOC.LBL and the source and
    the binary classes that make up the library are in the file
    DR_CODE.JAR.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    The AND will be delivered using CDROM media. Formats will be
    based on standards for such products established by the
    Planetary Data System (PDS) [PDSSR2001].
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The data presented in the AND is intended to be the second
    intermediate data set released for the neutron spectrometer
    sub-system of the GRS. Data presented here are a highly
    processed representation of the neutron data as received from
    the spacecraft. It is possible that changes will be made in the
    neutron processing algorithms if errors are found. If errors
    are found, the data will have to be regenerated from the DND
    data set.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    The AND was reviewed internally by the GRS team prior to
    release to the PDS. PDS will also perform an external peer
    review of the AND.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    Data presented in the AND product is by definition, i.e.
    inclusion in the DND data set, &apos;good&apos;.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    The major limitation of this data set is that it is averaged
    from the derived neutron data. The validity of the derived
    neutron data is based on the &apos;correctness&apos; of each step in the
    processing. It is possible that changes will be made in the
    neutron data processing if errors are found. If errors are
    found, the data will have to be regenerated from the newly
    processed derived neutron data set.
 
 
  Data Compression
  ===============
  No compression is used on the AND data set.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

