<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mro-m-hirise-2-edr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MRO MARS HIGH RESOLUTION IMAGE SCIENCE EXPERIMENT EDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:hirise.mro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-hirise-2-edr-v1.0__browserp_mro-m-hirise-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-hirise-2-edr-v1.0__browser_geo_mars_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-hirise-2-edr-v1.0__dvo_imaging_mro-m-hirise-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Eliason, E., HiRISE EDR &amp; RDR Archive Volumes Software Interface Specification,
                   JPL Document Number D-32005, NASA Planetary Data System, 2006.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ELIASON2006B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Eliason, E., Castalia, B., Leis, R., Becker, K., Software Interface
                   Specification for HiRISE Experimental Data Record Products, JPL Document Number
                   D-32004, NASA Planetary Data System, 2006.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ELIASONETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MRO-M-HIRISE-2-EDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MRO MARS HIGH RESOLUTION IMAGE SCIENCE EXPERIMENT EDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2006-09-29T15:16:33.333Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>ALFRED MCEWEN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            McEwen, A., Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter High Resolution Imaging
            Science Experiment, Experiment Data Record,
            MRO-M-HIRISE-2-EDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2007.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Experimental data records for MRO HiRISE (High Resolution Imaging
            Science Experiment).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set includes the Experimental Data Records from the
            HiRISE instrument on MRO. These products are the permanent record
            of the raw images obtained by the HiRISE Instrument and contain
            the properties of unprocessed and unrectified imaging maintaining
            the original spacecraft viewing orientation and optical
            distortion properties. .
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    These Experimental Data Record (EDR) products are the permanent
    record of the raw images obtained by the HiRISE Instrument.  The
    products contain the properties of unprocessed and unrectified
    imaging maintaining the original spacecraft viewing orientation
    and optical distortion properties. As part of the EDR generation
    process, FELICS- compressed images are decompressed and organized
    as raster images.  EDRs are organized at the channel level with
    two EDRs needed for each operating CCD. As many as 28 EDR products
    are needed to capture a single HiRISE observation. Maintaining an
    archive of EDR products enables reprocessing of the raw science
    observations as calibration and geometry processing routines
    improve.  Investigators interested in applying advanced
    calibration methods or needing to understand the properties of the
    raw imaging will find the EDRs a useful product. However, most
    science investigators will be interested in using the RDR products
    as geometry and radiometric processing has occurred on
    these products.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    EDR product creation is the resposibility of the HiRISE Operations
    Center (HiROC) at the Lunar and Planetary Laboratory, University
    of Arizona. The products are generated by an automated pipeline
    process called EDRgen. The pipeline is managed by the Conductor
    software (http://pirl.lpl.arizona.edu/software/Conductor.shtml) on
    as many HiROC systems simultaneously as seem appropriate to
    achieve the throughput and reliability needed to meet the HiRISE
    data production requirements. When the HiROC system detects that a
    new HiRISE observation data channel file is available at the JPL
    data distribution site it is automatically downloaded using the
    JPL File Exchange Interface (FEI) and the file is registered in
    the HiCat database as an EDRgen source ready for processing. A raw
    data file may also be manually submitted for processing, or
    reprocessing, by a HiROC operator.
 
    Each observation data channel file is subject to automated data
    verification. This includes consistency checks of data values and
    identification of spacecraft downlink data gaps noted in a JPL
    ground data system transaction log provided (and also
    automatically delivered) for each observation. Consistency checks
    include comparing the commanding parameters in the observation
    headers with the uplink commanding stored in the HiCat database.
    Other checks involve comparing the values against permitted values
    and ranges. Files with any data verification problems are
    automatically routed to a special processing pipeline of EDRgen.
    Here header data redundancy for an observation, and the original
    observation definition from the HiCat database, will be used to
    produce a PDS label with the best representation of the
    observation characteristics in the EDR product file. The inability
    to generate an acceptable PDS label is a failure condition that is
    automatically brought to the attention of a HiROC operator. The
    downlinked data will never be changed (except for FELICS
    decompression and even channel image data mirroring) and remains
    available in the EDR product file. All EDR data products are
    automatically queued for validation. Validation of a data product
    involves visual inspection by an operator and check-off against a
    set of acceptance criteria that are recorded in the HiCat
    database. The successful processing of an observation data channel
    file by EDRgen results in a PDS compliant EDR data product file
    and the update of the HiCat database with appropriate metadata
    from its ODL (Object Descriptor Language) label.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The format of the EDR data products is nearly identical to the
    original form of the data stream as produced by the instrument.
    Some processing was applied to the data for (1) FELICS
    decompressing an image (if the data were optionally compressed on
    the spacecraft), (2) identifying and filling gaps with &apos;no-data&apos;
    values, (3) mirroring the pixel order of an image line for data
    read out in reverse order for channel 1 products only, and (4)
    adding a PDS label to the beginning of the file.
 
    The EDR products are processed to NASA data processing level-0.
    (This corresponds to level 2 for the Committee on Data Management
    and Computation (CODMAC) data level numbering system). NASA level-
    0 products contain time-ordered raw instrument science data at
    full resolution with duplicate data removed and transmission
    anomalies identified and corrected whenever possible.
 
    An EDR is identified and described with PDS-labeling conventions
    with a PDS label located at the beginning of the file. Following
    the PDS label is the instrument data stream organized as objects
    each described by keywords in the PDS label area. The data objects
    store the raw image data and ancillary data needed to understand
    and process the image. The data objects contained in the EDR
    product were created by the HiRISE instrument flight software and
    remain in the original format except as noted above.
 
    The objects, describing various parts of the data stream, are
    summarized here.   Pointer  keywords in the PDS label, identified
    with a carat (^) as the first character, locate the objects in the
    file. The SCIENCE_CHANNEL_TABLE, LOOKUP_TABLE, and
    CPMM_ENGINEERING_TABLE objects contain metadata providing
    commanding, engineering, and instrument operating information
    related to the observation. The LINE_PREFIX_TABLE and
    LINE_SUFFIX_TABLE objects contain engineering and calibration data
    accompanying the observational data. The CALIBRATION_IMAGE
    contains image data useful for calibrating the instrument.  The
    IMAGE object contains the observational image data. The GAP_TABLE
    locates gaps (missing data) in the observation.
 
    Gaps consisting of missing data in the observation data stream can
    occur whenever there is an interruption in the downlink
    communications systems between the MRO spacecraft and the MRO
    operations center at JPL. Data gaps in the HiRISE EDR products can
    be identified in two ways. First, the GAP_TABLE object identifies
    the data gap locations in the EDR products. The GAP_TABLE is a
    binary table of two columns that specify the starting and ending
    byte location of each gap. There is a row for each gap (see the
    PDS example label in section 6.1 for a label description of the
    GAP_TABLE). Additionally, gaps can be identified in the data by
    searching for consecutive bytes with the hexadecimal value FF
    (decimal 255). A gap is identified as any byte sequence
    containing more than four consecutive  FF  values. HiRISE 8-bit
    image pixels with the hexadecimal value  FF  will be a missing
    pixel. For 16-bit pixel data, the hexadecimal value  FFFF
    identifies the pixel as missing. This is a reliable test because
    the HiRISE instrument can never create a  FF  8-bit pixel or a
    FFFF  16-bit pixel.
 
 
  Time Standards
  ==============
    Two time-related standards are used in HiRISE EDR PDS labels:
    o  Spacecraft clock;
    o  Coordinated Universal time (UTC).
 
    The spacecraft clock (SCLK) is the fundamental system on MRO for
    initiating spacecraft events (such as starting an observation for
    one of the instruments). The SCLK has a counting unit of 1/(216)
    seconds for each tick of its sub-seconds field. Thus there are
    65,536 SCLK ticks per second (a time interval of 15.2588
    microseconds).
 
    The HiRISE expose-time command initiated by the spacecraft
    contains     both the SCLK seconds and sub-seconds fields of that
    future moment in time at which the HiRISE exposure should begin.
    The HiRISE software will compute and store the corresponding
    future instant (converting SCLK sub-seconds notation to that of
    the HiRISE notation) at which time the exposure should begin. The
    HiRISE flight software will then set a 50-millisecond exposure-
    start software timer. Each time the expose-start timer elapses
    (every 50 milliseconds), the HiRISE flight software will check the
    current HiRISE time against the time at which  the exposure should
    begin, and will start the exposure the first time it sees that
    current HiRISE time is later in time than the exposure time. The
    HiRISE flight software will time-stamp the actual start of an
    exposure (placed in the science channel header) to within 50
    milliseconds of the actual start of the exposure. This time stamp,
    as well as all the other time stamps which the HiRISE flight
    software produces, will all be in units of the HiRISE clock (i.e.
    with the sub- seconds field counting in units of 16 milliseconds).
    HiROC ground data processing converts to SCLK units when computing
    the time at which various time-stamped HiRISE events occurred. The
    instrument sub- second field is converted back to the SCLK sub-
    second field and stored in the PDS labels. This conversion occurs
    in order to allow the SPICE NAIF toolkit (see http://pds-
    naif.jpl.nasa.gov/) to be used to process time fields. UTC times
    can be derived from the SCLK using the NAIF toolkit time routines
    and the SCLK kernel maintained by the MRO
    project.
 
 
  Data Storage Conventions
  ========================
    The HiRISE EDR products contain binary data. Image pixel values
    are stored as either unsigned 8-bit or unsigned 16-bit pixel
    values depending on the operating mode of the instrument. The PDS
    label sections are stored as ASCII character strings conforming to
    the requirements defined in the PDS Standards Reference. The
    storage order is most significant byte (MSB) first. MSB ordering
    is the order used on the MRO spacecraft and the HiRISE instrument.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
 
  This is a TBD data set.  Known problems are TBD.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    This archival data set has been examined by a peer review panel
    and has been accepted by the Planetary Data System (PDS). The peer
    review will be conducted in accordance with PDS
    procedures.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    EDR products are the permanennt record of raw and unprocessed
    images stored in a raster format as described by the IMAGE object
    defined in the PDS Standards Document.  The EDR contain all of the
    inherent properties and unprocessed and unrectified imaging.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

