<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.go-v-pws-2-refdr-vsafull-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GO V PWS REFORMATTED VENUS SPECTRUM ANALYZER FULL V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.galileo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:pws.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-v-pws-2-refdr-vsafull-v1.0__browserp_go-v-pws-2-refdr-vsafull-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Gurnett, D.A., W.S. Kurth, L.J. Granroth, S.C. Allendorf, and R.L. Poynter,
                   Micron-Sized Particles Detected Near Neptune by the Voyager 2 Plasma Wave
                   Instrument, J. Geophys. Res., Vol. 96, p. 19177, 1991.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GURNETTETAL1991</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GO-V-PWS-2-REFDR-VSAFULL-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GO V PWS REFORMATTED VENUS SPECTRUM ANALYZER FULL V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1997-01-13</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1990-02-10T04:32:12.200Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1990-02-10T05:25:10.199Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. WILLIAM S. KURTH</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>Unknown</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>Unknown</data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>Unknown</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
    This data set includes full resolution electric and magnetic wave spectra
    obtained during the ~ 53-minute period that the Galileo plasma wave
    receiver was operated at Venus.  In addition waveform survey data
    (uncalibrated) and all instrument housekeeping data are included.  The
    parameters provided for both the electric and magnetic field spectral data
    are uncalibrated data numbers.  Software and calibration tables provided
    as part of this data set allow for fully calibrated data for the electric
    field measurements in raw data numbers, voltage at the antenna inputs (V),
    electric field (V/m), electric field spectral density (V**2/m**2/Hz), or
    power flux (W/m**2/Hz).  The magnetic field measurements can be provided
    in units of magnetic field spectral density (nT**2/Hz).  The sources of
    these data are the High Frequency Receiver, Sweep Frequency Receiver, and
    Spectrum Analyzer which make up the Low Rate Science portion of the PWS.
    During the included time interval, the instrument cycled between the
    electric and magnetic antennas for the Sweep Frequency Receiver and the
    Spectrum Analyzer.  The High Frequency Receiver is always connected to the
    electric antenna.  Hence, for the Sweep Frequency Receiver and the
    Spectrum Analyzer, the temporal resolution for electric measurements is
    basically one spectrum per 37.33 seconds.  For the High Frequency
    Receiver, the time between spectra is 18.67 seconds.  Note that the lowest
    14 High Frequency Receiver channels are sampled twice per 18.67 seconds
    while the remaining channels are sampled only once.  The four Spectrum
    Analyzer channels are each sampled 7 times in an 18.67 sec interval.
 
    The waveform survey data are generated by the wideband receiver portion of
    the Plasma Wave Instrument.  These data are 4-bit measurements of the
    voltage across the preamplifier input at a rate of 201.6 k, 25.2 k or 3.2
    k samples per second (for the 80 kHz, 10 kHz, and 1 kHz bandwidth modes,
    respectively) using either the electric dipole or magnetic search coil
    antennas.  An automatic gain control receiver is used to set the gain at
    an optimum value so as to make the best use of the limited dynamic range
    afforded by the 4-bit analog-to-digital converter.  In principle, it is
    possible to use the Automatic Gain Control (AGC) readout contained in the
    data set to calibrate this voltage, but this capability does not currently
    exist for this data set.
 
    During the limited time of this data set, Galileo was skimming very close
    to the Venusian bow shock and actually executed several shock crossings
    during this time.  The plasma wave data included in this data set are
    summarized by Gurnett et al. [1991].
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
    This data set includes all available Low Rate Science spectrum analyzer
    data within the interval of time covered.  Included in this data set are
    data quality flags which indicate whether the parity of the data value was
    good or bad.  A bad parity flag indicates an error in the data value and
    the software provided with this data set will ignore such values.
    However, this is a simple parity scheme, hence, even numbers of bit errors
    will not be flagged as being bad.  The magnetic spectra contain narrowband
    interference lines at 2.4 kHz and harmonics.  Missing data are indicated
    by zero.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

