<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lro-l-spice-6-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LRO LUNAR SPICE KERNELS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-spice-6-v1.0__browserp_lro-l-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-spice-6-v1.0__browser_lro-l-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-spice-6-v1.0__browser_wgc_lro-l-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.naif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LRO-L-SPICE-6-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LRO LUNAR SPICE KERNELS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2015-09-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2009-06-18T21:32:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-06-15T00:00:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>NAYI CASTRO</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Calk, W.H., Casasanta, R.T., and Saylor, R.S., LUNAR
            RECONNAISSANCE ORBITER SPICE KERNELS V1.0, LRO-L-SPICE-6-V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 2010.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Navigation and ancillary data in the form of SPICE System kernel
            files for the Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set includes the complete set of Lunar Reconnaissance
            Orbiter SPICE data files (``kernel files&apos;), which can be
            accessed using SPICE software. The SPICE data contains geometric
            and other ancillary information needed to recover the full value
            of science instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide
            spacecraft and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting
            alignments, spacecraft orientation, and data needed for relevant
            time conversions.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
 
      This data set includes the complete set of Lunar Reconnaissance
      Orbiter SPICE data files (``kernel files&apos;), which can be
      accessed using SPICE software. The SPICE data contains geometric
      and other ancillary information needed to recover the full value
      of science instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide
      spacecraft and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting
      alignments, spacecraft orientation, and data needed for relevant
      time conversions.
 
      This data set is contained on a single virtual volume,
      LROSP_1000, including data from all mission phases and covering
      from launch, 2009-06-18, through the end time of the latest
      spacecraft trajectory file supplied in the data set. Until the
      end of the spacecraft lifespan this data set is accumulating with
      new data added approximately every three to six months.
 
 
      Data Types (SPICE kernel types)
      ===============================
 
      SPK kernels contain ephemerides for spacecraft, planets,
      satellites, comets and asteroids as well as for moving or fixed
      spacecraft and instrument structures. They provide position and
      velocity, given in a Cartesian reference frame. SPK files are
      located under the ``data/spk&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      PCK kernels contain certain physical, dynamical and cartographic
      constants for target bodies, such as size and shape
      specifications, and orientation of the spin axis and prime
      meridian. PCK files are located under the ``data/pck&apos; directory
      of this data set.
 
      IK kernels (Instrument description kernels) give descriptive and
      operational data peculiar to a particular scientific instrument,
      such as internal timing relative to the spacecraft clock and
      field-of-view model parameters. IK files are located under the
      ``data/ik&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      CK kernels describe pointing, containing a transformation
      traditionally called the C-matrix which is used to determine
      time-tagged pointing (orientation) angles for a spacecraft
      structure upon which science instruments are mounted. CK files
      are located under the ``data/ck&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      EK (Events) kernels are derived from the integrated sequence of
      events used to produce actual spacecraft commands. EK files are
      located under the ``data/ek&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      LSK (Leapseconds) kernels contain the leapseconds and the values
      of other constants required to perform a transformation between
      Universal Time Coordinated (UTC) and Ephemeris time (ET). LSK
      files are located under the ``data/lsk&apos; directory of this data
      set.
 
      SCLK (Spacecraft Clock) kernels contain on-board clock
      calibration data required to perform a mapping between Ephemeris
      time (ET) and spacecraft on-board time (SCLK). SCLK files are
      located under the ``data/sclk&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      FK (Frame Definitions) kernels contain information required to
      define reference frames, sources of frame orientation data and
      connections between these frames and other frames supported
      within the SPICE system. This includes mounting alignment
      information for each instrument. FK files are located under the
      ``data/fk&apos; directory of this data set.
 
 
      Kernel File Details
      ===================
 
      A brief overview of the different types of LRO kernels included
      in this data set is provided in the CONFIDENCE_LEVEL_NOTE section
      of this file while details specific to individual files are found
      in the ``*info.txt&apos; files in the corresponding data directory.
      The most detailed description of the data in each file is
      provided in metadata included inside the file -- in the
      description area of text kernels or in the comment area of binary
      kernels.
 
 
      Software
      ========
 
      The SPICE Toolkit contains software modules needed to read SPICE
      kernel files. SPICE software is highly documented via internal
      headers. Additional documentation is available in separate ASCII
      text files called Required Reading files. For example, the S- and
      P- Kernel (SPK) Required Reading File, named SPK.REQ, describes
      use of the SPK kernel file readers and contains sample programs.
 
      The latest SPICE Toolkit for a variety of computer platforms such
      as PC, Mac, SUN, etc. is available at the NAIF Node of PDS
      electronically (via anonymous FTP and WWW servers). Refer to
      information in ``software/softinfo.txt&apos; for details regarding
      obtaining this software. Each version of the Toolkit is also
      archived at the NASA National Space Science Data Center.
 
 
      Loading Kernel Files into a SPICE-based Application
      ===================================================
 
      The easiest way to make data from a collection of SPICE kernels
      available to a SPICE-based application is to list these kernels
      in a meta-kernel and load it into the program using the high
      level SPICE data loader routine FURNSH.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      This data set contains SPICE kernel files created during mission
      operations and after mission data reconstruction and analysis.
      Some general information about this collection follows here, but
      the prospective user is also referred to extensive descriptions
      about each file that are stored inside each kernel file. These
      metadata provide detailed information regarding the information
      source from which the data were derived, the type of processing
      applied to the source data, applicability of the data, etc.
      Metadata are located in the ``comment area&apos; for binary kernel
      types (SPK, CK, ESQ), accessible using either the COMMNT or
      SPACIT utility program found in the NAIF Toolkit. Metadata are
      located after ``\begintext&apos; markers within the text kernel types
      (PCK, IK, FK, LSK, SCLK, MK), accessible by using any available
      text file display tool such as a word processor, text editor, or
      the unix ``more&apos; or ``cat&apos; commands.
 
      Where there are questions about data accuracy or ``confidence&apos;
      not addressed herein the reader is invited to contact the NAIF
      node of the Planetary Data System for possible further
      information.
 
 
      SPK Files
      =========
 
      Three kinds of SP-kernel (SPK) files are provided in this
      archive: merged reconstructed spacecraft ephemeris SPK files,
      merged reconstructed reprocessed spacecraft ephemeris SPK files,
      and planetary ephemeris SPK files.
 
      The merged reconstructed spacecraft ephemeris SPK files were
      created at the time of archive preparation by merging together
      ``as is&apos; large sets daily LRO definitive spacecraft ephemeris
      SPK files (fdf29_???????_???????_???.bsp) to reduce the number of
      kernels provided in the archive. The daily LRO definitive
      spacecraft ephemeris files provided the definitive LRO spacecraft
      position and velocity relative to the Moon based only on S-Band
      tracking data. The spacecraft position and velocity vectors in
      these Type 13/degree 11 SPKs had sampling frequency of 1 minute.
      These SPKs were created by GSFC FDF on a daily basis and covered
      24 hours of a single day with coverage endpoints matching exactly
      those of the SPKs for the previous and next days. The accuracy of
      the position in these daily SPKs was better than 500 meters.
 
      The merged reconstructed reprocessed spacecraft ephemeris SPK
      files were created at the time of archive preparation by merging
      together ``as is&apos; sets LRO reprocessed spacecraft ephemeris SPK
      files (fdf36_???????_???????_???.bsp) to reduce the number of
      kernels provided in the archive. The LRO reprocessed spacecraft
      ephemeris files provided the definitive LRO spacecraft position
      and velocity relative to the Moon based on LRO Orbit
      Determination (OD) reprocessing results which included both laser
      tracking measurements and LOLA OD and Improved gravity model
      products. The spacecraft position and velocity vectors in these
      Type 13/degree 11 SPKs had sampling frequency of 1 minute. These
      SPKs were created by GSFC FDF on an irregular basis and covered
      varying intervals of time with coverage endpoints of given SPK
      matching exactly the coverage endpoints of the previous and next
      reprocessed SPKs. The accuracy of the position in these SPKs was
      better than 500 meters.
 
      The DE421 planetary ephemeris SPK file included in this data set
      contains ephemeris data for the Solar System planet barycenters,
      Sun, Mercury, Venus, Earth, Moon, and Lunar. This version of
      ephemerides was officially used by the project during mission
      operations. The internal comments included this SPK file provide
      detailed accuracy information.
 
      More information about LRO SPK files (include file naming
      conventions)is available in the file ``data/spk/spkinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      CK Files
      ========
 
      Four kinds of C-kernel (CK) files are provided in this archive:
      merged reconstructed spacecraft orientation CK files, merged
      reconstructed High Gain Antenna (HGA) orientation CK files,
      merged reconstructed Solar Array (SA) orientation CK files, and
      merged reconstructed DLRE orientation CK files.
 
      The merged reconstructed spacecraft orientation CK files were
      created at the time of archive preparation by merging together
      ``as is&apos; sets of 9 to 11 daily LRO definitive spacecraft CK
      files (moc42_???????_???????_v??.bc) to reduce the number of
      kernels provided in the archive. The daily LRO definitive
      spacecraft CK files provided orientation of the LRO spacecraft
      bus relative to the inertial frame J2000. These daily CKs were
      created by LRO MOC by storing spacecraft attitude quaternions
      determined on-board at sampling frequencies up to 5 Hz. These
      daily CKs usually covered 24 hours of a single day with a few
      minute overlap with the next day. The accuracy of the attitude in
      these daily CKs was [TBD] radians.
 
      The merged reconstructed HGA orientation CK files were created at
      the time of archive preparation by merging together ``as is&apos;
      sets of 9 to 11 daily LRO definitive HGA CK files
      (moc43_???????_???????_v??.bc) to reduce the number of kernels
      provided in the archive. The daily LRO definitive HGA CK files
      provided orientation of the LRO HGA relative to the LRO
      spacecraft bus. These CKs were created by LRO MOC by storing
      quaternions computed using the HGA articulation angles downlinked
      from the spacecraft at sampling frequencies up to 5 Hz. These
      daily CKs usually covered 24 hours of a single day with a few
      minute overlap with the next day. The accuracy of the HGA
      articulation angles used to produce these daily CKs was 10^-7
      radians.
 
      The merged reconstructed SA orientation CK files were created at
      the time of archive preparation by merging together ``as is&apos;
      sets of 9 to 11 daily LRO definitive SA CK files
      (moc44_???????_???????_v??.bc) to reduce the number of kernels
      provided in the archive. The daily LRO definitive SA CK files
      provided orientation of the LRO SA relative to the LRO spacecraft
      bus. These CKs were created by LRO MOC by storing quaternions
      computed using the SA articulation angles downlinked from the
      spacecraft at sampling frequencies up to 5 Hz. These daily CKs
      usually covered 24 hours of a single day with a few minute overlap
      with the next day. The accuracy of the SA articulation angles
      used to produce these daily CKs was 10^-7 radians.
 
      The merged reconstructed DLRE orientation CK files were created
      at the time of archive preparation by merging together ``as is&apos;
      sets hourly reconstructed DLRE CK files (lro_div_????-??-??_??.bc)
      into monthly files to reduce the number of kernels provided in
      the archive. The hourly reconstructed DLRE CK files provided
      orientation of the DLRE gimbal frames relative to the
      corresponding gimbal reference position frames, allowing in
      combination with the other DLRE frames computation of the orientation
      of the instrument detectors relative to the spacecraft bus. These
      hourly CKs were created by the DLRE team using the DLRE gimbal
      angles downlinked in the instrument housekeeping telemetry. Each
      of these hourly CKs usually covered one hour with a few second
      overlap with the next hour. The accuracy of the DLRE gimbal
      angles used to produce these daily CKs was [TBD] radians.
 
      More information about LRO CK files (include file naming
      conventions)is available in the file ``data/ck/ckinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      PCK Files
      =========
 
      PCK files provide size, shape and orientation data for ``target&apos;
      bodies such as the Moon. A description of these data items and
      reference to their source is provided inside the PCK file, which
      is a simple text file that can be viewed using any word
      processor, text editor or text display utility.
 
      The DE-421 based kernel file provide orientation of Lunar
      Principal Axis (PA) reference frame. More information about the
      PCK files included in this data set is available in the file
      ``data/pck/pckinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      FK Files
      ========
 
      Four kinds of Frame Kernel (FK) files are provided in this
      archive: LRO mission FK file, LRO instrument FK files, Lunar
      Reference Frames FK file, and Lunar Reference Frame Associations
      FK files.
 
      The LRO Mission FK file contains the complete set of frame
      definitions for the spacecraft, the solar array, and high gain
      antenna. Included are reference mounting angles and reference
      matrices for various spacecraft hardware and actuators, as well
      as the science instrument mounting alignments. Meta information
      provided in the comments included in this file consists of the
      frame definitions, description of the frame relationships, source
      of and accuracy of the mounting alignment information, etc.
      Multiple LRO groups provided inputs to create this file; those
      inputs were in the form of various project derived documentation.
 
      The LRO instrument FK files contain definitions of additional
      frames needed to compute observation geometry for a particular
      instrument.
 
      The Lunar Reference Frames FK file specifies lunar body-fixed
      reference frames associated with high-accuracy lunar orientation
      data provided by the JPL Solar System Dynamics Group&apos;s planetary
      ephemerides DE421. These reference frames realize the Lunar
      Principal Axis (PA) and Mean Earth/Polar Axis (ME) reference
      systems.
 
      The Lunar Reference Frame Associations FK files are used to
      associate a particular body-fixed frame with the Moon. Only one
      of these kernels (the one for the frame on interest) needs to be
      loaded at a time in order for some older SPICE APIs to perform
      computations in that frame. These kernels are not needed for the
      latest SPICE APIs.
 
      More information about the LRO FK files is available in the file
      ``data/fk/fkinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      IK Files
      ========
 
      Instrument kernel files provide specifications for geometric
      parameters and--where applicable--field-of-view size, shape and
      orientation for the named instruments. LRO did not levy any
      requirements on the individuals SOCs or instrument teams to
      create a corresponding Instrument kernel, which would provide
      the instrument field-of-view(s) size, shape and orientation.
      However, if the instrument teams or science centers created these
      files and forwarded them to the LRO MOC, the LRO MOC included
      them as part of the LRO SPICE archive.
 
      More information about LRO IK files is available in the file
      ``data/ik/ikinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      SCLK Files
      ==========
 
      Spacecraft Clock kernel files provide a tabulation of data needed
      for converting time measurements between ephemeris time (ET) and
      spacecraft clock time (SCLK). The SCLK kernel is a cumulative
      file for the entire mission.
 
      The LRO spacecraft maintained time in a combination of both
      hardware and software. The LRO clock is formatted as a 32 bit
      seconds and 16 bit subseconds count. The C&amp;DH flight software used
      the hardware counters, the MET, and the Spacecraft Time Correction
      Factor (STCF)(which included leap seconds) to represent one single
      value, the SC UT. The SC UT drifts because the clock oscillator
      frequency is not stable due to changing temperature and aging of
      the oscillator. Using an ultra-stable oscillator (USO) minimizes
      these effects. LRO has an Ultra Stable Oscillator (USO) 9500 and
      a USO 9600.  The USO 9500 is a Double Oven Controlled Crystal
      Oscillator (DOCXO) while the USO 9600 is an Oven Controlled Crystal
      Oscillator (OCXO). The ovens keep each oscillator at a near
      constant temperature.  The USO 9500 is the more accurate of the
      two clocks and therefore is the primary one used for operations.
      The USO 9600 is kept powered OFF unless needed due to a failure
      or anomaly with the USO 9500.
 
      Once LRO had launched it was determined that the spacecraft clock
      was drifting at approximately 6.7 milliseconds per day. The Project
      requirement is to keep the difference between the spacecraft clock
      and UTC on the ground to less than 100 milliseconds. Initially, LRO
      operations had decided to adjust the clock, should the difference
      reach 80 milliseconds. The drift rate experienced subsequent to
      launch required an adjustment approximately every 12 days. To reduce
      confusion and to standardize delivery of the SCLK files, constraints
      permitting, LRO operations decided to perform a routine clock adjust
      every Monday. However, instrument constrains may have delayed the
      actual execution of the adjustment.
 
      More information about the LRO SCLK files is available in the
      file ``data/sclk/sclkinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      LSK Files
      =========
 
      Leapseconds kernel files provide a tabulation of ``leapseconds&apos;
      and some other terms used in converting time measurements between
      ephemeris time (ET) and Universal Time (UTC). ``Spacecraft Event
      Time&apos; (SCET) is the commonly used name for UTC events measured
      at the spacecraft.
 
      Metadata describing how the LSK data are obtained or computed is
      contained inside the LSK text file. The time conversion provided
      by SPICE LSK files is accurate to approximately 0.000030 seconds.
 
      More information about the LSK files is available in the file
      ``data/lsk/lskinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      EK Files
      ========
 
      The Events (E)-kernel store different kinds of the spacecraft
      and science instrument events related information such as
      spacecraft and instrument commands, status parameters, records
      of spacecraft activities, ground events, and so on, and to
      systematize and provide access to this data in relational
      database-like fashion.
 
      The means of an access to the EK data are provided via SPICE
      Toolkit APIs, calls to which can be integrated into user application
      programs. The information regarding how to obtain the SPICE system
      toolkit for a number of languages and computer platforms is located
      in the ``/software&apos; subdirectory of the main directory of this data
      set.
 
      To use E-kernels with INSPEKT program, a Leapseconds (LSK) is
      required.
 
      Refer to the ``ek.req&apos; and ``inspekt.ug&apos; documents provided with
      the toolkit to get more information on how to access E-kernel data.
 
      The Events Kernel is consists of the complete set of event sequences
      (in sequential time-order) when any instrument is not collecting
      science data, such as during spacecraft station keeping maneuvers.
 
      The LRO Event kernel is a Binary-formatted file that intended to
      provide current and future users of LRO science data information on
      events and activities that affected science data collection and that
      can assist in extracting the full value of the science data returned
      from the LRO mission. The events documented by the event kernel can
      be planned or unplanned. Some examples of planned events are:
 
        - halting data collection for slews or calibrations;
        - delta-v maneuvers;
        - loading a FSW patch;
        - recovery from non-nominal modes such as safe mode.
 
      Some examples of unplanned events might be:
        - an anomaly resulting in the orbiter transitioning to safe mode
          or powering down instruments;
        - instrument anomaly.
 
      The information for the event kernel came primarily from a single
      source:
        - The LRO telemetry and command (T&amp;C) system event message log;
        - The spacecraft playback logs.
 
      The event kernel was generated by an automated process within the LRO
      Mission Operations Center (MOC). The LRO Event Kernel Utility ran
      once per week at 0000Z on Monday. The Utility scanned the T&amp;C and
      spacecraft playback logs for appropriate information to be included
      in the event kernel. The LRO GS&amp;O system engineering and mission
      operations team had the responsibility for determining which
      information is appropriate and configuring the LRO Event Kernel
      Utility accordingly.
 
      More information about LRO EK files is available in the file
      ``data/ek/ekinfo.txt&apos;.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

