<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ds1-a-c-spice-6-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DEEP SPACE 1 SPICE KERNELS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_space_1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.ds1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.ds1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.9969_braille::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.19p-borrelly_1_1904_y2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ds1-a-c-spice-6-v1.0__browserp_ds1-a-c-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ds1-a-c-spice-6-v1.0__browser_ds1-a-c-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ds1-a-c-spice-6-v1.0__browser_wgc_ds1-a-c-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.naif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DS1-A/C-SPICE-6-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DEEP SPACE 1 SPICE KERNELS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2003-10-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1998-10-24T09:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2003-12-31T00:00:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>BORIS V. SEMENOV</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Semenov, B.V., L.S. Elson, and C.H. Acton, DEEP SPACE 1 SPICE
            KERNELS V1.0, DS1-A/C-SPICE-6-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Navigation and ancillary data in the form of SPICE System kernel
            files for the Deep Space 1 (DS1) spacecraft.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set includes the complete set of Deep Space 1 (DS1)
            SPICE data files (``kernel files&apos;&apos;), which can be
            accessed using SPICE software. The SPICE data contains geometric
            and other ancillary information needed to recover the full value
            of science instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide
            spacecraft and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting
            alignments, spacecraft orientation, spacecraft sequences of
            events, and data needed for relevant time conversions.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
 
      This data set includes the complete set of Deep Space 1 (DS1)
      SPICE data files (``kernel files&apos;&apos;), which can be accessed using
      SPICE software. The SPICE data contains geometric and other
      ancillary information needed to recover the full value of science
      instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft
      and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments,
      spacecraft orientation, spacecraft sequences of events, and data
      needed for relevant time conversions.
 
 
      Data Types (SPICE kernel types)
      ===============================
 
      SPK kernels contain ephemerides for spacecraft, planets,
      satellites, comets and asteroids as well as for moving or
      fixed spacecraft and instrument structures. They provide
      position and velocity, given in a Cartesian reference frame.
      SPK files are located under the data/spk directory on the
      volumes comprising this data set.
 
      PCK kernels contain certain physical, dynamical and
      cartographic constants for target bodies, such as size and shape
      specifications, and orientation of the spin axis and prime
      meridian. PCK files are located under the data/pck directory
      on the volumes comprising this data set.
 
      IK kernels (Instrument description kernels) give descriptive and
      operational data peculiar to a particular scientific instrument,
      such as internal timing relative to the spacecraft clock and
      field-of-view model parameters. IK files are located under the
      data/ik directory on the volumes comprising this data set.
 
      CK kernels describe pointing, containing a transformation
      traditionally called the C-matrix which is used to determine
      time-tagged pointing (orientation) angles for a spacecraft
      structure upon which science instruments are mounted. CK files
      are located under the data/ck directory on the volumes comprising
      this data set.
 
      EK (Events) kernels are derived from the integrated sequence of
      events used to produce actual spacecraft commands. EK files are
      located under the data/ek directory on the volumes comprising
      this data set.
 
      LSK (Leapseconds) kernels contain the leapseconds and the values
      of other constants required to perform a transformation between
      Universal Time Coordinated (UTC) and Ephemeris time (ET). LSK
      files are located under the data/lsk directory on the volumes
      comprising this data set.
 
      SCLK (Spacecraft Clock) kernels contain on-board clock calibration
      data required to perform a mapping between Ephemeris time (ET)
      and spacecraft on-board time (SCLK.) SCLK files are located under
      the data/sclk directory on the volumes comprising this data set.
 
      FK (Frame Definitions) kernels contain information required to
      define reference frames, sources of frame orientation data and
      inter-connections between these frames and other frames supported
      within the SPICE system. This includes mounting alignment
      information for each instrument. FK files are located under
      the data/fk directory on the volumes comprising this data set.
 
 
      Kernel File Details
      ===================
 
      Details specific to individual files are found in the *info.txt
      files in the corresponding data directory. The most detailed
      description of the data in each file is provided in metadata
      included inside the file -- in the description area of text
      kernels or in the comment area of binary kernels.
 
 
      Software
      ========
 
      The SPICE Toolkit contains software modules needed to read
      SPICE kernel files. SPICELIB software is highly documented
      via internal headers. Additional documentation is available
      in separate ASCII text files called Required Reading files.
      For example, the S- and P- Kernel (SPK) Required Reading File,
      named SPK.REQ, describes use of the SPK kernel file readers
      and contains sample programs.
 
      The latest SPICE Toolkit for a variety of computer platforms such
      as PC, Mac, SUN, HP, SGI, VAX, DEC Alpha, etc. is available at
      the NAIF Node of PDS electronically (via anonymous FTP and WWW
      servers). Each version of the Toolkit is also archived at the
      NASA National Space Science Data Center.
 
 
      Loading Kernel Files into a SPICE-based Application
      ===================================================
 
      The following list of kernels in SPICE meta-kernel format can be
      used with a SPICE-based application running on a UNIX workstation
      to load all DS1 SPICE data provided in this data set together
      (note that the logical path provided the PATH_VALUES keyword and
      pointing to the volume root directory should be changed to be the
      actual path of the volume root directory on the system where the
      volume is mounted):
 
         \begindata
 
            PATH_VALUES       = (
                                 &apos;./data&apos;
                                )
            PATH_SYMBOLS      = (
                                 &apos;KERNELS&apos;
                                )
            KERNELS_TO_LOAD   = (
                                 &apos;$KERNELS/lsk/naif0007.tls&apos;
                                 &apos;$KERNELS/pck/ds1_borrelly_v01.tpc&apos;
                                 &apos;$KERNELS/pck/ds1_braille_v02.tpc&apos;
                                 &apos;$KERNELS/pck/pck00007.tpc&apos;
                                 &apos;$KERNELS/fk/ds1_v70.tf&apos;
                                 &apos;$KERNELS/ik/ds1_micas_v32.ti&apos;
                                 &apos;$KERNELS/ik/ds1_pepe_v20.ti&apos;
                                 &apos;$KERNELS/sclk/ds1_sclkscet_00071.tsc&apos;
                                 &apos;$KERNELS/spk/de405s.bsp&apos;
                                 &apos;$KERNELS/spk/ds1_radionav.bsp&apos;
                                 &apos;$KERNELS/spk/ds1_opnav_borrelly.bsp&apos;
                                 &apos;$KERNELS/spk/ds1_opnav_braille.bsp&apos;
                                 &apos;$KERNELS/ck/ds1_sa_1998.bc&apos;
                                 &apos;$KERNELS/ck/ds1_sa_1999.bc&apos;
                                 &apos;$KERNELS/ck/ds1_sa_2000.bc&apos;
                                 &apos;$KERNELS/ck/ds1_sa_2001.bc&apos;
                                 &apos;$KERNELS/ck/ds1_sc_1998.bc&apos;
                                 &apos;$KERNELS/ck/ds1_sc_1999.bc&apos;
                                 &apos;$KERNELS/ck/ds1_sc_2000.bc&apos;
                                 &apos;$KERNELS/ck/ds1_sc_2001.bc&apos;
                                )
 
         \begintext
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      This volume contains SPICE kernel files created during mission
      operations and after mission data reconstruction and analysis.
      Some general information about this collection follows here,
      but the prospective user is also referred to extensive
      descriptions about each file that are stored inside each kernel
      file. These metadata provide detailed information regarding
      the information source from which the data were derived, the
      type of processing applied to the source data, applicability
      of the data, etc. Metadata are located in the ``comment area&apos;&apos;
      for binary kernel types (SPK, CK, ESQ), accessible using either
      the COMMNT or SPACIT utility program found in the NAIF Toolkit.
      Metadata are located after ``\begintext&apos;&apos; markers within the
      text kernel types (PCK, IK, FK, LSK, SCLK), accessible by
      using any available text file display tool such as a word
      processor, text editor, or the unix ``more&apos;&apos; or ``cat&apos;&apos;
      commands.
 
      In some cases data accuracy information does not exist, or
      may be estimated after mission completion.
 
      Where there are questions about data accuracy or ``confidence&apos;&apos;
      not addressed herein the reader is invited to examine subsequent
      SPICE archive releases associated with this data set (if such
      exist), or to contact the NAIF node of the Planetary Data System
      for possible further information.
 
 
      SPK Files
      =========
 
      SP-Kernel files included in this data set provide the trajectory
      of the Deep Space 1 spacecraft. These files also include
      ephemeris data for the mission targets -- asteroid Braille and
      comet Borrelly -- along with ephemeris data for Earth, Moon, and
      Sun. The spacecraft trajectory stored in these SPKs was
      determined by the Deep Space 1 Radio Navigation (Radio NAV) and
      Optical Navigation (OPNAV) teams, both from JPL.
 
      The SPKs produced by DS1 Optical NAV team were created by
      processing images taken during the approach to and departure from
      the target. These solutions provide the best trajectory relative
      the specific target ephemerides that has been included in these
      SPKs to ensure that the s/c trajectory and that specific target
      ephemerides are always used together. These SPKs provide more
      accurate trajectory relative the target and, therefore, should be
      used to compute derived geometry during the encounters.
 
      The substantial difference between the DS1 trajectory provided by
      the OPNAV and Radio NAV solutions -- on average about 400 km for
      the Braille encounter and about 120 km for the Borrelly encounter
      -- can be attributed to the error in the knowledge of the target
      position. Since the OPNAV solution was done relative to the
      target and the Radio NAV was done relative to the Solar System
      ephemerides, the error is the target position became the main
      contributor to the difference between the two spacecraft
      trajectory solutions.
 
      Unfortunately the coverage of the OPNAV SPKs is relatively short,
      starting about a month before each encounter and ending shortly
      after it. For this reason the Radio NAN SPKs should be used
      wherever OPNAV SPK coverage is not available.
 
 
      CK Files
      ========
 
      C-kernel files included in this data set provide orientation of
      the spacecraft bus and its solar array. Both kinds
      of CK files are produced from engineering telemetry downlinked
      from the spacecraft. As is often the case with spacecraft
      engineering telemetry-based  measurements, considerable
      uncertainty exists as to the accuracy of such measurements, and,
      data quality (accuracy and completeness) can vary significantly.
 
      Spacecraft Bus CK Files
      -----------------------
 
      These CK files containing the orientation of the spacecraft bus
      (``the spacecraft&apos;&apos;) are provided to support interpretation of
      data obtained by all science experiments. The spacecraft
      orientation CK file included in this data set were produced from
      the stream of orientation quaternions computed on-board
      and send down in channelized telemetry.
 
      The fact that the spacecraft could successfully point to and
      track the desired targets (Borrelly and Braille) and that the
      targets were found close to the expected location in the images
      indicates that the accuracy of orientation information sent down
      from the spacecraft was within the mission requirements. At the
      same time it should be mentioned that at the time of this archive
      release there are no known reports assessing accuracy of the
      spacecraft orientation provided in these CK files.
 
      Attitude knowledge, represented by quaternions stored in the
      reconstructed s/c orientation CK files, ceased to be valid within
      a short time of the failure of the SRU on November 11, 1999.
      On-board knowledge (based on inertial celestial reference) was
      not restored until 01:00 on June 15, 2000. The reconstructed s/c
      orientation CKs provide no data during this period.
 
      Attitude knowledge was also subject to gyro drift inaccuracies
      during the following periods, in which our Science Camera/Star
      Tracker lost lock:
 
         2000-07-16T20:00  until  2000-07-19T01:00
         2001-03-13T16:00  until  2001-03-16T20:00
         2001-07-15T20:00  until  2001-07-24T18:00
         2001-08-16T12:00  until  2001-08-24T11:00
         2001-09-13T17:00  until  2001-09-14T01:00
         2001-12-02T16:00  until  2001-12-04T23:00
 
      Although the magnitude of the inaccuracy is not known for each
      period, the reconstructed s/c orientation CKs provide data during
      these periods because the attitude was determined using real gyro
      measurements and may be, at least at the starts of the intervals,
      close to reality.
 
      This data set also includes a CK providing DS1 spacecraft
      predicted orientation for Borrelly encounter. Although the
      reconstructed orientation is available for the encounter, this
      file is included in the archive because its comments provide a a
      detailed description of the encounter attitude profile.
 
      Solar Array CK Files
      --------------------
 
      These CK files containing orientation of the solar arrays
      relative to the spacecraft bus are provided to support the PEPE
      data analysis. The orientation data in these files was computed
      the solar array gimbal angles measured on-board and sent down
      in channelized telemetry.
 
      The validation of the data in these CKs involved computing the
      angle between the solar array normal direction from the
      spacecraft to the Sun and verifying that it was close to zero. While
      it was the case whenever the arrays were supposed to be tracking
      the Sun no formal reports assessing accuracy of the solar array
      orientation provided in these CK files were available at the time
      of archiving.
 
      Though a solar array CK file is provided for each year of the
      mission, the combination of all these files is lacking coverage
      from 1999-11-10 through 2001-09-08 (two little coverage windows
      in Dec 2000 and May 2001 are exceptions.)
 
      Caution on Using CK Files
      -------------------------
 
      While not a data accuracy issue, the CK user is nevertheless
      cautioned to understand and properly use the data found and
      tolerance arguments that are inputs to the CK reader provided
      in the SPICE Toolkit. Descriptions about how to read CK files
      are found in the CK reader routine headers (top of the source
      code files) and in the ``CK Required Reading&apos;&apos; document; these
      are contained in each SPICE Toolkit package.
 
 
      PCK Files
      =========
 
      PCK files provide size, shape and orientation data for ``target&apos;&apos;
      bodies such as planets, satellites, comets and asteroids. A
      description of these data items and reference to their source is
      provided inside the PCK file, which is a simple text file that
      can be viewed using any word processor, text editor or text
      display utility.
 
      The two PCK files provided in this data set are for the mission
      target -- asteroid Braille and comet Borrelly. Both files are
      were created around the times of encounters and contain
      preliminary size and orientation data.
 
 
      FK Files
      ========
 
      Frames kernel files provide specifications for how one reference
      frame is defined relative to another frame. The Deep Space 1 FK
      provided in this data set contains a complete set of frame
      definitions for the spacecraft, its structures such as solar
      arrays, and all of its science instruments. Meta information
      provided in the comments included in this file consists of the
      frame definitions, description of the frame relationships, source
      of and accuracy of the mounting alignment information, etc.
 
 
      IK Files
      ========
 
      Instrument kernel files provide specifications for the optical
      and physical instrument parameters and -- where applicable --
      field-of-view size, shape and orientation for the named
      instrument. Metadata describing these estimates are provided in
      each IK file included in this archive.
 
 
      SCLK Files
      ==========
 
      Spacecraft Clock kernel files provide a tabulation of data
      needed for converting time measurements between ephemeris time
      (ET) and spacecraft clock time (SCLK). A SPICE SCLK file is
      made from a similar file -- SCLK/SCET file, or SCLKvSCET
      file -- produced by another mission entity. Each newly made SCLK
      file fully replaces the previous SCLK file.
 
      While no formal report on the Deep Space 1 time correlation
      accuracy was available at the time of archiving, since the
      SCLK/SCET were created by the same process as the SCLK/SCET files
      for other JPL mission the accuracy can be assumed to be better
      than a few tens of milliseconds. The SPICE SCLK file has
      essentially the same accuracy as the SCLK/SCET file.
 
      SPICE software does not prohibit an SCLK file from being used
      for time conversions occurring for ``future times&apos;&apos; (or more
      accurately, for epochs that occur later than the epoch of the
      last telemetry data used in producing the last correlation
      coefficients found in the SCLK file). Such ``predict&apos;&apos; time
      conversions are likely to be inaccurate (changed somewhat)
      once the epoch of interest has been passed.
 
      Note that this SCLK provides correlation for the main spacecraft
      on-board clock. While this clock was used to tag sequences
      up-linked to and all telemetry sent from the spacecraft, a
      different time was used to tag MICAS images (i.e. was included
      into the image headers.) That time was a count of ephemeris
      seconds past 1998 JAN 01 12:00:00 ET. Because this counter was
      also ``running&apos;&apos; on-board the spacecraft, it was not ``running&apos;&apos;
      at the true ET rate. Instead it was ``running&apos;&apos; at the rate of
      the main on-board clock and, therefore, was drifting from the
      true ET as time when on. To correct the drift, a special command
      was sent to the spacecraft every so often -- once every few weeks
      -- to synchronize the counter with the actual ET.
 
      If an image was taken long after the previous counter adjustment,
      the drift had usually accumulated into a substantial error, up to
      a few seconds. If an image was taken right after adjustment, the
      error have not yet accumulated and the counter value was very
      close to the true ephemeris time. Fortunately, the counter was
      adjusted right before both encounters and, therefore, the error
      between the counter value and the actual ET for in the encounter
      images is less than 0.1 second.
 
      The following small fragment of SPICE FORTRAN and C code
      illustrates how the 1998-based ET counter (IMGTIM/imgtim)
      provided in the MICAS image headers can be converted to UTC:
 
         FORTRAN:
 
            CALL STR2ET ( &apos;1998 JAN 01 12:00:00 TDB&apos;, ETBASE )
            ET = ETBASE + IMGTIM
            CALL TIMOUT ( ET, &apos;YYYY-MM-DDTHR:MN:SC.###&apos;, UTC )
 
         C:
 
            str2et_c ( &apos;1998 JAN 01 12:00:00 TDB&apos;, &amp;etbase );
            et = etbase + imgtim;
            timout_c ( et, &apos;YYYY-MM-DDTHR:MN:SC.###&apos;, utc );
 
      This example does not take the drift into account; should it try
      to do that, the accumulated drift, in seconds, has to be
      estimated and added to the ET before converting to UTC.
 
 
      LSK Files
      =========
 
      Leapseconds kernel files provide a tabulation of ``leapseconds&apos;&apos;
      and some other terms used in converting time measurements
      between ephemeris time (ET) and Universal Time (UTC). ``Spacecraft
      Event Time&apos;&apos; (SCET) is the commonly used name for UTC events
      measured at the spacecraft.
 
      Metadata describing how the LSK data are obtained or computed
      is contained inside the LSK text file. The time conversion
      provided by SPICE LSK files is accurate to approximately
      0.000030 seconds.
 
 
      EK Files
      ========
 
      One kind of Events kernel (EK) files is included in this
      archive -- predicted Sequence EKs for target encounters.
 
      Sequence EKs comprise a summary of the commands sent to the
      spacecraft as well as instrument state (status) summaries as
      modeled by the sequence generation tools. This data set includes
      predicted Sequence EKs created from integrated sequence Predicted
      Events Files (PEFs) produced by the Deep Space 1 Sequence team.
      As seen from the source product name these files contain
      predicted information -- background sequences, as should have
      executed by the spacecraft. Because of that the EK records have
      times different from the actual command execution times (although
      very close in most cases.) These EKs are also missing any
      commands that were not part of the background sequences
      (real-time commands).
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>DVD-R</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>PSCM-00028</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>PSCM-00028</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

