<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.sdu-c-navcam-2-edr-wild2-v2.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>STARDUST NAVCAM IMAGES OF WILD 2 - VERSION 2.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.stardust::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.sdu::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:navcam.sdu::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.81p-wild_2_1978_a2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.sdu-c-navcam-2-edr-wild2-v2.0__browserp_sdu-c-navcam-2-edr-wild2-v2.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>SDU-C-NAVCAM-2-EDR-WILD2-V2.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>STARDUST NAVCAM IMAGES OF WILD 2 - VERSION 2.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2004-07-02</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2003-01-28T12:33:36.243Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2004-01-13T02:30:46.445Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STARDUST DATA MANAGEMENT AND ARCHIVE TEAM</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Semenov, B.V., R.L. Newburn, H.W. Taylor, C. Hash, and C.H.
            Acton, T.L. Farnham, STARDUST NAVCAM IMAGES OF WILD 2,
            SDU-C-NAVCAM-2-EDR-WILD2-V2.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2008.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw images taken by STARDUST Navigation Camera during the comet
            Wild 2 encounter.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains raw pre-encounter and encounter images
            taken by the Stardust Navigation Camera during the encounter with
            comet Wild 2.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
 
      This data set contains raw pre-encounter and encounter images
      taken by the Stardust Navigation Camera during the encounter
      with comet Wild 2. This is version 2.0 of the dataset, in which
      the IMG formatted images have been converted to FITS format, and
      a number of corrections, described below, have been applied.
      This version supersedes version 1.0.
 
      Every image provided in this data set was taken as a part of a
      particular imaging sequence, each of which is described in this
      section by the NAVCAM Science Lead, Dr. Raymond L. Newburn, Jr.
      For the complete list of images and their parameters, refer to
      the data set&apos;s index table, INDEX/INDEX.TAB. For additional
      notes on individual images also consult with the document ``Log
      of Stardust NAVCAM Flight Images&apos;&apos;, DOCUMENT/PIIMGLOG.PDF,
      provided with this data set.
 
      2003 JAN 28 12:33:36 -- Images 477-509
      --------------------------------------
        The primary purpose of images 477 through 507 was geometric
        calibration of images taken through the periscope. Images 508
        and 509 were tests of windowing, using a 151 x 151 window.
        Photometric calibration of these was a secondary goal. The
        target for all images was the Pleiades (M45, an open cluster).
        For the primary purpose, the scan mirror was set at one degree
        intervals from 0 through 20 degrees. All images showed a
        significant amount of scattered light, but they still were
        useful for geometric calibration of images taken through the
        periscope. The images showed significant doubling with part of
        the light coming through the periscope and part of it around
        the periscope, the two images separated by about 17 pixels.
        None of the images were of significant use for photometric
        calibration.
 
      2003 MAY 21 21:09:43 -- Images 510-513
      --------------------------------------
        After almost four months since the last image, this series of
        four images (510-513) was intended as a check of the camera and
        the state of its optical system. Image 510, taken through the
        periscope, seemed to indicate severe contamination, both of the
        periscope and the rest of the optical system. Image 511, taken
        of the calibration lamp showed the lamp filament plainly but
        also showed a very mottled background. This showed that there
        was contamination of both the periscope and the camera optics.
        The final images, off the periscope, seemed to indicate that
        the camera was in better shape than the periscope. Clearly,
        another heating cycle was needed to clean up the camera.
 
      2003 OCT 08 22:11:21 -- Images 514-517
      --------------------------------------
        Much of the contamination seen in the images 4 1/2 months
        earlier was on the periscope, which could not be heated without
        turning the Sun on the battery immediately above it. This is
        not permitted by spacecraft flight rules. We could, however,
        turn the Sun on the camera radiator once again, if necessary.
        Images 514 through 517 were an additional check on the state of
        the camera, and the camera was found to be heavily
        contaminated. The first image, of the calibration lamp, showed
        it to be in much worse shape than it had been the previous May.
        The other three images, of a star field and off the periscope,
        were virtually blank, even with a five second exposure for two
        of them.
 
      2003 OCT 11 23:06:37 -- Images 518-521
      --------------------------------------
        On October 11 the previous cycle of images was repeated as
        numbers 518 through 521. A few stars in the two 5 second
        exposures indicated that the contamination was now ``only&apos;&apos;
        about 2 1/2 magnitudes (a factor of 10)! Just turning on the
        CCD heater prior to this data set had helped, but not nearly as
        much as needed, so commands were sent to put the Sun on the CCD
        radiator once again.
 
      2003 OCT 30 15:07:34 -- Images 522-525
      --------------------------------------
        Following a full heating with the Sun on the radiator and the
        CCD and scan mechanism heaters turned on, this set of four
        image (522 through 525) was meant to determine how successful
        we had been in clearing off the contamination adhering to
        camera components. We found that contamination had been reduced
        from 2.5 magnitudes to about 0.5 magnitudes (a factor of ten to
        a factor of 1.58 reduction in transmission). These much
        improved images utilized exposures of one second, five seconds,
        five seconds, and finally 20 milliseconds with the calibration
        lamp turned on. For some reason, the calibration lamp didn&apos;t
        seem to have been turned on. (This happened again just before
        the Wild 2 encounter. It may have been caused by solar particle
        radiation flipping a bit somewhere in the lamp or shutter logic
        circuits.)
 
      2003 NOV 08 16:15:03 -- Images 526-527
      --------------------------------------
        Images 526 and 527 were intended as shutter checks, because the
        calibration lamp hadn&apos;t appeared in image 525. Image 526 was a
        five second timed exposure on a star field. It appeared
        perfectly normal. Image 527 tested the bulb mode, where the
        shutter is commanded open and stays open until it receives the
        close command. This method also worked perfectly. The lack of
        an image of the calibration lamp in image 525 remains an
        enigma.
 
      2003 NOV 13 06:56:05 -- Images 528-530
      --------------------------------------
        Images 528, 529, and 530 were 3 second full frames exposed on
        the encounter field. We were concerned about the number of
        background stars available for optical navigation, this not
        being the richest field in the sky. We also wanted to check,
        once again, how much scattered light might confront us. As we
        expected, there were no severe problems with scan mirror
        settings of less then 170 degrees. Since these images were of
        the encounter field, chief optical navigator Shyam Bhaskaran
        scanned a frame looking for Wild 2. There seemed to be
        something at about the correct position. He co-added the three
        frames and was convinced he had found Wild 2. Others present at
        his request were even more sure that he had found the comet.
        These were the first images taken to search for Wild 2, and the
        project heaved a huge sigh of collective relief at the comet
        having been located in nearly the predicted place more than six
        weeks before the encounter.
 
      2003 NOV 17 16:59:59 -- Images 531-555
      --------------------------------------
        Images 531 through 555 were a test of windowing and pattern
        matching. All images in this group used four 51 x 51 pixel
        windows, three on stars and one on the expected position of
        Wild 2. Image 532, if it ever existed, was not transmitted to
        the ground. The proper windows were created in every case, but
        the pattern matching varied from no match, to matched with
        stars near the edge of the window to stars nearly centered. All
        were taken with exposures of 5 seconds (531 through 550) or 15
        seconds (551 through 555). Individually, none provided an
        obvious image of Wild 2.
 
      2003 NOV 20 17:00:00 -- Images 556-558
      --------------------------------------
        This was a set of three full frame images. The first of them,
        556, was missing some packets and was a bit of a mess. The
        other two were fine 5 second and 15 images and served to
        confirm quite definitely the presence and location of Wild 2.
        Needless to say, having definitely acquired the location of
        Wild 2 this early was a huge relief to the STARDUST team.
 
      2003 NOV 24 04:00:00 -- Images 559-583
      --------------------------------------
        Images 559 through 583 were windowed images, in this case three
        51 x 51 images and one 71 x 71 image, the latter the window on
        the predicted comet position. Twenty of these were 5 second
        exposures and five were 15 second exposures. Eight images were
        not pattern matched, while the other 17 seemed to work
        perfectly. The image of Wild 2 can be seen in each individual 71
        x 71 image, that is properly locked, by using a bit of stretch.
 
      2003 NOV 27 17:00:00 -- Images 584-608
      --------------------------------------
        Images 584 through 608 were a repeat of the previous set,
        except they were divided into 10 at five second exposures and
        15 at fifteen second exposures. The same window sizes were
        used, 51 x 51 for the stars and 71 x 71 for the comet. This
        time only five did not lock up (pattern match). These images
        were intended for optical navigation, as was the previous set.
 
      2003 DEC 01 05:00:24 -- Images 609-633
      --------------------------------------
        Images 609 through 633 were intended to be another set of 25
        optical navigation images using three 51 x 51 pixel images and
        one 71 x 71 pixel image. Only four of them achieved pattern
        matching, however, and those were very poorly centered. These
        were of little use.
 
      2003 DEC 04 10:44:18 -- Images 634-673
      --------------------------------------
        Images 634 through 673 were periscope checks, intended to see
        how well the spacecraft could be guided when it had to be
        pointed in the ram direction. The first nine frames were full
        frame 5 second exposures at a scan mirror angle of 1.94
        degrees. All exhibited considerable scattered light. The next
        four images were again full frame, but this time at a scan
        mirror angle of 1.57 degrees. The exposures were 15, 7.5, 5,
        and 3 seconds. Again there was a great deal of scattered light.
        The remainder of the frames were taken at a mirror angle of
        16.82 degrees. The first two of these were again full frames
        using a 15 second exposure. The remainder were all windowed,
        using three 51 x 51 pixel sizes and one using 71 x 71 pixels.
        They utilized exposures of 5 seconds or 15 seconds. All of
        these contained a great deal of scattered light, and none were
        successful in pattern matching.
 
      2003 DEC 08 13:00:00 -- Images 674-698
      --------------------------------------
        The next set of 25 images, 674 through 698, were taken off
        periscope at a scan mirror angle of 34.24 degrees. All were
        windowed with three windows 51 x 51 pixels and one window 71 x
        71 pixels. The first five images had five second exposures, the
        next five had 10 second exposures, and the final 15 used 15
        second exposures. The first five images did not achieve lock,
        nor did the last of the 10 second exposures. The first four 10
        second exposures and all of the 15 second exposures achieved a
        good lock.
 
      2003 DEC 09 05:00:00 -- Images 699-724
      --------------------------------------
        This set of 25 images (699 through 724) was taken strictly for
        optical navigation purposes. The first five received an
        exposure of 5 seconds, the second five 10 seconds, and the
        third, a group of 15, received an exposure of 15 seconds.
        Pattern matching was not achieved on the first five (699-703),
        nor on 705, 706, 708, 710, 714, 716, 718, 722, or 723. Image
        724 which is a full frame, shows considerable scattered light
        as well as a strange artifact of several adjacent columns. This
        artifact also appears in the other images of this group, but
        fortunately it does not cross any of the windows. Looking back,
        the artifact apparently first appeared in image 701. All of
        this still left 11 good images for optical navigation purposes.
        P/Wild 2 still is an easy target in the 71 x 71 window of each
        image.
 
      2003 DEC 10 05:00:00 -- Images 725-749
      --------------------------------------
        This set of 25 images (725 through 749) again was taken
        strictly for optical navigation purposes. The first five
        received an exposure of 5 seconds, the second five 10 seconds,
        and the third, a group of 15, received an exposure of 15
        seconds. Pattern matching was achieved on only four windows,
        730, 732, 734, and 738. The artifact, first seen in image 701,
        is apparent in this set of images as well.
 
      2003 DEC 11 05:00:00 -- Images 750-774
      --------------------------------------
        This set of 25 images (750 through 774) again was taken
        strictly for optical navigation purposes. The first five
        received an exposure of 5 seconds, the second five 10 seconds,
        and the third, a group of 15, received an exposure of 15
        seconds. Pattern matching was achieved on only five images, 755
        through 759. The artifact, first seen in image 701, is apparent
        in this set of images as well, but seems to be fading.
 
      2003 DEC 12 11:59:59 -- Images 775-800
      --------------------------------------
        This set of images, 775 to 800, was another set taken just like
        previous sets except the scan mirror was set at an angle of
        31.84 degrees. Again exposures were set at 5 seconds for the
        first five, 10 seconds for the second five, and 15 seconds for
        the final fifteen. The first fourteen of the 15 second
        exposures were windowed, three at 51 x 51 pixels and one at 71
        x 71 pixels. The last image was a full frame. The pattern was
        not matched on ANY of the windowed images. So we were left with
        only one image, number 800, and that had severe scattered light
        problems.
 
      2003 DEC 13 05:59:59 -- Images 801-825
      --------------------------------------
        This set of images, 801 to 825, was another set taken just like
        previous sets except the scan mirror was set at an angle of
        31.43 degrees and the final image was also windowed. Again
        exposures were set at 5 seconds for the first five, 10 seconds
        for the second five, and 15 seconds for the final fifteen. All
        25 exposures were windowed, three windows at 51 x 51 pixels and
        one at 71 x 71 pixels. The pattern was not matched on any of
        the first 24 images. So we were left with only one properly
        pattern matched image, number 825, which showed the comet quite
        clearly.
 
      2003 DEC 14 12:00:00 -- Images 826-850
      --------------------------------------
        This set of images, 826 to 850, was another set taken just like
        earlier sets, except the scan mirror was set at an angle of
        30.63 degrees and the final image again was windowed. Again
        exposures were set at 5 seconds for the first five, 10 seconds
        for the second five, and 15 seconds for the final fifteen. All
        25 exposures were windowed, three windows at 51 x 51 pixels and
        one at 71 x 71 pixels. One image, 835, was missing many
        packets. Two windows were missing entirely and the third was
        only partially present. The pattern was matched on only five
        images, 831, 833, 839, 847, and 850.
 
      2003 DEC 15 12:00:00 -- Images 851-853
      --------------------------------------
        Realizing the poor yield of the pattern matching program with
        small windows, it was decided to use fewer but much larger
        windows, 201 x 201, and not to attempt pattern matching. Image
        851 utilized three of these much larger windows. Image 852 used
        two 201 x 201 windows and one 1 x 1 image, which significantly
        reduced the amount of data to be returned. Image 853 once again
        used three 201 x 210 windows. All were 15 second exposures at
        30.69 degrees scan mirror setting, and all showed the comet.
 
      2003 DEC 16 05:00:00 -- Images 854-856
      --------------------------------------
        The December 16 set of Op Nav images was composed of three 201
        x 201 pixel windows, 854, 855, and 856. These were all 15
        second exposures at a scan mirror angle of 30.29 degrees. The
        only significant problem was that the bad columns, that first
        appeared in image 701, fell right across two of the windows,
        which were set a bit too far to the right in the frame.
 
      2003 DEC 17 05:00:00 -- Images 857-859
      --------------------------------------
        The December 17 set of Op Nav images was composed once again of
        two 201 x 201 pixel windows and one 1 x 1 pixel window. These
        are numbered as windows 857, 858, and 859. All were 15 second
        exposures at a scan mirror angle of 29.65 degrees. All were
        properly placed, with the bad columns now falling between
        windows.
 
      2003 DEC 18 04:00:00 -- Images 860-876
      --------------------------------------
        The sequence of December 18 was meant to serve two purposes.
        The first 14 full frame uncompressed images were meant to
        photometrically calibrate the camera for the encounter, now
        only two weeks off. Images 860 and 873 are bias frames. Images
        861 through 869 were off periscope images taken at a scan
        mirror setting of 23.98 degrees. Images 870, 871, and 872
        included the periscope in the light path with the scan mirror
        set at 0.20 degrees. The final three frames, 874, 875, and 876
        were meant to further understand periscope use when it included
        light both through the periscope and around it. The sad thing
        is that none of these images were of significant use. All
        contained many thousands of hot pixels as well as a generally
        high background level. The camera electronics had been left
        turned on to prevent possible failure due to excessive on and
        off cycles, the time when most electronics fail, if they are
        going to do so. Hereafter the electronics were turned off when
        not in use, and everything worked just fine. There was now no
        time for an additional photometric calibration before
        encounter, so it was decided to go with just the planned
        post-encounter photometric calibration.
 
      2003 DEC 19 12:00:00 -- Images 877-879
      --------------------------------------
        Images 877 through 879 were once again for optical navigation.
        These images all used 15 second exposures with the scan mirror
        set at 28.40 degrees. Wild 2 was now quite easy to see on each
        individual frame.
 
      2003 DEC 20 12:00:00 -- Images 880-882
      --------------------------------------
        Images 880 through 882 were once again for optical navigation.
        These images all used 15 second exposures with the scan mirror
        set at 27.88 degrees. Wild 2 was now quite easy to see on each
        individual frame.
 
      2003 DEC 21 11:59:59 -- Images 883-885
      --------------------------------------
        Images 883 through 885 were once again for optical navigation.
        These images all used 15 second exposures with the scan mirror
        set at 27.25 degrees. Wild 2 is now quite easy to see on each
        individual frame.
 
      2003 DEC 22 03:59:59 -- Images 886-889
      --------------------------------------
        Images 886, 887, and 888 were again for optical navigation.
        Image 889 does not exist for unknown reasons. These images all
        used 15 second exposures with the scan mirror set at 26.96
        degrees. All continued to use three 201 x 201 pixel windowing.
 
      2003 DEC 24 03:00:44 -- Images 890-906
      --------------------------------------
        Images 890 through 906 were still taken for optical navigation.
        All images were taken with a 20 second exposure at a scan
        mirror angle of 24.10 degrees. All consist of three windows,
        now 301 x 301 pixels in size.
 
      2003 DEC 25 02:00:44 -- Images 907-924
      --------------------------------------
        Images 907 through 924 were still taken for optical navigation.
        All images were taken with a 20 second exposure at a scan
        mirror angle of 24.10 degrees. All were meant to consist of
        three windows, again 301 x 301 pixels in size. Image 907 does
        not exist. Images 908, 909, and 910 are all incomplete,
        consisting in each case of a single incomplete window. The
        remainder of the images are very good normal frames. Since new
        data were being taken every day, no attempt was made to
        retransmit the incomplete images.
 
      2003 DEC 26 03:00:45 -- Images 925-942
      --------------------------------------
        Images 925 through 942 were still taken for optical navigation.
        All images were taken with a 20 second exposure at a scan
        mirror angle of 23.57 degrees. All were meant to consist of
        three windows, again 301 x 301 pixels in size. Image 925 does
        not exist. Images 927 through 930 are also missing for unknown
        reasons. The remainder, 931 through 942 are excellent. Again no
        attempt was made to retransmit the missing images, if in fact
        they ever existed. So many images were being taken that it was
        pretty easy to lose track of which had and which had not been
        taken. It was always much safer to skip a few numbers than to
        give two images the same number.
 
      2003 DEC 26 16:00:00 -- Images 943-960
      --------------------------------------
        This set of images made up the second optical navigation
        sequence of December 26, as optical navigation prepared for the
        final TCMs, if they proved necessary. They are images 943
        through 960, consisting of 20 second exposures at a scan mirror
        angle of 23.30 degrees. Each consisted of three 301 x 301
        windows. All turned out quite well.
 
      2003 DEC 28 02:01:30 -- Images 961-978
      --------------------------------------
        Following a day ``off&apos;&apos; when an additional heating cycle was
        carried out for a decontamination of the camera, optical
        navigation images were resumed, images which also determined
        the then current state of the camera. Images 961 and 962 appear
        not to exist. Image 963 appears to consist of one window with
        many missing packets. Images 964 and 965 have single partial
        windows, each with many missing packets. Image 967 consists of
        two windows, only one of which is complete, but the complete
        window does contain a usable image of the comet. Images 966
        and 968 through 978 have the normal three windows of 301 x 301
        pixels. Three of these have 20 second exposures and nine were
        given 10 second exposures. All were taken with the scan mirror
        at 22.49 degrees.
 
      2003 DEC 29 05:00:00 -- Images 979-996
      --------------------------------------
        In the series of images 979 through 996, only 983 and 984 are
        missing packets. All images were acquired at a scan mirror
        angle of 21.87 degrees. Images 979 through 982 and 985 through
        987 were given 20 second exposures, while 988 through 996
        received 10 second exposures. All complete images had three 301
        x 301 pixel windows.
 
      2003 DEC 30 05:27:15 -- Images 997-1014
      ---------------------------------------
        Images 997 through 999 were missing the first packet, thereby
        ruining each entire image. In this hectic period, no attempt
        was made to reconstruct them. Image 1000 consisted of one
        normal 301 x 301 pixel window and two 1 x 1 pixel windows. The
        image of Wild2 was in one of the latter. Images 1001 through
        1014 were normal, each having three 301 x 301 windows. The
        first five good frames received 20 second exposures, and the
        last nine were all 10 second exposures. These, of course, were
        again taken for optical navigation purposes.
 
      2003 DEC 30 22:35:15 -- Images 1015-1032
      ----------------------------------------
        The second set of December 30 images probably included 1015
        through 1021, which are missing. I say this because there are
        only two images with 20 second exposures instead of the usual
        nine. The two 20 second images are 1022 and 1023. These are
        followed by 1024 through 1032, which are 10 second exposures.
        All were taken at a scan mirror angle of 21.00 degrees and with
        three 301 x 301 pixel windows.
 
      2003 DEC 31 07:00:00 -- Images 1033-1050
      ----------------------------------------
        Images 1033 through 1050 constituted the first set of December
        31 exposures. All were taken at a scan mirror angle of 20.77
        degrees and with three 301 x 301 pixel windows. The first nine
        were 20 second exposures and the second nine were 10 second
        exposures.
 
      2003 DEC 31 20:18:00 -- Images 1051-1058
      ----------------------------------------
        The second set of December 31 images consisted of eight images
        numbered 1051 through 1058. The first four were 15 second
        exposures, the second four 10 seconds. All utilized a scan
        mirror of 24.49 degrees. Each consisted of three windows of 291
        x 291 pixels.
 
      2004 JAN 01 00:18:00 -- Images 1059-1066
      ----------------------------------------
        The first set of January 1 images, 1059 through 1066, were
        taken at a scan mirror angle of 24.49 degrees. All were
        windowed images using three 291 x 291 pixels with a scan mirror
        angle of 24.49 degrees. The first four were 15 second
        exposures, the second four, 10 second exposures.
 
      2004 JAN 01 05:18:00 -- Images 1067-1074
      ----------------------------------------
        The second set of January 1 images, 1067 through 1074, were
        also taken at a scan mirror angle of 24.49 degrees. All were
        windowed images using three 291 x 291 pixels with a scan mirror
        angle of 24.49 degrees. The first four were 15 second
        exposures, the second four, 10 second exposures.
 
      2004 JAN 01 08:18:00 -- Images 1075-1082
      ----------------------------------------
        The third set of January 1 images, 1075 through 1082, once
        again were taken at a scan mirror angle of 24.49 degrees. All
        were windowed images using three 291 x 291 pixels with a scan
        mirror angle of 24.49 degrees. The first four were 15 second
        exposures, the second four, 10 second exposures.
 
      2004 JAN 01 12:18:00 -- Images 1083-1090
      ----------------------------------------
        The fourth set of January 1 images, 1083 through 1090, once
        again were taken at a scan mirror angle of 24.49 degrees. All
        were windowed images using three 291 x 291 pixels with a scan
        mirror angle of 24.49 degrees. The first four were 15 second
        exposures, the second four, 10 second exposures.
 
      2004 JAN 01 16:18:00 -- Images 1091-1098
      ----------------------------------------
        The fifth set of January 1 images, 1091 through 1098, once
        again were taken at a scan mirror angle of 24.49 degrees. All
        were windowed images using three 291 x 291 pixels with a scan
        mirror angle of 24.49 degrees. The first four were 15 second
        exposures, the second four, 10 second exposures.
 
      2004 JAN 01 21:18:44 -- Images 1099-1106
      ----------------------------------------
        The sixth set of January 1 images, 1099 through 1106, were
        taken at a scan mirror angle of 24.49 degrees. All were
        windowed images using three 291 x 291 pixel windows. Image 1099
        was missing. Image 1100 had two windows, but only the image
        containing the comet was complete. Images through 1102 were 15
        second exposures, the last four were 10 second exposures.
 
      2004 JAN 02 05:18:44 -- Images 1107-1122
      ----------------------------------------
        Images 1107 through 1115, one complete set, are missing. The
        final set of optical navigation images, numbered 1116 through
        1122, were acquired using three 291 x 291 pixel windows and a
        scan mirror angle of 24.49 degrees. The first three utilized 15
        second exposures and the final four 10 second exposures.
 
      2004 JAN 02 18:54:28 -- Images 2000-2115 -- Wild 2 Encounter Set
      ----------------------------------------------------------------
        Images 2005 through 2115 are the 81P/Wild 2 encounter set.
        There are 72 complete images in this set, the missing numbers
        having been used only to establish the auto-tracking on the
        nucleus. There was sufficient memory only for the 72 images. It
        is the nature of the shutter that alternate exposures are 1.65
        milliseconds shorter than the set exposure time. The even
        numbered images are the shorter ones taken during the
        encounter. We were quite limited in the number of changes that
        could be made in the exposure time, so most were taken at
        settings of either 100 milliseconds (actually 98.35
        milliseconds) or 10 milliseconds. Many of the longer exposures
        were saturated, but these serve very well to bring out the many
        jets of gas and dust ejected by the comet. Scan mirror angles
        ranged from 1.37 degrees for image 2005 through 176.05 degrees
        for image 2115. The images with the mirror at more than 170
        degrees all exhibit a great deal of scattered light, probably
        from the sample return capsule. There are lesser amounts of
        scattered light on images back to about 160 degrees. There is a
        problem with images taken near 0 degrees as well, from light
        scattered from the launch vehicle adapter ring which actually
        occludes a bit of the periscope.
 
      2004 JAN 13 02:24:28 -- Images 2116-2130
      ----------------------------------------
        Images 2116 through 2130 were taken to attempt to calibrate all
        of the images, to check the post-encounter state of the
        periscope, and to check the calibration lamp, which appeared to
        have failed pre-encounter. Images 2116 and 2129 were bias
        frames. Images 2117 through 2125 constituted the very limited
        calibration set. Images 2126 through 2128 were for the
        periscope check, and 2130 was the calibration lamp check. The
        calibration images all were taken at scan mirror angles near 24
        degrees, four with 1 second exposures, four with 5 second
        exposures and one with a 15 second exposure. All were
        uncompressed full frame images. The periscope checks were done
        at an angle of -0.10 degrees and were full of scattered light.
        This was expected to some extent, but the very mottled
        appearance of the images indicated that one or both mirrors of
        the periscope were thoroughly sandblasted by the passage
        through the Wild 2 coma. The check of the calibration lamp
        unfortunately was done with a 1 second exposure rather than 20
        milliseconds. It was obviously working just fine, since every
        pixel in the frame was saturated.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      The images in this data set were created by the DMAPKTDECOM
      program developed by Applied Coherent Technology Corp, Herndon,
      Virginia and operated by the Stardust Data Management and Archive
      Team at JPL, Pasadena, California. This program assembled images
      from raw telemetry packets sent down by the spacecraft and
      populated the images labels with housekeeping values, decommutated
      the binary image headers, and computed geometry parameters using
      SPICE kernels. This program did not apply correction of any kind
      to the image data.
 
      In the cases when only certain sections of the detector were
      downlinked, the program filled the pixels in the image
      corresponding to the areas for which data had not been downlinked
      with hex null values (i.e., zeroes). In such images window
      objects were used to define the areas containing non-null data.
 
      The images were converted from PDS format into FITS format at
      the PDS Small Bodies Node.  For the images that originally
      consisted of window objects, the window data has been embedded
      into full-frame images, with regions that were not downlinked
      set to zero.  During the conversion process, the overscan pixels
      on both sides of the images were recovered from the IMG
      files. (For consistency, the overscan regions were inserted into
      the windowed images, though their pixel values are set to zero.)
      Also, the orientation set up so that the images are properly
      oriented when displayed as defined by the LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION
      and SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION keywords, and the twist angle was
      corrected to conform to the PDS definition.
 
    Data
    ====
 
      The images in this data set were originally produced in standard
      PDS format, and then converted to FITS format. Each file
      includes a detached PDS label.  The label also describes the
      circumstances surrounding the collection of the calibration
      image.
 
      Camera Description
      ------------------
        The camera has a 1024x1024 array as the active portion of the
        CCD. The images that are stored on this volume, however, contain
        more than just the active portion of the CCD. Each line contains
        a sync pattern, a line counter, 12 baseline stabilization pixels,
        the 1024 pixels from the active portion of the CCD, and finally 8
        over-clock pixels used to measure the quantum efficiency. The
        number of rows for each image is always 1024, no matter what
        compression mode is used, but the number of columns for each
        image depends on the compression mode used.
 
      Compression Modes
      -----------------
        The NAVCAM images can be either 8-bit or 12-bit data. The 12-bit
        data is commonly referred to as &apos;uncompressed data&apos;, while the
        8-bit is referred to as &apos;compressed data&apos;. This compression is
        accomplished by a 12-bit to 8-bit square-root look-up-table
        compression method, which is implemented in the hardware of the
        camera electronics. This compression is lossy and the estimate of
        the 12-bit image can be recovered using the look-up table
        mentioned in Appendix 3 of the Calibration Document. Both the
        image and histogram portions of the data file require different
        amounts of storage space, dependent on the compression mode used.
 
        In uncompressed mode with 12-bit data, the pixels are expressed
        in two bytes, as 16 bits per pixel. The upper nibble of the most
        significant byte is always zero for these images.
 
        During the conversion to FITS format, all of the images were
        stored as 16-bit integers.  A record of whether the original
        data were compressed or not is retained in the
        COMPRESSION_TYPE keyword in the PDS labels (COMPRESS in the
        FITS header).  A value of &apos;8_BIT&apos; indicates the 8-bit data, and
        a value of &apos;NONE&apos; denotes uncompressed images.
 
 
      Exposure Durations
      ------------------
        The double-bladed shutter utilized by the camera has a delay
        in its slide mechanism that introduces an offset in the actual
        exposure time, compared to the commanded exposure time.
        During the recalibration of the NAVCAM as part of the Stardust
        NExT mission, it was determined that the original information
        about the exposure time offsets and the forward/reverse
        shutter parity were incorrect.  In this version (2.0) the
        images have been corrected to account for the updated
        information.  See the file SHUTTER_CORRECTION.ASC in the
        documents directory for more information.
 
 
      Target Name in the Image Labels
      -------------------------------
        The target name in the image labels was set only for the images
        where the target is either seen in the image or computed to be
        within the camera field of view. For all other images the target
        name was set to ``CALIBRATION FIELD&apos;&apos;.
 
        Consequently the label geometry items pertaining to the target
        -- spacecraft-target position, velocity and distance, pixel
        scales, and phase angle -- are only supplied for the images
        where target name is not ``CALIBRATION FIELD&apos;&apos; and were computed
        for that specified target.
 
      Windowed Images
      ---------------
        The IMAGE size parameter in the image label reflects the size
        of the detector, however in some cases data from only certain
        sections of the detector were downlinked. In  these cases the
        pixels in the image corresponding to the areas for which data
        had not been downlinked are filled with hex null values (i.e.,
        zeroes).
 
      Noise in the Images
      -------------------
        If the images are stretched to the limit, regular wide
        horizontal stripes appear in every image at the level of 1 to 2
        dn above background. These appear to be the product of coherent
        noise somewhere in the data stream or from a power supply.
        Their source is unknown.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
 
      The geometry items included in the image labels were computed
      using the following SPICE kernels archived in the Stardust SPICE
      data set, SDU-C-SPICE-6-V1.0:
 
         Kernel Type   File Name
         ------------  ---------------------
         LSK           naif0008.tls
         PCK           pck00007.tpc
         PCK           sdu_wild2_v01.tpc
         SCLK          sdu_sclkscet_00141.tsc
         FK            sdu_v20.tf
         IK            sdu_navcam_v22.ti
         SPK           sdu_l_2003_w2.bsp
         SPK           sdu_l_2004.bsp
         SPK           sdu_w2_opnav.bsp
         CK (s/c)      sdu_sc_rec_2003_w2_v2.bc
         CK (s/c)      sdu_sc_rec_2004_v2.bc
         CK (s/c)      sdu_sc_rec_w2_opnav.bc
         CK (camera)   sdu_nc_rec_v2.bc
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
 
      Geometric Parameter Reference Frame
      -----------------------------------
        Earth Mean Equator and Vernal Equinox of J2000 is the inertial
        reference system used to specify observational geometry items
        provided in the image labels. Geometric parameters are based on
        best available SPICE data at time of image creation.
 
      Epoch of Geometric Parameters
      -----------------------------
        All geometric parameters provided in the image labels were
        computed at the epoch specified in the START_TIME label field.
 
      Image Orientation and Geometry
      ------------------------------
        In version 1.0 of this data set, the image orientation was
        was flipped from what would be seen by an actual observer.  In
        addition, the TWIST_ANGLE that was given did not correspond to
        the definition in the PDS Data Dictionary.  Both of these
        inconsistencies have been corrected in this version of the
        data.  When displayed as defined in the
        SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION and LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION keywords,
        the image would appear as it would to an in situ observer, and
        the TWIST_ANGLE corresponds to the definition given in the PDS
        Data Dictionary.  Additional keywords have been added to the
        FITS header to better define the geometry, including the
        Celestial and Ecliptic North clock angles and the projected
        sunward vector clock angle.
        In this version, all geometric parameters have been recomputed
        using the most recent SPICE kernels (listed above)
 
 
    Software
    ========
 
      The images in this data set are in standard FITS format and,
      therefore, can be viewed by any standardized FITS reader.  For
      this reason no special software is provided with this data set.
 
 
    Contact Information
    ===================
 
      For any questions regarding the data in this archive,
      contact the SBN:
 
        Tony L. Farnham
        Phone: +1 (301)  405-3856
        Electronic mail address: farnham@astro.umd.edu
 
        Department of Astronomy
        University of Maryland
        College Park, MD 20742
        USA
 
      or Stardust Data Management and Archive Team (SDMA):
 
        Charles H. Acton, Jr.
        Phone: +1 (818) 354-3869
        Electronic mail address: Charles.Acton@jpl.nasa.gov
 
        Boris V. Semenov
        Phone: +1 (818) 354-8136
        Electronic mail address: Boris.Semenov@jpl.nasa.gov
 
        MAIL STOP 301-125L
        Jet Propulsion Laboratory
        California Institute of Technology
        4800 Oak Grove Drive
        Pasadena, CA, 91109-8099
        USA
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
 
      During the processing of the image data in preparation for
      delivery with this volume, the structure of each image was
      verified. This verification included detection of both the sync
      word and the line count bytes at the beginning of each line.
 
 
    Review
    ======
 
      The images have been reviewed and validated by the imaging team
      members as well as by the other project teams -- Optical
      Navigation Team (OPNAV) and Data Management and Archive Team
      (DMA.)
 
      This dataset will be peer reviewed in October 2009.
 
 
    Missing Data
    ============
 
      Due to the operational constraints on telemetry playback, some of
      the pre-encounter images taken by the camera could not have been
      reconstructed due to incomplete set of packets and, therefore,
      are not present in this data set. Specifically an image could not
      have been reconstructed if its first packet was missing or if
      it was a windowed image and any packet was missing.
 
      The images missing from this data set are:
 
        Image Number(s)   Reason for Absence
        ---------------   -----------------------------------------
             532          Missing first packet
             556          Windowed image missing some packets
             835          Windowed image missing some packets
             875          Windowed image missing some packets
             889          Missing first packet
             907          Missing first packet
           908-910        Windowed image missing some packets
             925          Missing first packet
           927-930        Missing most/all packets
           963-965        Windowed image missing some packets
             967          Windowed image missing some packets
             984          Windowed image missing some packets
           997-999        Missing first packet
            1000          Windowed image missing some packets
          1015-1021       Missing most/all packets
            1115          Missing first packet
 
      For the encounter the image counter was reset to 2000 (from
      1122). In the encounter image number range (2000 through 2115)
      the missing numbers having been used for axillary images, that
      were intended to establish the auto-tracking of the nucleus.
      Since there was sufficient memory only for the 72 images, these
      additional auto-tracking images have not been recorded on board
      and are not considered missing.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

