<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.vl1-vl2-m-lr-2-edr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>VL1/VL2 MARS LABELED RELEASE V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.viking::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vl1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vl2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:lr1.vl1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:lr2.vl2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vl1-vl2-m-lr-2-edr-v1.0__browserp_vl1_vl2-m-lr-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vl1-vl2-m-lr-2-edr-v1.0__dvo_geo_vl1_vl2-m-lr-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Levin, G.V., and P.A. Straat, Viking Labeled Release biology experiment:
                   Interim results, Science, 194, 1322-1328, 1976.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEVIN-STRAAT1976B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Levin, G.V., and P.A. Straat, Recent results from the Viking Labeled
                   Release experiment on Mars, J. Geophys. Res., 82, 4663-4667, 1977.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEVIN-STRAAT1977A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Levin, G.V., and P.A. Straat, Life on Mars? The Viking Labeled Release
                   experiment, BioSystems, 9, 165-174, 1977.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEVIN-STRAAT1977B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Levin, G.V., and P.A. Straat, Completion of the Viking Labeled Release
                   experiment on Mars, J. Mol. Evol., 14, 167-183, 1979.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEVIN-STRAAT1979A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Levin, G.V., and P.A. Straat, Laboratory Simulations of the Viking Labeled
                   Release Experiment: Kinetics following second nutrient injection and the
                   nature of the gaseous end product, J. Mol. Evol., 14, 185-197, 1979.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEVIN-STRAAT1979B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Levin, G.V., and P.A. Straat, A search for a nonbiological explanation of
                   the Viking Labeled Release life detection experiment, Icarus, 45, 494-516,
                   1981.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEVIN-STRAAT1981A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Levin, G.V., and P.A. Straat, Antarctic soil no. 726 and implications for
                   the Viking Labeled Release experiment, J. Theor. Biol., 9, 41-45, 1981.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEVIN-STRAAT1981B</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>VL1/VL2-M-LR-2-EDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>VL1/VL2 MARS LABELED RELEASE V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2000-10-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1976-07-22T21:54:23Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>GILBERT V. LEVIN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Levin, G. V., P. A. Straat, E. A. Guinness, P. G. Valko, J. H.
            King, and D. R. Williams, VL1/VL2 MARS LABELED RELEASE V1.0,
            VL1/VL2-M-LR-2-EDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2000
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Viking Lander Labeled Release Data Set contains results of
            the experiment to test for the presence of heterotrophic
            metabolism due to microbial organisms in the soil.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Labeled Release (LR) instrument on each Viking Lander
            operated throughout the Primary Mission and continued into the
            Extended Mission. The basic analysis cycle for the Labeled
            Release experiment was to deliver a sample of martian soil to one
            of four test cells, seal the cell and moisten the soil with an
            aqueous solution of carbon-14 labeled organic media. A second
            nutrient injection was typically done about 7-8 Mars days after
            the first injection. The test cell was continuously monitored for
            the release of radioactive labeled gas as an indicator of
            heterotrophic metabolism. Viking Lander 1 (VL1) conducted four
            analysis cycles with two nutrient injections for cycles 1, 2, and
            4 and three injections for cycle 3. Viking Lander 2 (VL2)
            conducted five analysis cycles. The first four cycles had two
            nutrient injections each, and the fifth cycle had one injection
            [LEVIN&amp;STRAAT1976B
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The Labeled Release (LR) instrument on each Viking Lander
    operated throughout the Primary Mission and continued into the
    Extended Mission.  The basic analysis cycle for the Labeled
    Release experiment was to deliver a sample of martian soil to one
    of four test cells, seal the cell and moisten the soil with an
    aqueous solution of carbon-14 labeled organic media.  A second
    nutrient injection was typically done about 7-8 Mars days after
    the first injection.  The test cell was continuously monitored
    for the release of radioactive labeled gas as an indicator of
    heterotrophic metabolism.  Viking Lander 1 (VL1) conducted four
    analysis cycles with two nutrient injections for cycles 1, 2, and
    4 and three injections for cycle 3.  Viking Lander 2 (VL2)
    conducted five analysis cycles.  The first four cycles had two
    nutrient injections each, and the fifth cycle had one injection
    [LEVIN&amp;STRAAT1976B; LEVIN&amp;STRAAT1977A; LEVIN&amp;STRAAT1979A].
 
    Data collected by the LR instruments included radioactivity
    counts from evolved carbon-14 labeled gas and temperatures of the
    detectors and the headspace (i.e., the volume of test cell above
    the sample).  Radioactivity was counted for 16-minute intervals
    during an analysis cycle, except for several hours around the
    time of nutrient injection where intervals of 2- to 4-minutes
    were used.  Detector and headspace temperatures were measured at
    16-minute intervals throughout the cycle.
 
    The Labeled Release data were originally archived on microfilm
    housed at NSSDC.  These data were combined with the other two
    Viking Lander biology data sets on the microfilm.  A second
    source for the LR data was a set of computer printouts from the
    personal archives of Co-Investigator Dr.  Patricia Ann Straat.
    The data in this PDS archive were keypunched into a set of
    digital files from these two sources with the Straat printouts
    being the primary source used.
 
    The LR experiment included an extensive test program that not
    only tested the operating characteristics of the LR instrument,
    but also analyzed many terrestrial samples for comparison with
    the Mars results.  These test data are not currently part of the
    PDS Labeled Release archive.  However, many of the terrestrial
    sample analyses have been published in the scientific literature
    [e.g., LEVIN&amp;STRAAT1981A; LEVIN&amp;STRAAT1981B; LEVIN&amp;STRAAT1979B;
    LEVIN&amp;STRAAT1977B; LEVIN&amp;STRAAT1976A].
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The Labeled Release data set comprises three basic data
    measurements: radioactivity counts, detector temperature, and
    headspace temperature.  Measurements are tagged with the time
    they were made and are stored in a time-ordered format.
 
    RADIOACTIVITY COUNTS: Radioactivity in the Labeled Release data
    set are given as counts/minute.  Counting was generally done over
    a 16-minute period and then normalized by the length of the
    counting interval to determine the average number of
    counts/minute within that interval.  Each LR instrument had two
    solid-state beta detectors and could be commanded to use either
    one or both detectors.  In cases where only one detector was
    used, radioactivity values were corrected to values equivalent to
    counting with both detectors.  See the Analysis Cycle Section for
    the specific correction factors used in each cycle.  The LR
    detectors recorded a significant background signal from the two
    Radioisotope Thermoelectric Generators (RTGs) that powered the
    Viking Landers.  Background levels were determined from
    radioactivity measurements made for several Mars days at the
    start of an analysis cycle.  These background measurements are
    stored in a separate data file within the set of files for a
    given cycle.  In addition, radioactivity values with and without
    background correction are provided for measurements made during
    the incubation period of an analysis cycle.
 
    TEMPERATURES: Both detector and headspace temperatures in the
    Labeled Release data set are given in degrees Celsius.
    Temperatures were measured every 16-minutes throughout an
    analysis cycle.  Sample temperatures are less than those recorded
    by the headspace temperature sensor because the test cell heaters
    and temperature sensors are located at the top of the test cell
    above the sample.  See LEVIN&amp;STRAAT1977A for information on
    correlating headspace and sample temperatures.
 
    TIME: The primary time tag for the Labeled Release data set is
    known as Mars mission time.  It is defined as the number of Earth
    seconds past midnight of Sol 0, where Sol 0 is the day of
    landing.  All other time fields (e.g., local lander time and UTC)
    in the Labeled Release data files were derived from the Mars
    mission time (see Processing Section below).  One ancillary time
    field is what Viking scientists referred to as local lander time.
    Viking scientists used the format of sol number, hour, minute,
    and second for local time with times going beyond 24 hours
    because a Mars day is about 24 hours and 39 minutes.  This usage
    is different from the PDS standard usage of local lander time.
    As a result, this time format is called native time in the
    Labeled Release data files.  The files also include time fields
    of elapsed time since nutrient injection and since a specific Sol
    number.  These fields are included in the data files to allow
    easy plotting of the data in forms similar to previously
    published figures [e.g., LEVIN&amp;STRAAT1979A; LEVIN&amp;STRAAT1977A;
    LEVIN&amp;STRAAT1976B].
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    All radioactivity, temperature and Mars mission time data in this
    Labeled Release data set were keypunched by hand into a series of
    data files.  The primary data source was the copies of computer
    printouts supplied by P. A. Straat.  The NSSDC microfilm was used
    to recover data for gaps in the computer printouts.  Personnel at
    the PDS Geosciences Node did the keypunching of the computer
    printouts, whereas personnel at NSSDC transcribed the microfilm.
    All data entered by hand was checked for accuracy by an
    independent person.  However, typographical errors may still
    exist in the data set.  See the CONFIDENCE_LEVEL_NOTE for
    estimates of the data entry accuracy.
 
    All ancillary time fields in the LR data set were computed from
    the Mars mission time parameter.  Local lander time (native
    time), times since injections or a specific sol number were
    computed from Mars mission time using a value of 88,775.2140
    second/Sol.  The constant was determined to be consistent with
    values of Mars mission time and local lander time on the computer
    printouts of P. A. Straat.  UTC values were computed from the
    Mars mission time using a SPICE toolkit routine and a standard
    NAIF leap seconds kernel (NAIF0007.TLS).  The UTC value for
    midnight of Sol 0 was estimated from acquisition times of Viking
    Lander images taken on Sol 0 for each lander.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The Labeled Release data set consists of up to four tables for
    each analysis cycle.  Each table has an associated detached PDS
    label.  The tables include:
 
    (1) Background radioactivity counts
    (2) Detector temperatures
    (3) Headspace temperatures
    (4) Radioactivity counts during incubation
 
 
    (1) Background radioactivity counts
    -----------------------------------
      This table includes fields of raw radioactivity counts in
      counts/minute, channel number to indicate the left, right, or
      dual counting mode, Mars mission time, and several derived time
      fields (see PDS label).  These data were usually acquired for
      several Mars days prior to the first nutrient injection for a
      sample.  Counts were not corrected to dual channel mode if only
      one channel was counting.  Data are sorted in increasing Mars
      mission time order.
 
 
    (2) Detector temperatures
    -------------------------
      This table includes fields of detector temperature, Mars
      mission time, and several derived time fields (see PDS label).
      File usually includes temperatures measured during the
      background counting and incubation phases of an analysis cycle.
      Data are sorted in increasing Mars mission time order.
 
 
    (3) Headspace temperatures
    --------------------------
      This table includes fields of headspace temperature, Mars
      mission time, and several derived time fields (see PDS label).
      File usually includes temperatures measured during the
      background counting and incubation phases of an analysis cycle.
      Data are sorted in increasing Mars mission time order.
 
 
    (4) Radioactivity counts during incubation
    ------------------------------------------
      This table includes fields of raw and background-corrected
      radioactivity counts, channel number, Mars mission time, and
      several derived time fields (see PDS label).  Data usually
      start shortly before the first injection of an analysis cycle
      and continue until the purge sequence occurs.  The
      background-corrected field was derived from the raw
      radioactivity field by subtracting a constant background value
      determined from data collected prior to nutrient injection (see
      background radioactivity table).  Data collected in single
      channel mode were corrected to dual channel mode (using a
      constant multiplier) before background correction.  Data are
      sorted in increasing Mars mission time order.
 
 
  Analysis Cycles
  ===============
    A number of published papers describe the soil sampling and
    analysis rationale for the Labeled Release experiment, along with
    the scientific results [e.g., LEVIN&amp;STRAAT1979A;
    LEVIN&amp;STRAAT1977A; LEVIN&amp;STRAAT1976B].  A summary of the sampling
    and analysis strategy information from these papers is given here
    as a high-level description of the LR experiment.
 
 
    Viking Lander 1 Cycle 1
    -----------------------
      The sample for VL1 cycle 1 was acquired from a smooth patch of
      fine-grained material named Sandy Flats.  The sample came from
      the top 4 cm of the surface.  VL1 cycle 1 was performed
      autonomously according to preflight instructions.
 
      Sample Site             :  Sandy Flats
      Collection Temperature  :  -83 deg C
      Collection Sol          :  8 (fresh)
      Experiment Type         :  Active
      First Injection Sol     :  10
      Second Injection Sol    :  17
      Purge                   :  23
 
 
    Viking Lander 1 Cycle 2
    -----------------------
      This sample was acquired on Sol 8 (see VL1 cycle 1) from Sandy
      Flats and stored in the biology hopper for about 20 sols.
      Before nutrient incubation, this sample was heated to 160 deg C
      for about 3 hours to sterilize the sample as a control for
      comparison to VL1 cycle 1 results.
 
      Sample Site             :  Sandy Flats
      Collection Temperature  :  -83 deg C
      Collection Sol          :  8 (stored in hopper for 20 sols)
      Experiment Type         :  160 deg C control
      First Injection Sol     :  29
      Second Injection Sol    :  35
      Purge                   :  37
 
 
    Viking Lander 1 Cycle 3
    -----------------------
      The VL1 cycle 3 sample was also acquired from Sandy Flats close
      to the site of the first VL1 sample (cycles 1 and 2).  The
      sample came from the top 4-5 cm of the surface.  This analysis
      performed a long active incubation (about 50 sols).  The sample
      also received three injections of nutrient.
 
      Sample Site             :  Sandy Flats
      Collection Temperature  :  -21 deg C
      Collection Sol          :  36 (fresh)
      Experiment Type         :  Active, long incubation
      First Injection Sol     :  39
      Second Injection Sol    :  55
      Third Injection Sol     :  80
      Purge                   :  89
 
 
    Viking Lander 1 Cycle 4
    -----------------------
      This sample was collected during the Extended Mission from the
      same Sandy Flats area as the previous VL1 samples.  It was
      collected on Sol 91 and stored in the Biology hopper in the
      dark, open to the Mars atmosphere, and at temperatures between
      10 and 26 deg C until analysis started on Sol 230.  The
      original intent for this cycle was to collect a fresh sample,
      but concerns by the surface sampler team about possible damage
      to the sampler arm changed the scenario.  The two nutrient
      injections for this sample occurred about 4 hours apart.  It
      was calculated that enough nutrient remained in the reservoir
      for the two injections.  It is likely that a complete first and
      second injection occurred for this cycle [LEVIN&amp;STRAAT1979A].
 
      Sample Site             :  Sandy Flats
      Collection Temperature  :  -71 deg C
      Collection Sol          :  91 (stored)
      Experiment Type         :  Active
      First Injection Sol     :  232
      Second Injection Sol    :  232
      Purge                   :  250
 
 
    Viking Lander 2 Cycle 1
    -----------------------
      This sample was collected from a crusty to cloddy material in
      an area known as Beta.  The material came from the top 3.5 cm
      of the surface.  VL2 cycle 1 was performed autonomously
      according to preflight instructions.
 
      Sample Site             :  Beta
      Collection Temperature  :  -23 +/- 5 deg C
      Collection Sol          :  8 (fresh)
      Experiment Type         :  Active
      First Injection Sol     :  11
      Second Injection Sol    :  18
      Purge                   :  24
 
 
    Viking Lander 2 Cycle 2
    -----------------------
      The VL2 cycle 2 sample was collected from the same area of Beta
      as for VL2 cycle 1 sample.  It was a fresh sample collected on
      Sol 28.  The sample was heated in the test cell at about 50 deg
      C for 3 hours before the nutrient was injected.  The
      sterilization process was intented to serve as a control for
      comparison to cycle 1 results.
 
      Sample Site             :  Beta
      Collection Temperature  :  -23 +/- 5 deg C
      Collection Sol          :  28 (fresh)
      Experiment Type         :  51 deg C control
      First Injection Sol     :  34
      Second Injection Sol    :  38
      Purge                   :  47
 
 
    Viking Lander 2 Cycle 3
    -----------------------
      This sample was acquired from under a rock called Notch Rock.
      The rock was pushed aside to expose the soil.  The pushing
      occurred about 1 hour after sunrise and the soil was expose to
      low angle sunlight for approximately 37 minutes before delivery
      to the biology sample processor.  The intent of this sample was
      to analyze soil that was protected from ultraviolet radiation
      for a long period of time.  This analysis performed a long
      incubation of nearly 90 sols with two nutrient injections.
 
      Radioactivity data was collected in single channel mode for
      part of the beginning of this cycle.  Data were corrected to
      dual channel mode by multiplying by a factor of 1.95 prior to
      nutrient injection and a factor of 2.06 after the first
      injection.  A constant background value of 658.46 counts/minute
      was used for the entire cycle.
 
      Sample Site             :  Beneath Notch Rock
      Collection Temperature  :  -66 deg C
      Collection Sol          :  51 (fresh)
      Experiment Type         :  Active, long incubation
      First Injection Sol     :  53
      Second Injection Sol    :  60
      Purge                   :  140
 
 
    Viking Lander 2 Cycle 4
    -----------------------
      This sample was collected from the same general area as the
      samples for VL2 cycles 1 and 2 in the Beta location.  The
      material for this sample mostly came from the top 5 cm of the
      surface.  The sample may also contain material disturbed during
      the cycle 2 sample acquisition.  The sample was heated to 46
      deg C for about 3 hours before nutrient was injected.
 
      Sample Site             :  Beta
      Collection Temperature  :  -84 deg C
      Collection Sol          :  145 (fresh)
      Experiment Type         :  46 deg C, control
      First Injection Sol     :  147
      Second Injection Sol    :  161
      Purge                   :  171
 
 
    Viking Lander 2 Cycle 5
    -----------------------
      The original intent for VL2 cycle 5 was to incubate a fresh
      sample at sub-freezing temperatures to more closely simulate
      the actual Mars surface conditions.  A previously used test
      cell was required for this cycle because all four test cells
      had already been used.  A surface sampler anomaly during the
      sample acquisition attempt on Sol 195 prevented the collection
      of a fresh sample.  Thus, a previously stored sample collected
      on Sol 145 was used for VL2 cycle 5.  The sample was stored for
      84 sols in the hopper or LR test cell prior to nutrient
      injection.  The 0.5 cc sample was placed on top of about 1.2 cc
      of unused sample dumped into the cell from previous
      acquisitions plus about 0.5 cc of material from VL2 cycle 1.
 
      The LR instrument froze prior to nutrient injection during a
      power shutdown.  It is possible that nutrient delivery lines or
      valves may have ruptured due to freezing.  In addition, only a
      small amount of nutrient (0.64 cc) was calculated to remain in
      the reservoir.  These two facts suggest that complete nutrient
      delivery is uncertain, although as least a partial delivery is
      likely [LEVIN&amp;STRAAT1979A].
 
      Sample Site             :  Beta
      Collection Temperature  :  -84 deg C
      Collection Sol          :  145 (stored)
      Experiment Type         :  Soil-on-soil in used cell
      First Injection Sol     :  229
      Second Injection Sol    :  UNK
      Purge                   :  242
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The sources for the Labeled Release data were photocopies of
    Co-Investigator P. A.  Straat&apos;s original computer printouts and
    microfilm stored at NSSDC.  The P. A.  Straat computer printouts
    were used as the primary data source with the microfilm data used
    to fill in gaps.  The computer printout photocopy quality was
    good, yet there still existed a few values that were difficult to
    decipher.  The microfilm contained images of computer pages with
    variable quality.  Again, some values were difficult to decipher.
    For both data sources, information was manually entered by one
    person and then checked by a different individual.
 
    For VL2 Cycle 3, there was some data that were available in both
    sources.  A comparison of about 2000 radioactivity readings
    revealed a 0.25% error rate (5 values total) in NSSDC&apos;s keypunch
    and quality control process.  The errors found included a single
    digit miskeyed, two digits reversed, or fractional digits
    replaced with zeroes.  It is possible that the error rate is
    similar for data values where the microfilm is the only source.
    The data keypunched from the P. A.  Straat source was validated
    by entering both the raw and background-corrected values into a
    spread sheet program and automatically checking that the
    difference between the two values equaled the known constant
    background value.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    Steps were taken to insure that this data set is complete and
    contains as few errors as possible.  However, there are several
    data gaps.  Most data gaps are on the order of one or two
    sampling intervals, but some are on the order of Sols.  It would
    appear that these data were never taken or lost in transmission.
 
    The data set contains a few spikes of spurious readings.  These
    are usually obvious as a single data point that is very much
    larger than the values prior to and after the spike.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

