<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.go-a-mag-4-summ-gaspra-summary-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GALILEO ORBITER A MAG SUMM GASPRA SUMMARY V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.galileo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mag.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.gaspra::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-a-mag-4-summ-gaspra-summary-v1.0__browserp_go-a-mag-4-summ-gaspra-summary-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kivelson, M.G., K.K. Khurana, J.D. Means, C.T. Russell, and R.C. Snare, The
                   Galileo Magnetic Field Investigation, Space Science Reviews, 60, 1-4, 357, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KIVELSONETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kivelson, M., L. Bargatze, K. Khurana, D. Southwood, R. Walker, and P. Coleman,
                   Magnetic Field Signatures Near Galileo&apos;s Closest Approach to Gaspra, Science,
                   Vol. 261, pp. 331-334, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KIVELSONETAL1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Wang, Z., and M.G. Kivelson, Asteroid interaction with solar wind, J. Geophys.
                   Res., 101, 24479, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.WANG-KIVELSON1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GO-A-MAG-4-SUMM-GASPRA-SUMMARY-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GALILEO ORBITER A MAG SUMM GASPRA SUMMARY V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2004-05-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1991-10-29T06:03:20.834Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1991-10-30T02:51:03.452Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>MARGARET G. KIVELSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Kivelson, M.G., Khurana, K.K., Russell, C.T., Walker, R.J., Joy,
            S.P.,Green, J., GALILEO ORBITER A MAG SUMM GASPRA SUMMARY V1.0,
            GO-A-MAG-4-SUMM-GASPRA-SUMMARY-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2004
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Galileo Orbiter Magnetometer (MAG) calibrated averaged data from
            the Gaspra flyby in RTN coordinates. These data cover the
            interval 1991-10-29 06:03 to 1991-10-30 02:51.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Galileo Orbiter Magnetometer (MAG) calibrated averaged data from
            the Gaspra flyby in RTN coordinates. These data cover the
            interval 1991-10-29 06:03 to 1991-10-30 02:51.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Dataset Overview
  ================
    This dataset contains data acquired by the Galileo Magnetometer
    during the Gaspra flyby on Oct 29. 1991. The browse dataset has been
    created by averaging samples from the  7.68 kB Low Rate Science
    (LRS) tape record mode to 20 s second sampling and merging the data
    with the 8 RIM averages of the optimal averager to provide a
    continuous dataset for the encounter day. Limited space on the tape
    recorder forced the magnetometer team to limit their high time
    resolution observations to a few short intervals in the
    pre-encounter solar wind, a main record period near closest
    approach. The optimal averager section of the instrument (please see
    the instrument description) was configured to acquired 8 RIM (~8
    minute) averages to fill in the gaps between the recorded intervals.
    All of these data have been fully processed to remove instrument
    response function characteristics and interference from magnetic
    sources aboard the spacecraft. The magnetometer data are provided in
    heliographic (RTN) coordinates. Trajectory data have been provided
    as a separate archive product.
 
    Primary Dataset Reference:
 
      Kivelson, M.G., L.F. Bargatze,  K.K. Khurana, D.J. Southwood,
      R.J. Walker, P.J. Coleman, &apos;Magnetic Field Signatures Near
      Galileo&apos;s Closest Approach to Gaspra&apos;, Science, Vol. 261,
      p331-334, 16 July, 1993. [KIVELSONETAL1993]
 
      Wang, Z., and Kivelson, M.G., &apos;Asteroid interaction with solar
      wind&apos;, J. Geophys. Res., 101, 24479, 1996.
      [WANG&amp;KIVELSON1996]
 
    Primary Instrument Reference:
 
      Kivelson, M.G., K.K. Khurana, J.D. Means, C.T. Russell, and
      R.C. Snare, &apos;The Galileo magnetic field investigation&apos;, Space
      Science Reviews, 60, 1-4, 357, 1992. [KIVELSONETAL1992]
 
 
  Data
  ====
 
    ------------------------------------------------------------------
    Table 1. Data record structure, RTN Coordinates
    ------------------------------------------------------------------
    Column   Description
    ------------------------------------------------------------------
    time     S/C event time (UT) given in PDS time format
             YYYY-MM-DDThh:mm:ss.sssZ
    Br       Magnetic field radial component in RTN coordinates &lt;nT&gt;
    Bt       Magnetic field tangential component in RTN coordinates &lt;nT&gt;
    Bn       Magnetic field normal component in RTN coordinates &lt;nT&gt;
    Bmag     Average magnetic field magnitude &lt;nT&gt;
 
    Missing data value = 99999.999
    Fortran Format of the data file: (1X, A24, 4F11.3)
 
 
    Data Acquisition
    ----------------
      The data for this dataset were all acquired in by the outboard
      magnetometer sensors in the flip left mode in the low field mode
      (ULLR). This mode has a digitization step size of 0.0625
      nanoTesla. However, these data are acquired at 30 vectors/second
      and then recursively filtered in the instrument. The high rate
      data that are recorded to tape have a sample rate of 4.5
      vectors/second. If there is sufficient variation in the 6-7 input
      samples that make up a single output sample, then the effective
      digitization step size becomes much smaller. The long averages
      provided in the browse dataset should not show any quantization
      effects.
 
 
    Data Sampling
    -------------
      The high rate recorded data are not evenly sampled within a minor
      frame.  However, these data have been averaged using an averaging
      routine to produce evenly sampled data. The averaging process
      takes all available data during a 20 second period centered on the
      output time tag. Averages are not overlapping. The time tag gives
      the spacecraft event time (SCET) of the center of the averaging
      interval in universal time (UT).
 
      The optimal averager section of the instrument &apos;averages&apos; data by
      applying a recursive filter to onboard processed and despun data
      and then decimating the data at the appropriate sample times. This
      process is explained in detail in the &apos;cruise&apos; dataset that has
      been included with this archive product. The final processed
      product that has been incorporated into this dataset is sampled
      about every 8 minutes where the time tag marks the center of the
      averaging interval in SCET / UT.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    The data are provided in heliographic RTN (radial-tangential-normal)
    coordinates. The radial direction is taken along the instantaneous
    Sun-&gt;S/C line, positive away from the sun. The tangential direction
    is found by taking the cross product of the sun spin axis with the
    radial (T = Omega x R) direction.  Finally, the normal direction is
    the cross product of R and T (N = R x T).
 
    The magnetic field perturbation associated with the Gaspra flyby
    [KIVELSONETAL1993] is most easily understood in a coordinate system
    that is organized by the interplanetary magnetic field (IMF). The
    IMF coordinate system used by [KIVELSONETAL1993] to analyze the
    Gaspra flyby data takes data from the GaSE coordinate system and
    rotates about the Asteroid-Sun line (X) such that the average
    upstream IMF direction (between 22:30 and 22:33 UT) lies in the X-Y
    plane. This requires a righthanded rotation of 32.44 degrees about
    the GaSE X-axis to generate By_imf and Bz_imf from By_GaSe and
    Bz_GaSE.  An IMF coordinate system is only valid for a short
    interval near the time interval that defines the IMF direction.
    [KIVELSONETAL1993] uses this coordinate system only in the analysis
    of data acquired between 22:15 and 23:05 UT on the day of encounter
    (10/29/91).
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    A subset of the Galileo interplanetary cruise magnetometer dataset
    (GO-SS-MAG-4-SUMM-CRUISE-RTN-V1.0) has been supplied as an ancillary
    data product with this archive. The cruise data are provided to
    place the encounter data in context with large scale structures in
    the solar wind and IMF. These data are provided in RTN coordinates
    which is a standard coordinate system for solar wind data analysis.
    The time interval provided (9/10/91 - 11/24/91) spans roughly 3
    solar rotations centered on the asteroid flyby. These data show that
    the Gaspra encounter occurred in an &apos;away&apos; sector a day or so before
    a large field compression associated with a corotating interaction
    region.  The data are stored as an ASCII table in the file
    &apos;CRUISE.TAB&apos;. These data
 
 
    ------------------------------------------------------------------
    Table 2. Data record structure, RTN coordinates cruise data
    ------------------------------------------------------------------
    Column    Description
    ------------------------------------------------------------------
    time      S/C event time (UT) given in PDS time format
    sc_clk    S/C clock counter given in the form rim:mod91:mod10:mod8
    Br        Magnetic field radial component &lt;nT&gt;
    Bt        Magnetic field tangential component &lt;nT&gt;
    Bn        Magnetic field normal component &lt;nT&gt;
    Bmag      |B| Magnitude of B &lt;nT&gt;
    R         Radial distance of the spacecraft from the Sun &lt;AU&gt;
    LAT       Solar latitude of the spacecraft &lt;degrees&gt;
    LON       Solar east longitude of the spacecraft &lt;degrees&gt;
    avg_con   Onboard averaging interval for the magnetometer data
              &lt;RIM*&gt;
    delta     Magnetic inclination angle: delta=arcsin(Bn/Bmag)
              &lt;radians&gt;
    lambda    Magnetic azimuth angle: lambda = atan2(Bt/Br) &lt;radians&gt;
 
    * 1 RIM = 60.667 seconds (spacecraft major frame)
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The sources of error which are the most significant are those
    associated with magnetic sources aboard the spacecraft, especially
    those with temporal or spacecraft orientation variations. The next
    greatest contributor of error is the data from the AACS which
    affects our knowledge of the spacecraft orientation and hence
    rotates the magnetic field vector. Lastly, telemetry or software
    errors which produce &apos;spikes&apos; or bit errors in the data are error
    sources.
 
    In this dataset the magnetic sources associated with the spacecraft
    were fairly constant and magnetic field values are accurate to at
    least 0.01 nT.  The spacecraft orientation has been well determined
    and is known to better the 0.1 degree.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

