<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-e-v-h-mascs-3-uvvs-cdr-caldata-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER E/V/H MASCS 3 UVVS CALIBRATED DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mascs.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-3-uvvs-cdr-caldata-v1.0__browserp_mess-e-v-h-mascs-3-uvvs-cdr-caldata-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-3-uvvs-cdr-caldata-v1.0__browser_geo_mercury_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-3-uvvs-cdr-caldata-v1.0__browser_mess-e-v-h-mascs-3-uvvs-cdr-caldata-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-3-uvvs-cdr-caldata-v1.0__dvo_geo_mess-e-v-h-mascs-3-uvvs-cdr-caldata-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   McClintock, W.E., and M.R. Lankton, The Mercury Atmospheric and Surface
                   Composition Spectrometer for the MESSENGER mission, Space Science Reviews, 131,
                   481-521, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MCCLINTOCK-LANK2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-E/V/H-MASCS-3-UVVS-CDR-CALDATA-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESSENGER E/V/H MASCS 3 UVVS CALIBRATED DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-05-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-240T22:06:46Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-120T15:03:45Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>NOAM IZENBERG</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Izenberg, N., MESSENGER E/V/H MASCS 3 UVVS CALIBRATED DATA V1.0,
            MESS-E/V/H-MASCS-3-UVVS-CDR-CALDATA-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2008.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The MESSENGER MASCS UVVS calibrated observations consist of
            science and instrument data collected by the UVVS detector during
            cruise, flyby operations of Earth/Moon, Venus, and Mercury, and
            orbit operations of Mercury.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== This data set consists of the MESSENGER MASCS
            UVVS calibrated observations, also known as CDRs. The MASCS UVVS
            experiment is a scanning grating monochromator equipped with
            three photomultiplier tubes. There are three UVVS CDR data
            products, one for each detector, which cover the wavelength
            ranges of the far ultraviolet (FUV), middle ultraviolet (MUV),
            and visible (VIS).
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
   Data Set Overview
   =================
     This data set consists of the MESSENGER MASCS UVVS calibrated
     data records (CDRs). The UVVS experiment is equipped with three
     photomultiplier tubes, which are sensitive to three different
     wavelength ranges. Resulting spectra cover the wavelength ranges
     of the far ultraviolet (FUV)(115-190 nm), middle ultraviolet (MUV)
     (160-320 nm), and visible (VIS) (250-600 nm), with a resolution
     of 0.5 nm for the FUV channel and 1.0 nm for the MUV and VIS
     channels. There is a data overlap with VIRS in the VIS
     wavelength range.
 
     There are four standard UVVS data products: FUV data, MUV data,
     VIS data, and Housekeeping data. The housekeeping EDR contains
     instrument parameters that may be useful in analyzing the UVVS
     data. Housekeeping data are incorporated into the three standard
     CDR data products (one each for FUV, MUV, VIS). Each CDR product
     is comprised of a Header (HDR) file, showing the instrument
     command parameters for a given observation, and a Science (SCI)
     file showing counts, derived science data, and pointing
     information for each step of an observation.
 
   Instrument Overview
   ===================
     The MASCS instrument consists of a small Cassegrain telescope
     that simultaneously feeds the UVVS and VIRS experiments. The
     MASCS UVVS experiment is a scanning grating monochromator
     equipped with three photomultiplier tubes, providing spectral
     information in the far ultraviolet (115-190 nm), middle
     ultraviolet (160-320 nm), and visible (250-600 nm) wavelength
     ranges. The UVVS detector will help determine the global
     composition and structure of Mercury&apos;s exosphere by measuring
     emission from known species as well as search for new ones.
 
     See the INST.CAT file for more information and
     [MCCLINTOCK&amp;LANK2007] for full details.
 
   Parameters
   ==========
    The principal parameters when observing with the MASCS UVVS are as
    follows:
 
    * Start Position: The start position where the grating drive
    begins a scan.
 
    * Step Size: The step size in units of grating step. One grating
    step is equal to one arcmin. The wavelength delta of a single UVVS
    grating step is detector dependent. Wavelength and sensitivity
    tables are provided in the UVVS_EDR2CDR document, and the
    equations describing step wavelengths are provided in the
    MASCS_CAL_RPT document. These documents are located in the
    DOCUMENT directory.
 
    * Step Count: The number of steps the grating drive will take in a
    scan. The Step Count multiplied by the Step Size relates to the
    range of wavelengths that will be observed in one UVVS
    observation.
 
    * Integration Time: Integration time in grating drive loop control
    interrupt periods (nominally 3000 Hz).
 
    * Step Time: The step time in the grating drive loop control
    interrupt periods (nominally 3000 Hz).
 
    * Phase Offset: The phase offset between the beginning of the
    grating drive step and the start of a PMT integration in units of
    0.3 milliseconds. Default value is 0 (no phase offset). By setting
    the phase offset to a non-zero value (reserved for contingency
    operations), the user will tell the software to initiate a step
    before the end of an integration, accounting for latencies in the
    motor controller.
 
    * Number of Scan Cycles: The number of times to repeat a scan.
 
    * Zigzag Option: Indicates whether grating drive moves in a
    &apos;triangle&apos; (stepping up, then stepping down), or &apos;sawtooth&apos;
    (stepping up, then &apos;flying&apos; down) motion. A &apos;triangle&apos; observation
    takes one grating scan stepping up the grating, then reverses
    direction and takes the next grating scan stepping back down the
    grating. A &apos;sawtooth&apos; observation takes one grating scan stepping
    up the grating, then &apos;flies&apos; the grating back to the START_POSITION
    to take the next observation.
 
    * Compression: Selects between 16 bit data (uncompressed) or 9 bit
    data (compressed).
 
    * Slit Mask Position: Indicates whether the slit mask is in the
    atmospheric (open) or surface (closed) position. Atmospheric slit
    results in a 1 deg. by 0.04 deg. instantaneous field of view
    (iFOV). Surface slit results in a 0.05 deg. by 0.04 deg. iFOV.
 
    * FUV On: Select if the far ultraviolet photomultiplier tube is
    powered on or off.
 
    * MUV On: Select if the middle ultraviolet photomultiplier tube
    is powered on or off.
 
    * VIS On: Select if the visible photomultiplier tube is powered
    on or off.
 
   Calibration Overview
   ====================
     This data set consists of calibrated data derived from MASCS UVVS
     Experimental Data Records (EDR). The Science EDRs are the raw
     data records used to derive emission and reflectance data used
     for scientific analysis. The Science EDRs contain raw counts of
     the UVVS photomultiplier tubes (PMT) at the commanded step of the
     UVVS grating, which corresponds to a specific wavelength of
     light. Wavelength range and sensitivity of each PMT at each
     grating step vary, as documented in the MASCS Calibration Report,
     MASCS_CAL_RPT.PDF, provided in the DOCUMENT directory. Before the
     science data can be used for scientific analysis, the count rates
     in the EDRs must be converted to physical units and the data must
     be transformed into meaningful physical reference systems. This
     conversion yields calibrated data which are stored in Calibrated
     Data Records (CDRs). The processing steps from the EDR to the CDR
     level include:
 
     1. Determine wavelength and timing for each step of a given
        grating scan observation.
 
     2. Account for zig-zag scans if observation uses grating zig-zag.
 
     3. Apply empirical PMT temperature correction to dark counts.
 
     4. Remove solar scattering where possible.
 
     5. Correct for PMT nonlinearity.
 
     6. Apply PMT sensitivity for every step of every observation,
     convert counts to radiance at sensor.
 
     7. Determine pointing parameters (geometry fields calculated from
     SPICE) for every step of every observation. Surface pointing
     parameters are determined relative to the Mercury DEM.
 
     8. Assign data quality flags and indicators.
 
     The processing steps are detailed in the documents UVVS_CDR_DDR_SIS
     and UVVS_EDR2CDR, located in the DOCUMENT directory.
 
 
     FUV Calibration Update
 
     Observations of Spica and Sirius by the UVVS are used to correct
     errors in the ground calibration for FUV, MUV and VIS channels.
     Motivated by differences we see in our observations compared to
     observations of Spica with the UVS on the Venus Express mission,
     a more careful analysis of the original Spica data was performed
     in September 2013. The result is a small adjustment (~15%) to the
     radiometric sensitivity of the short wavelength portion of the FUV
     channel. The adjustment to the FUV channel was included in PDS
     delivery 11.
 
   Coordinate Systems
   ==================
 
     MASCS UVVS data are represented in the following coordinate
     systems:
 
     * Planetocentric body fixed: The MBF coordinate system is defined
     by the planetocentric position, Cartesian X, Y, Z coordinates
     related to the planetocentric distance, latitude measured
     positive northward from the equator, and longitude measured
     positive eastward from the prime meridian.
 
     * Cartographic: Surface observations use IAU planetocentric
     system with East longitudes being positive for planetary
     surfaces. The IAU2000 reference system for cartographic
     coordinates and rotational elements was used for computing
     latitude and longitude coordinates of planets.
 
   Data
   ====
 
     There are three UVVS CDR data products, one for each detector
     (FUV, MUV, VIS). Data from the MASCS housekeeping EDR product
     generated by the MASCS instrument, which is the same for both the
     UVVS and VIRS components of the MASCS experiment, are
     incorporated into the CDRs.
 
     The CDR for one of the three detectors consists of two files. The
     Header file (HDR) contains values for the instrument command
     parameters set that apply for the entirety of the observation
     encapsulated by the CDR. The Science file (SCI) data are the
     counts accumulated by the photomultiplier tube at a given
     position of the grating, in the order that the counts were
     collected. By using the values of the specific observing
     parameters that are related to the grating start position, number
     of grating steps, pattern of grating steps, and number of scans,
     each grating position can be determined and mapped to a specific
     wavelength. All other per-step information on counts, calibrated
     data, spacecraft time and orientation, target location, and other
     pointing parameters, are kept in the Science file.
 
     A separate CDR is created for each commanded scan set of one of
     the three detectors. Due to power considerations, a maximum of
     two photomultiplier tubes may record data at any given time; if
     two detectors acquire data simultaneously, two separate CDRs are
     still created. Data for the three UVVS detectors of the FUV, MUV,
     and VIS are always in separate EDRs.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
   Confidence Level Overview
   =========================
     The MASCS UVVS Calibrated Data Record (CDR) data released for the
     UVVS consists of the calibrated data converted to physical units
     and represented in physical coordinate systems. Data presented
     here are an accurate representation of the UVVS data as received
     from the spacecraft, and reflect the processing steps from the
     MASCS UVVS Experimental Data Records (EDRs) to CDR level detailed
     in the document UVVS_EDR2CDR located in the DOCUMENT directory.
     The UTC and MET time tags have been corrected for timing
     latencies in the instrument so that the UTC and MET correspond to
     the physical time of the observation.
 
   Review
   ======
     The UVVS CDR was reviewed internally by the MASCS team prior to
     release to the PDS. PDS also performed an external review of the
     MASCS UVVS CDRs (FUV, MUV and VIS photomultiplier tube (PMT) data
     each have separate CDR types).
 
   Data Coverage and Quality
   =========================
     Data reported are the calibrated data received from the
     spacecraft during the mission phases: Launch, Earth Cruise,
     Earth Flyby, Venus 1 Cruise, Venus 1 Flyby, Venus 2 Cruise,
     Venus 2 Flyby, Mercury 1 Cruise, Mercury 1 Flyby, Mercury 2
     Cruise, Mercury 2 Flyby, Mercury 3 Cruise, Mercury 3 Flyby,
     Mercury 4 Cruise, Mercury Orbit, Mercury Orbit Year 2,
     Mercury Orbit Year 3, Mercury Orbit Year 4, and Mercury Orbit
     Year 5. These mission phases are defined as:
 
                             Start time         End time
     Phase Name              Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)
     -----------------       -----------------  -----------------
     Launch                  03 Aug 2004 (216)  12 Sep 2004 (256)
     Earth Cruise            13 Sep 2004 (257)  18 Jul 2005 (199)
     Earth Flyby             19 Jul 2005 (200)  16 Aug 2005 (228)
     Venus 1 Cruise          17 Aug 2005 (229)  09 Oct 2006 (282)
     Venus 1 Flyby           10 Oct 2006 (283)  07 Nov 2006 (311)
     Venus 2 Cruise          08 Nov 2006 (312)  22 May 2007 (142)
     Venus 2 Flyby           23 May 2007 (143)  20 Jun 2007 (171)
     Mercury 1 Cruise        21 Jun 2007 (172)  30 Dec 2007 (364)
     Mercury 1 Flyby         31 Dec 2007 (365)  28 Jan 2008 (028)
     Mercury 2 Cruise        29 Jan 2008 (029)  21 Sep 2008 (265)
     Mercury 2 Flyby         22 Sep 2008 (266)  20 Oct 2008 (294)
     Mercury 3 Cruise        21 Oct 2008 (295)  15 Sep 2009 (258)
     Mercury 3 Flyby         16 Sep 2009 (259)  14 Oct 2009 (287)
     Mercury 4 Cruise        15 Oct 2009 (288)  03 Mar 2011 (062)
     Mercury Orbit           04 Mar 2011 (063)  17 Mar 2012 (077)
     Mercury Orbit Year 2    18 Mar 2012 (078)  17 Mar 2013 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 3    18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 4    18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 5    18 Mar 2015 (077)  30 Apr 2015 (120)
 
     To validate the initial CDR dataset, the MASCS team did the
     following:
 
        * Examined the Mercury 1 flyby dataset from Jan 14 2008 in
          detail. These were the most scientifically significant
          observations that had been made at the time of initial
          validation.
 
            - Checked all data columns for format and sanity numbers
            - Compared calibration numbers for earlier independent
              analysis before CDR development
            - Compared pointing information (vectors, lats, lons,
              distances, angles) to previous independent solutions
 
        * Spot checked additional data sets preceding Mercury 1 flyby.
 
     The orbital CDR dataset is evaluated on an ongoing basis,
     checking for completeness and data integrity.
 
     MASCS UVVS data were collected during all phases except
     Venus 1 Flyby. During these planned operational periods, the UVVS
     functioned nominally and the data quality was good. Additional
     numbered notes added as necessary. This is a high-level
     presentation of CDR validation. Lower level CDR details,
     including, e.g. SBOS trips, temperature alarms, and footprints
     on/off planet are best obtained through the Data Quality Index
     (DQI) of the UVVS CDR. Specific MASCS operational periods were:
 
                       Start time         End time
 Phase Name            Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)         Operations
 --------------------  -----------------  -----------------  ------------
 Launch                03 Aug 2004 (216)  12 Sep 2004 (256)  Checkout
 Earth Cruise          13 Sep 2004 (257)  18 Jul 2005 (199)  Starcals (1),
                                                             Cover Open
 Earth Flyby           19 Jul 2005 (200)  16 Aug 2005 (228)  Earth/Moon (2)
 Venus 1 Cruise        17 Aug 2005 (229)  09 Oct 2006 (282)  Starcals
 Venus 1 Flyby         10 Oct 2006 (283)  07 Nov 2006 (311)  n/a
 Venus 2 Cruise        08 Nov 2006 (312)  22 May 2007 (142)  Starcals (3,4),
                                                             Venus,
                                                             Operation Tests
 Venus 2 Flyby         23 May 2007 (143)  20 Jun 2007 (171)  Venus (5)
 Mercury 1 Cruise      21 Jun 2007 (172)  30 Dec 2007 (364)  Starcals (6),
                                                             Operation Tests
 Mercury 1 Flyby       31 Dec 2007 (365)  28 Jan 2008 (28)   Mercury (7),
                                                             Lyman Alpha
 Mercury 2 Cruise      29 Jan 2008 (029)  21 Sep 2008 (265)  Starcals,
                                                             Operation Tests
 Mercury 2 Flyby       22 Sep 2008 (266)  20 Oct 2008 (294)  Mercury,
                                                             Lyman Alpha
 Mercury 3 Cruise      21 Oct 2008 (295)  15 Sep 2009 (258)  Starcals (8),
                                                             Venus
 Mercury 3 Flyby       16 Sep 2009 (259)  14 Oct 2009 (287)  Mercury (9),
                                                             Lyman Alpha
 Mercury 4 Cruise      15 Oct 2009 (288)  03 Mar 2011 (062)  (10), Starcals,
                                                             Venus,
                                                             Operation Tests
 Mercury Orbit         04 Mar 2011 (063)  17 Mar 2012 (077)  Mercury (11-13),
                                                             Starcals, Venus
 Mercury Orbit Year 2  18 Mar 2012 (078)  17 Mar 2013 (076)  Mercury (14-16),
                                                             Starcals
 Mercury Orbit Year 3  18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)  Mercury (17-18),
                                                             Starcals
 Mercury Orbit Year 4  18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)  Mercury (19),
                                                             Comet Encke,
                                                             Comet ISON,
                                                             Starcals
 Mercury Orbit Year 5  18 Mar 2015 (077)  30 Apr 2015 (120)  Mercury (20-21)
 
     Notes:
 
     (1)  Starcals before June 2005 viewed through cover window.
     (2)  UVVS command errors in corona scans reduced number of scans
          executed by ~1/2. SBOS trips at moon stopped UVVS VIS-PMT
          data as expected. 10 missing MUV packets at this time.
     (3)  One starcal missed target due to star tracker error.
     (4)  Test and switch over to macro-based commanding of UVVS.
     (5)  SBOS trips at Venus stopped green line scan.
     (6)  S/C event during starcal; instrument turned off during
          starcal.
     (7)  UVVS grating offset affects data during first Mercury
          flyby. CDR data during this time period will suffer in two
          ways. First, the range of wavelengths actually measured is
          different from the nominal range and spectra will be shifted
          to longer wavelengths. Second, and more importantly, the
          normal pipeline processing will not work on these data,
          so *ALL* calibrated data in this time range are incorrectly
          processed. A correction at a later date will be necessary.
          The offset was 5 grating steps.
     (8)  Pointing error during May 2009 starcal; star not observed.
     (9)  Flyby anomaly - no data after Mercury Closest Approach until
          post-flyby Mercury-as-star observations.
     (10) Missing packet in Dec 2010 turn-on sequence.
          Missing packets (5 second observations) noted in some H
          Lyman alpha scans, possibly simply timing cutoffs; no data
          quality compromise.
     (11) Some dates affected by coronal mass ejections (CMEs).  See
          complete list below.
     (12) On 20110430 - UVVS inadvertently looked at sunlit planet,
          triggering SBOS trips.
     (13) Single Event Upsets (SEUs):
            11250 X-Class solar flare
            12064 EEPROM hit lost a few days of data
     (14) Some dates affected by CMEs; see list below.
     (15) UVVS grating offset affects data during March and April
          2012. See note #7 above for description of effects. The
          offset was 5 grating steps.
     (16) Switch from 12-hour orbit to 8-hour orbit causes unusually
          large gap in data collection.
     (17) Some dates affected by CMEs; see list below.
     (18) UVVS grating offset affects data from September 5 through
          November 22, 2013. See note #7 above for description of
          effects. The offset was 5 grating steps.
     (19) Some dates affected by CMEs; see list below.
     (20) Some dates affected by CMEs; see list below.
     (21) Temperature Fault protection software disabled during final
          days in orbit.
 
 
          Current list of dates during which the UVVS detectors were
          affected by CMEs or other solar events. These events
          generally result in elevated background levels in the UVVS
          which can take some time (days) to return to normal. The
          list also includes dates for other instrumental issues (see
          notes).  It is **STRONGLY** recommended that data from these
          dates not be used in science analysis.
 
          Dates on which MASCS data are affected:
 
          01-01-2008 through 01-31-2008
                     (see note #7 above)
          04-10-2011
          06-05-2011
          06-06-2011
          06-07-2011
          06-08-2011
          08-10-2011
          08-15-2011
          09-10-2011
          09-20-2011
          10-04-2011
          11-01-2011
          11-15-2011
          12-01-2011
          12-05-2011
          12-22-2011
          01-01-2012
          01-20-2012
          03-05-2012 through 04-23-2012
                     (CMEs plus other issues, see notes #15 and #16
                     above)
          06-01-2012
          06-20-2012
          06-25-2012
          07-10-2012
          08-10-2012
          09-20-2012
          09-21-2012
          10-10-2012
          04-24-2013
          04-25-2013
          08-20-2013
          08-21-2013
          09-05-2013 through 11-22-2013
                     (see note #18 above)
          09-01-2014
          09-02-2014
          09-03-2014
          09-04-2014
          12-04-2014
          12-13-2014
          12-14-2014
          12-15-2014
          12-16-2014
          03-24-2015
 
     Cruise operations/observations have additional details in the
     Master Cruise Table (a Microsoft Excel file) in the Extras
     directory.
 
     There are slightly fewer UVVS Science CDRs because there were a
     few EDRs that contained no data at all, just header information
     (i.e. loop was begun, but halted by normal macro operations
     before data were taken.)
 
     Some Visible Detector CDRs (labels beginning with UVC) that have
     step wavelength values greater that 250 nm may have erroneous
     values for the field entries listed below. The user can identify
     these by inspecting the value in item 42. If the dark_rate is
     greater than 100, then the entries should be considered
     unreliable.
 
     42. DARK_RATE
     43. SCATTERED_LIGHT_RATE
     44. FULLY_CORRECTED_COUNT_RATE
     45. FULLY_CORRECTED_COUNT_RATE_UNCERTAINTY
     46. STEP_RADIANCE_KR
     47. STEP_RADIANCE_W
     48. STEP_RADIANCE_SIGNAL_TO_NOISE
     49. PMT_TEMPERATURE
 
     Values in the data quality index are unreliable in this version
     of the data released through the PDS.
 
   Limitations
   ===========
     This data set is calibrated data.  The data are received from the
     spacecraft telemetry and ingested into the MESSENGER Science
     Operations Center (SOC), then run through the MASCS calibration
     pipeline. No data uncharacterized gaps have been identified for
     any of the MASCS operational periods.
 
     An independent derivation of the Release 4 UVVS CDR geometry
     fields revealed a few discrepancies greater than 0.1 percent,
     which we note here.  Each component of the vector
     &apos;PLANET_SC_VECTOR_J2&apos; was found to be smaller than the CDR values
     by 0.5 percent.  The y-components of the vector
     &apos;PLANET_SUN_VECTOR_TG&apos; and &apos;SUN_POSITION_VECTOR_TG&apos; were found to
     be smaller than the CDR values by 0.4 percent.
 
     The data have been calibrated to the best possible level;
     however, there are both particle-induced effects due to solar
     events and temperature-dependent effects in the background
     removal and wavelength calibration that are being evaluated on an
     ongoing basis.  The user is warned that these effects will
     sometimes result in false positives in the calibrated radiance
     (i.e., false detections).  Care should be exercised in using the
     CDR data, particularly when results are anomalous in appearance,
     but the erroneous measurements are not always obvious.  These
     issues are significantly less of a problem in the DDR products
     (but not entirely eliminated), which have been scrubbed to a
     higher level of confidence.  Users are strongly encouraged to
     use the DDR data for scientific analysis.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

