<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dawn-a-grand-3-rdr-vesta-counts-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DAWN GRAND CALIBRATED (RDR) VESTA COUNTS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.dawn_mission_to_vesta_and_ceres::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:grand.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.4_vesta::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dawn-a-grand-3-rdr-vesta-counts-v1.0__browserp_dawn-a-grand-3-rdr-vesta-counts-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lawrence, D.J., W.C. Feldman, J.O. Goldsten, S. Maurice, P.N. Peplowski, B.J.
                   Anderson, D. Bazell, R.L. McNutt, Jr., L.R. Nittler, T.H. Prettyman, D.J.
                   Rodgers, S.C. Solomon, and S.Z. Weider, Evidence for water ice near Mercury&apos;s
                   north pole from MESSENGER Neutron Spectrometer measurements, Science, 339,
                   292-296, 2013.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LAWRENCEETAL2013</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Peplowski, P. N., D. J. Lawrence, T. H. Prettyman, N. Yamashita, D. Bazell, W.
                   C. Feldman, L. Le Corre, T. J. McCoy, V. Reddy, R. C. Reedy, C. T. Russell, and
                   M. J. Toplis, Compositional variability on the surface of 4 Vesta revealed
                   though GRAND measurements of high-energy gamma rays, Meteoritics and Planetary
                   Science, DOI: 10.1111/maps.12176
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PEPLOWSKIETAL2013</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Prettyman, T.H., W.C. Feldman, F.P. Ameduri, B.L. Barraclough, E.W. Cascio,
                   K.R. Fuller, H.O. Funsten, D.J. Lawrence, G.W. McKinney, C.T. Russell, S.A.
                   Soldner, S.A. Storms, C. Szeles, and R.L. Tokar, Gamma-ray and neutron
                   spectrometer for the Dawn mission to 1 Ceres and 4 Vesta, IEEE Trans. Nucl.
                   Sci., Volume 50, Issue 4, pp. 1190-1197, August 2003, DOI
                   10.1109/TNS.2003.815156
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PRETTYMANETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Prettyman, T.H., W.C. Feldman, H.Y. McSween, Jr., R.D. Dingler, D.C. Enemark,
                   D.E. Patrick, S.A. Storms, J.S. Hendricks, J.P. Morgenthaler, K.M. Pitman, R.C.
                   Reedy, Dawn&apos;s Gamma Ray and Neutron Detector, Space Sci. Rev. (2011)
                   163:371-459, doi:10.1007/s11214-011-9862-0
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PRETTYMANETAL2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Prettyman, T.H., D.W. Mittlefehldt, N. Yamashita, D.J. Lawrence, A.W. Beck,
                   W.C. Feldman, T.J. McCoy, H.Y. McSween, M.J. Toplis, T.N. Titus, P. Tricarico,
                   R.C. Reedy, J.S. Hendricks, O. Forni, L. Le Corre, J.-Y. Li, H. Mizzon, V.
                   Reddy, C.A. Raymond, C.T. Russell, Elemental Mapping by Dawn Reveals Exogenic H
                   in Vesta&apos;s Regolith, Science (2012) 338(6104):242-246, DOI
                   10.1126/science.1225354
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PRETTYMANETAL2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Prettyman, T., D. Mittlefehldt, N. Yamashita, A. Beck, W. Feldman, J.
                   Hendricks, D. Lawrence, T. McCoy, H. McSween, P. Peplowski, R. Reedy, M.
                   Toplis, L. Le Corre, H. Mizzon, V. Reddy, T. Titus, C. Raymond, C.T. Russell,
                   Neutron absorption constraints on the composition of 4 Vesta, Meteoritics and
                   Planetary Science (2013), DOI: 10.1111/maps.12244
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PRETTYMANETAL2013</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Yamashita, N., T.H. Prettyman, D.W. Mittlefehldt, M.J. Toplis, T.J. McCoy, A.W.
                   Beck, R.C. Reedy, W.C. Feldman, D.J. Lawrence, P.N. Peplowski, O. Forni, H.
                   Mizzon, C.A. Raymond, C.T. Russell, Distribution of iron on Vesta, Meteoritics
                   &amp; Planetary Science (2013), DOI: 10.1111/maps.12139
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.YAMASHITAETAL2013</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DAWN-A-GRAND-3-RDR-VESTA-COUNTS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DAWN GRAND CALIBRATED (RDR) VESTA COUNTS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2011-05-03T16:36:19Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2012-08-09T01:41:33Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>THOMAS H. PRETTYMAN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Prettyman, T.H. AND N. YAMASHITA, DAWN GRAND CALIBRATED (RDR)
            VESTA APPROACH AND ORBITAL COUNTS V1.0,
            DAWN-A-GRAND-3-RDR-VESTA-COUNTS-V1.0. NASA Planetary Data System,
            2014.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The GRaND Reduced Data Records (RDR) contain a time series of
            calibrated spectra, counting data, ephemeris, pointing, and
            geometry information for use in geochemical studies of Vesta.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The GRaND Reduced Data Records (RDR) contain a time series of
            calibrated spectra, counting data, and ephemeris, pointing, and
            geometry (EPG) data. The data set is specific to Vesta encounter.
            The EPG data are contained in a single file, with an entry for
            every science data record acquired by GRaND at Vesta. Each record
            has a unique identifier, spacecraft clock ticks, which is used as
            a serial number to identify data from the same record in other
            files containing spectra and counting data. The RDR data set
            includes a time series of corrected gamma ray spectra acquired by
            GRaND&apos;s bismuth-germanate (BGO) scintillator.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Acronyms and Abbreviations
  ==========================
 
  BGO             Bismuth Germanate
  CDP             Claudia Double Prime coordinate system
  EDR             Experimental data records (Level 1A)
  EPG             Spacecraft Ephemerides, Pointing, and measurement Geometry
  GCR             Galactic Cosmic Ray
  HED             Howardite, Eucrite, and Diogenite meteorites
  PDS             Planetary Data System
  RDR             Reduced data records (Level 1B)
  SBN             Small Bodies Node of the Planetary Data System
  SCLK            Spacecraft Clock
 
  Overview
  ========
 
  This data set contains Reduced Data Records (RDR) from the Dawn
  mission&apos;s Gamma Ray and Neutron Detector (GRaND). A description of GRaND
  can be found in the instrument catalog (included in the archive) and in
  the literature [PRETTYMANETAL2003, PRETTYMANETAL2011].  The archive
  includes data from all phases of Dawn&apos;s encounter with Vesta.  GRaND
  data were used to study Vesta&apos;s geochemistry [PRETTYMANETAL2012,
  LAWRENCEETAL2013, PEPLOWSKIETAL2013, PRETTYMANETAL2013,
  YAMASHITAETAL2013].  Maps developed by these studies are available from
  the PDS Small Bodies Node (SBN) as Level 2 data products for hydrogen,
  iron, neutron counting products, and high energy gamma rays.
 
  The RDR includes calibrated, time-series spectra and counting rates
  along with information needed for analysis and mapping. Improved
  reduction and analyses of gamma ray spectra has enabled the
  identification of additional elements [Yamashita et al., 2014, 45th
  Lunar and Planetary Science conference, Abstract 2674] and
  quantification of global concentrations of K and Th ; Prettyman et al.,
  2014, 45th Lunar and Planetary Science conference, Abstract 2565].
  Energy-calibrated and corrected gamma ray spectra included in this
  volume support studies of Vesta&apos;s geochemistry. The RDR data set
  includes position, pointing, and measurement geometry data that can be
  used with both the RDR and Experimental Data Records (EDR) for studies
  with neutron and gamma ray data.
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
  The RDR are a time-ordered collection of corrected and calibrated pulse
  height spectra and counting rates acquired by GRaND at Vesta.
  Spacecraft ephemerides, pointing, and measurement geometry (EPG)
  accompanies the counting data. The RDR were derived from a subset of the
  EDR (Level 1A) data archived at the PDS SBN.  Portions of the EDR data
  set have not been subjected to energy calibration and, therefore, are
  not included in the RDR. For example, spectral data for the boron-loaded
  plastic (BLP) and lithium-loaded glass (LiG) phoswiches do not vary
  appreciably in gain and are free of digitization artifacts. For this
  data set, peak areas can be reliably extracted from the EDR within
  selected epochs for which instrument settings are constant
  [PRETTYMANETAL2012]. In contrast, spectra acquired by the bismuth
  germanate (BGO) scintillator contain pronounced digitization artifacts
  and must be subjected to gain-offset corrections in order to achieve the
  highest possible resolution for gamma ray elemental analysis.
 
  EPG data and selected scaler counting products are included in a single
  file, which contains an entry for every record found in the EDR for
  Vesta encounter (from 3-May-2011 to 9-Aug-2012):
 
    GRD-L1B-110503-120809_YCMCDC-EPG.TAB
 
  where YCMCDC is the creation date of the data file.  Each record of the
  EPG file includes data for a single science accumulation interval.
  Entries include the time of acquisition, mission phase, instrument
  setting and live time, the spacecraft position at the midpoint of the
  data acquisition interval, the solid angle subtended by Vesta at the
  spacecraft, and the triple coincidence counting rate.  The latter can be
  used as a proxy for the galactic cosmic ray flux.  Example uses of the
  EPG data include binning counts in longitude and latitude (mapping),
  correcting counting rates for variations in geometry (solid angle) and
  fluctuations in the galactic cosmic ray flux [e.g. see
  PRETTYMANETAL2011, PRETTYMANETAL2012].
 
  Corrected and energy-calibrated gamma ray spectra are provided in
  separate files for each phase of Vesta encounter. The files have the
  following naming convention:
 
    GRD-L1B-Y0M0D0-Y1M1D1_YCMCDC-PHS-BGOC.TAB
 
  where PHS is the three-letter mission phase identifier (e.g. VSL is
  Vesta Science LAMO; see the mission catalog for a complete list), Y0M0D0
  is the date on which the first science record was acquired during the
  mission phase and Y1M1D1 is the date for the last science data record.
  YCMCDC is the creation date of the data file.  Each record contains the
  spacecraft ephemeris time (SCET) in UTC format and the spacecraft clock
  (SCLK) ticks (seconds) followed by counts/channel for each of 1024
  channels.  Each spectrum has been subjected to a linear energy
  calibration and rebinned to a common energy scale. The midpoint of each
  channel can be obtained by multiplying the channel index (0 to 1023) by
  8.9 keV/channel.  Digitization artifacts caused by the differential
  nonlinearity of the analog-digital converter have been removed.
 
  ***Cross-referencing with SCLK***
     ===========================
 
  Every GRaND EPG science data record and RDR record is labeled with
  spacecraft clock (SCLK) ticks, represented as a 9-digit integer.  The
  value of SCLK is unique for each record.  Thus, SCLK can be used as a
  serial code to identify the same science data record within other data
  files.  Each record of the EPG file includes SCLK.  This allows
  instrument settings, live time, position, pointing, solid angle, and GCR
  corrections to be reliably matched with data in any EDR or RDR file.
 
  Processing
  ==========
 
  Processing steps and validation of the ephemeris, pointing and geometry
  data are described in GRD_L1B_Ephemeris_Pointing_Geometry_v1.pdf. A
  description of the BGO data processing can be found in
  GRD_L1B_BGO_Data_Processing_v4.pdf. The data processing documents can be
  found in the DOCUMENTS directory.
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
 
  Spacecraft ephemerides and pointing data were determined using NASA&apos;s
  Navigation and Ancillary Information Facility (NAIF) SPICE Toolkit for
  IDL (version N65).  SPICE kernels for Vesta encounter were downloaded
  from the NASA Planetary Data System (dawnsp_1000).  The planetary
  constants kernel for Vesta (dawn_vesta_v04.tpc) for the Claudia
  coordinate system was modified with the latest pole position, per
  private communication by R. Gaskell. The modified PCK file
  (dawn_vesta_v04b.tpc) can be found in the EXTRAS directory.
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
 
  Longitudes are given in the International Astronomical Union (IAU)
  Claudia Double Prime (CDP) coordinate system.  A method to convert from
  CDP to the Claudia coordinate system, used by the Dawn mission, can be
  found in the EPG label file and data processing document.
 
  The instrument coordinate system (Fig. 1) determines the naming
  convention of the sensors and orientation of the instrument relative to
  the spacecraft. The use of MZ indicates a sensor on the -Z (zenith-
  facing during mapping) side of GRaND;  PZ indicates the sensor is on the
  +Z (spacecraft) side; MY indicates the sensor is on the -Y side
  (inboard) side of the instrument; and PY indicates the sensor is on the
  +Y side (outboard, towards the +Y solar panel) side of the instrument.
  The phototube assembly, marked &apos;P&apos; on the diagram in Fig. 1 points along
  the +X axis (towards the high gain antenna).
 
  The RDR/EPG contains pointing information.  Direction cosines found in
  each EPG record specify the direction of Vesta body center in the
  instrument coordinate system. The cosines DIR_U, DIR_V, DIR_W are
  measured relative to the X-, Y-, and Z-axes, respectively.
 
   .................
   . ooooooooooooo .
   . o           o .
   . o           o .
   . o    +Z     o .
   . o   (PZ)    o .
   . o           o .---&gt; +Y (PY)
   . ooo       ooo .
   .   P       P   .
   .   P       P   .
   .   PPPPPPPPP   .
   .               .
   .................
           |
           v
        +X (PX)
 
  Figure 1. The coordinate system for GRaND is the same as that of the
  S/C. For the diagram above, the observer is looking in the -Z (MZ)
  direction and can see the outline of the phoswich assembly (o) on the +Z
  side of GRaND. The phototubes are on the +X side and the scintillators
  are on the -X side. During mapping at Vesta and Ceres, the planetary
  surface is in the +Z direction.
 
  Software
  ========
 
  No software is provided with the archived data.
 
  Media/Format
  ============
 
  The RDR files are delivered by electronic transmission to the PDS.  The
  RDR consists of ASCII tables with separate labels containing the format
  specification.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Review
  ======
 
  The RDR were reviewed internally by the Dawn Science Team prior to
  submission to the PDS.  The EPG and BGO data have been used in studies
  carried out by the Dawn Geochemistry team [PRETTYMANETAL2012,
  LAWRENCEETAL2013, PEPLOWSKIETAL2013, PRETTYMANETAL2013,
  YAMASHITAETAL2013].  The PDS will conduct an external peer review of the
  EDR prior to releasing the data to the general public.
 
  Data Coverage/Quality
  =====================
 
  The RDR were derived from the archived EDR data set, which includes all
  of the data acquired during flight.  Nonetheless, the EDR contained gaps
  associated with instrument and spacecraft operations as well as
  corrupted data.  A complete description of the EDR data coverage can be
  found in the CONFIDENCE_LEVEL_NOTE for the EDR data set.
 
  The EPG data file contains spacecraft position and pointing for each and
  every EDR record.  Thus, the EPG data can be used in the analysis of any
  GRaND time-series data product (EDR or RDR).  Position and geometry data
  are available for all records; however, for a small portion of the
  records triples counts, live time, and information regarding instrument
  configuration are unavailable and are flagged by MISSING_CONSTANT.  In
  addition, the counting data may occasionally contain anomalies, such as
  spikes in live time or the triples rate.  In some cases these may result
  from corrupt data (e.g. data for which the master frame contained an
  invalid checksum, which cannot be identified by the GRaND team).  In
  others, the fluctuations may be due to natural, short-term variations in
  the energetic particle flux.
 
  Solid angles were calculated from a shape model as described in the RDR
  data processing document (GRD_L1B_Ephemeris_Pointing_Geometry_v1.pdf).
  Solid angles are accurate to better than 0.5% over the entire range of
  positions reported in the EPG file.
 
  Live time determination is described in detail in the EPG data reduction
  document (GRD_L1B_Ephemeris_Pointing_Geometry_v1.pdf). Live times
  reported in the EPG file are valid only for quiet Sun conditions.
  During solar energetic particle (SEP) events, the dead time counter can
  roll an indeterminate number of times, resulting in inaccurate
  determination of live time.  SEP intervals can be identified by
  examining the triples counting rate. During SEP events, the triples rate
  is elevated.  No attempt has been made to flag these intervals in the
  EPG file; however, records within periods of elevated SEP flux have been
  excluded from the BGO RDR data file. Additional exclusion rules to weed
  out invalid data from the BGO time series are described in
  GRD_L1B_BGO_Data_Processing_v4.pdf. These include out of range scaler
  values, records with abnormal spectral shape (due to anomaly or
  incomplete instrument configuration), and large accumulation times
  during which instrument settings were adjusted.
 
  Neither the EPG nor the BGO RDR contain replicate records.  This is in
  contrast to the EDR, for which some records are repeated at the
  beginning and end of downlink intervals.
 
  Limitations
  ===========
 
  The RDR gamma ray spectra can be used in the analysis of elemental
  composition and mapping studies.  Standard methods for gamma ray peak
  fitting can be applied to extract counting rates.  However, care must be
  taken when subtracting spectra accumulated during different mission
  phases. Background subtraction can introduce artifacts that can be
  misinterpreted as gamma ray peaks. A spectrum of gamma rays originating
  from Vesta can be obtained by subtracting a spectrum accumulated during
  approach (VSA) from one accumulated in low altitude mapping orbit (VSL).
  This approach to remove background contributions from the spacecraft
  will result in the introduction of artifacts due to variations in the
  energy resolution of the BGO sensor over large periods of time.  To
  avoid introduction of artifacts, both spectra must be appropriately
  adjusted (by convolution) so that they have the same energy resolution
  prior to subtraction. The RDR time series is properly calibrated;
  however, no attempt has been made to adjust energy resolution on a
  spectrum-by-spectrum basis.
 
  The linear model used for energy calibration of BGO pulse height spectra
  produces relatively large absolute residuals in comparison to a
  quadratic model (see Fig. 5B, GRD_L1B_BGO_Data_Processing_v4.pdf).  The
  observed deviations are likely due to a combination of the
  nonproportionality of BGO and the nonlinearity of the pulse processing
  electronics chain (from the photomultiplier tube through the analog-to-
  digital-converter).  The linear calibration was selected for archive for
  the following reasons:
    - The linear model does a better job at predicting channel for the 7.6
      MeV Fe neutron-capture peak than the quadratic model;
    - Users of the data set can re-calibrate the spectra without knowledge
      of the original calibration constants.
  As our understanding of nonlinear effects matures, the GRaND team will
  distribute improved versions of the calibrated spectra.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

