<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.co-s-mimi-4-inca-calib-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CASSINI S MIMI INCA SENSOR CALIBRATED DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mimi.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.saturn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.co-s-mimi-4-inca-calib-v1.0__browserp_co-s-mimi-4-inca-calib-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Krimigis, S.M., D.G. Mitchell, D.C. Hamilton, S. Livi, J. Dandouras, S.
                   Jaskulek, T.P. Armstrong, J.D. Boldt, A.F. Cheng, G. Gloeckler, J.R. Hayes,
                   K.C. Hsieh, W.-H. Ip, E.P. Keath, E. Kirsch, N. Krupp, L.J. Lanzerotti, R.
                   Lundgren, B.H. Mauk, R.W. McEntire, E.C. Roelof, C.E. Schlemm, B.E. Tossman, B.
                   Wilken, and D.J. Williams, Magnetosphere Imaging Instrument (MIMI) on the
                   Cassini Mission to Saturn/Titan, Space Sci Rev. 114, 233-329, 2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KRIMIGISETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kusterer, M.B., L.M. Burke, Level 1A File Layouts, Cassini/MIMI Data Analysis
                   Center Level 1A File Layouts, The Johns Hopkins University Applied Physics
                   Laboratory Document, Revision 18, December 2003.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KUSTERER-BURKE2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Manweiler, J.W., W.A. Rasmuss, and S. Joy, MIMI Standard Data Products and
                   Archive Volume Software Interface Specification, v2.1, JPL Document D-31634,
                   Cassini document IO-AR-006, 2005.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MANWEILERETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   J.D. Vandegriff, R. DiFabio, D. Hamilton, M.B. Kusterer, J. Manweiler, D.G.
                   Mitchell, C. Paranicas, E. Roussos, Cassini/MIMI Instrument Data User Guide
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.VANDEGRIFFETAL2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CO-S-MIMI-4-INCA-CALIB-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CASSINI S MIMI INCA SENSOR CALIBRATED DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-04-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-01-01T00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-06-30T23:59:47.828Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>Martha B. Kusterer</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Vandegriff J., Kusterer M.B., Mafi J.,
            CO-S-MIMI-4-INCA-CALIB-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2012.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains all of of the calibrated Saturn tour data
            for the INCA sensor of the MIMI instrument aboard the Cassini
            spacecraft for the Cassini mission. INCA stands for Imaging
            Neutral Camera.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Ion and Neutral Camera (INCA) obtains remote images of the
            global distribution of energetic ions for energies from 7
            keV/nucleon to 8 MeV/nucleon, discriminated according to energy
            and mass species (oxygen and hydrogen). To obtain the images,
            INCA measures the arrival directions, energy and mass species of
            Energetic Neutral Atoms (ENA&apos;s) using the relatively new
            technique of ENA imaging. INCA also can be commanded to obtain
            very high sensitivity ion measurements, providing the angular,
            energy and species distributions of in-situ O and H ions. The
            Cassini Magnetospheric Imaging Instrument(MIMI) Imaging Neutral
            Camera (INCA) calibrated data set includes all image data
            collected from the MIMI Data Processing Unit during the Saturn
            tour. The original data has been decommutated, decoded,
            calibrated and further processed by software at the Applied
            Physics Laboratory (APL). The calibrated image data is provided
            in three forms: an averaged form where the original image N x N
            pixel images pixels intensity are averaged to a single value for
            one species and time-of-flight (TOF) combination, browse images
            which display rows and columns of images for one species and TOF
            combination, and movies which display averaged ENA image skymaps.
            Calibration of INCA data has been described fully in the
            Cassini/MIMI Data User Guide. [VANDEGRIFFETAL2012] This data set
            should be among the first used by a user of any of the MIMI INCA
            archive as it will lead one to information required to search for
            more detailed or highly specialized features in the original data.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
       The Ion and Neutral Camera (INCA) obtains remote images of the global
       distribution of energetic ions for energies from 7 keV/nucleon to 8
       MeV/nucleon, discriminated according to energy and mass species
       (oxygen and hydrogen). To obtain the images, INCA measures the arrival
       directions, energy and mass species of Energetic Neutral Atoms (ENA&apos;s)
       using the relatively new technique of ENA imaging. INCA also can be
       commanded to obtain very high sensitivity ion measurements, providing
       the angular, energy and species distributions of in-situ O and H ions.
 
       INCA image data are available in three different flavors, each flavor
       being simultaneously generated. High spatial resolution images have a
       larger number of pixels than other INCA images (up to 64 by 64), but
       are available for fewer numbers of energies (usually just 2 energy
       channels) and are taken at lower time resolution (one image every 4
       sectors). High time resolution images are acquired each sector, but
       have lower spatial resolution (usually 16 by 16 pixels)High
       time-of-flight and mass resolution images are taken for 9 energy
       ranges, but only every 4 sectors and with lower spatial resolution.
 
       In neutral mode, which is used to obtain ENA images, alternate
       collimator plates are charged to a high positive and negative voltage,
       and these collimators sweep up ions and electrons entering the sensor.
       Neutral atoms pass by the collimators through a slit. Alternately,
       in ion mode, the collimators are not charged and the ions and
       electrons pass into the detector.
 
       The Cassini Magnetospheric Imaging Instrument(MIMI) Imaging Neutral
       Camera (INCA) calibrated data set includes all image data collected
       from the MIMI Data Processing Unit during the Saturn tour. The
       original data has been decommutated, decoded, calibrated and further
       processed by software at the Applied Physics Laboratory (APL).
 
       The calibrated image data is provided in three forms: an averaged
       form where the original image N x N pixel images pixels intensity are
       averaged to a single value for one species and time-of-flight (TOF)
       combination, browse images which display rows and columns of images
       for one species and TOF combination,  and movies which display
       averaged ENA image skymaps.
 
       Calibration of INCA data has been described fully in the
       Cassini/MIMI Data User Guide.  [VANDEGRIFFETAL2012]
 
       This data set should be among the first used by a user of any of the
       MIMI INCA archive as it will lead one to information required to
       search for more detailed or highly specialized features in the
       original data.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
      This data set comprises image pixel angle averages where the original
      image N x N pixel image (where N is usually 16, 32 or 64) images pixels
      intensity in are averaged to a single value for one species and TOF
      combination. The value displayed is the image intensity in
      counts/(centimeters squared*steradian*seconds*keV). These are called
      angle averages since each image pixel has a particular look direction
      out of the INCA instrument specified in azimuth and elevation. The
      azimuth directions range from -45 to 45 degrees over the index range
      0 to N, where N is the number of rows in the image. The elevation
      values for each pixel range from 60 to -60 degrees (note: this is
      backwards) over the index range 0 to N, where N is the number of
      columns in the image. The pixel sizes are different depending on the
      resolution of the image. Also note that the look direction angles for
      each pixel are relative to the center of the INCA image, which may be
      offset from its nominal center due to the way images are integrated on
      the spacecraft. The registration of an INCA image against the sky in a
      specific coordinate system involves proper interpretation of the offset
      of the image center from its nominal direction. Full details describing
      this process has been described fully in the Cassini/MIMI Data User
      Guide.  [VANDEGRIFFETAL2012]
 
      The standard product ID&apos;s are:
 MIMI_INCA_ANGAVE_S for the high spatial resolution angle averages
 MIMI_INCA_ANGAVE_T for the high time resolution angle averages
 MIMI_INCA_ANGAVE_M for the high mass TOF resolution angle averages
 
      The data is organized in time by the spin of the spacecraft.  When the
      spacecraft is in staring mode then the MIMI DPU automatically creates
      a virtual spin that divides the time collection periods into 16
      sectors, 16 subsectors, and 16 microsectors and maintains a simple
      organizational structure for characterizing the collection of the time
      into time segments.  When the spacecraft is spinning at a minimally
      defined spin rate (adopted by the MIMI DPU) then the MIMI data is
      automatically segregated into 16 sectors, 16 subsectors, and 16
      microsectors.  The INCA instrument collection times are then also
      keyed to these values. The high spatial and high mass TOF image
      averages are collected over 4 sectors and the high time resolution
      image averages are collected over 1 sector.
 
      Each file contains all the species and tof combination image angle
      averages for one image resolution type. The resolution type, species
      and TOF values are included in the parameter set.
 
      In addition, this data set includes two types of browse products. One
      product type is a PNG file containing three rows by N columns of
      panels, where the bottom three rows are a continuation in time of the
      top three rows. Each row contains spin averaged high spatial ENA
      image skymaps (each one accumulated over four sectors), displayed for
      one species and TOF combinations.
 
      The other browse product type is a PNG file containing 1 up to 10
      columns, high TOF browse ion thumbnail images displayed for seven
      time-of-flight ranges (rows) for one species. The value
      displayed is the log of the image intensity in
      counts/(centimeters squared*steradian*seconds*keV).
 
      The standard product ID&apos;s are:
 MIMI_INCA_ENAIMG_HO for the ENA image skymaps
 MIMI_INCA_IONANG_H for the ion hydrogen image thumbnails
 MIMI_INCA_IONANG_O for the ion oxygen image thumbnails
 
      The data set also contains MP4 movies which display averaged ENA image
      skymaps (averaged over a variable, listed number of original on-board
      images), for one species and TOF combination. The value displayed is
      the log of the image intensity in
      counts/(centimeters squared*steradian*seconds*keV).
 
      The standard product ID&apos;s for the movies are
 MIMI_INCA_ENAMV_SH0 for the high spatial resolution hydrogen low TOF movies
 MIMI_INCA_ENAMV_SH7 for the high spatial resolution hydrogen high TOF movies
 MIMI_INCA_ENAMV_S00 for the high spatial resolution oxygen low TOF movies
 MIMI_INCA_ENAMV_S07 for the high spatial resolution oxygen high TOF movies
 MIMI_INCA_ENAMV_TA0 for the high time resolution low TOF movies
 MIMI_INCA_ENAMV_TA7 for the high time resolution low TOF movies
 
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
      Data in this data set were processed by the use of a number of
      software programs which calibrate the images to differential intensity,
      calculate the image angle averages, and display the images in either
      the skymap or thumbnail display. The skymap and thumbnail images are
      further processed by averaging the images together and displaying them
      in rows and columns in browse products which reduces a days worth of
      images to a few pages.
 
      The display software makes use of the JPL Naif SPICE software which
      contains algorithms to handle the various spacecraft rotation modes.
      The MIMI team has created and maintain an analysis SPICE kernel set
      which is available on the MIMI website. The many useful frames of
      reference fordisplaying the INCA images with celestial bodies have
      been included in the frame kernel. The SPICE frames used in the
      products described here have been
      explained in the coordinate system section below.
 
      The skymaps are created by transforming the original image into
      the following SPICE reference frame. The skymap frame is a dynamically
      defined frame, XINCA_BORESIGHT_CENTERED, which is defined in the
      Coordinate Systems section below.
 
      Creation of the skymap and thumbnail image displays starts with the
      calculation of each original image pixels look direction in aximuth
      and elevation, based on the INCA boresight vector as well as the
      azimuth and elevation offsets if applicable based on image collection
      mode. The pixel matching the look direction in the skymap or thumbnail
      display frame is calculated and the original image pixel intensity
      value is loaded into the display frame pixel.
 
      The thumbnail images are created by transforming the original images
      into the INCA azimuth and elevation SPICE reference frame. The
      definition of the thumbnail frame, CASSINI_MIMI_INCA_LL is described
      in the Coordinate Systems section below. The elevation of the image
      goes from -60 degrees at the bottom to 60 degrees at the top of the
      image. The azimuth of the image goes from -45 degrees on the left
      to 45 degrees on the right.
 
      The MP4 movies are created using the skymap display software to output
      consecutive ENA skymaps in time.  The QuickTime software was used to
      convert the PNG files into the movies. Typically the movies display
      the INCA image data in the Saturn frame, XINCA_SATURN_CENTERED which
      is described in the Coordinate System section below. The Titan frame,
      XINCA_TITAN_CENTERED, is used to display the images for the Titan
      flybys. It is also described below in the Coordinate System section.
      The use of the Saturn centered or Titan centered frame improves the
      continuity of movies because it reduces the effect of the
      spacecraft motion on the movie.
 
 
  Data
  ====
      The MIMI INCA calibrated data set includes image angle averages,
      browse images and movies. The image angle averages are an ASCII CSV
      table. Each table contains variable length records for which the
      fields are comma delimited.
 
    INCA Image Angle Average Data
    ---------------------------
 
      Fields include:
      a purpose identifier where science data records are identified
      with purpose = sci
      starting and ending ephemeris times
      Spin, sector, subsector (and for INCA Fine Rate (FRT) data
      microsector)
      SCLOCK and spin period that are used to derive the starting
      ephemeris time
         Notes regarding the SCLOCK value:
         1.  Only the SCLOCK major segment value is provided - MIMI
             currently does not have access to the fine SCLOCK value
             hence SCLOCK resolution is limited to +- 1/2 SCLOCK count
         2.  The SCLOCK is only available from telemetry at the
             beginning of each spin. All other published SCLOCKS are
             derived from the spin starting SCLOCK, the spin numbers
             (for the current and next available spins), and the spin
             period.
         3.  SCLOCK values are assumed to drive the value of the
             ephemeris times and not vice-versa. All effort is made to
             validate the published ephemeris times but since updates to
             the Cassini SCLOCK kernel in SPICE can occur the values of
             ephemeris time are only as accurate as the currently
             published Cassini SCLOCK SPICE kernel.
       Spacecraft staring mode where staring = 0 when spinning and 1
       otherwise
 
       INCA Images are organized as:
         Type ID: a 4 byte word characterized as:
                  Byte 0 - Type: 0 = High Spatial, 1 = High Time,
                           2 = High m-TOF
                  Byte 1 - Charge: 0 = Neutral, 1 = Ion
                  Byte 2 - Species: 0 = H, 1 = He, 2 = CNO, 3 = Heavy,
                           4 = Other, 5 = All
                  Byte 3 - TOF: 0 = Low, 1-6 = Medium, 7 = High
       Compression bits, Compression method, log compressed identifier
       Theta and Phi offsets from spacecraft coordinates
       The angle average and uncertainty are in units as image intensity in
       counts/(centimeters squared*steradian*seconds*keV)
 
       Each file contains all the species and tof combination image angle
       averages for one image resolution type. The resolution type, species
       and TOF values are included in the parameter set.
 
    INCA Browse Images
    ------------------
      The skymap browse images are in PNG files containing three rows by N
      columns of panels, where the bottom three rows are a continuation
      in time of the top three rows. Each row contains spin average
      high spatial ENA image skymaps (each one accumulated over four
      sectors), displayed for one species and TOF combinations.
 
      Row one contains the high TOF hydrogen images, row two contains the low
      TOF hydrogen images and row three contains the low TOF oxygen images.
      The energy range for each TOF range is shown to the right of each row.
      ENA images are collected when a high voltage is present on the INCA
      collimator. The value displayed is the log of the image intensity which
      is counts/(centimeters squared*steradian*seconds*keV). The color bars
      for each row are independent and are determined by the minimum and
      maximum pixels in that row (i.e., for the entire day).
 
      Each original image was 64 x 64 pixels and was transformed into the
      skymap frame, XINCA_BORESIGHT_CENTERED, which is described below in
      the coordinate system section. One days data is contained in one to
      three PNG files.
 
      The thumbnail browse images are in PNG files containing 1 up to 10
      columns, high TOF browse ion thumbnail images displayed
      for seven TOF ranges (rows). Ion images are
      collected when no voltage is present on the INCA collimator.
      The image species include hydrogen at TOF ranges, where the energy
      range for each TOF range is shown to the right of each row. The
      value displayed is the log of the image intensity which is
      counts/(centimeters squared*steradian*seconds*keV).
 
      The color bars for each row are independent and are determined by the
      minimum and maximum pixels in that row (i.e., for the entire day).
      Each original image was 16 x 16 pixels and was transformed into
      the INCA azimuth and elevation frame, CASSINI_MIMI_INCA_LL,
      which is described below in the coordinate system section.
 
      One days data is contained in one to twenty-four PNG files.
 
 
    INCA ENA Movies
    ----------------
      The INCA ENA movies consist of MP4 movies displaying averaged ENA
      image skymaps (averaged over a variable, listed number of original
      on-board images), for one species and TOF combination. ENA images are
      collected when the voltage on the INCA collimator is high, typically
      4kV. This excludes ions with E/q values less than ~180 to 200keV/q.
      The value displayed is the log of the image intensity in
      counts/(centimeters squared*steradian*seconds*keV).
 
      The INCA ENA images are only produced for interesting features in the
      INCA data and Titan flybys.
 
      The color bar limits are set to a common minimum and maximum value
      over the entire movie, chosen to  bring out the salient features over
      the time covered. These values typically change from one movie to the
      next, based on activity levels and orbital position.
 
      Each original image N x N pixel image (where N is usually 32 or 64)
      was transformed into the Saturn frame, XINCA_SATURN_CENTERED, which is
      described in the coordinate system section below. For Titan flybys, the
      image was transformed into the Titan frame, XINCA_TITAN_CENTERED which
      is described in the coordinate system section below.
 
      Typically, though not always, the orbit of Titan, Dione and Rhea
      (dotted line), Titan center (dot), and the axis for Saturn equatorial
      system frame (white, centered at Saturn) are displayed. The definition
      of the Saturn equatorial system frame, is described in the coordinate
      system section below.
 
      The pink axis (when present) is the Saturn Kilometric Radiation frame.
      Due to the work of the RPWS team we now have several Saturn Kilometric
      Radiation frames available for use.[1] The SKR frame is also described
      below in the coordinate system section
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
      The MIMI INCA display software makes primary use of three SPICE frames
      of reference which are used to display the images along with celestial
      bodies. These SPICE frames are provided in their MIMI SPICE analysis
      kernels set in the frame kernel.
 
      The skymap frame, XINCA_BORESIGHT_CENTERED, is a dynamically defined
      frame, defined as follows. The primary axis X is the INCA boresight
      axis. The secondary Z axis is the Z axis of the IAU_SATURN frame. The
      Y-axis completes the right-handed system. The skymap display is
      defined to display every frame with the Z axis up,  X axis into the
      page and Y axis out to the left. So in the skymap, using this frame,
      Z or up is the spin axis of Saturn, into the page is the boresight.
 
      The Saturn frame, XINCA_SATURN_CENTERED, a frame dynamically defined as
      follows. The primary axis is the CASSINI spacecraft-to-Saturn vector
      and is labeled X. The  secondary (Z) axis is the Z axis of the
      IAU_SATURN frame (the Saturn spin axis). The Y-axis completes the
      right-handed system.
 
      The Titan frame, XINCA_TITAN_CENTERED, a frame dynamically defined as
      follows. The primary axis is the CASSINI spacecraft-to-Titan vector and
      is labeled X. The  secondary (Z) axis is the Z axis of the IAU_TITAN
      frame (the Titan spin axis). The Y-axis completes the right-handed
      system.
 
      The INCA Azimuth and elevation frame, CASSINI_MIMI_INCA_LL, is the
      primary axis X is the INCA boresight axis which goes into the page.
      The secondary Z axis is the Z axis of Cassini. The Y-axis completes
      the left-handed system.
 
      The definition of the Saturn equatorial system,
      SATURN_EQUITORIAL_SYSTEM, frame has the primary axis, labeled Z,
      parallel to the Saturn spin axis. The Y-axis is then defined as the
      cross product of this vector with the Saturn-Sun vector. The X-axis
      completes the right-handed system and is directed roughly sunward,
      lying in the plane containing both Z and the Saturn-sun vector.
 
      The MIMI INCA display software also displays the axis of Saturn using
      the Saturn Kilometric Radiation frame (SKR). Due to the work of the
      RPWS team we now have several Saturn Kilometric Radiation frames
      available for use.[1] The Z-axis is coincident with the instantaneous
      body rotation vector (spin axis) of Saturn. [1] A SLS4 Longitude system
      based on a tracking filter analysis of the rotation modulation of
      Saturn kilometric radiation. D.A. Gurnett, et. al.
 
  Software
  ========
      There is IDL software provided on the MIMI web site, which will
      calibrate the INCA images conversion of count rates into flux.  In
      addition, web applications are provided on the MIMI web site to
      display the INCA images in the skymap and thumbnail displays both
      singly and in multiple formats.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
      These data are supplied to the Planetary Data System via electronic
      means and are then broken into segments based upon the media currently
      prescribed by PDS.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
      This data set contains all calibrated data for the INCA Detector as
      part of the Cassini MIMI instrument for the interval described above.
      Every effort has been made to ensure that all data returned to APL
      from the spacecraft is included and that the calibrated browse data
      products are accurate.
 
      As of this writing there are no known issues associated with the INCA
      detector that would limit the usability or reliability of the data.
 
  Review
  ======
      The MIMI INCA data will be reviewed internally by the Cassini MIMI
      team prior to release to the PDS. The data set will also be peer
      reviewed by the PDS.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
      All data in the stated interval are included, to the best of our
      knowledge and attempts to determine completeness.
 
    Large Data Gaps:
    1.  Post SOI                  2004-187 - 2004-193 - Spacecraft Safing
                                                     shut off
    2. Tour                       2005-006 - 2005-015 -
    3. Tour                       2007-254 - 2007-258 - Spacecraft Safing
                                                     shut off
    3. Tour                       2007-279 - 2007-291 - Spacecraft Flight
                                                     S/W testing shut off
    3. Extended Mission           2009-071 - 2009-076 - Spacecraft Thruster
                                                     branch swap,deactivated
                                                     S48 background sequence.
    3. Extended-Extended Mission  2010-306 - 2010-319 - Spacecraft Safing
                                                     shut off
    3. Extended-Extended Mission  2012-293 - 2012-303 - Spacecraft Propellant
                                                     Gauging Test shut off.
 
      On those days for which the instrument did not collect data either due
      to the instrument being off or due to communication issues, the data
      set will not contain any files.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
      As noted above there are no know issues associated with the data from
      the INCA detector as of the writing of this catalog.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>IN_PEER_REVIEW</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

