<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.msl-m-navcam-5-rdr-mosaic-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MSL MARS NAVIGATION CAMERA 5 RDR MOSAIC V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_science_laboratory::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.msl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:nav_left_a.msl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.msl-m-navcam-5-rdr-mosaic-v1.0__browserp_msl-m-navcam-5-rdr-mosaic-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.msl-m-navcam-5-rdr-mosaic-v1.0__dvo_imaging_msl-m-navcam-5-rdr-mosaic-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Alexander, D. and R. Deen, Mars Science Laboratory Project Software Interface
                   Specification (SIS) for Camera &amp; LIBS EDR and RDR Data Products, Jet Propulsion
                   Laboratory Document D-38107, Version 3.5, 14 August 2014.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JPLD-38107</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Maki, J.N., et al., Mars Exploration Rover Engineering Cameras, J. Geophys.
                   Res., 108(E12), 8071, doi:10.1029/2003JE002077, 2003.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MAKIETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Maki, J.N., et al., The Mars Science Laboratory Engineering Cameras, Space Sci.
                   Rev. 2012, doi:10.1007/s11214-012-9882-4, 10 May 2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MAKIETAL2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MSL-M-NAVCAM-5-RDR-MOSAIC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MSL MARS NAVIGATION CAMERA 5 RDR MOSAIC V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2014-03-17</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2012-01-01T12:34:56.789Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JUSTIN MAKI</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Maki, Justin, MSL Mars Navcam Mosaic Images RDR V1.0, NASA
            Planetary Data System, MSL-M-NAVCAM-5-RDR-MOSAIC-V1.0, 2012.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Mars Science Laboratory Navigation Camera Mosaic Images, Reduced
            Data Record, Version 1.0
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>Unknown</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set contains images where  multiple frames are mosaicked
    into a single RDR product. The methods for this process are applied
    by the Multimission Instrument Processing Lab (MIPL) under the
    Operational Product Generation Subsystem (OPGS), associating projections
    with the mosaicking process. It should be noted that governing methods
    and software can differ between OPGS and other operations subsystems or
    science instrument teams. For additional information about mosaic
    processing, including the purpose and content of ancillary files,
    consult the MSL_CAMERA_SIS.PDF in the DOCUMENT directory of this volume.
 
 
  Products
  ==========
    Below is a high level description of the types of mosaics produced to
    support MSL rover operations:
 
    - Cylindrical Projection: images are overlaid onto azimuth and
      elevation grid lines. In this case each pixel represents a fixed angle
      in azimuth and elevation. Rows are of constant elevation in the
      selected Mars coordinate frame. Optionally, individual frame boundries
      may be super-imposed and annotated by number.
 
 
    - Camera Point Perspective: a perspective projection from a synthetic
      camera, behaving as if the camera had a much larger field of view.
      Point-perspective mosaics give the most natural view of small areas,
      and are suitable for stereo viewing, but cannot be used for large
      fields of view.  For MSL, this type of mosaic is typically computed
      in Rover Frame, and thus may have a tilted horizon if the rover was not
      level.
 
    - Cylindrical-Perspective Projection: used for large stereo panoramas,
      and work across a full 360 degrees of azimuth.  Stereo is preserved
      because a baseline separation is maintained between the camera eyes
      at different azimuths.
 
    - Polar Projection: provide a quasi-overhead view that still allows
      viewing all the way to the horizon.  Nadir is at the convergent
      center and the horizon is corrected for lander tilt.
 
    - Vertical Projection: provide a view of the surroundings as if you were
      looking straight down.  They are useful for establishing environmental
      context or comparing with orbital imagery, but suffer from severe
      distortion with any variance of the scene from the surface model. In
      particular, rocks appear elongated, and terrain is not taken into
      account.
 
    - Orthographic Projection: this type of mosaic is a generalization
      of the vertical projection. It differs in that an arbitrary axis of
      projection (as well as X- and Y-axes in the plane of projection)
      can be specified.
 
    - Orthorectified Projection: used to show a &apos;true&apos; view of the scene
      from a different point of view, without distortion due to parallax.
      The point of view is usually overhead, resulting in an image suitable
      for comparison with satellite imagery.  The removal of parallax leads
      to gaps in the mosaic, which do not occur in other projections.
 
    - Non-image Mosaics: Normally mosaics are created using imagery, where
      each pixel is either a raw or radiometrically corrected intensity value.
      However, mosaics can be created using other types of pixels, e.g. XYZ,
      surface normal (UVW), range or slope.  Any projection may be used, and
      all output values must be defined in the same coordinate system.
 
  Data
  ====
    The mosaics are typically 1 or 3 banded 16-bit signed integer or floating
    point files - the actual format matches the format of the input data.
    Each mosaic has a dual ODL3/VICAR label attached to the binary file,
    accompanied by a detached PDS3 label.
 
  Software
  ========
    The MIPL Mars Program Suite was used to generate these mosaics.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
NULL
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

