<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.sdu-c-src-6-geometry-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>STARDUST DUST COLLECTOR GEOMETRY V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.stardust::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.sdu::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:src.sdu::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.81p-wild_2_1978_a2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:unk.unk::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.sdu-c-src-6-geometry-v1.0__browserp_sdu-c-src-6-geometry-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>SDU-C-SRC-6-GEOMETRY-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>STARDUST DUST COLLECTOR GEOMETRY V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2006-07-07</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2000-02-22T01:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2004-01-02T23:00:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>Tony Farnham</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Farnham, T.L., Semenov, B., STARDUST DUST COLLECTOR GEOMETRY,
            SDU-C-SRC-6-GEOMETRY-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2006.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Geometry and orientations of the Stardust spacecraft and
            collection plate during the dust collection phases of the mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Data set describing the geometry and orientations of the
            spacecraft and the collector plate during the two interstellar
            dust collection phases and the Wild 2 encounter.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
Author
------
The descriptions in this file were written by Tony Farnham using
information from the &apos;Stardust Mission Plan&apos; document  (used with
permission from the Stardust project).
 
 
Data Set Overview
=================
 
This data set describes the geometry and orientations of the
spacecraft and the collector plate during the two interstellar dust
collection phases and the Wild 2 encounter.
 
 
Dust Sample Collector
---------------------
 
The sample collector was a passive system for collecting dust grains.
It consisted of an aluminum grid encasing multiple microporous silica
aerogel blocks.  The grid array was exposed to a stream of dust
particles, which were gradually slowed and captured by the low-density
aerogel.  The aerogel dissipated the kinetic energy of the particles
so they were not destroyed during the collection process.  Graded
density media was used to give even lower density for the initial
impact.  The collector grid has two sides, each of which contains
separate aerogel blocks.  One side of the collector was used to
collect samples during the comet encounter and the opposite side was
used for interstellar dust collection.  Each side of the collector
contained a total of 1000 cm^2 of useful collecting area.
 
The collector was housed in the Sample Return Capsule (SRC), a
container about a meter in diameter, attached to the Stardust
spacecraft along the -x-axis direction.  The SRC opened like a
clamshell, allowing the collecting grid to be deployed into the dust
stream to collect samples.  Stowage of the collector was achieved by
first folding the collector grid onto the boom via the wrist joint and
then folding the boom/collector into the SRC canister via the shoulder
joint.  At the end of the mission, the SRC detached from the
spacecraft and returned to Earth, where the dust samples can be
analyzed in detail.
 
In addition to allowing the collector grid to fold up into the SRC,
where it was protected, the deployment mechanism was the key for
maximizing the amount of time available for the capture of
interstellar dust particles. The mechanism allowed the collector to be
steered via the wrist joint about the spacecraft y-axis toward the
-z-axis. The collector field-of-view remained unobstructed by the SRC
backshield for 51 degrees of this motion, half the grid was in shadow
at 63 degrees, and all of the grid was in shadow at 75 degrees.  (Note
that for the shadow definition, the ISP stream is assumed to be
incoming perpendicular to the aerogel grid.) It is worth noting that
the collector field-of-view would remain completely unobstructed for
65 degrees of the motion should the shoulder joint be used during
interstellar dust particle collection.  However, usage of the shoulder
joint with the collector fully deployed was considered to be an
unnecessary risk.
 
The collector was deployed during three separate subphases to obtain
dust samples: two periods of Interstellar Particle (ISP) collection
and the encounter with Wild 2, where comet samples were obtained.  The
first ISP collection period lasted from February 22 through May 1,
2000, and the second from August 5 through December 9, 2002.  For the
collection of comet dust at Wild 2, the collector was deployed on
December 24, 2003 and remained deployed until January 2, 2004.
 
 
Spacecraft Geometry
-------------------
 
                                ^ +Y
                                |
                                |
                                |
         _______________ ______________ ______________
        |               |              |              |||
        |               |              |    solar     |||
        |               |              |    panel     |||
        |_______________|_ __________ _|______________|||
                      __| \__________/ |
                    /|  |    ___       ||||
         SRC -----&gt;/ |  |   /HGA\      |||| &lt;---Whipple      -------&gt;  +X
                   \ |  |   \___/      ||||     Shield
                    \|__|  __________  ||||
         _______________|_/__________\_|______________
        |               |              |              |||
        |               |              |    solar     |||
        |               |              |    panel     |||
        |_______________|______________|______________|||
 
 
 
                                ^ +Z
                                |
                                |
               High-gain -.     |                 .-- Solar panels
                 Antenna   \                     /
                            \.                  /
        ________________ __.&apos;_`._______ _______/______|||
                      __|--------------||||           |||
                    /|  |              ||||
        SRC -----&gt; / |  |  Spacecraft  |||| &lt;---Whipple      -------&gt;  +X
                   \ |  |     Bus      ||||     Shield
                    \|__|______________||||
 
 
 
 
Interstellar Particle (ISP) Streams
-----------------------------------
 
For collecting interstellar dust particles, the Stardust project made
use of the fact that the solar system is moving through an environment
of interstellar dust grains.  This motion causes the ISPs to appear to
stream through interplanetary space in a preferred direction.  The
upstream direction for this flow (in ecliptic latitude and longitude)
is in the vicinity of (7.7 degrees, 259 degrees), which is the value
adopted for designing the ISP collection.  For this direction, the ISP
flow has a speed of 26 km/sec relative to the solar system.
 
The flight paths of ISPs are modified by the gravity of the sun, the
solar radiation pressure and various other complex processes not well
or easily formulated.  If one considers only the simple effects of
solar gravity and solar pressure, the velocities of ISPs of various
sizes can be calculated easily as a function of beta, where beta is
the ratio of the solar pressure to solar gravity.  High beta particles
(greater than 1) are believed to be low density, fluffy grains while
low beta particles (less than 1) are denser and more compact.  One to
one correspondence between the beta group and the particle size cannot
be made without knowledge of individual particle density, shape and
radiative parameters, though assumptions can be made to estimate the
range of grain sizes that are likely to be encountered.  Typical
results indicate that grains from 0.1 to a few microns should be
expected.
 
 
ISP Collection Planning Constraints
-----------------------------------
 
A number of constraints were used to guide the planning of the ISP
collection phases.
 
   o Larger particles are preferred for laboratory analysis. As such,
     the best orientation for the collection of interstellar particles
     is one that tracks the beta=1 particle.  Optimization for these
     grains means that solar radiation pressure balances solar
     graivity, and so the trajectories of the dust are largely
     unaffected by passage through the solar system.
   o The collector pointing strategy should be consistent throughout
     the collection periods. If this is attained, then it is expected
     that the tracks left in the aerogel will reveal inertial
     direction information of the collected particles.
   o Low impact velocities (less than 25 km/s) are required to assure
     higher chance of successful capture of the particles.
   o Collection of interplanetary particles is to be avoided to
     prevent corruption of the interstellar dust sample.
     Interplanetary particles are assumed to have a velocity of 50
     km/s and to be traveling radially outward from the sun.  This
     constraint can be relaxed to allow for communications, TCMs, and
     spacecraft deadbanding.
   o Contamination of the interstellar sample by plume impingement
     (rocket exhaust from the spacecraft) is to be kept to a
     minimum. As such, no collection is permitted during DSMs (or TCMs
     &gt; 20 m/s), but allowed during other TCMs.
   o Collection is allowed with as much as half of the collector grid
     in the SRC backshell &apos;shadow&apos; if required to lengthen the
     collection periods.
 
 
ISP Collection Strategy
-----------------------
 
Interstellar dust collection was concentrated in the part of the
spacecraft&apos;s trajectory where the interstellar dust impact velocity
was relatively low (e.g., the spacecraft was moving in roughly the
same direction as the dust stream) For this configuration, the dust
was overtaking the spacecraft from behind, which allowed the ISPs to
be collected on the back side of the dust collector.
 
Given the passive nature of the collection instrument and the
uncertainty in the direction of the interstellar stream (as large as
30 degrees), stringent attitude control was unnecessary, and the
optimum periods for collecting ISPs corresponded well to the inbound
portions of the cruise phases.  Collection was performed only during
the first two orbits, resulting in 201 days of total collection time.
Collection was not performed on the third loop to avoid contamination
of the cometary samples collected during the encounter with Wild-2.
 
In addition to the science constraints described above, a number of
spacecraft constraints were imposed for the planning of interstellar
dust science. The following spacecraft guidelines apply to the design
of these experiments:
 
   o Off-sun angles of the +z-axis are limited to 15 degrees
     (absolute) when pointing the +x-axis (whipple shields) toward the
     sun and 35 degrees (absolute) when pointing the -x-axis (SRC)
     toward the sun. Assume 15 degrees deadbands during ISP collection
     and CIDA periods, such that, maximum &apos;center-of-deadband&apos; off-sun
     limits are 0 degrees and 20 degrees, respectively.
 
   o Off-Earth angles are limited such that Earth must always be kept
     within one of the low gain antenna fields-of-view.
 
   o The aerogel grid is to be deployed only once per ISP collection
     period.
 
   o Science periods should avoid conflicts with other mission phases
     (Launch, EGA, Encounter) and key geometrical events (solar
     conjunction).
 
 
ISP Collection Subphases
------------------------
 
Capture of ISPs was accomplished via the passive aerogel collector
that was maintained inside the SRC and deployed during the ISP
collection subphases.  As previously stated, the collection subphases
are defined via the previously discussed constraints.  The off-sun
angle and beta meteoroid constraints in conjunction with the aerogel
collector deployment geometry were the primary geometric factors that
defined the start and end of each collection period.
 
Each ISP collection period was established using two different
strategies for tracking the spacecraft relative to the ISP velocity
vector. The first strategy was implemented during the first part of
each collection period and involved taking advantage of the deployment
motion (about the wrist joint) of the aerogel grid to track the motion
of the ISP stream in the spacecraft x-z axis plane. The out-of-plane
component of the ISP stream was tracked by yawing (yaw is a rotation
about the z-axis) the spacecraft sufficiently to place the s/c
relative ISP stream in the x-z axis plane. The +z-axis of the
spacecraft, and as a result the solar panels, remained oriented toward
the sun.
 
Once the aerogel grid wrist was fully extended it could no longer be used
to track the ISP stream and the second strategy was invoked. The second
strategy involved pointing the spacecraft -x-axis toward the incoming
ISP stream. With the grid wrist fully extended, the vector normal to
the grid surface was parallel to the spacecraft x-axis. The strategy was
implemented until the off-sun angle was such that the beta meteoriod
constraint was violated, which typically occured prior to reaching power
related off-sun angle constraints.
 
Both of these strategies were consistent with the above stated off-sun
angle limits. As previously stated, the maximum allowable
&apos;center-of-deadband&apos; off-sun angles, given 15 degrees deadbands, are 0
degrees and 20 degrees, respectively. The aerogel grid deployment
geometry allows collection to start much earlier than would be
possible by a simple off-sun pointing strategy, especially in light of
the 0 degrees +x-axis-to-sun off-sun angle constraint.
 
 
Comet Dust Collection
---------------------
 
For the comet encounter sub-phase, the dust collector was fully
deployed nine days before closest approach.  The spacecraft&apos;s attitude
was such that the +x-axis was aligned with the spacecraft&apos;s velocity
vector (relative to the comet).  This oriented the collector so that
it was perpendicular to the incoming dust, which would impinge on the
front side of the grid.  About five hours after the closest approach
to comet Wild 2, the collector was stowed, where it remained protected
until it was opened after returning to the Earth .
 
Collector Deployed Configurations
---------------------------------
 
           Collector fully extended          Collector steered into
             (comet encounter and                  ISP stream
            ISP tracking strategy 2)        (ISP tracking strategy 1)
 
                        ||                           \\
   Collector Grid ----&gt; ||                            \\
                        ||                             \\
          Wrist ------&gt; o                               o
                        |                               |
                        |                               |
                        | _____                         | _____
        Shoulder -----&gt; o|     |                        o|     |
                         |     |                         |     |
                         | SRC |                         |     |
                /`._     |     |                /`._     |     |
                \   `._  |     |                \   `._  |     |
 Heatshield ---&gt; \     `.|_____|                 \     `.|_____|
   (open)         \______/                        \______/
 
 
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
The geometry configurations listed
    in this data set were derived from SPICE kernals for the Stardust
    spacecraft.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

