<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mgn-v-rss-1-bsr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MAGELLAN BISTATIC RADAR RAW DATA RECORDS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.magellan::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mgn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.mgn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgn-v-rss-1-bsr-v1.0__browserp_geo_mgn-v-rss-1-bsr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgn-v-rss-1-bsr-v1.0__dvo_geo_mgn-v-rss-1-bsr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hapke, B., and D. Blewett, Coherent backscatter model for the unusual radar
                   reflectivity of icy satellites, Nature, 352, 46-47, 1991.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAPKE-BLEWETT1991</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Pettengill, G.H., P.G. Ford, and R.A. Simpson, Electrical properties of the
                   Venus surface from bistatic radar observations, Science, 272, 1628-1631, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PETTENGILLETAL1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Simpson, R.A., Spacecraft Studies of Planetary Surfaces Using Bistatic Radar,
                   IEEE Transactions on Geoscience and Remote Sensing, 31, 465-482, March 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SIMPSON1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MGN-V-RSS-1-BSR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MAGELLAN BISTATIC RADAR RAW DATA RECORDS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1997-12-31</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1993-10-06</start_time>
        <stop_time>1994-06-06</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>RICHARD A. SIMPSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Simpson, R. A., MAGELLAN BISTATIC RADAR RAW DATA RECORDS V1.0,
            MGN-V-RSS-1-BSR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 1997
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Magellan Bistatic Radar (BSR) Raw Data archive is a
            time-ordered collection of raw and partially processed data from
            bistatic radar experiments conducted using the Magellan
            spacecraft while it orbited Venus.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Magellan (MGN) Bistatic Radar (BSR) Raw Data Archive (RDA) is
            a time-ordered collection of raw and partially processed data
            from bistatic radar experiments conducted using the Magellan
            spacecraft while it orbited Venus.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Magellan (MGN) Bistatic Radar (BSR) Raw Data Archive (RDA)
      is a time-ordered collection of raw and partially processed
      data from bistatic radar experiments conducted using the
      Magellan spacecraft while it orbited Venus.
 
      The spacecraft radio system was used as the signal source.  The
      spacecraft high-gain antenna (HGA) beamed those signals toward
      the surface of Venus where they were scattered and then
      received at stations of the NASA Deep Space Network (DSN) on
      Earth.  Changes in the amplitude, frequency, and polarization
      of the received signal can be related to the electrical and
      physical properties of the scattering surface.  Bistatic
      experiments have been described by [SIMPSON1993].
 
      Two types of experiments were conducted using Magellan.  In
      &apos;spotlight&apos; experiments a point on the surface was selected
      and, as the spacecraft moved over that point, the HGA was aimed
      toward it.  Experiments conducted on 6 October 1993 over Gula
      Mons and on 31 May 1994 over Maxwell Montes used the spotlight
      configuration.  In both cases, orbits and targets were chosen
      so that the backscatter geometry was included in the
      observation period.  The goal was to seek &apos;enhanced
      backscatter&apos; [HAPKE&amp;BLEWETT1991] from the target at exactly the
      time when the Earth, spacecraft, and target were aligned.
      Predictions were that such a detection would be marginal, at
      best, given the experiment parameters; but both spot targets
      were in regions known to have higher reflectivity than the
      average Venus surface.
 
      In the second type of experiment, the HGA was aimed toward the
      point on Venus&apos; surface where specular (mirror-like) reflection
      would be expected.  As the spacecraft moved in its orbit, the
      specular point moved along the ground.  Dispersion of the echo
      signal by reflection from multiple points on the surface, each
      with its own Doppler shift, is diagnostic of surface roughness.
      Total power is proportional to the Fresnel reflection
      coefficient for the surface material.  In these experiments,
      the total echo power is much stronger than in spotlight
      experiments.  S-band detections were predicted for
      quasi-specular experiments conducted on 9 November 1993 and on
      5 June 1994.
 
      Transmitted polarization along the boresight of the spacecraft
      antenna was linear at the S-band wavelength (13 cm, or 2298
      MHz) and circular at the X-band wavelength (3.5 cm, or 8415
      MHz).  Signals could be received coherently in both right- and
      left- circular polarizations at both wavelengths when a 70-m
      antenna was used at the DSN station.
 
      During these experiments, frequency of the spacecraft
      transmitter was controlled by an onboard crystal oscillator.
 
      Prior to and after most experiments, the high-gain antenna was
      pointed toward Earth both so that the frequency of the directly
      propagating signal could be measured and also so that the phase
      relationship between the two orthogonally polarized S-band
      receivers could be related to the spacecraft&apos;s linearly
      polarized transmissions.
 
      Spacecraft attitude was not adjusted during the experiments to
      account for refractive bending in the Venus atmosphere.
 
      Results from the quasi-specular experiments over Maxwell Montes
      on 5 June 1994 have been published [PETTENGILLETAL1996].
 
      The data set includes Original Data Records (ODRs), which are
      digitized recordings of baseband receiver output; the ODR is
      considered to be the primary data type in this archive.
      Archival Tracking Data Files (ATDFs or TDFs), records of
      closed-loop receiver output, are also included; they serve as
      low resolution backup to the ODRs but are not likely to include
      measures of scattered signal.
 
      Typical users of the data set would compute the expected
      frequency of the signal from the target point, compute Fourier
      transforms from the data samples, and sum the power spectra
      incoherently.  The amplitude and spectral width of a detected
      echo can be related to physical and electrical properties of
      the scattering surface (and to experimental parameters, such as
      the illumination footprint of the HGA on Venus&apos; surface).  The
      analysis which has been published [PETTENGILLETAL1996] included
      inference of surface properties from the polarization of the
      received echo signal.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      Open loop data records (ODRs) contain 8-bit samples of receiver
      output.  Each block of 4000 data samples is accompanied by a
      166 byte header.  The ODR is described by a Software Interface
      Specification (SIS), included as RSC11_11.TXT in the DOCUMENT
      directory of the data set archival volume.
 
      For experiments in 1993, two X-band (3.5 cm wavelength)
      open-loop receivers were used, one capturing right-circularly
      polarized signals and the other capturing left-circularly
      polarized signals.  These are identified in the data stream as
      Channels 1 and 3, respectively.  Two S-band open-loop receivers
      were also used for 70-m observations in 1993, yielding right-
      and left-circularly polarized output on Channels 2 and 4,
      respectively.  Failures in the data acquisition equipment make
      these four-channel 1993 data more difficult to use.
 
      By 1994, capabilities of the sampling equipment had degraded to
      the point where only two signals from the 70-m antennas could
      be recorded simultaneously.  For these experiments, the usual
      practice was to record two polarizations at X-band on one
      orbit, alternating with two polarizations at S-band on the next
      orbit.
 
      Each ATDF data record contains 117 parameters, stored in
      records of 288 bytes at rates up to one per second.  The
      parameters include estimates of received signal strength and
      frequency as well as status information on components of the
      DSN system.  The ATDF is described by a Software Interface
      Specification (SIS), included as TRK_2_25.TXT in the DOCUMENT
      directory of each archival volume.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      With the following exceptions, open loop data (ODRs) were not
      edited or otherwise processed before being incorporated into
      the archival volumes.
 
      (1) A 32-byte label at the beginning of each ODR tape is not
          included in the data file.  The 32-byte label gives the
          version of the data taking software; this information has
          been copied to the PDS label that accompanies the data
          file.  The software version recorded in the &apos;NOTE&apos; keyword
          is more likely to be accurate than the version recorded
          with the &apos;SOFTWARE_VERSION&apos; keyword.  Because the 32-byte
          label is no longer part of the data stream, users can treat
          the remaining file as an integral number of fixed-length
          records.
 
      (2) Some tapes were delivered with record lengths truncated to
          566 bytes rather than the expected 4166 bytes.  The
          truncation may have occurred during copying at the DSN
          station; no cause was ever determined and the original
          (uncorrupted) data were not recovered.  Records truncated
          to 566 bytes have been padded to their original 4166-byte
          lengths with binary zeroes before being stored in the
          archival volumes.  A list of these files is given in the
          ERRATA.TXT file at the root of the archival volume.
 
      The DSN Navigation Team sometimes edits ATDF records to remove
      values clearly outside the nominal range.  The extent of
      editing on Magellan bistatic radar ATDFs is not known.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      Original Data Records (ODRs) were the primary data type for
      this raw data archive.  ODRs were generated at stations of the
      NASA Deep Space Network (DSN) and were distributed on 6250 bpi
      tape.  Those tapes have been copied to disk files, defined as
      PDS TABLE Objects, and archived on these CD-WO volumes.  ODRs
      are stored on CD-WO volumes in chronological order; ancillary
      data files (to support analysis) accompany ODRs in the CALIB,
      GEOMETRY, and DOCUMENT directories.  The table FILELIST.TAB in
      the DOCUMENT directory shows relationships among ODR files and
      ancillary data.
 
      A nominal ODR contains 24000 records, each record having 166
      bytes of header data and 4000 bytes of 8-bit sample data.  Each
      of four receiver channels (X-RCP, S-RCP, X-LCP, and S-LCP) was
      sampled at 50000 samples per second in 1993; these appear in
      the output record as channels 1 through 4, respectively [see
      RSC11_11.TXT in the DOCUMENT directory of the archival volume].
      A single file represented 8 minutes of observing time.  For
      most experiments in 1994, only two channels were sampled
      (usually X-RCP and X-LCP, Channels 1 and 3, respectively; or
      S-RCP and S-LCP, Channels 2 and 4, respectively).  The sampling
      rates on each channel remained at 50000 per second, but the
      rate for each analog-to-digital converter was only 25000.  A
      single file usually represented 16 minutes of data.
 
      On MGN BSR archival volumes, ODR files have names of the form
      ydddhhmm.ODR where y gives the least significant digit of the
      year, ddd is the 3-digit day-of-year, hh is the 2-digit hour,
      and mm is the 2-digit minute on which data acquisition for the
      file began.
 
      Each ODR data file is accompanied by a full PDS detached label
      with name ydddhhmm.LBL which completely describes the contents
      of the ODR file.  The format and content of the ODR are also
      described in RSC11_11.TXT in the DOCUMENT directory of each
      archival volume.
 
      Archival Tracking Data Files (ATDFs or TDFs) are considered to
      be primary raw data for many radio science experiments.  In
      this case, they served a backup and ancillary role.  ATDFs are
      generated by the Radio Metric Data Conditioning Team in the
      DSN.  They were delivered either on computer-compatible tape or
      as electronic files.  They have been copied to disk, defined as
      PDS TABLE objects, and archived on these CD-WO volumes.
 
      A typical ATDF covered several days and had a volume of 35
      MBytes.  ATDF rates for these Magellan BSR experiments were
      typically one sample every 60 seconds.  Each sample was of 117
      items, including measurements of signal amplitude and frequency
      from closed loop receivers, and was stored as a single record
      of 288 bytes.  Sampling of the signals was limited to one
      polarization at S-band and one polarization at X-band.  Time
      resolution was more coarse than from the ODR and no information
      on signal phase was retained.  It is unlikely that the
      closed-loop receivers locked to the echo signal during bistatic
      maneuvers.  The ATDF, from this perspective, provided
      low-resolution backup to the ODR only during times when the HGA
      was pointed toward Earth.
 
      Each ATDF has a file name of the form ydddeeeX.TDF where y is
      the least significant digit of the year and ddd is the
      day-of-year for the first ATDF record.  The eee gives
      day-of-year for the last data record in the ATDF, and X is set
      to &apos;A&apos;.
 
      Each ATDF is accompanied by a full PDS detached label with name
      ydddeeeA.LBL which completely describes the contents of the
      ATDF.  The format and contents are also described in
      TRK_2_25.TXT in the DOCUMENT directory of each archival volume.
 
      A set of &apos;browse&apos; files is included on each CD-WO volume.  Each
      file is a composite PostScript file containing plots from three
      steps in a &apos;quick-look&apos; processing of the ODR data.  Each file
      will produce a single 8-1/2 x 11 inch page giving results from
      one &apos;channel&apos; from an ODR.  Plots are: (1) histogram of 8-bit
      sample values, (2) 60-second average power spectra, and (3)
      1-second average values of sample power versus time.  Also
      included in the fourth &apos;panel&apos; on each page is a text extract
      from the top of the ODR PDS label.  Plots were created as the
      archive was being assembled.  The plots should provide quick
      low resolution access to the contents of each ODR to users able
      to display or print PostScript files.  The plot files are
      located in the BROWSE directory.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      For each ODR, there is a set of ancillary files needed for
      analysis.  These files are stored in the CALIB and GEOMETRY
      directories, as appropriate.  A table FILELIST.TAB in the
      DOCUMENT directory shows relationships among ODRs and ancillary
      files.
 
 
      High-Gain Antenna (HGA) Radiation Pattern
      -----------------------------------------
        The radiation pattern of the high-gain antenna (HGA) is
        described in a PDS document with both ASCII and PostScript
        components in the CALIB directory.  The HGA pattern would be
        needed to estimate the illumination of any point on the Venus
        surface.  The HGA calibration document is described in the
        detached PDS label HGA_XXX.LBL in the CALIB directory; it is
        included on all CD-WO volumes.
 
 
      Observing Geometry
      ------------------
        Files describing the observing geometry are stored in the
        GEOMETRY directory.  These include NAIF &apos;text&apos; format SPK
        files and NAIF &apos;transfer&apos; format ephemerides.  Files
        describing spacecraft attitude are also included in the
        GEOMETRY directory, but are described in the next section.
 
        NAIF (PDS Navigation and Ancillary Information) &apos;text&apos; format
        SPK files are available for all observations except those on
        1994-05-31.  Data for 1994-05-31 are available in NAIF SPK
        &apos;transfer&apos; format.  SPK files contain the positions of
        Magellan, Venus, Earth, and the Sun in data modules that can
        be used readily with NAIF Toolkit software.  Each &apos;text&apos; SPK
        file has a name ending with the extension &apos;TSP&apos;; each
        &apos;transfer&apos; SPK file name ends with &apos;XSP&apos;.  Each SPK data file
        is accompanied by a detached PDS minimal label having the
        same file name but ending with the &apos;LBL&apos; extension.
 
        For all orbits, predicted Keplerian orbital elements for the
        Magellan spacecraft are available in the file KEPELEMS.TAB.
 
        A single NAIF &apos;transfer&apos; format file (PEPH8996.XSP) contains
        solar system ephemerides.  For reconstruction of observing
        geometry, this file may be used in conjunction with
        KEPELEMS.TAB as an alternative to the NAIF SPK files.
 
        Before using either &apos;text&apos; or &apos;transfer&apos; NAIF files, the user
        should convert ASCII carriage-return line-feed delimiters on
        each record to the default delimiter for text files on the
        local system, then use the NAIF utility SPACIT to convert the
        archival file to local binary.
 
        Information on acquisition, installation, and use of the NAIF
        software can be found in TK_FTP.TXT in the DOCUMENT
        directory.
 
 
      Spacecraft Attitude (Quaternions)
      ---------------------------------
        Since maneuvers were executed to point the HGA toward the
        surface during each bistatic radar experiment, information on
        the spacecraft attitude is required for proper analysis and
        interpretation of the results.
 
        Attitude data are available as spacecraft quaternion
        polynomial coefficients during maneuvers and as fixed
        quaternions prior to and after the maneuvers (during Earth
        point).  Quaternion files are in the GEOMETRY directory and
        have names of the form yydddeee.QPC where &apos;yy&apos; gives the
        2-digit year and &apos;ddd&apos; and &apos;eee&apos; give the start and end
        day-of-year for which the file applies.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      SPK ephemeris files and quaternion files were produced for the
      J2000 inertial reference frame.  NAIF reader routines may be
      used to convert these to other coordinate systems.
 
      Other data types are not dependent on definition of a
      coordinate system.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      Software for parsing, reducing, and analyzing data such as
      these has been developed at Stanford University and elsewhere.
      Because such software must usually operate at the bit-level and
      is written for a narrow range of platforms, it is not suitable
      for general distribution.  No software is included with this
      archival data set.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The archival data set is written on CD-WO media using the Young
      Minds CD Studio authoring system.  The CD-WO volumes conform to
      ISO 9660 standards.
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      With the exception of the quasi-specular track across Maxwell
      Montes [PETTENGILLETAL1996], relatively little analysis had
      been performed on the raw data at the time they were archived.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was reviewed by a peer review panel
      prior to its acceptance by the Planetary Data System (PDS).
      The peer review was conducted in accordance with PDS
      procedures.
 
      Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data
      set, key elements of the archive were distributed for
      preliminary review.  These included electronic versions of
      example PDS labels, CATALOG files, and Software Interface
      Specifications.  These materials were distributed to PDS
      personnel, the experiment investigator, and others, as
      appropriate.
 
      Data on the CD-WO volumes were checked using Stanford parsing
      and reduction software to ensure that they were both complete
      and accurate replicas of the data contained in the original
      tape files.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      The times covered by ODR tapes are given in FILELIST.TAB in the
      DOCUMENT directory.  The experiments are summarized briefly
      here.
 
      6 October 1993 (Orbits 9331, 9335, and 9336)
      --------------------------------------------
        This was a set of three spotlight experiments with Gula Mons
        as the target.  The summit of Gula Mons appears brighter than
        average in radar backscatter.  The objective was to detect
        enhanced backscatter in the bistatic configuration and to
        compare it with scatter at other angles.  Chances of bistatic
        detection were predicted to be marginal because of the
        rapidly changing bistatic geometry and the relatively small
        area at the summit of Gula Mons with enhanced reflectivity.
 
        Orbit 9331 was observed using the 70-m Goldstone antenna;
        X-RCP, S-RCP, X-LCP, and S-LCP were recorded.  A malfunction
        in the data acquisition equipment resulted in loss of about
        two-thirds of the records.  It may be possible to recover the
        remainder, but considerable care will be required in handling
        the remainder since sampling coherence has been lost -- at
        least at some record-to-record boundaries and possibly within
        single records.
 
        Orbits 9335 and 9336 were observed using the 70-m Canberra
        antenna.  Signals recorded included X-RCP, S-RCP, X-LCP, and
        S-LCP.  For both orbits, the data acquisition equipment
        functioned normally for several minutes, but then a 2-second
        modulation on all channels began.  There is some evidence
        that pairs of samples were being lost on a regular basis,
        effectively toggling RCP and LCP on both the X- and S-band
        channels every two seconds.  These data may be recoverable;
        but care will be required if the effects of the modulation
        are to be properly characterized and removed.
 
        From an early analysis, no clear echo signal was identified
        on any channel from any of the three orbits on 6 October.
 
     DSS  Start Time Stop  Time  Channels   Archive  Notes
     ---  ---------- ----------  --------   -------  ------------------
      14   13:24:14   13:32:31   XRSRXLSL   MG_2301  Lost records
      14   13:39:35   13:43:35   XRSRXLSL   MG_2301  Post-maneuver data
      --   --------   --------   --------   -------
      43   19:42:46   19:50:45   XRSRXLSL   MG_2301
      43   19:50:46   19:58:40   XRSRXLSL   MG_2301  Modulation
      --   --------   --------   --------   -------
      43   21:17:26   21:25:25   XRSRXLSL   MG_2301  Modulation
      43   21:25:26   21:33:20   XRSRXLSL   MG_2301  Modulation
 
 
      9 November 1993 (Orbits 9846 through 9848)
      ------------------------------------------
        Parts of three quasi-specular tracks were observed using the
        70-m DSN antenna near Madrid.  The tracks extended from near
        (27S, 67E), crossed the equator at 67E, passed near (76N,
        167E), and ended at approximately (57N, 210E).  Incidence
        angle was minimum (73 deg) near (41N, 73E) and increased to
        about 75.5 deg at both ends of the ground track, in all cases
        including a preliminary adjustment for atmospheric
        refraction.  Signals were received in X-RCP, S-RCP, X-LCP,
        and S-LCP polarizations.  The objective was to observe
        variations in reflected signal amplitude and bandwidth as the
        specular point moved across the surface.  Predicted signal
        strengths were more than adequate for detection at S-band;
        because of increased atmospheric attenuation and frequency
        dispersion during the surface scattering process, predicted
        performance at X-band was uncertain.
 
        Fifteen of 22 digital tapes that were received contained good
        data; the other 7 contained records from which about 90
        percent of the data samples had been truncated.  The cause
        for this was never determined, but there are suggestions that
        an incorrect record length may have been entered during
        copying.  The original tapes were recycled at the DSN station
        before the error was discovered.  Records in the archive have
        been padded to the correct length with binary zeroes to allow
        processing, albeit with artifacts in the output from the
        padding.
 
        S-band echoes were observed in both polarizations in real
        time, though amplitudes and echo widths varied considerably
        -- and the signal disappeared entirely at times.  No X-band
        echoes have been seen in preliminary reductions of the data,
        though confusion over monitor display settings led to early
        belief that both S- and X-band echoes were being seen in real
        time.
 
     DSS  Start Time Stop  Time  Channels   Archive  Notes
     ---  ---------- ----------  --------   -------  ----------
      63   09:17:32   09:25:31   XRSRXLSL   MG_2302  Orbit 9846
      63   09:25:32   09:33:31   XRSRXLSL   MG_2302  Orbit 9846
      63   09:33:32   09:41:31   XRSRXLSL   MG_2302  Orbit 9846
      --   --------   --------   --------   -------
      63   10:03:12   10:11:11   XRSRXLSL   MG_2302  Orbit 9846
      63   10:11:12   10:17:40   XRSRXLSL   MG_2302  Orbit 9846
      --   --------   --------   --------   -------
      63   10:51:41   10:59:40   XRSRXLSL   MG_2303  Orbit 9847
      63   10:59:41   11:07:40   XRSRXLSL   MG_2303  Orbit 9847
      63   11:07:41   11:15:40   XRSRXLSL   MG_2303  Orbit 9847
      63   11:15:41   11:22:41   XRSRXLSL   MG_2303  Orbit 9847
      63   11:23:09   11:31:08   XRSRXLSL   MG_2303  Orbit 9847
      63   11:31:09   11:39:08   XRSRXLSL   MG_2304  Orbit 9847
      63   11:39:09   11:47:08   XRSRXLSL   MG_2304  Orbit 9847
      63   11:50:32   11:53:02   XRSRXLSL   MG_2304  Orbit 9847
      --   --------   --------   --------   -------
      63   12:26:11   12:34:11   XRSRXLSL   MG_2304  Orbit 9848
      63   12:34:12   12:42:11   XRSRXLSL   MG_2304  Orbit 9848
      63   12:42:12   12:50:11   XRSRXLSL   MG_2304  Truncated records
      63   12:50:12   12:51:37   XRSRXLSL   MG_2305  Truncated records
      63   12:53:24   12:58:35   XRSRXLSL   MG_2305  Truncated records
      63   12:59:08   03:02:45   XRSRXLSL   MG_2305  Truncated records
      63   13:07:08   13:15:07   XRSRXLSL   MG_2305  Truncated records
      63   13:15:08   13:23:07   XRSRXLSL   MG_2305  Truncated records
      63   13:23:08   13:27:02   XRSRXLSL   MG_2305  Truncated records
 
 
      31 May 1994 (Orbits 12955 through 12958)
      ----------------------------------------
        Spotlight experiments were carried out over a target in the
        south- eastern part of Maxwell Montes; all receiving was done
        using the 70-m DSN antenna near Madrid.  The objective was to
        detect enhanced backscatter in the bistatic configuration and
        to compare it with scatter at other angles.  Chances of
        bistatic detection were predicted to be poor because of the
        rapidly changing bistatic geometry and the low radar cross
        section for Maxwell at the highly oblique viewing angles --
        despite its enhancement relative to nearby areas.
        Quasi-specular observations were planned over the same target
        five days later.
 
        Data were collected from four consecutive orbits.  The first
        orbit was observed using all four receiver channels (X-RCP,
        S-RCP, X-LCP, and S-LCP).  The second and fourth orbits were
        observed using only S-RCP and S-LCP; the third orbit was
        observed using only X-RCP and X-LCP.
 
        Tapes generally contained good data, but no signal was
        detected during preliminary processing.  Modulation was
        noticed on the X-RCP carrier prior to the first spotlight
        maneuver; its cause was not determined.
 
     DSS  Start Time Stop  Time  Channels   Archive  Notes
     ---  ---------- ----------  --------   -------  ----------------
      63   11:31:38   11:39:37   XRSRXLSL   MG_2306  Pre-cal
      63   11:39:38   11:47:30   XRSRXLSL   MG_2306  Pre-cal
      --   --------   --------   --------   -------
      63   12:15:34   12:23:01   XRSRXLSL   MG_2306  X-RCP modulation
      63   12:23:36   12:31:06   XRSRXLSL   MG_2306  X-RCP modulation
      63   12:31:21   12:39:04   XRSRXLSL   MG_2306  Orbit 12955
      63   12:40:06   12:42:21   XRSRXLSL   MG_2306  Orbit 12955
      63   12:49:16   12:54:58   XRSRXLSL   MG_2306  Orbit 12955
      63   12:55:31   13:03:30   XRSRXLSL   MG_2307  Orbit 12955
      63   13:03:31   13:10:33   XRSRXLSL   MG_2307  Orbit 12955
      --   --------   --------   --------   -------
      63   13:50:11   14:06:02   SRSLSRSL   MG_2307  Orbit 12956
      63   14:06:17   14:22:02   SRSLSRSL   MG_2307  Orbit 12956
      63   14:26:23   14:35:53   SRSLSRSL   MG_2307  Orbit 12956
      --   --------   --------   --------   -------
      63   15:25:10   15:41:09   XRXLXRXL   MG_2308  Orbit 12957
      63   15:41:10   15:57:09   XRXLXRXL   MG_2308  Orbit 12957
      63   15:57:10   16:03:01   XRXLXRXL   MG_2308  Orbit 12957
      --   --------   --------   --------   -------
      63   17:00:11   17:16:10   SRSLSRSL   MG_2308  Orbit 12958
      63   17:16:11   17:32:10   SRSLSRSL   MG_2308  Orbit 12958
      63   17:32:11   17:45:57   SRSLSRSL   MG_2308  Orbit 12958
 
 
      5 June 1994 (Orbits 13032 through 13040)
      ----------------------------------------
        Eight quasi-specular tracks were observed using two 70-m DSN
        antennas.  Each track extended from south of the Venus
        equator to beyond Maxwell Montes in the north.  The objective
        was to observe changes in reflected signal amplitude and
        dispersion as the specular point moved over different surface
        units.  Of particular interest was Maxwell Montes, targeted
        five days earlier in a spotlight bistatic experiment.
        Predictions were for real-time observation of echoes at
        S-band and possible detection (with intense non-real-time
        processing) of X-band echoes.
 
        Six orbits were captured using DSS 63 near Madrid; four were
        captured using DSS 14 near Goldstone.  Madrid began with
        S-RCP and S-LCP on the first orbit, switched to X-RCP and
        X-LCP on the second, and continued to alternate on successive
        orbits thereafter.  On the fifth orbit, DSS 14 began with
        X-RCP and X-LCP (while DSS 63 collected S-RCP and S-LCP), and
        alternated thereafter.
 
        Tuning predictions for the open-loop receivers were
        calculated at Stanford; owing to a sign error, the
        predictions failed to achieve the desired result, but
        real-time corrections to the tuning were sufficient to keep
        the S-band signal within the passband for all but the first
        of the DSS 63 observations.
 
        At DSS 14 an error in ground antenna pointing reduced signal
        levels considerably; those data probably have very little
        value when compared with the DSS 63 results.
 
        Some of the tapes received from DSS 63 had truncated records;
        for the archive, those have been padded with binary zeroes,
        as was done with the truncated records from 31 May 1994.
 
        About half the tapes received from DSS 14 were unreadable;
        the unreadable tapes are not included in the archive.
 
        S-band echoes were observed in real time from DSS 63; no
        X-band echoes were seen.  A paper based on this set of
        experiments has been published [PETTENGILLETAL1996].
 
     DSS  Start Time Stop  Time  Channels   Archive  Notes
     ---  ---------- ----------  --------   -------  -----------------
      63   13:09:31   13:25:30   SRSLSRSL   MG_2309
      63   13:25:31   13:41:30   SRSLSRSL   MG_2309
      63   13:41:31   13:48:39   SRSLSRSL   MG_2309
      --   --------   --------   --------   -------
      63   14:25:09   14:41:08   XRXLXRXL   MG_2309  Truncated records
      63   14:41:09   14:57:08   XRXLXRXL   MG_2309
      63   14:57:09   15:13:08   XRXLXRXL   MG_2309
      63   15:13:09   15:21:26   XRXLXRXL   MG_2310  Truncated records
      --   --------   --------   --------   -------
      63   15:58:12   16:14:11   SRSLSRSL   MG_2310
      63   16:14:12   16:30:11   SRSLSRSL   MG_2310
      63   16:30:12   16:46:11   SRSLSRSL   MG_2310
      63   16:46:12   16:54:17   SRSLSRSL   MG_2310
      --   --------   --------   --------   -------
      63   17:31:12   17:47:11   XRXLXRXL   MG_2310  Truncated records
      63   17:47:12   18:03:11   XRXLXRXL   MG_2311
      63   18:03:12   18:19:11   XRXLXRXL   MG_2311
      63   18:19:12   18:28:06   XRXLXRXL   MG_2311  Truncated records
      --   --------   --------   --------   -------
      63   19:10:25   19:26:24   SRSLSRSL   MG_2311
      63   19:26:25   19:42:24   SRSLSRSL   MG_2311
      63   19:42:25   19:58:24   SRSLSRSL   MG_2311
      63   19:58:25   20:00:23   SRSLSRSL   MG_2311
      --   --------   --------   --------   -------
      63   20:37:11   20:53:10   XRXLXRXL   MG_2312  Truncated records
      63   20:53:11   21:09:10   XRXLXRXL   MG_2312
      63   21:09:11   21:21:07   XRXLXRXL   MG_2312
      --   --------   --------   --------   -------
      14   18:52:34   19:01:20   XRXLXRXL   MG_2312  Pre-cal
      14   19:02:27   19:10:01                       Tape unreadable
      --   --------   --------   --------   -------
      14   19:33:44   19:49:43   XRXLXRXL   MG_2312  Bad Pointing
      14   19:49:44   20:01:25                       Tape unreadable
      --   --------   --------   --------   -------
      14   20:36:10   20:52:09   SRSLSRSL   MG_2312  Bad Pointing
      14   20:52:10   20:55:38                       Tape unreadable
      14   20:55:54   21:11:53   SRSLSRSL   MG_2313  Bad Pointing
      14   21:11:54   21:27:53                       Tape unreadable
      14   21:27:54   21:36:11   SRSLSRSL   MG_2313  Bad Pointing
      --   --------   --------   --------   -------
      14   22:09:09   22:25:08   XRXLXRXL   MG_2313  Bad Pointing
      14   22:25:09   22:41:08                       Tape unreadable
      14   22:41:09   22:57:08   XRXLXRXL   MG_2313  Bad Pointing
      14   22:57:09   23:06:53                       Tape unreadable
      --   --------   --------   --------   -------
      14   23:39:53   23:55:52   SRSLSRSL   MG_2313  Bad Pointing
      14   23:55:53   00:11:52                       Tape unreadable
      --   --------   --------   --------   -------
      14   00:11:53   00:27:37   SRSLSRSL   MG_2313  Bad Pointing
 
        Orbit numbers are not uniquely identified with the data
        collection intervals listed above; the table below may
        provide guidance.  Times after 11:00:00 are for 5 June 1994;
        times before 02:00:00 are for 6 June 1994.
 
            Orbit Number      Start Time (UTC)     Stop Time (UTC)
            ------------      ----------------     ---------------
                13032              11:48:08            13:21:04
                13033              13:21:05            14:54:02
                13034              14:54:12            16:26:59
                13035              16:27:00            17:59:56
                13036              17:59:57            19:32:54
                13037              19:32:54            21:05:51
                13038              21:05:52            22:38:48
                13039              22:38:49            00:11:46
                13040              00:11:46            01:44:43
 
 
      12 December 1995
      ----------------
        A test of the DSN equipment was carried out in December 1995
        to measure the phase shift introduced by attenuators on
        open-loop receivers.  The test was intended to show whether
        adding attenuation could change the inferred phase on one
        S-band channel with respect to the other.  Such a
        differential phase shift could lead to errors in
        reconstruction of linear received polarizations from the
        circulars that are actually recorded on the ground.
        Attenuator settings are included with the DSP header
        information, but the test data were never analyzed to the
        precision required to answer the question posed.  Data were
        collected at the DTF 21 DSN-equivalent site at JPL; sample
        rate was 200 Hz, so data records have lengths of 566 bytes.
 
     DSS  Start Time Stop  Time  Channels   Archive  Notes
     ---  ---------- ----------  --------   -------  -------------------
      06   17:13:13   17:39:59   XRSRXLSL   MG_2313  Phase vs atten test
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The limitations in this data set follow from the quality of the
      execution, which is described above under Data Coverage and
      Quality.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

