<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mer1-m-mb-4-sumspec-sci-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MER 1 MOESSBAUER 4 SUMMED SPECTRA RDR SCIENCE V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_exploration_rover::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mer1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mb.mer1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer1-m-mb-4-sumspec-sci-v1.0__browser_geo_mer1-m-mb-4-sumspec-sci-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer1-m-mb-4-sumspec-sci-v1.0__dvo_geo_mer1-m-mb-4-sumspec-sci-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer1-m-mb-4-sumspec-sci-v1.0__pds.geo.mer.analysts_notebook::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klingelhoefer, G., et al., The Athena MIMOS II Moessbauer Spectrometer
                   Investigation, Journal of Geophysical Research, 2003.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLINGELHOFERETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klingelhoefer, G., et al., Jarosite and hematite at Meridiani Planum from
                   Opportunity&apos;s Moessbauer Spectrometer, Science, 306, 1740-1745, 2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLINGELHOFERETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mars Exploration Rover Mission, Moessbauer Spectrometer RDR Software
                   Interface Specification, 2003
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MBRDRSIS2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Morris, R.V., et al., Mineralogy at Gusev Crater from the Moessbauer
                   Spectrometer on the Spirit Rover, Science, 305, 833-836, 2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MORRISETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MER1-M-MB-4-SUMSPEC-SCI-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MER 1 MOESSBAUER 4 SUMMED SPECTRA RDR SCIENCE V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2004-08-24</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-01-26T08:54:45.951Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>Goestar Klingelhoefer</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Klingelhoefer, Goestar, MER 1 Moessbauer 4 Summed Spectra RDR
            Science V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            MER1-M-MB-4-SUMSPEC-SCI-V1.0, 2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains Moessbauer Summed Spectra Science Reduced
            Data Records (RDRs) acquired by Opportunity (MER 1) during the
            Mars Exploration Rover Mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This archive contains Mars Exploration Rover Moessbauer Summed
            Spectra Reduced Data Record (RDR) products and ancillary files.
            Each product has a detached PDS label that describes the file
            structure and instrument parameters used for that image. The
            products archived on this volume were generated by the Moessbauer
            instrument team from Moessbauer EDR (Experiment Data Record)
            products. Supporting documentation and label files conform to the
            Planetary Data System (PDS) Standards, Version 3.6, Jet
            Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) document number D-7669.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The MB RDR data products are ASCII formatted tables.  Each ASCII
    table has an associated detached PDS label, also formatted as
    ASCII.  There are several types of MB RDR data products from
    intermediate data reduction to more highly derived ones.  MB
    Summed Spectra RDR products are expressed as summed spectra in
    counts as a function of channel number.
 
    Mineralogical interpretations by the Moessbauer Team of the
    Moessbauer data have been published in the following articles.
 
    Morris, R.V., et al., Mineralogy at Gusev Crater from the
    Moessbauer Spectrometer on the Spirit Rover, Science, 305, 833-836,
    2004 [MORRISETAL2004].
 
    Klingelhoefer, G., et al., Jarosite and hematite at Meridiani
    Planum from Opportunity&apos;s Moessbauer Spectrometer, Science, 306,
    1740-1745, 2004 [KLINGELHOEFERETAL2004].
 
  Processing
  ==========
    This dataset uses the Committee On Data Management And
    Computation (CODMAC) data level numbering system to describe the
    processing level of the MB RDR data products.  These data
    products are considered CODMAC Level 4 [&apos;Resampled Data&apos;
    equivalent to NASA Level 1-B].
 
    The MB RDR data products are produced by MB instrument team
    members from the Johannes Gutenberg University (Mainz, Germany)
    using software tools developed by the MB team.  The RDR data
    products - summed spectra in counts as a function of
    channel number - is generated after each sol in which MB data
    were acquired.  This step comprises an extraction of the MB
    spectra from the EDR products and subsequent conversion into
    ASCII formatted tables.
 
    MB RDR data products are generated from binary EDR files that are
    extracted from the OSS to the MB team workstations.  Once RDR
    data products are generated, they are transferred back to the OSS
    for access by other MER science and operations team members.
    After a science validation period, the MB RDR data products are
    transferred to the PDS for final validation and archiving in
    accordance with the MER archive plan.
 
  Data
  ====
    Each MB RDR data file is a table.  The number of columns and rows
    in the table is dependent on the type of RDR.  Columns are
    variable length and are delimited with commas.  Each row is
    terminated with a carriage return and line feed character.  There
    are 6 product types in this data set as described below.  The
    first product type (MGC) is a table of 14 keV (gamma-ray) MB
    spectra as a function of channel number.  The second product type
    (MXC) is a table of 6 keV (X-ray) MB spectra as a function of
    channel number.  The third product type (RSC) is a table of 14
    keV reference spectra as a function of channel number.  The
    fourth product type (DSC) is a table of differential signal as a
    function of channel number.  The fifth product type (ESC) is a
    table of energy spectra as a function of channel number.  The
    sixth product type (ESE) is a table of energy
    spectra in counts as a function of energy.
 
    Velocity calibration files for surface and CCT measurements are
    provided in the CALIB directory of the archive.  These files consist
    of thirteen columns: one per each temperature window.  The
    temperature windows correspond to the temperature windows in the
    MB spectra products (MGC and MXC).  The last temperature window in
    each velocity calibration file contains a room temperature
    extrapolation of the velocity scale.
 
  Software
  ========
    MB RDRs are formatted so that they can be directly imported into
    spreadsheet and plotting software packages.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    The data set will initially be delivered and kept online.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
NULL
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

