<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.uly-j-swoops-5-rdr-plasma-hires-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ULY JUP ENCOUNTER SWOOPS PLASMA HIRES DATA</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.ulysses::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.uly::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:swoops.uly::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.uly-j-swoops-5-rdr-plasma-hires-v1.0__browserp_uly-j-swoops-5-rdr-plasma-hires-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Bame, S.J., D.J. McComas, B.L. Barraclough, J.L. Phillips, K.J. Sofaly, J.C.
                   Chavez, B.E. Goldstein, and R.K. Sakurai, The Ulysses solar wind plasma
                   experiment, Astron. Astrophys. Suppl. Ser: 92, 237-265, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BAMEETAL1992A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Bame, S.J., B.L. Barraclough, W.C. Feldman, G.R. Gisler, J.T. Gosling, D.J.
                   McComas, J.L. Phillips, and M.F. Thomsen, Jupiter&apos;s Magnetosphere: Plasma
                   Description from the Ulysses Flyby, Science, 257, 1539, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BAMEETAL1992C</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hammond, C.M., J.L. Phillips, S.J. Bame, and E.J. Smith, Ulysses
                   Observations of the Planetary Depletion Layer at Jupiter, Planet. Space
                   Sci., 41, 853, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAMMONDETAL1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hoogeveen, G.W., J.L. Phillips, and M.K. Dougherty, Ulysses Observations of
                   Corotation Lags in the Dayside Jovian Magnetosphere: An Evaluation of the
                   Hinged Magnetodisc and Magnetic Anomaly Models, J. Geophys. Res.,
                   submitted, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HOOGEVEENETAL1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lin, N., P.J. Kellogg, J.P. Thiessen, D. Lengyel-Frey, B.T. Tsurutani, and
                   J.L. Phillips, Whistler Mode Waves in the Jovian Magnetosheath, J. Geophys.
                   Res., 99, 23527, 1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LINETAL1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Moldwin, M.B., E.E. Scime, S.J. Bame, J.T. Gosling, J.L. Phillips, and A.
                   Balogh, Plasma Electron Signatures of Magnetic Connection to the Jovian Bow
                   Shock: Ulysses Observations, Planet. Space Sci., 41, 795, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MOLDWINETAL1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Phillips, J.L., S.J. Bame, M.F. Thomsen, B.E. Goldstein, and E.J. Smith,
                   Ulysses Plasma Observations in the Jovian Magnetosheath, J. Geophys. Res.,
                   98, 21189, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PHILLIPSETAL1993A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Phillips, J.L., S.J. Bame, B.L. Barraclough, D.J. McComas, R.J. Forsyth, P.
                   Canu, and P.J. Kellogg, Ulysses Plasma Electron Observations in the Jovian
                   Magnetosphere, Planet. Space Sci., 41, 873, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PHILLIPSETAL1993B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Prange, R., P. Zarka, G.E. Ballester, T.A. Livengood, L. Denis, T. Carr, F.
                   Reyes, S.J. Bame, and H.W. Moos, Correlated Variations of UV and Radio
                   Emissions During an Outstanding Jovian Auroral Event, J. Geophys. Res., 98,
                   18779, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PRANGEETAL1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Schulz, M., J.B. Blake, S.M. Mazuk, A. Balogh, M.K. Dougherty, R.J.
                   Forsyth, E. Keppler, J.L. Phillips, and S.J. Bame, Energetic-Particle,
                   Plasma, and Magnetic-Field Signatures of a Poloidal Pulsation in Jupiter&apos;s
                   Magnetosphere, Planet. Space Sci., 41, 963, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SCHULZETAL1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tsurutani, B.T., J.K. Arballo, B.E. Goldstein, C. Ho, E.J. Smith, N.
                   Cornilleau-Wehrlin, R. Prange, N. Lin, P.J. Kellogg, J.L. Phillips, A.
                   Balogh, N. Krupp, and M. Kane, Plasma Wave Characteristics of the Jovian
                   Magnetopause Boundary Layer: Can Wave-Particle Interactions Cause the
                   Jovian Aurora?, J. Geophys. Res., submitted, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TSURUTANIETAL1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>ULY-J-SWOOPS-5-RDR-PLASMA-HIRES-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ULY JUP ENCOUNTER SWOOPS PLASMA HIRES DATA</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1998-05-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1992-01-25T00:07:16.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1992-02-17T23:56:31.000Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JOHN L. PHILLIPS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            ULY JUP ENCOUNTER SWOOPS PLASMA HIRES DATA
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The SWOOPS (Solar Wind Observations Over the Poles of the Sun)
            experiment has two electrostatic analyzers, one for positive ions
            and one for electrons. The instrument is fully described in:
            [BAMEETAL1992A]. The electron and ion analyzers are separate
            instruments that operate asynchronously.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The SWOOPS (Solar Wind Observations Over the Poles of the Sun)
      experiment has two electrostatic analyzers, one for positive
      ions and one for electrons. The instrument is fully described
      in: [BAMEETAL1992A].  The electron and ion analyzers are
      separate instruments that operate asynchronously.
 
      The following publications contain descriptions of SWOOPS
      operations and instrumental limitations at Jupiter:
 
      [PHILLIPSETAL1993A]
 
      [PHILLIPSETAL1993B]
 
      The electron instrument functioned well throughout the
      encounter, subject of course to its inherent energy
      limitations and to the energetic particle background present
      in the magnetosphere.  The ion experiment, which was
      optimized for solar wind measurements and thus has a limited
      field of view, produced useful measurements in the outbound
      magnetosheath only.  A summary of the ion measurements
      follows:
 
      INBOUND MAGNETOSHEATH.  The look direction of the experiment
      was ground-commanded, based on expectations of sheath flow
      direction.  During the brief inbound sheath encounter, the
      flow was anomalous (sunward at times). Thus the instrument
      &apos;missed the beam&apos; and returned no useful measurements.
 
      OUTBOUND MAGNETOSHEATH.  Here the flow was more or less as
      expected. The ion experiment captured most of the sheath flow
      beam during most outbound sheath intervals.  The measurements
      are shown in the sheath paper cited above.  In general, flow
      velocities agreed with the electron velocities.  Disagreements
      occurred when the ion sensor missed the heart of the beam.
      Densities and temperatures were generally substantially
      underestimated by the ion experiment due to its limited
      angular coverage.
 
      MAGNETOSPHERE.  Due to the limited energy range and look
      direction of the instrument, as well as the energetic
      particle background, the ion instrument did not return useful
      data in the magnetosphere.
 
      As a result of these problems, the SWOOPS ion observations
      inside the Jovian bow shock are not included in the archived
      Jupiter data.
 
      Data provided start at the beginning of day 25 (January 25,
      1992) and run through the end of day 48 (February 17) and
      include all bow shock and magnetopause crossings.  Both
      experiments were shut down for a 25-hour interval surrounding
      closest approach due to elevated penetrating background.
 
      The interval specified by PDS for this encounter includes
      substantial intervals of solar wind.  In general, the SWOOPS
      ion experiment provides superior characterization of solar
      wind density and speed in the solar wind, while the electron
      experiment provided the only easily usable data inside the
      Jovian bow shocks.  In order to provide the best observations
      for each phase of the encounter, the following schemes were
      adopted:
 
      0000 UT on Day 25 until 1200 UT on Day 33: Solar wind scheme.
      Electron temperature, charge-weighted ion (proton + alpha)
      density, and proton velocity.  Ion data were averaged to
      coincide with the electron spectral times.
 
      1200 UT of Day 33 until 1200 UT on Day 47: Jupiter scheme.
      Electron temperature, density, and velocity
 
      1200 UT on Day 47 until 2400 UT on Day 48: Solar wind scheme.
 
      The minor plasma discontinuities occurring at 1200 UT on days
      33 and 47 are artifacts of the switch-over between Jupiter and
      solar wind schemes.
 
      While the solar wind ion products included in the archive are
      created through routine data reduction, the electron
      parameters required unique Jupiter-specific processing.  A
      description of the experiment and processing follows.
 
 
    INTRODUCTION TO THE SWOOPS ELECTRON EXPERIMENT
    ----------------------------------------------
      The SWOOPS electron spectrometer is a 120-degree spherical
      section electrostatic analyzer which measures the 3-d velocity
      space distributions of solar wind electrons.  In the mode used
      at Jupiter, the instrumental energy range was 1.6 to 862 eV in
      the spacecraft frame.  Since the spacecraft charged to +2 to
      +44 volts during the encounter, 2 to 44 eV are subtracted from
      the measured energies (electrons measured at energies below
      the spacecraft potential are electrostatically trapped
      photoelectrons).
 
      Each spectrum takes 2 minutes to accumulate, but telemetry
      takes longer. During the Jupiter encounter, spectra were
      returned every 5.7 minutes. The analyzer uses 7 channel
      electron multipliers (CEMs) to count electrons discretely
      over 95% of the unit sphere in look direction.  For telemetry
      conservation, 2 out of every 3 spectra are &apos;two-
      dimensionalized&apos; onboard the spacecraft, that is the count
      rates are averaged over all 7 CEMs.  These 2-d spectra thus
      return electron counts as a function of energy and spacecraft
      spin angle. The full 3-d spectra return counts as a function
      of energy, spacecraft spin angle, and polar angle (measured
      from the spacecraft spin axis, which points at Earth).  The
      3-d spectra incorporate 32 spin-angle steps, for a total
      spectral content of 20 energies x 32 azimuths x 7 polar
      angles, while the 2-d spectra include 20 energies x 64
      azimuths x 1 angle.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The first step in data reduction is determination of the
      spacecraft potential. This is done by identifying inflections
      in the angle-averaged energy spectra. While this is automated
      in the solar wind, it was done by eye, spectrum-by spectrum,
      for the Jupiter encounter.  Potential averages +6 V in the
      solar wind and sheath, and substantially higher in the
      magnetosphere.  The count rate arrays are corrected for
      spacecraft potential and converted to phase-space density
      arrays.
 
      Plasma moments are then calculated by numerical integration of
      the velocity weighted ion distributions.  A total integration
      is performed from the spacecraft potential (corresponding to
      zero energy solar wind electrons) to the instrumental energy
      limit.  Since the first few eV above the spacecraft potential
      are contaminated with photoelectrons on non-radial
      trajectories, it is necessary to use a biMaxwellian fit to the
      lowest energy points to fill in this part of the distribution.
 
      The integrations produce density, temperature components,
      velocity, and heat flux.  At this time, densities, scalar
      temperatures, and 3-d velocity vectors (for 3-d measurements
      only) are being provided for archiving.
 
      5. BOUNDARIES AND TRANSITIONS OBSERVED DURING THE ENCOUNTER
 
      The following boundaries and regions were identified by the
      SWOOPS experiment team (see the papers cited above for
      details):
 
      Day       Time    Feature
 
      33        1733    Cross bow shock (BS) into magnetosheath
      33        2222    Cross magnetopause (MP) into boundary layer (BL)
      33        2308    Enter magnetosphere
      34        1655    Enter BL
      34        1720    Cross MP into sheath
      34        1945    Cross MP into BL
      35        0025    Cross MP into sheath
      35        0100    Cross MP into BL
      35        0125    Cross MP into sheath
      35        0250    Cross MP into BL
      35        0400    Enter magnetosphere
      38        1132    Enter open field region
      38        1335    Enter magnetosphere
      38        2137    Enter open field region
      38        2310    Enter magnetosphere
      39        0054    Last usable data before shutdown
      40        0152    First usable data after shutdown
      40        1126    Enter open field region
      40        1232    Enter magnetosphere
      40        2125    Enter open field region
      40        2241    Enter magnetosphere
      43        0024    Enter BL
      43        0100    Enter magnetosphere
      43        1058    Enter BL
      43        1226    Enter magnetosphere
      43        1337    Enter BL
      43        1357    Cross MP into sheath
      43        1700    Cross MP into BL
      43        1740    Enter magnetosphere
      43        1820    Enter BL
      43        1910    Cross MP into sheath
      45        0037    Cross BS into solar wind
      45        0428    Cross BS into sheath
      45        0933    Cross MP into BL
      45        1030    Enter magnetosphere
      45        1400    Enter BL
      45        1600    Enter magnetosphere
      45        1815    Enter BL
      45        1825    Enter magnetosphere
      45        2045    Enter BL
      45        2140    Cross MP into sheath
      47        0753    Cross BS into solar wind
 
 
    Data
    ====
      The data provided to the NSSDC are the total charge density
      (electron or charge-weighted ion), electron temperature, and
      plasma (electron or proton) velocity.  Electron data were
      integrated over the full instrumental energy range but not
      extrapolated to higher energies.  Spacecraft position is also
      provided. The times specified in the file are the centers of
      each 2-minute spectrum.
 
      The data file was created with Fortran on a Vax running VMS.
      It can be opened and read as follows:
 
      open (3, file=&apos;SWOOPS.TAB&apos;, status=&apos;old&apos;, recl=151)
 
      c      time           - spacecraft event time in the format
      c                       yyyy-mm-ddThh:mm:ss.sssZ
      c      idim           - dimension of electron spectrum (2 or 3)
      c      rj             - Jupiter-spacecraft distance, Rj
      c      xlat           - Jovigraphic latitude of spacecraft,
      c                       degrees
      c      xmlat          - magnetic latitude of spacecraft,
      c                       degrees
      c      lt             - local time of spacecraft, hhmm
      c      density        - charge density per cubic cm
      c      temp           - electron temperature, Kelvins
      c      vx,vy,vz       - plasma bulk velocity, in km/s in XYZ
      c                       system
      c      vr,vtheta,vphi - plasma bulk velocity, in km/s in
      c                       spherical system
 
            read(31,88)
           &gt;    time,idim,rj,xlat,xmlat,lt,
           &gt;    density,temp,vx,vy,vz,vr,vtheta,vphi
 
      88    format(a24,1x,i2,1x,f8.3,2(1x,f8.2),1x,i4,8(1x,e11.4))
 
      Velocity components are flagged (-9.9999e+10) for 2-d spectra
      when Jupiter scheme is in use.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      The following coordinate systems are used:
 
      1.  XYZ is a Jupiter-centered cartesian system with solar
      longitude fixed.  Z is northward along the planetary rotation
      axis, X is perpendicular to Z in the plane containing Z and
      the Sun-Jupiter line, positive anti-sunward, and Y completes
      the right-handed set, positive dawnward.
 
      2. Spherical is a standard spherical system based on the
      Jupiter-centered spacecraft position, with R positive outward,
      Theta positive in a southward sense, and Phi positive in the
      sense of planetary rotation.
 
      8. FURTHER INFORMATION
 
      For information on acquiring other types of data not provided
      to the PDS contact the Principal Investigator, Dr. John L.
      Phillips, at the Los Alamos National Laboratory,
      jlphillips@lanl.gov, 505-667-3101. Also contact Dr. Phillips
      for information on the reduction and analysis of data from the
      electron experiment. For information on the reduction and
      analysis of data from the positive ion experiment, contact Dr.
      Bruce E. Goldstein at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory,
      bgoldstein@jplsp2.jpl.nasa.gov, 818-354-7366.
 
      Researchers with innovative ideas who would like to
      collaborate with the SWOOPS team in analysis of these data,
      are invited to contact Dr. Phillips.
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      In the magnetosphere, a very simple scheme was used for
      background rejection. The lowest count rate for a given
      spectrum was subtracted from all pixels in that spectrum.
      Thus any changes in background during the course of a 2-
      minute spectra accumulation time are not accounted for.
      While the resulting plasma densities were corroborated by
      comparison with the plasma frequency-based densities from the
      URAP experiment (see magnetosphere paper cited above), the
      possibility exists that some roll-modulated background exists
      and distorts the plasma velocities.  At the time of this
      submission, the velocities provided are the best values
      available. However, the SWOOPS team is actively pursuing a
      roll-modulated background rejection scheme, and the data will
      be updated as appropriate.  The user should be cautious in
      interpreting the electron velocities.
 
      During the intervals indicated as open field regions in the
      listing above, there are significant uncertainties in all
      plasma parameters. This is due to uncertainties in the
      spacecraft potential.  While it is clear that the densities
      are relatively high and the temperatures are low in these
      regions, small errors in spacecraft potential can create
      large errors in all derived plasma parameters.  These values
      will be updated as the SWOOPS team research into the open
      field regions continues.
 
      The spacecraft ephemeris was provided by the Ulysses project
      at high resolution during the encounter proper.  Far from the
      planet (i.e. the beginning and ending of the SWOOPS data
      file), the ephemeris resolution was coarser, and you will see
      large steps in spacecraft position in the SWOOPS data file.
      Higher-resolution position information may be available
      through the PDS.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>90-090B-00C</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

