<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ear-a-i0035-5-sdsstax-v1.1</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>SDSS-BASED ASTEROID TAXONOMY V1.1</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.support_archives::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.obs413t2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:i0035.obs413t2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.asteroid::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-a-i0035-5-sdsstax-v1.1__browserp_ear-a-i0035-5-sdsstax-v1.1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Bus, S.J. and R.P. Binzel, Phase II of the small main-belt asteroid
                   spectroscopic survey: A feature-based taxonomy, Icarus 158, 146- 177, 2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BUS-BINZEL2002B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Carvano, J. M., P.H. Hasselmann, D. Lazzaro, and T. Mothe-Diniz, SDSS-based
                   taxonomic classification and orbital distribution of main belt asteroids,
                   Astronomy and Astrophysics, Volume 510, id.A43, DOI:
                   10.1051/0004-6361/200913322, 2010.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CARVANOETAL2010</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Ivezic, Z. and 31 others, Solar System objects observed in the Sloan Digital
                   Sky Survey commissioning data, AJ 122, 2749-2784, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.IVEZICETAL2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Ivezic, Z., M. Juric, R.H. Lupton, S. Tabachnik, T. Quinn, and the SDSS
                   Collaboration, SDSS Moving Object Catalog V3.0. EAR-A-I0035-3-SDSSMOC-V3.0.
                   NASA Planetary Data System, 2010.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.IVEZICETAL2010</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>EAR-A-I0035-5-SDSSTAX-V1.1</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>SDSS-BASED ASTEROID TAXONOMY V1.1</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2011-05-31</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1998-09-19</start_time>
        <stop_time>2007-03-14</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>PEDRO HENRIQUE HASSELMANN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Hasselmann, P. H., Carvano, J. M., and Lazzaro, D., SDSS-based
            Asteroid Taxonomy V1.1. EAR-A-I0035-5-SDSSTAX-V1.1. NASA
            Planetary Data System, 2012.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Asteroid taxonomic classifications of the Sloan Digital Sky
            Survey Moving Object Catalog, as reported in Carvano et al.
            (2010).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Sloan Digital Sky Survey Moving Object Catalog (SDSS-MOC) is
            a large data set that provides five-filter magnitudes and
            astrometric information for all moving objects identified in the
            SDSS images (Izevic et al., 2010). The photometric observations
            were classified by Carvano et al. (2010) into nine taxonomic
            classes: Vp, Op, Qp, Sp, Ap, Lp, Dp, Xp and Cp, which are related
            to the classes and complexes of Bus Taxonomy (Bus &amp; Binzel,
            2002b). This data set is contains the taxonomic classification of
            each SDSS detections and its compilation for each observed
            asteroid.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The Sloan Digital Sky Survey Moving Object Catalog (SDSS-MOC) is a large
    data set that provides five-filter magnitudes and astrometric information
    for all moving objects identified in the SDSS images. Its 4th release
    contains 471,569 detections prior to March 2007, where 220,101 are linked
    to 104,449 unique objects (Izevic et al. 2010). This actual data set is
    the result of the taxonomic classification for the SDSS-MOC asteroid
    observations.
 
    The asteroid observations are classified into nine classes: Vp, Op, Qp,
    Sp, Ap, Lp, Dp, Xp, and Cp, all related to the classes and complexes of
    Bus taxonomy (Bus &amp; Binzel, 2002b). Furthermore the probability for each
    observation to belong each class are also computed. After this, the
    taxonomic classifications for each observation are collapsed into a single
    classification for each asteroid. Asteroids and observations were allowed
    to be assigned to more than one class. Further information about the
    method, the defining limits for each class and the classification
    algorithm can be found in Carvano et al. (2010).
 
    The data set is composed of three tables:
 
    The SDSS Taxonomy Observation Table (107,467 records) containing the
    taxonomic types for the multiple SDSS-MOC observations of each asteroid.
    This file also contains the classification probability score and the
    logarithmic reflectance values.
 
    The SDSS Taxonomy Asteroid Table (63468 records) containing the SDSS
    observed asteroids with their respective taxonomic type. This file also
    contains the probability scores, typical observations, binary flags and
    supporting astrometric informations.
 
    The SDSS Taxonomy Templates (9 records) is the table containing templates
    representing each taxonomic type. Each template has its modal logarithmic
    reflectance value and its color ranges used on the classification
    procedure.
 
     == Logarithmic Reflectances ==
 
    Logarithmic reflectances (log reflectances) are directly proportional to
    calibrated  magnitude colors, but their values are independent of
    reference reflectance,  which reduces the influence of the normalization
    on asteroid spectra. Therefore log reflectances are not absolute values
    but a differential quantity relative to the reference filter.
 
    The calibrated magnitude colors are obtained by the difference of the SDSS
    magnitudes relative to a reference filter and subtracting it the solar
    colors, obtained from Izevic et al. (2001). Finally the log reflectances
    can be simply derived from Pogson equation, where log reflectance is
    -0.4*Cx + log(Rref), whereas magnitude color Cx = mx - mref - (mxsun -
    mrefsun). The uncertainties were calculated by propagation of the
    magnitude errors.
 
    The g&apos; band is set as reference due to its band peak (0.47 micrometers) be
    located close to the standard reference wavelength position at 0.550
    micrometers.
 
 
     == References ==
 
    Bus, S.J. and R.P. Binzel, Phase II of the small main-belt asteroid
    spectroscopic survey: A feature-based taxonomy, Icarus 158, 146- 177,
    2002.
 
    Carvano, J. M.; Hasselmann, P. H.; Lazzaro, D.; Mothe-Diniz, T. SDSS-based
    taxonomic classification and orbital distribution of main belt asteroids,
    Astronomy and Astrophysics, Volume 510, id.A43, DOI:
    10.1051/0004-6361/200913322, 2010.
 
    Ivezic, Z., Juric, M., Lupton, R.H., Tabachnik, S., Quinn, T., and the
    SDSS Collaboration, SDSS Moving Object Catalog V3.0.
    EAR-A-I0035-3-SDSSMOC-V3.0. NASA Planetary Data System, 2010.
 
    Ivezic, Z. and 31 others, Solar System objects observed in the Sloan
    Digital Sky Survey commissioning data, AJ 122, 2749-2784, 2001.
 
     == Modification History ==
 
    The data set was updated to version 1.1 in early 2012 to correct colunm
    name and descriptions in the file sdsstax_obs_table.lbl, changing
    REFLECTANCE_xxx to LOG_REFLECTANCE_xxx, and to add a description of the
    derivation of the  log reflectances to the data set description. Typos and
    sentences were corrected, also some minor changes were made in the data
    set description to clarify the text.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    All the photometric and astrometric data are provided by the SDSS MOVING
    OBJECT CATALOG V3.0 (Izevic et al. 2010), thus any information about the
    confidence level must be located there.
 
    The data was sampled before the classification procedure,
    which is represented by the binary flag at the colunm BAD.
    This quality flag is raised when one or more magnitudes had
    uncertainties above the 3rd quartile of the error distributions.
    The taxonomic classification for these observations and asteroids must
    be handled with caution. For further information about this quality flag,
    see Carvano et al. (2010).
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

