<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ear-j-aat-3-edr-sl9-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ANGLO-AUSTRALIAN OBSERVATORY DATA FROM SL9 IMPACTS</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.support_archives::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.aao::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:iris.aao::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.sl9::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-j-aat-3-edr-sl9-v1.0__browserp_ear-j-aat-3-edr-sl9-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>EAR-J-AAT-3-EDR-SL9-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ANGLO-AUSTRALIAN OBSERVATORY DATA FROM SL9 IMPACTS</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1997-10-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1994-07-17T05:03:08Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1994-07-22T12:25:59Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>VIKKI MEADOWS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Meadows,V., ANGLO-AUSTRALIAN OBSERVATORY DATA FROM SL9 IMPACTS,
            EAR-J-AAT-3-EDR-SL9-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 1997.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This SL9 data set contains imaging, spectroscopy, &amp; spectral
            mapping ofJupiter from 1994Jul16 through 1994Jul23. This includes
            datafrom the C,D,G,K,N,R,V, and W impacts in addition to before
            andafter observations for baseline and comparison.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This SL9 data set contains imaging, spectroscopy, &amp; spectral
            mapping of Jupiter from 1994Jul16 through 1994Jul23. This
            includes data from the C,D,G,K,N,R,V, and W impacts in addition
            to before and after observations for baseline and comparison.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
Data Set Overview
=================
 
The data set contains imaging, spectroscopy, and spectral mapping of
Jupiter from July 16, 1994 through July 23, 1994.  This includes data
from the C, D, G, K, N, R, V, and W impacts in addition to before and
after observations for baseline and comparison.
 
The imaging for the V impact is composed of .455 second exposures of the
planet taken about 10 seconds apart with one image per file.  This mode
has a low duty cycle, but allows continuous monitoring of the event
without significant loss of large blocks of time which is encountered
when dumping a data cube to disk.
 
The imaging for the N impact is composed of 100 .455-second exposures
taken one after another and then all dumped onto disk at once in a
60x60x100 cube with the x and y dimensions corresponding to spatial
dimensions (xy planes are IMAGES in this case, in comparison to the
spectral mapping data, where the yz plane holds the image) and the z
dimension corresponding to time.  These large image cubes took a
significant amount of time to dump to disk, causing the N data to be
composed of 45 second periods of constant monitoring with excellent
temporal resolution interspersed with data gaps of approximately 40
seconds.
 
The majority of the impact sequences (C, D, G, K, R, W) were done using
spectral mapping.  This is done by taking multiple spectra through a
slit and then moving the slit back and forth across the planet to obtain
a second dimension of spatial information.  So:  these cubes will (most
likely) be 128x128x153 cubes with the x dimension being a spectral
dimension and corresponding to a wavelength scale between 2.2 and 2.39
microns for K-band data.  The y dimension corresponds to spatial
information, with high y values being farther to astronomical east.  The
z dimension corresponds to both north-south spatial information and
temporal information as well.  The slit was moved first from south to
north, and then from north to south across the planet to produce each
discrete cube.  Thus when a ytplane is cut through the cube at a desired
wavelength range, two images of Jupiter appear in the resulting image.
The image on the left has south to the left and north to the right, and
the image on the right is flipped, having north to the left and south to
the right.  It is important to also remember that the image on the right
is actually from a later point in time than the image on the left, thus
fast moving objects (satellites) may change position slightly between
the two images and fast changing objects (impact sites) will change in
either morphology or intensity (or both) between the two images as well.
For a full planet scan, the data cube takes about 4 minutes to complete
a double scan and 1-2 minutes to dump to disk.  We therefore monitor the
impact region with a temporal resolution of 3 minutes in the full scan
case, but this time interval can be decreased by sacrificing spatial
coverage.  This compromise was made for parts of the C, K and G
sequences, resulting in temporal resolution as fast as 15 seconds
between impact spectra.   Therefore the spectral mapping achieves
coarser temporal resolution compared to photometric imaging
observations,  but in return provides near simultaneous acquisition of
spatially resolved spectra across the entire impact region.
 
There are also several image cubes of nonstandard size, such as those
taken with a small (60 pixel) window and/or those which scan across the
impact site only, but many times thus improving the temporal resolution
of the impact data.
 
Lastly, there are many two-dimensional spectra such as sky frames and
standard stars which are similar to the spectral mapping cubes but with
only one frame.  In these, like in the mapping cubes, the x dimensions
correspond to spectral data and the y dimensions to spatial data.
 
 
Parameters
==========
 
Wavelengths are measured in microns and intensities
in Watts per meter squared per micron.
(W/(m^2*um)  or sometimes W*m^-2*um^-1).
 
In the spatial dimension, pixels are 0.6 arcseconds square (yz).
 
The slit used was 1.2 arcseconds wide.
 
Coordinate System
=================
 
1950AD equinox.
 
Software
========
 
No software is provided with this data set. However, this data set was
written using the Figaro software package which is publicly available
from the AAO. See the following URLs for access to this software
package: http://www.aao.gov.au/ http://www.aao.gov.au/figaro.html A
sample summary of how to view the images using Figaro follows: In the
following description, Figaro commands are shown lowercase in line
commands, and in uppercase in the general text.  However, they should
always be typed all lowercase on Unix systems.
 
Once Figaro is installed and running:
 
Type FIGDISP to bring up the Figaro display window.  On a Sun, press the
F6 key to bring up the pixel position and value display on the top bar
of the Figaro window (pressing F5 will display help information on the
features of this image display program).
 
To read in a given *.fit file, type RDFITS with a carriage return and
answer the prompts for input and output file names.  On a Sun, take the
defaults (yes) for byte swapping and conversion to floating point.  Note
that all the parameters can be entered on the command line, thus:
 
rdfits filename.fit figaro_out \\
 
will read in filename.fit, take the defaults for byte swapping and
conversion to floating point, and output a file figaro_out.sdf which is
in Figaro format.
 
To add the wavelength scale, use RDIPSO to convert the wavelengths.dat
file into a Figaro file:
 
rdipso wavelengths.dat 2 wavelength_scale \\
 
This will create a Figaro file wavelength_scale.sdf which should then be
XCOPYd onto the Figaro data, so:
 
xcopy figaro_out wavelength_scale figaro_out
 
This will replace the x-axis in the file figaro_out with wavelength
value in microns.  The above command will write the output file back
over the input file.  If you wish to keep both steps, change the second
&apos;figaro_out&apos; to something else.
 
The Figaro format cube can now be examined using the commands XYPLANE,
YTPLANE, IMAGE and EXTRACT.
 
YTPLANE will slice through the cube in the YT direction (corresponding
to the YZ direction in the PDS data) to show image planes within the
cube.  The user must specify over which X range (wavelength) the image
is to be extracted.  To extract an image in the wavelength range 2.32 to
2.38um, use the command
 
ytplane figaro_out 2.32 2.38 ytimage \\
 
If you have not tacked the wavelength scale on yet, simply specifying a
range of pixel values will also work.
 
Now, ytimage can be displayed:
 
image ytimage reset opt=0 \\
 
will give an autoscaled version of the image in the figdisp window.  You
can also simply type in IMAGE, carriage return, and answer the prompts
to optimize the display.
 
The command XYPLANE works in much the same way, extracting and adding
together a range of contiguous planes in the t (PDS z) direction.  t in
this case corresponds to time, or scan step, and in the ytimage you have
just displayed, you can isolate which t pixels correspond to the desired
spatial region you wish to extract a spectrum from (e.g.  the impacts,
or perhaps the poles).  The t pixels correspond to the x-axis direction
in a ytplane. Once you have your chosen t range (say, t1 to t2, where t1
and t2 are integers) from the ytplane image, use:
 
xyplane figaro_out t1 t2 xyimage \\
 
image xyimage reset opt=0 \\
 
This will now show you the spatially resolved spectra for that scan time
and region, with the x axis corresponding to x in the cube, and being
the wavelength axis, and y being a spatial dimension along the slit.
Isolate which spectrum you wish to extract on the xyimage by choosing a
range of y values (say y1 to y2) and then use:
 
extract xyimage y1 y2 impact_spectrum \\
 
To display the spectrum, use the figaro SPLOT command:
 
splot impact_spectrum wh au \\
 
will bring up a graphics window and autoscale the spectrum.  Again,
typing SPLOT and carriage return will allow you to step through the
prompts and optimize the display.
 
Further information on more detailed functions with Figaro can be found
at http://www.aao.gov.au/figaro.html
 
 
The QUBE OBJECT does not have much software support in the PDS at this
time. However, because these files are in FITS format, they are easily
read in by a standard FITS reading routine such as in IDL.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
Confidence Level Overview
=========================
 
The AAT data were taken in photometric conditions with seeing that was
typically 1 arcsec.  Poorer seeing was experienced during the R impact
(up to ~ 5&apos;&apos;).  However, although the data were taken in photometric
conditions, the drift-scanning technique used to take the majority of
the data contains inherent errors which compromise photometric accuracy
when used on point sources (such as the early stages of the impact
phenomena).  As the narrow slit is stepped across the object, variations
in seeing result in a time-varying point-spread function (PSF) which
changes both FWHM and spatial position, making it difficult to correctly
sample the object&apos;s PSF.  This effect can be ameliorated by taking
several scans back and forth across the object to average the effects of
the seeing.  However, for the rapidly changing phenomena associated with
the impact events, this was not possible. In an attempt to quantify the
error, we performed aperture photometry on the Galilean satellites
present in the impact data (as approximations to point sources) and
found typical standard deviations of 10%, with errors as large as 23% on
21 July (R impact).  This error is correlated with the seeing, being
larger on nights of poorer seeing.  However, when the observations are
averaged, absolute fluxes derived for the same satellite observed on
different nights show a standard deviation of 12% for Europa, which was
observed on 17, 19 and 21 July (if measurements taken only on 17 and 19
July are considered, this discrepancy falls to 3%), and 1% for Io, which
was observed on 19 and 21 July.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>GD-11F</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

