<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lp-l-rss-5-gravity-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LP LUNAR GRAVITY V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_prospector::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.lp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lp-l-rss-5-gravity-v1.0__browserc_lp-l-rss-5-gravity-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lp-l-rss-5-gravity-v1.0__browserp_geo_lp-l-rss-5-gravity-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lp-l-rss-5-gravity-v1.0__dvo_geo_lp-l-rss-5-gravity-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Konopliv, A.S., N.J. Borderies, P.W. Chodas, E.J. Christensen, W. Sjogren, B.G.
                   Williams, G. Balmino, and J.P Barriot, Venus Gravity and Topography: 60th
                   Degree and Order Model, Geophysical Research Letters, 20, 2403-2406, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KONOPLIVETAL1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Konopliv, A. S., A. B. Binder, L. L. Hood, A. B. Kucinskas, W. L. Sjogren, and
                   J. G. Williams, Improved gravity field of the moon from Lunar Prospector,
                   Science, 281, 1476-1480, 1998.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KONOPLIVETAL1998</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lemoine, F.G., D.E. Smith, M.T. Zuber, G.A. Neumann, and D.D. Rowlands, A 70th
                   Degree Lunar Gravity Model (GLGM-2) from Clementine and Other Tracking Data,
                   Journal of Geophysical Research, 102, 16339-16359, 1997.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEMOINEETAL1997</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Newhall, X X, and J. G. Williams, Estimation of the Lunar Physical
                   Librations, Celestial Mechanics and Dynamical Astronomy, 66, 21-30, 1997.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NEWHALL-WILLIAMS1997</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Smith, D.E., M.T. Zuber, G.A. Neumann, and F.G. Lemoine, Topography of the Moon
                   from the Clementine Lidar, Journal of Geophysical Research, 102, 1591-1611,
                   1997.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SMITHETAL1997</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Wieczorek, M.A., and R.J. Phillips, Potential Anomalies on a Sphere:
                   Applications to the Lunar Crust, Journal of Geophysical Research, 103,
                   1715-1724, 1998.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.WIECZOREK-PHILLI1998</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LP-L-RSS-5-GRAVITY-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LP LUNAR GRAVITY V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1999-04-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1998-01-11</start_time>
        <stop_time>1999-02-08</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>ALEXANDER S. KONOPLIV</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Konopliv, A. S., LP LUNAR GRAVITY V1.0, LP-L-RSS-5-GRAVITY-V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 1999
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The gravitational signature of the Moon was determined from
            velocity perturbations of the Lunar Prospector (LP) spacecraft as
            measured from the Doppler shift of the S-band radio tracking.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The gravitational signature of the Moon was determined from
            velocity perturbations of the Lunar Prospector (LP) spacecraft as
            measured from the Doppler shift of the S-band radio tracking
            signal. LP was tracked by NASA&apos;s Deep Space Network (DSN) at
            Goldstone, California, Canberra, Australia, and Madrid, Spain.
            The tracking data were used to determine the LP orbit about the
            Moon, as well as the lunar gravity field [KONOPLIVETAL1998].
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The gravitational signature of the Moon was determined from
    velocity perturbations of the Lunar Prospector (LP) spacecraft as
    measured from the Doppler shift of the S-band radio tracking
    signal.  LP was tracked by NASA&apos;s Deep Space Network (DSN) at
    Goldstone, California, Canberra, Australia, and Madrid, Spain.
    The tracking data were used to determine the LP orbit about the
    Moon, as well as the lunar gravity field [KONOPLIVETAL1998].
 
    The LP data were combined with S-band tracking observations from
    Lunar Orbiters 1, 2, 3, 4, and 5 and from the Apollo 15 and 16
    subsatellites [KONOPLIVETAL1993] and from Clementine
    [LEMOINEETAL1997].
 
    There are several gravity products in this archive.  These
    include two 75th degree and order spherical harmonic
    gravitational field models, designated LP75D and LP75G, and one
    100th degree and order spherical harmonic gravitational field
    model LP100J for which the coefficients are available.  Free-air,
    geoid, and Bouguer maps are also available for the LP75D and
    LP100J models.  The LP75D model was a preliminary model that was
    presented at the LP Press Conference in March, 1998.  It contains
    LP data to February 17, 1998.  The LP75G model was published in
    the special LP Science issue in September 1998
    [KONOPLIVETAL1998].  It contains data to April 12, 1998.  The
    LP100J model includes all the LP Doppler and range data through
    February 8, 1999.  This includes all the near 100 km altitude
    data (Jan.  11, 1998 to Dec.  19, 1998), the data from the 40 km
    average altitude orbit (Dec.  19, 1998 to Jan.  29, 1999) and the
    first 10 days of the 30 km average altitude orbit.  The LP
    nominal mission lasted for one year to mid-January 1999 and the
    extended mission will continue at a 30 km average altitude to the
    end of July, 1999.  More models and maps will become available
    after the completion of the extended mission.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    There are 3 data types for the gravity products found on this
    volume: tabular, array, and image data.  The files containing the
    spherical harmonic coefficients of the Moon&apos;s gravity field
    (LP75D, LP75G, LP100J) are in tabular format, with each row in
    the table containing the degree index m, the order index n, the
    coefficients Cmn and Smn, and the uncertainties in Cmn and Smn.
 
    The gridded digital maps (at 1 degree resolution) of Free-air
    gravity anomalies, Free-air gravity errors, Bouguer anomalies,
    Geoid anomalies, and Geoid anomaly errors are 64-bit binary
    images.  There are also gridded ASCII 2-D data arrays of each of
    the digital maps, and byte-scaled images of each of the gridded
    products.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The gravitational signature of the Moon was determined from
    velocity perturbations of the LP and previous spacecraft
    (Clementine, Lunar Orbiters and Apollo 15 and 16 subsatellites)
    as measured from the Doppler shift of the S-band radio tracking
    signal.  The LP Doppler data from the DSN stations were acquired
    with a count interval of 1 second but were compressed to 10
    seconds for this gravity analysis.  Most of the historic Doppler
    data were at a count interval of 60 seconds except for Clementine
    which had a count time of 10 seconds.  In addition, ranging data
    to LP was included.
 
    The Free-air gravity anomalies of the Moon (in milligals, mGals,
    where 1 mGal = 0.01 mm/s^2) are evaluated at the reference sphere
    of 1738.0 km, and are determined from the indicated gravity
    solution.  The Free-air gravity errors are also in mGals.  Geoid
    anomalies and errors are in meters.  The Bouguer anomaly is the
    observed gravity as given by the indicated gravity model minus
    the theoretical gravity from the topography model.  A crustal
    density of 2.8 and mean density of 3.34 gm/cm^3 are used together
    with the GLTM-2C 90th degree and order topography model
    [SMITHETAL1997] to determine the theoretical gravity.  The degree
    one terms are not included and there is no correction for maria
    fill.  The method of computing the theoretical gravity of a
    topography model was done by expanding in powers
    [WIECZOREK&amp;PHILLI1998].
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The LP100J gravity solution consists of 2,969,982 observations,
    of which 2,589,003 were contributed by LP.  The data were divided
    into 491 spans or independent arcs based on considerations of
    data coverage and timing of maneuvers.  The table below
    summarizes the number of observations and arcs from each
    spacecraft:
 
    Satellite            Number   Typical Arc     Total Observations
                         of Arcs  Length (days)
 
    Lunar Orbiter-1         58        1             37,651
    Lunar Orbiter-2         82        1             69,827
    Lunar Orbiter-3         48        1             56,472
    Lunar Orbiter-4          5        3              9,309
    Lunar Orbiter-5         41        1             39,752
    Apollo-15 subsatellite  21        3             45,438
    Apollo-16 subsatellite   7        4             25,475
    Clementine              29        3             97,055
    LP (LP75D)              23        2            250,520
    LP (LP75G)              36        2            604,997
    LP (LP100J @100km)     176        2          2,282,094
    LP (LP100J @40km&amp;30km)  24        2            306,909
 
        Total              491                   2,969,982
 
    For each arc certain parameters were determined: for example, the
    spacecraft state (position and velocity), solar radiation
    pressure coefficients, Doppler biases for each station over the
    arc to account for frequency biases, and increments in velocity
    to account for spacecraft manuevers.  The DE403 set of planetary
    and lunar ephemerides was used in the analyses.
 
    The data in LP75G and LP100J solutions were weighted near the
    residual rms of the Doppler data in the arc which for LP was near
    1 mm/s.  The a priori constraint on the LP75G solution was a
    power law rule (Kaula constraint) of 15 x 10e-5/L^2, where L is
    the spherical harmonic degree.  For the LP100J solution, the a
    priori was also a power law but relaxed to 36 x 10e-5/L^2.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    N/A
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    The coordinate system for the gravity data, and the coefficients
    in the LP75D, LP75G and LP100J gravity fields, is selenocentric,
    center of mass, longitude positive east.  The location of the
    pole and the prime meridian are defined by the principal axes as
    given by the integrated lunar librations of DE403
    [NEWHALL&amp;WILLIAMS1997].
 
 
  Software
  ========
    N/A
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    The LP gravity dataset will be available electronically via the
    World-Wide Web and anonymous FTP transfer:
    http://pds-geophys.wustl.edu/pds/lunar_prospector/harmonics_maps.
    The archive will also be delivered to the National Space Sciences
    Data Center (NSSDC) using compact disk write once (CD-WO) media.
    Formats will be based on standards established by the Planetary
    Data System (PDS).
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The data noise on the historic Doppler data ranged from 0.3 to
    several mm/s, depending on the arc, and most of the data were at
    a count interval of 60 seconds.  The Clementine Doppler data from
    the DSN stations had a data noise of 0.25 mm/s with a count
    interval of 10 seconds.  Clementine was also tracked by a 30
    meter antenna of the Naval Research Lab in southern Maryland.
    These data were also at 10 second count intervals and had a
    significantly higher data noise of 2.5 to 3.0 mm/s and so this
    data from the Pomonkey tracking station was not included in the
    LP gravity solutions.
 
    Errors in the Free-air gravity anomalies from LP75D, LP75G, and
    LP100J models are difficult to access because of no direct
    farside gravity measurements.  The more recent LP100J model has a
    more realistic representation of the errors.  The errors for the
    equatorial nearside are about 20 milligals and are as large as
    100+ milligals for farside short wavelength mascon features.
 
    Errors in the Geoid range from 4 meters on the nearside to about
    30 meters for the farside.
 
    Gridded digital maps showing the errors associated with the
    Free-air gravity and Geoid anomalies are included in the archive.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    The volume containing the LP gravity dataset will be formally
    reviewed by the PDS.
 
 
  Data Coverage/Quality
  =====================
    Lunar Prospector is the first circular polar orbiter for the Moon
    in a low altitude orbit of 100 km.  The only previous low
    altitude data (about 100 km) was from the Lunar Orbiters and
    Apollo subsatellites at low inclination (&lt; 30 degrees).  Lunar
    Orbiters 4 and 5 provided some near equatorial data at low
    altitude from their polar eccentric orbit, but no low altitude
    data for the high latitudes.  Clementine, with its eccentric
    near-five hour orbit, had a periapse altitude of 415 km and so
    provided long wavelength information on the gravity field.
 
    Because of the Moon&apos;s synchronous rotation, spacecraft cannot be
    directly tracked from Earth over a large part of the lunar
    farside, so there is no tracking data from 120 to 240 degrees
    longitude in the +/- 70 degree latitude band.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    See Data Coverage/Quality above.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>98-001A-04A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

