<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.go-a-c-ssi-2-redr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GALILEO ORBITER ASTEROID AND COMET SL9 SOLID STATE IMAGING 2</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.comet_sl9-jupiter_collision::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.galileo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:ssi.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.ida::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.non_science::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-a-c-ssi-2-redr-v1.0__browserp_go-a-c-ssi-2-redr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-a-c-ssi-2-redr-v1.0__dvo_imaging_go-a_c-ssi-2-redr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Cribbs, M.A., and D.A. Wagner, Planetary Science Data Dictionary, JPL Document
                   D7116, November, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CRIBBS1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   McLaughlin, Bruce, EJ-7 Shoemaker-Levy 9 DMS Data Return
                   Strategy,GLL-MDT-94-096.IOM, May 13, 1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MCLAUGHLIN1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Wainio, Lisa, SSI REDR Software Interface Specification (SIS), JPL Document
                   D12109, April 20, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.WAINIO1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   White, Mitchell, SSI REDR CD-ROM Software Interface Specification (SIS),
                   JPL Document D232-15, July 9, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.WHITE1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GO-A/C-SSI-2-REDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GALILEO ORBITER ASTEROID AND COMET SL9 SOLID STATE IMAGING 2</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1995-10-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1993-07-22T22:35:34.497Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1994-07-22T07:45:16.781Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>MICHAEL J. S. BELTON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Galileo Imaging (SSI) Asteroid and Comet Shoemaker-Levy 9
            Experiment Data Records
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set has been generated by NASA&apos;s Galileo Project
            in order to distribute the images acquired by the Solid State
            Imaging (SSI) camera to the scientists and later to the Planetary
            Data System (PDS). The collection resides on volume GO_0016 and
            consists of all images acquired by the Galileo spacecraft during
            the period from the flyby of Ida through the Shoemaker-Levy 9
            (SL9) comet impact on Jupiter. This includes data from SCLK
            197327200 through 249221800 and contains the following targets:
            stars, Ida and Jupiter.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set has been generated by NASA&apos;s Galileo Project in
    order to distribute the images acquired by the Solid State
    Imaging (SSI) camera to the scientists and later to the
    Planetary Data System (PDS).  The collection resides on volume
    GO_0016 and consists of all images acquired by the Galileo
    spacecraft during the period from the flyby of Ida through the
    Shoemaker-Levy 9 (SL9) comet impact on Jupiter.  This includes
    data from SCLK 197327200 through 249221800 and contains the
    following targets: stars, Ida and Jupiter.
 
 
    Ida Overview
    ------------
      The Ida science data return plans and resulting spacecraft
      sequences were complex due to several factors including among
      others, uncertainty in the relative location of Ida and the
      spacecraft, uncertainty in spacecraft attitude and instrument
      pointing and downlink data rate constraints.  At the outset,
      it was decided to return Ida data only when the
      telecommunications downlink supported 40 bps telemetry rate.
      Due to the limited time available for data playback at 40
      bps, the intent was to identify and return only the highest
      priority data.
 
      The playback of Ida data was accomplished by spacecraft
      stored sequence control.  Sequences included a preview of the
      data on the tape recorder (Jailbar Search) so that the high
      priority data could be located for later return.  On the
      basis of the jailbar search data, mini-sequences were
      developed to control the positioning of the tape within the
      tape recorder so that the desired data would be transferred
      from the tape recorder to the central computer and then to
      the ground.
 
 
    SL9 Overview
    ------------
      During Shoemaker-Levy 9 (SL9), multiple exposures of Jupiter
      were acquired on the CCD array by simultaneously slewing the
      scan platform and activating the shutter while suppressing
      CCD read-out.  The resulting multiple exposure image is
      called an on-chip mosaic (OCM), and is referred to as the
      readout frame or playback image.  Each of the single
      exposures within the OCM is called a shutter event.
 
      The intent of the SL9 Data Return Strategy was to return a
      key subset of the acquired data based upon successive
      refinement of the comet fragment impact timing uncertainties.
      This goal was achieved through the use of two types of OCM
      observation patterns, diagonal scan and discrete shutter
      events, and the use of Jail Bar data playback techniques.
      These data acquisition approaches are described in the
      Parameters Section.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
    Ida Data
    --------
      The Galileo SSI camera acquires data in a digital
      raster-format containing 800 scan lines and 800 samples per
      scan line.  Each picture element (pixel) in the two
      dimensional image array is represented as an 8-bit value
      between 0 and 255, proportional to the amount of light
      detected at that point (with 0 being the least amount of
      light and 255 being the greatest amount of light).  The
      camera is equipped with seven color filters and a clear
      filter such that images taken through complementary filters
      can be combined during ground processing to produce color
      images.  To make full scientific use of the image collection,
      the radiometric and geometric properties of the camera system
      should be understood.
 
      The ancillary disc, GO_0001, will provide calibration files
      and technical documentation necessary for the understanding
      of the images produced by the SSI camera.  Presently,
      calibration files and software are available through the
      VICAR software system at MIPS and SPICE files are available
      through the Galileo Science Data Team.
 
 
    SL9 Data Acquisition - Diagonal Scan
    ------------------------------------
      Impacts K and N were observed with a pattern of 6 25-second
      diagonal scans, one scan per OCM shuttering, followed by CCD
      readout in the HCM mode.  This pattern used the CCD as a
      tracing photometer, as the images of Jupiter were
      deliberately smeared across many pixels.  Impact signatures
      can therefore be observed as brighter pixels in the smear,
      and at finer time resolution than the fastest 2-1/3 second
      shuttering mode.  The pattern occupies approximately 1/3 of
      the SSI field of view.  The SCLKs of the six playback images
      for the impact K OCMs are: 248806645, 248807000, 248807300,
      248807700, 248808045 and 248808400.  The SCLKs of the three
      playback images for the impact N OCMs are: 248949900,
      248950200 and 248950600.
 
 
    SL9 Data Acquisition - Discrete Shutter Events
    ----------------------------------------------
      Impact W was observed with a discrete 8x8 pattern of 2-1/3
      second OCM shutterings, followed by CCD readout in the IM4
      mode.  This pattern leaves (nominally) 40 pixels between each
      60 pixel image.  Each discrete image of Jupiter represents
      one point in a 2-1/3 second time series of data points, with
      one readout (or playback image) providing up to 64 discrete
      data points.  In this manner, the time domain is translated
      into the spatial domain in the image.  Fifty-six of the
      shutter events are within the field of view (FOV) in each
      playback image.  The SCLKs of the playback images for the
      four discrete OCMs are: 249220555 (40 shutter events within
      the FOV played back), 249221000, 249221400 and 249221800.
 
 
    SL9 Data Acquisition - Jail Bar Data Playback
    ---------------------------------------------
      The Jail Bar Searches (MCLAUGHLIN1994) were used to locate
      the actual image shuttering and scanning pattern within each
      SSI FOV (the locations of which varied from the nominal due
      to scan platform pointing uncertainties) and also to provide
      a correspondence between the image data and locations on the
      spacecraft tape.  The Jail Bar Searches guaranteed return of
      two image lines out of every 80 for the diagonal scans and
      two lines of 40 for the discrete images.  The images returned
      during Jail Bar Searches were selected based upon ground
      observations and timing information available from other
      spacecraft instruments.
 
      Based upon the results of the Jail Bar Searches, the discrete
      shuttering events were subjected to a Jail Bar Return of up
      to eight 40 to 50 line swaths per frame for the four frames
      returned.  The Jail Bar Returns for the diagonal scan
      observations returned four lines (guaranteeing two) out of
      every eight.  See Processing Section (SL9-Specific
      Processing) for information about additional data recovery of
      lines for the diagonal scans.
 
 
    SL9 Signal to Noise Ratio
    -------------------------
      In order to improve the quality of data returned, the Deep
      Space Network sometimes used Block V Receivers to capture the
      data.  This improved the quality of data returned, but
      impacted the reliability of the signal to noise ratio value
      recorded in the binary line prefix of the REDR images.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
 
    REDR Processing
    ---------------
      The Raw Experiment Data Records (REDRs) were produced by the
      Multimission Image Processing Subsystem (MIPS) at the Jet
      Propulsion Laboratory using several Video Image
      Communications and Retrieval (VICAR) programs.  The
      processing included the following steps:
 
      --The original telemetry data was processed into
        raster-formatted files (GLLTELEMPROC)
 
      --Multiple versions of each data file obtained from separate
        downlinks or playbacks were merged together to create the
        best version of the data (SSIMERGE)
 
      --The VICAR label was updated to reflect the most recent
        pointing information (CATLABEL)
 
      --Bad data value information was then added to the Telemetry
        Header (BADLABELS)
 
      --Missing line gaps of two lines or less were filled in, as
        specified by the SSI Team. (GLLFILLIN)
 
      --The PDS  Index table and detached PDS label files were
        generated. (CDGEN)
 
      --The VICAR files and PDS files were premastered onto a WORM
         CD-ROM which was validated.
 
      --The WORM CD-ROM was sent to a vendor and CD-ROM&apos;s were
        generated.
 
       --A final CD-ROM was compared bit-by-bit with the original
         data to ensure the quality of the vendor product.
 
 
    SL9 Special Processing
    ----------------------
      To maximize the data return from the diagonal scan playbacks,
      the telemetry data was massaged so the MIPS Real-Time
      Subsystem would process embedded lines not normally recovered
      from HCM playbacks.  As a result, the number of returned
      image lines doubled.  A side-effect of this process
      introduced artifacts which appeared in the form of an entire
      (formerly blank) line of pixels set to DN value 255.  These
      lines were nullified by setting the affected pixel DN values
      to 0.  Nullified lines are identified in the VICAR label of
      the affected images.
 
      Dominating Reed-Solomon errors also existed in the diagonal
      scan playback images.  At the request of the SSI team,
      partial lines were nullified to minimize the distracting
      visual effects of these errors.  These nullified partial
      lines are also recorded in the VICAR label.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The volume contains approximately 800 images stored as VICAR
    files.  A detached PDS label has been included for each image.
    Documentation files have been provided which inform the user
    about the organization and contents of the disc, and the
    definition of the labels.  An index files have also been
    provided which contain information about the images in the data
    set.
 
    The REDR data are generated by MIPS using procedures
    specifically developed or adapted for Galileo.  The files are
    generated on a VAX and are written in VAX compatible (LSByte
    first) format.
 
 
    REDR File Format
    ----------------
      The Galileo REDR format (WHITE1993) was originally reserved
      for SSI calibration data or data which should not be
      radiometrically corrected.  The SSI Team recently decided
      that the REDR format will be used to archive all raw SSI
      data.
 
      Each REDR file consists of a VICAR label, the telemetry
      header, the bad-data value header records (if there are any),
      and the Image Data which is preceded by a Binary Prefix.
      There are 800 line records of image data.  All records are
      fixed length.  The line record length is 1000 bytes; 200
      bytes of a binary line prefix and 800 bytes of 8 bit pixel
      data.  (Note, for the AI8 format or summation mode, the
      record length is still 1000, but the data is placed in the
      first 400 pixel samples and 400 lines only.) There will be a
      one-to-one correspondence between line records and image
      lines.  Data not received will be zero-filled.
 
      The BINARY HEADER is composed of a Telemetry header and a
      Bad-Data Value Header containing ancillary information
      specific to the image.  The TELEMETRY HEADER is split into
      two physical records.  The first 1000 bytes are placed in the
      first physical record after the VICAR label, and the last 800
      bytes are placed in the next physical record.  The last 200
      bytes are zero filled.  The BAD-DATA VALUE HEADER is composed
      of records describing several types of bad data values.  Each
      record describes only one type and depending on the number of
      bad pixels, they may span over several physical records.
      Each record is identified by the Record IDS field which is
      located at byte 0.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    All document files and detached label files contain a carriage
    return character (ASCII 13) and a line feed character (ASCII
    10) at the end of each record.  This allows the files to be
    read by the MacOS, DOS, Unix, and VMS operating systems.
    Tabular files are also described by a detached PDS label.  The
    PDS label file has the same name as the data file it describes,
    with the extension .LBL; for example, the file IMGINDEX.TAB is
    accompanied by the detached label file IMGINDEX.LBL in the same
    directory.  The detached PDS labels for REDR images contain
    information pertaining to the image.
 
    Tabular files are formatted so that they may be read directly
    into many database management systems on various computers.
    All fields are separated by commas, and character fields are
    enclosed in double quotation marks.  Character fields are left
    justified, and numeric fields are right justified.  The start
    byte and bytes values listed in the labels do not include the
    commas between fields or the quotation marks surrounding
    character fields.  The records are of fixed length, and the
    last two bytes of each record contain the ASCII carriage return
    and line feed characters.  This allows a table to be treated as
    a fixed length record file on computers that support this file
    type and as a normal text file on other computers.
 
 
    SL9 Special Handling of Ancillary Information
    ---------------------------------------------
      Due to the OCM images in the SL9 data set ancillary
      information required special handling.
 
      In the past, the telemetry format for the SSI instrument data
      matched the telemetry format for the spacecraft, so the
      spacecraft telemetry format was automatically recorded in the
      data labels.  During the OCM process, the camera operated
      independently and under a different telemetry format than the
      spacecraft.  In the PDS and VICAR labels for the SL9 data
      set, the SSI telemetry format is provided.
 
      The imaging mode provided by the NAIF mini-e kernel for the
      first shutter event included in each of the discrete playback
      images had the value of the imaging mode of the playback
      image (8-2/3), not the shutter event.  This value was
      manually modified to reflect the shutter events&apos; imaging mode
      (2-1/3).
 
      In theory, the exposure duration of the playback images
      should be 0, but this would hinder subsequent image
      processing, such as radiometric correction.  Therefore the
      EXPOS_TIME for the playback images has been set to match the
      exposure time of the shutter events.
 
 
    SL9 Graphics Files
    ------------------
      A graphics file corresponding to each playback image has been
      generated to simplify the identification of shutter event
      PICNOs within playbacks.  The graphics files were generated
      by contrast enhancing a copy of the playback image to make
      the target more visible, then overlaying the text information
      onto the image.  Due to the quantity of shutter events within
      the playbacks, in order to make the graphics file readable,
      only the last four digits of the PICNOs are used in the
      graphics file to identify shutter events.  Although the files
      have been called graphics files they are still VICAR files
      with the same data format as the REDR.
 
 
      Each graphics file and its detached PDS label is located in
      the same directory as the corresponding playback image, and
      will have essentially the same filename as the playback,
      except the last character will be a G instead of an R.
 
 
    SL9 Index File
    --------------
      An additional text file, SL9INDEX.TXT (also located in the
      INDEX directory) has been generated which provides the
      spacecraft clock rim and mod91, Earth Observation Time (EOT),
      playback image filename, graphics filename, and a
      (line,sample) location of each shutter event.  The EOT is the
      time (UTC) that an Earth observer would have witnessed an
      event on Jupiter that was observed by the spacecraft during
      the specified shutter event.  The EOT is calculated by
      starting with the time at shutter midpoint, subtracting
      one-way light time to the subspacecraft point on Jupiter, and
      adding one-way light time from Jupiter to the Earth.  For the
      diagonal scans, the (line,sample) is a point roughly in the
      center of the slew, and for the discrete shutter events, the
      (line,sample) is a point on Jupiter.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The following CD-ROM copy, display and processing software has
    been successfully tested using the Galileo SSI data:
 
 
    Copy Software
    -------------
      --DCL  COPY (VMS) - available with VMS
      --VICAR Copy (VMS and UNIX) - Available with VICAR package from
        COSMIC.
 
 
    Display Software
    ----------------
      --VICAR JDISP  (VMS and UNIX) - Available with VICAR package
        from COSMIC.
 
      --PIXEL PUSHER (Apple Macintosh) - Available from COSMIC.
 
      --NIH IMAGE  (Apple Macintosh) - A public domain program
        available from the National Institute of Health.
 
      --CDBROWSE  (UNIX/Motif) - Software may be obtained from
        richard@ben.jpl.nasa.gov on the internet.
 
      --IMDISP (IBM PC) - Program and information  about this program
        are available from PDS.
 
 
    Processing Software
    -------------------
      --VICAR (VMS and UNIX) - Available from COSMIC
      --ISIS (VMS and UNIX) - Available through the USGS in Flagstaff
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    Each CD-ROM disc has been formatted such that a variety of
    computer systems may access the data.  Specifically, the discs
    are formatted according to the ISO 9660 level 1 Interchange
    Standard, and file attributes are specified by Extended
    Attribute Records (XARs).  Formats are based on standards for
    archive EDR CD-ROM products established by PDS.
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The SSI REDRs contain raw data as received from Galileo
    telemetry.  All 120 of the images received were processed and
    are contained on this volume.  Included in the limitations
    section are explanations of the VICAR and PDS keywords and
    values, as well as a description of a problem found with one
    frame in the data set.  This data set contains all of the data
    acquired during the Ida and Shoemaker-Levy 9 period, the
    processing has been verified, and is currently in use by
    science team members in their analysis
 
 
  Review
  ======
    The SSI REDRs are reviewed prior to archiving by the SSI team.
    Data received is compared with data expected, and replays of
    missing data is requested.  The status and validity information
    on the REDRs themselves is examined.  Format and documentation
    of the CD-ROM archive volume is reviewed by PDS and is
    documented in WAINIO1992.  The mastered and replicated CD-ROM
    volumes received from the vendor are compared bit-by-bit with
    the original data to ensure the quality of the product.
 
 
  Data Coverage And Quality
  =========================
    Sequences and Objectives:
 
    The SSI team correlates sequences of images with imaging and
    science objectives through the use of Activity Ids.  Below are
    the SSI Activity Ids and their objectives for the
    Shoemaker-Levy 9 data set..
 
    OPNAV_02_XCAL           optical navigation during Ida approach
    OPNAV_04_XCAL           optical navigation during Ida approach
    OPNAV_05_XCAL           optical navigation during Ida approach
    IDUSROTATI01003IDAB     Ida rotation movie 1
    IDUSROTATI02018IDAC     Ida rotation movie 2
    IDUSFINROT01100IDAC     Ida rotation movie
    IDUS6COLOR01111IDA6     Ida target for 6-color 1X1 and 4-color 2X2
    IDUNIDACHM01115IDAS     Ida composition at 102 wavelength
    IDUSHIRES_01120IDAH     Ida HiRes 95% confidence observation
    SLJIMPCTK01             SL9 impact K, diagonal slew
    SLJIMPCTN01             SL9 impact N, diagonal slew
    SLIMPCTW01              SL9 impact W, discrete shutter events
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    General Information:
 
    This section documents the currently known bad images,
    saturated frames and any problems which have currently been
    identified in the Ida and Shoemaker-Levy 9 data sets.  For the
    purpose of this memo CD refers to the SSI REDR CD-ROM GO_0016.
    There were 120 frames received and processed.
 
    The following datasets are included on the CD.  The starting
    and ending SCLK&apos;s have been identified, as well as any general
    information that might be needed to document the dataset.
 
 
    IDA OPNAV
    ---------
      SCLKs 197327200 thru 201554000
      - VICAR/PDS labels incomplete due to lack of SPICE info.
      - Activity id not in standard format
 
 
    IDA
    ---
      SCLKs 202530700 thru 202562800
      - SPICE info available
 
 
    SHOEMAKER-LEVY 9
    ----------------
      SCLKs 248806645 thru 249221800
      - SPICE available
 
      It should be noted that the processing for this dataset was
      identical for each file; (only bad data values were
      identified).
 
 
    VICAR Labels
    ------------
      Definitions for VICAR field names can be found in WHITE1993.
 
      A) The RAD field (ring radius at frame center) within the VICAR
         label was not applicable and is equal to 0.0, for the CD.
 
      B) The following fields in the VICAR label were not implemented
         for the entire CD. The current values are listed below.
 
      HRA                            = -999.0
      SMEAR                          =   -999.0
      SMRAZ                          =   0.0
      SOLRANGE (Calib. frames only)  = 7.779091
 
      C) For targets other than a planetary body or asteroid (e.g.
         black sky, stars, calibration etc.) most pointing
         information is not available.   A listing of the missing
         fields is provided below.  More detailed information can be
         found in the CATSTAT.TXT file which located in the DOCUMENTS
         directory on all of the CD&apos;s.  These fields are also missing
         if no corresponding SPICE SP information is available for an
         image. The current values are listed below.
 
      EMA                            = -999.0
      PHA                            = 0.0
      INA                            =  -999.0
      LAT                            =  0.0
      LON                            = 0.0
      TCA                            = &apos;closest time&apos;
      HSCL                           = -999.0
      VSCL                           =  0.0
      PLRANGE                        =  0.0
      SLRANGE                        = 0.0
      SUNAZ                          = 0.0
      NORAZ                          = 0.0
      SCAZ                           =0.0
      SOLRANGE                       = 7.779091
 
      D) PLRANGE is now always equivalent to the spacecraft central
         body range.
 
 
    PDS Labels
    ----------
      Definitions for PDS field name can be found in CRIBBS1992.
 
      A) The following PDS fields were not applicable for the entire
         CD. The current values are listed below.
 
      BLEMISH_FILE_NAME              = &apos;N/A&apos;
      CENTER_RING_RADIUS             = 0.0
      DARK_CURRENT_FILE_NAME         =&apos; N/A&apos;
      EDR_FILE_NUMBER                =&apos; N/A&apos;
      EDR_TAPE_ID                    = &apos;N/A&apos;
      MEAN_RADIANCE                  = &apos;N/A&apos;
      MEAN_REFLECTANCE               = &apos;N/A&apos;
      ORBIT_NUMBER                   = &apos;null&apos; or 20559  or 17481
      RADIANCE_SCALING_FACTOR        = &apos;N/A&apos;
      REFLECTANCE_SCALING_FACTOR     = &apos;N/A&apos;
      SHUTTER_OFFSET_FILE_NAME       = &apos;N/A&apos;
      SLOPE_FILE_NAME                = &apos;N/A&apos;
      UNEVEN_BIT_WEIGHT_CORR_Flag    = &apos;N/A&apos;
 
      B) SPICE_FILE_NAME was changed to SOURCE_PRODUCT_ID.  If the
         kernel was not available, it was identified as NULL.
 
      C) The following PDS fields were not implemented for the entire
         CD.  The current values are listed below.
 
      LOCAL_HOUR_ANGLE               = &apos;unk&apos;
      SMEAR_AZIMUTH                  = 0.000
      SMEAR_MAGNITUDE                = &apos;unk&apos;
      SOLAR_DISTANCE
      Calibration Only               = 7.779091
 
      D) For targets other than a planetary body or asteroid (e.g.
         black sky, stars, calibration etc.) or if the SPICE SP
         information is missing, the following pointing information
         is not available in the PDS labels .
 
      A_AXIS_RADIUS                  = &apos;unk&apos;
      B_AXIS_RADIUS                  = &apos;unk&apos;
      CENTER_LONGITUDE               = 0.00000
      CENTRAL_BODY_DISTANCE          = 0.00000
      EMISSION_ANGLE                 = &apos;unk&apos;
      HORIZONTAL_PIXEL_SCALE         = 0.00000
      INCIDENCE_ANGLE                = &apos;unk&apos;
      NORTH_AZIMUTH                  = 0.000
      PHASE_ANGLE                    = &apos;unk&apos;
      SATELLITE_TIME_FROM_CLST_APR   = &apos;unk&apos;
      SLANT_DISTANCE                 = 0.00000
      SUB_SOLAR_AZIMUTH              = 0.000
      SUB_SOLAR_LONGITUDE            = &apos;unk&apos;
      SUB_SPACECRAFT_AZIMUTH         = 0.000
      SUB_SPACECRAFT_LATITUDE        = &apos;unk&apos;
      SUB_SPACECRAFT_LINE            = &apos;unk&apos;
      SUB_SPACECRAFT_LINE_SAMPLE     = &apos;unk&apos;
      SUB_SPACECRAFT_LONGITUDE       = &apos;unk&apos;
      TARGET_CENTER_DISTANCE         = &apos;unk&apos;
      TIME_FROM_CLOSEST_APPROACH     = &apos;unk&apos;
      VERTICAL_PIXEL_SCALE           = 0.00000
 
      E) ORBIT_NUMBER for frames between 197327200 through 202562800
         incorrectly reads 20559 or 17481 instead of UNK.
 
      F) A few new keywords were added.  They are POSITIVE_LONGITUDE_
         DIRECTION, ^LINE_PREFIX_TABLE, INTERCHANGE_FORMAT in the
         Vicar Image Header Object, and TYPE in the Bad Data Value
         Header Object
 
 
    PDS Index Table
    ---------------
      A) The following fields in the PDS Index table were not
         applicable for the entire. The current values are listed.
 
      CENTER_RING_RADIUS             = 0.0
      MEAN_RADIANCE                  = &apos;N/A&apos;
      MEAN_REFLECTANCE               = &apos;N/A&apos;
      ORBIT_NUMBER                   = &apos;unk&apos; or 205 or 174
      RADIANCE_SCALING_FACTOR        = &apos;N/A&apos;
      REFLECTANCE _SCALING_FACTOR    = &apos;N/A&apos;
 
      B) The following fields in the PDS Index table were not
         implemented for the entire. The current values are listed
         here.
 
      LOCAL_HOUR_ANGLE               =&apos;unk&apos;
      SMEAR_AZIMUTH                  = 0.000
      SMEAR_MAGNITUDE                = &apos;unk&apos;
      SOLAR_DISTANCE
      Calibration only               = 7.779091
 
      C) For targets other than a planetary body or asteroid (e.g.
         black sky, stars, calibration etc.) or the corresponding
         SPICE SP information is missing, some pointing information is
         not available.  A listing of the missing fields is provided
         below.
 
      CENTER_LATITUDE                = 0.00000
      CENTER_LONGITUDE               = 0.00000
      CENTRAL_BODY_DISTANCE          = 0.00000
      EMISSION_ANGLE                 = &apos;unk&apos;
      HORIZONTAL_PIXEL_SCALE         = 0.00000
      INCIDENCE_ANGLE                = &apos;unk&apos;
      NORTH_AZIMUTH                  = 0.000
      PHASE_ANGLE                    = &apos;unk&apos;
      SATELLITE_TIME_FROM_CLST_APR   = &apos; unk&apos;
      SLANT_DISTANCE                 = 0.00000
      SUB_SOLAR_AZIMUTH              = 0.000
      SUB_SOLAR_LATITUDE             = &apos;unk&apos;
      SUB_SOLAR_LONGITUDE            = &apos;unk&apos;
      SUB_SPACECRAFT_LATITUDE        = &apos;unk&apos;
      SUB_SPACECRAFT_LINE            = &apos;unk&apos;
      SUB_SPACECRAFT_LINE_SAMPLE     = &apos;unk&apos;
      SUB_SPACECRAFT_LONGITUDE       = &apos;unk&apos;
      TARGET_CENTER_DISTANCE         = &apos;unk&apos;
      TIME_FROM_CLOSEST_APPROACH     = &apos;unk&apos;
      VERTICAL_PIXEL_SCALE           = 0.00000
 
      D) In the TARGET field of the index file, there is a limitation
         to 10 characters which caused NON_SCIENCE to appear as
         NON_SCIENCE.  The PDS labels contain the full target name.
 
 
    Reed-Solomon Overflow
    ---------------------
      Reed-Solomon overflows were not removed in this dataset via
      processing.  Most of the overflows have been identified
      within this dataset in the Binary Line Prefix of the VICAR
      label.  Due to a known anomaly, a small percentage of the
      Reed-Solomon errors may have failed to be flagged in the
      Binary Prefix.
 
      The Reed-Solomon overflow may occur in images which were
      Reed-Solomon encoded by the Galileo spacecraft.  If the data
      was received on the ground and the Reed-Solomon decoder was
      unable to completely decode the data, this overflow feature
      is present in the data.
 
      The Reed-Solomon overflow feature may be identified by the
      following criteria.  It is present on a single line or series
      of lines.  It starts about midway through a line and always
      continues through sample 800.  The data numbers (dn&apos;s) can
      shift between white, black or shades of gray.  In some cases,
      the dn&apos;s may be just a few dn brighter or darker than the
      surrounding lines.  Reed-Solomon overflows should not be
      confused with the data gaps caused by the decompression of
      data.  Decompression gaps are usually at the extreme right of
      an image, they always have a dn=0 (black) and they are
      clearly identified in the VICAR Binary Prefix.
 
 
    Additional Failures Discovered in the Data Set
    ----------------------------------------------
      A)  TIME_FROM_CLOSEST_APPROACH and SATELLITE_TIME_FROM_CLST_APR
          are not in the standard DATE/TIME format.  Since they are
          not a date and only a time, PDS is in the process of
          defining a new data type for these keywords.  PDS software
          is being modified to handle this.
 
      B)  The REDR file  GO_0016:[ida.C020256]1945R.IMG contains
          extraneous data on lines 378 and 379, which should be dark
          sky. A redo of this image will be published on the next
          REDR CD.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>89-084B-10C</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

