<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.nh-j-sdc-2-jupiter-v2.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>NEW HORIZONS SDC JUPITER ENCOUNTER V2.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.new_horizons::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.nh::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:sdc.nh::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:dust.dust::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.nh-j-sdc-2-jupiter-v2.0__browserp_nh-j-sdc-2-jupiter-v2.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>NH-J-SDC-2-JUPITER-V2.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>NEW HORIZONS SDC JUPITER ENCOUNTER V2.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2009-03-04</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2007-01-01T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2007-06-27T00:00:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JOSEPH PETERSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Horanyi, M., NEW HORIZONS SDC JUPITER ENCOUNTER V2.0,
            NH-J-SDC-2-JUPITER-V2.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2007.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw data taken by New Horizons Student Dust Counter instrument
            during the JUPITER mission phase.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains Raw data taken by the New Horizons Student
            Dust Counter instrument during the Jupiter encounter mission
            phase.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
 
      This data set contains Raw data taken by New Horizons
        Student Dust Counter
      instrument during the JUPITER mission phase.
 
      For the Jupiter encounter mission phase, SDC collected no
      science data during the Jupiter flyby, as the requisite
      spacecraft configuration prevented SDC from operating.  There
      were some very sparse data taken from December, 2006 through
      April, 2007, and some of very short (or zero) duration after the
      Jupiter flyby from April, 2007 through June, 2007.
 
      Note that some SDC data files have the same stop and start time
      and a zero exposure time.  The reason for this is that the start
      and stop time for SDC data files are the event times for the
      first and last events in the files, so for files that contain a
      single event, these two values are identical.
 
      Every observation provided in this data set was taken as a part of a
      particular sequence.  A list of these sequences follows:
 
      Sequence IDs &amp; start times (end times are the start times
      of the following Sequence IDs) for the SDC instrument
      during the JUPITER phase of the New Horizons Mission
      =========================================================
 
      Sequence ID:  JESD_PLACEHOLDER
      Start UTC:    2007-01-01T00:00:00
      Start SCLK:   1/0029915517:30912
      Description:  The SDC instrument did not have any sequenced data taken
                    during Jupiter encounter.  This entry is only a
                    placeholder to cover any data that exist.
 
      For the list of observations and their parameters, refer to
      the data set index table (typically INDEX.TAB &amp; CUMINDEX.TAB,
      initially in the /INDEX/ area of the data set).
 
 
    Time
    ====
 
      There are several time systems, or units, in use in this dataset:
      New Horizons spacecraft MET (Mission Event Time or Mission Elapsed
      Time), UTC (Coordinated Universal Time), and TDB Barycentric
      Dynamical Time.
 
      This section will give a summary description of the relationship
      between these time systems.  For a complete explanation of these
      time systems the reader is referred to the documentation
      distributed with the NAIF/SPICE toolkit from the NAIF PDS node.
 
      The most common time unit associated with the data is is the
      spacecraft MET.  MET is a 32-bit counter on the New Horizons
      spacecraft that runs at a rate of about one increment per second
      starting from a value of zero at
 
        19.January, 2006 18:08:02 UTC
 
      or
 
        JD2453755.256337 TDB.
 
      The leapsecond adjustment (DELTA_ET = ET - UTC) over this dataset
      is 65.184s.
 
      The data labels for any given product in this dataset usually
      contain at least one pair of common UTC and MET representations
      of the time at the middle of the observation.  Other portions
      of the products, for example tables of data taken over periods
      of up to a day or more, will only have the MET time associated
      with a given row of the table.
 
      For the data user&apos;s use in interpreting these times, a reasonable
      approximation (+/- 1s) of the conversion between Julian Day (TDB)
      and MET is as follows:
 
        JD TDB = 2453755.256337 + ( MET / 86399.9998693 )
 
      For more accurate calculations the reader is referred to the
      NAIF/SPICE documentation as mentioned above.
 
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      The data in this data set were created by a software data
      processing pipeline on the Science Operation Center (SOC) at
      the Southwest Research Institute (SWRI), Department of Space Studies.
      This SOC pipeline assembled data as FITS files from raw telemetry
      packets sent down by the spacecraft and populated the data labels
      with housekeeping and engineering values, and computed geometry
      parameters using SPICE kernels. The pipeline did not resample
      the data.
 
 
    Data
    ====
 
      The observations in this data set are stored in data files using
      standard Flexible Image Transport Sytem (FITS) format.  Each FITS
      file has a corresponding detached PDS label file, named according
      to a common convention.  The FITS files have image and/or table
      extensions; see the PDS label plus the DOCUMENT files for a
      description of these extensions and their contents.
 
 
      This Data section comprises the following sub-topics:
 
      - Filename/Product IDs
      - Other sources of information useful in interpreting these Data
      - CODMAC Level 2 SDC data details
      - Instrument description
      - Visit Description, Visit Number, and Target in the Data Labels
      - Unresolved Liens on the Data
 
 
      Filename/Product IDs
      --------------------
 
        The filenames and product IDs of observations adhere to a
        common convention e.g.
 
         ALI_0123456789_0X0AB_ENG_1.FIT
         ^^^ ^^^^^^^^^^ ^^^^^ ^^^ ^\__/
         |        |       |    |  | ^^
         |        |       |    |  |  |
         |        |       |    |  |  +--File type (includes dot)
         |        |       |    |  |     - .FIT for FITS file
         |        |       |    |  |     - .LBL for PDS label
         |        |       |    |  |     - not part of product ID
         |        |       |    |  |
         |        |       |    |  +-- Version number from the SOC
         |        |       |    |      (Science Operations Center)
         |        |       |    |
         |        |       |    +--ENG for CODMAC Level 2 data *
         |        |       |       SCI for CODMAC Level 3 data *
         |        |       |
         |        |       +--Application ID (ApID) of the telemetry data
         |        |          packet from which the data come
         |        |
         |        +--MET (Mission Event Time) i.e. Spacecraft Clock
         |
         +--Instrument designator
 
          * For those datasets where the NH project is delivering
            CODMAC Level 1 &amp; 2 data (REX &amp; PEPSSI), ENG and SCI apply
            to CODMAC Level 1 &amp; 2 data, respectively.
 
 
        Instrument   Instrument designators              ApIDs
        ===========  ==================================  =============
         SDC          SDC                                0X700
 
         * Not all values in this range are used
 
         There are other ApIDs that contain housekeeping values and
         other values.  See the documentation for more details.
 
 
        Here is a summary of the types of files generated by each ApID
        along with the instrument designator that go with each ApID:
 
 
      ApIDs   Data product description/Prefix(es)
      =====   ===================================
      0x700 - SDC Science Data/SDC
 
 
      Other sources of information useful in interpreting these Data
      --------------------------------------------------------------
 
        Refer to the following files for more information about these data
 
          NH Trajectory table:
 
            /DOCUMENT/NH_TRAJECTORY.*
 
          SDC Field Of View definitions:
 
             /DOCUMENT/NH_FOV.*
             /DOCUMENT/NH_SDC_V###_TI.TXT
 
 
 
 
      Instrument description
      ----------------------
 
        Refer to the following files for a description of this instrument.
 
        CATALOG
 
          SDC.CAT
 
        DOCUMENTS
 
          SDC_SSR.*
          NH_SDC_V###_TI.TXT  (### is a version number)
          SOC_INST_ICD.*
 
 
      Visit Description, Visit Number, and Target in the Data Labels
      ---------------------------------------------------------------
 
        The observation sequences were defined in Science Activity
        Planning (SAP) documents, and grouped by Visit Description and
        Visit Number.  The SAPs are spreadsheets with one Visit Description
        &amp; Number per row.  A nominal target is also included on each row
        and included in the data labels, but does not always match with the
        TARGET_NAME field&apos;s value in the data labels.  In some cases, the
        target was designated as RA,DEC pointing values in the form
        ``RADEC=123.45,-12.34&apos;&apos; indicating Right Ascension and Declination,
        in degrees, of the target from the spacecraft in the Earth
        Equatorial J2000 inertial reference frame.  This indicates either
        that the target was either a star, or that the target&apos;s ephemeris
        was not loaded into the spacecraft&apos;s attitude and control system
        which in turn meant the spacecraft could not be pointed at the
        target by a body identifier and an inertial pointing value had to
        be specified as Right Ascension and Declination values.  The PDS
        standards do not allow putting a value like RADEC=... in the PDS
        TARGET_NAME keyword&apos;s value; in those cases the PDS TARGET_NAME
        value is set to CALIBRATION.
 
 
      Unresolved Liens on the Data
      ----------------------------
 
        None exist at the present time.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
 
      The geometry items included in the data labels were computed
      using the SPICE kernels archived in the New Horizons SPICE
      data set, NH-X-SPICE-6-JUPITER-V1.0.
 
 
    Reference Frame
    ===============
 
 
      Geometric Parameter Reference Frame
      -----------------------------------
        Earth Mean Equator and Vernal Equinox of J2000 (EMEJ2000) is the
        inertial reference frame used to specify observational geometry
        items provided in the data labels.  Geometric parameters are based
        on best available SPICE data at time of data creation.
 
 
      Epoch of Geometric Parameters
      -----------------------------
        All geometric parameters provided in the data labels were
        computed at the epoch midway between the START_TIME and
        STOP_TIME label fields.
 
 
 
    Software
    ========
 
      The observations in this data set are in standard FITS format
      with PDS labels, and can be viewed by a number of PDS-provided
      and commercial programs. For this reason no special software is
      provided with this data set.
 
 
    Contact Information
    ===================
 
      For any questions regarding the data format of the archive,
      contact the person whose PDS_USER_ID is MHORANYI
      as described in PERSONNEL.CAT.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      During the processing of the data in preparation for
      delivery with this volume, the packet data associated with each
      observation were used only if they passed a rigorous verification
      process including standard checksums.
 
      In addition, raw (Level 2) observation data for which adequate
      contemporary housekeeping and other ancillary data are not available
      are not reduced to calibrated (Level 3) data.  This issue is raised
      here to explain why some data products in the raw data set,
 
        NH-J-SDC-2-JUPITER-V2.0,
 
      do not have corresponding data products in the calibrated data set,
 
        NH-J-SDC-3-JUPITER-V2.0.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      The data have been reviewed and validated by the instrument team
      members, as well as by SOC personnel.
 
 
    SDC updates for Data Sets V2.0
    ==============================
 
 
      None of the formats for the Calibrated data will change.  The data
      file will look the same, including the data formats.  The changes
      are improvements to the processing code.  There were 3 changes made
      to the code:
 
 
      Change to dust impact velocity assumption
      -----------------------------------------
 
        An assumption is needed for the the dust impact velocity to
        calculate its mass.  Before this update the pipeline used only the
        normal component of the total velocity between the dust and
        instrument (assuming the particle is in Keplerian orbit).
        Now this has been changed to the total relative velocity of the
        particle (still assumed to be in Keplerian orbit) and the
        instrument.
 
 
      Using multiple sensors for temperature correction
      -------------------------------------------------
 
        There are two thermistors on the analog board.  The analog board
        temperature is used for calibrating a particular channel on the
        board.  Before this update, for a given channel the temperature
        of the closest thermistor to a that channel.  Now a linear fit
        to the temperatures is used.
 
 
      New charge-velocity-mass calibration curve
      ------------------------------------------
 
        The calibrated data contains the mass of the particle.  The
        charge to mass curve used to be
 
          Q=3.18E17*m^1.3*v^3.0
 
        where m is the mass, Q is the charge and v is the relative speed.
        This was the Simpson-Tuzzolino curve.  The new curve is a function
        of detector temperature as well:
 
          Q=(1.15E15+6.75E12*T)*m^1.052*v^2.883
 
        where T is the temperature.  A paper with this new calibration
        curve will  be submitted for publication in Spring, 2009.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

