<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dif-cal-hrii-2-epoxi-calibrations-v2.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>EPOXI INFLIGHT CALIBRATIONS - HRII RAW SPECTRA V2.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.epoxi::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:hrii.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dif-cal-hrii-2-epoxi-calibrations-v2.0__browserp_dif-cal-hrii-2-epoxi-calibrations-v2.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hampton, D.L., J.W. Baer, M.A. Huisjen, C.C. Varner, A. Delamere, D.D.
                   Wellnitz, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, and K.P. Klaasen, An Overview of the Instrument Suite
                   for the Deep Impact Mission, Space Science Reviews, 117, 43-93, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3390-8.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAMPTONETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., B. Carcich, G. Carcich, E.J. Grayzeck, and S. McLaughlin, Deep
                   Impact: The Anticipated Flight Data, Space Science Reviews, 117, 335-372, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3385-5.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., M.F. A&apos;Hearn, M. Baca, A. Delamere, M. Desnoyer, T. Farnham, O.
                   Groussin, D. Hampton, S. Ipatov, J. Li, C. Lisse, N. Mastrodemos, S.
                   McLaughlin, J. Sunshine, P. Thomas, and D. Wellnitz, Deep Impact Instrument
                   Calibration, Rev. Sci. Instrum., 79, 091301, 2008, doi:10.1063/1.2972112.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., M. A&apos;Hearn, S. Besse, D. Bodewits, B. Carcich, T. Farnham, L.
                   Feaga, O. Groussin, D. Hampton, M. Huisjen, M.S. Kelley, S. McLaughlin, F.
                   Merlin, S. Protopapa, J. Sunshine, P. Thomas, and D. Wellnitz, EPOXI Instrument
                   Calibration, Icarus, 225(1), 643-680, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.icarus.2013.03.024.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DIF-CAL-HRII-2-EPOXI-CALIBRATIONS-V2.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>EPOXI INFLIGHT CALIBRATIONS - HRII RAW SPECTRA V2.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2011-06-30</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2007-10-04T22:23:49.183Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2011-02-06T11:41:51.591Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STEPHANIE MCLAUGHLIN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            McLaughlin, S.A., B. Carcich, S.E. Sackett, K.P. Klaasen, and
            D.D. Wellnitz, EPOXI INFLIGHT CALIBRATIONS - HRII RAW SPECTRA
            V2.0, DIF-CAL-HRII-2-EPOXI-CALIBRATIONS-V2.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2011.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw calibration spectra acquired by the Deep Impact High
            Resolution Infrared Spectrometer from 04 October 2007 through 07
            Feb 2011 for the EPOXI mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset contains raw calibration spectra acquired by the
            High Resolution Infrared Spectrometer (HRII) from 04 October 2007
            through 07 February 2011 during the EPOCh, 103P/Hartley 2
            Encounter, and cruise phases of the EPOXI mission.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This dataset contains version 2.0 of raw calibration spectra acquired
    by the High Resolution Infrared Spectrometer (HRII) from 04 October 2007
    through 07 February 2011 during the EPOCh, 103P/Hartley 2 Encounter, and
    cruise phases of the EPOXI mission.  This dataset supersedes version 1.0
    which contained raw calibration data only through May 2010.
 
    The purpose of these data are to monitor the HRII spectrometer and
    improve its calibration as needed.  EPOXI calibration activities
    generally followed those designed for the Deep Impact mission.  For
    example standard calibration targets continued to include the Moon,
    16 Cyg A, 47 Tuc, Beta Hyi, HD 79447, NGC 7027, Vega, sky frames, and
    dark frames.  The Deep Impact calibration pipeline was the foundation
    for EPOXI until improvements were implemented for the Hartley 2
    encounter as described in the Hartley 2 calibration summary report
    located in the DOCUMENT directory.  For a detailed discussion of how the
    instruments were calibrated for EPOXI see Klaasen, et al. (2011, in
    preparation) [KLAASENETAL2011].  The Deep Impact instrument calibration
    is described by Klaasen, et al. (2008) [KLAASENETAL2006] and Klaasen,
    et al. (2005) [KLAASENETAL2005].
 
    A list of the calibration activities relevant to this dataset is
    provided below and a description of each activity follows.  The EPOXI
    in-flight calibrations summary chart in the DOCUMENT directory provides
    a quick-look at the activities.
 
      ------------------------------------------------------------------------
      Phase and                                                Exposure ID
      Calibration Activity          Obs Date/DOY    Target    Start    Stop
      ----------------------------  --------------  --------  -------  -------
      Cruise 1
        Instrument Checkout         2007-10-04/277  Sky       1010100  1010107
        Instrument Checkout Retest  2007-12-04/338  Sky       1010200  1010208
        Lunar Calibration           2007-12-29/363  Moon      1000005  1070000
        Standard Cruise Cal         2008-01-09/009  Beta Hyi  2000000  2000001
                                                    HD 79447  2000002  2000002
                                                    47 Tuc    2000003  2000004
                                                    Vega      2010000  2010001
                                                    16 Cyg A  2010002  2010003
                                                    Dark      2011000  2012010
                                                    NGC 7207  2012011  2012012
        Dark Retake for Lunar Cal   2008-01-16/016  Dark      1000000  1000054
                                    2008-01-17/017  Dark      1000005  1000154
      EPOCh
        Darks for Earth Obs #1      2008-03-18/078  Dark      1000000  1000001
                                    2008-03-19/079  Dark      1002024  1002025
        Darks for Earth Obs #4      2008-05-28/149  Dark      1000000  1000001
                                    2008-05-29/150  Dark      1002024  1002025
        Darks for Earth Obs #5      2008-06-04/156  Dark      1000000  1000001
                                    2008-06-05/157  Dark      1002024  1002025
        Standard Cruise Cal         2008-06-23/175  Vega      2010000  2010001
                                                    16 Cyg A  2010002  2010003
                                                    NGC 7207  2010004  2010005
                                                    Dark      2011000  2012020
                                    2008-06-24/176  Beta Hyi  2000000  2000001
                                                    HD 79447  2000002  2000002
                                                    47 Tuc    2000003  2000004
      Cruise 2
        HRII Reciprocity Test       2008-09-18/262  Dark      3200000  3200019
        HRII Dark Flush Test        2008-09-26/270  Dark      3000001  3000011
        HRII Encounter Darks Rerun  2008-10-02/276  Dark      9000030  9020002
        HRII Dark Gap Test          2008-10-08/282  Dark      3100000  3100024
        HRII Subframe Gain Cal/Moon 2009-01-26/026  Moon      4000001  4000153
                                                    Dark      4100001  4100335
        EPOCh Earth N.Pole Darks    2009-03-27/086  Dark      1000000  1000001
                                    2009-03-28/087  Dark      1002024  1002025
        HRII Lunar Flats&amp;Radiometry 2009-06-01/152  Moon      1000000  1000000
                                    2009-06-02/153  Moon      1000000  1000076
        HRII Lunar Antisat Fltr&amp;Rad 2009-06-09/160  Moon      1000000  1000519
        HRII Linearity Cal          2009-06-18/169  Dark      2011000  2012020
        EPOCh Earth S.Pole #1 Darks 2009-09-27/270  Dark      1000000  1000001
        Checkout after HRI Turnoff  2009-09-30/273  Sky       1010100  1010107
        EPOCh Earth S.Pole #2 Darks 2009-10-04/277  Dark      1000000  1000001
                                    2009-10-05/278  Dark      1002024  1002025
        HRII Rad Cal #1 (Beta Hyi)  2009-10-13/286  Beta Hyi  ExpIDs 2000000
                                      through                  through 2000005
                                    2009-10-24/297             repeatedly used
        HRII Dark Subframe Test     2009-11-20/324  Dark      4000001  4000293
        EPOCh Mars Darks            2009-11-20/324  Dark      1000000  1000001
                                    2009-11-21/325  Dark      1002024  1002025
        HRII Lunar Flats/Rad Cal#1  2009-12-05/339  Moon      1000000  1000076
        HRII Lunar Flats/Rad Cal#2  2009-12-12/346  Moon      1000000  1000076
        HRII Lunar S.Pole Rad       2009-12-18/352  Moon      1000000  1000002
        Standard Cruise Cal         2010-02-16/047  Dark      2011000  2012020
                                                    Vega      2010000  2010001
                                                    16 Cyg A  2010002  2010003
                                                    NGC 7027  2010004  2010005
                                                    Beta Hyi  2000000  2000001
                                                    HD 79447  2000002  2000002
                                                    47 Tuc    2000003  2000004
        HRII NoSave Flush Test      2010-04-20/110  Dark      4000000  4000227
        HRII Rad Cal #2 (Beta Hyi)  2010-05-03/123  Beta Hyi  ExpIDs 2000000
                                      to                      through 2000005
                                    2010-05-17/137             repeatedly used
      Hartley 2 Encounter
        Standard Cruise Cal         2010-09-28/271  Dark      2011000  2012020
          (pre-encounter)                           Vega      2010000  2010001
                                                    16 Cyg A  2010002  2010003
                                                    NGC 7027  2010004  2010005
                                                    Beta Hyi  2000000  2000001
                                                    HD 79447  2000002  2000002
                                                    47 Tuc    2000003  2000004
        Standard Cruise Cal         2010-11-27/331  Dark      2011000  2012020
          (post-encounter)            to            Vega      2010000  2010001
                                    2010-11-28/332  16 Cyg A  2010002  2010003
                                                    NGC 7027  2010004  2010005
                                                    Beta Hyi  2000000  2000001
                                                    HD 79447  2000002  2000002
                                                    47 Tuc    2000003  2000004
        IR 50-Frame Extended LinCal 2011-02-05/036  Darks     5000000  5000084
          (pre-encounter)             to
                                    2011-02-06/037
      ------------------------------------------------------------------------
 
      Instrument Checkout:  On 4 October 2007 the three science instruments
        were turned on for the first time in more than two years.  Sky
        frames acquired by the HRII spectrometer confirmed the mechanical
        components were functioning.  The instrument exhibited nominal
        behavior of background levels although several detector pixels had
        an odd response when compared to Deep Impact.
 
      Instrument Checkout Retest:  On 4 December 2007 a retest of the
        October instrument checkout sequence was performed for the three
        science instruments.  The focus of this retest was to determine if
        HRII pixels that had an odd response during checkout had changed or
        improved.
 
      Lunar Calibration:  On 29 December 2007 as the spacecraft approached
        Earth, the three science instruments used the Moon as a target to
        acquire data for recalibration purposes.  The sequence included
        along- and cross-slit HRII scans of the moon for flat fields and
        characterization of the HRII anti-saturation filter.  (Please note
        the flat-field data were mostly saturated at long wavelengths).
        Due to a minor error in the lunar calibration sequence, a series of
        HRII dark frames were not recorded.  A retest to acquire the missing
        HRII darks was scheduled for 16-17 January 2008.
 
      Standard Cruise Calibration:  On 9 January 2008, the first of the
        standard cruise calibrations for the three science instruments was
        performed.  The calibration sequence included observations of
        several standard stars, both solar analogs and hot stars with few
        absorption lines in their spectra for absolute calibration of all
        instruments, a stellar cluster for checking geometric distortion in
        the cameras, and a planetary nebula for checking the wavelength
        calibration of the spectrometer.  This sequence was designed such
        that it could be rerun, with few if any changes, after completion of
        the EPOCh observations and then again just before and just after the
        observing program for comet 103P/Hartley 2.
 
      HRII Dark Retake for Lunar Cal:  Due to a minor error in the lunar
        calibration sequence that was executed in December, a series of HRII
        dark frames was not recorded.  However the darks were successfully
        rerun for the HRII spectrometer on 16-17 January 2008. The darks
        help characterize the IR background level.
 
      EPOCh Earth Obs Darks:  At the beginning and end of each EPOCh Earth
        observation period in 2008, HRII dark frames were acquired for
        calibration purposes and included in this dataset.
 
      Standard Cruise Calibration:  A second standard cruise calibration
        was performed on 23-25 June 2008 for the HRII and HRIV instruments.
        The sequence was very similar to that used for the calibration
        performed on 9 January 2008, except the MRI instrument was turned
        off because of thermal and telecommunication concerns.
 
      HRII Reciprocity Test:  On 18 September 2008, an HRII reciprocity
        test was performed to determine the background signal level of the
        READ and RESET frames of the IR spectrometer as a function of the
        past history of integration delay times and the timing gap between
        sets of frames using the diagnostic imaging mode (number 6).  The
        ultimate objective of this test along with the HRII Dark Flush, HRII
        Dark Gap, and HRII Subframe Gain tests performed over the next four
        months is to develop a more accurate model of the variation in the
        background level of the IR spectrometer.
 
      HRII Dark Flush Test:  On 26 September 2008, an HRII dark frame
        flush test was performed to determine the type of IR spectrometer
        instrument operation needed to remove all traces of the residual
        (previous) image.
 
      HRII Encounter Darks Rerun:  On 02 October 2008 a set of HRII dark
        frames for several exposure IDs from the Deep Impact Tempel 1
        encounter sequence was acquired.  The exposures were those acquired
        from about 19 minutes before the impact with Tempel 1 through the
        first few hours of lookback imaging.
 
      HRII Dark Gap Test:  On 08 October 2008, an HRII dark gap test was
        performed to characterize the change in the residual image and the
        dark level in the IR spectrometer as a function of wait time and
        number of readouts after acquiring data in the subframe imaging
        modes (numbers 2 and 3).
 
      HRII Subframe Gain Calibration:  On 26 January 2009, an HRII subframe
        gain calibration was conducted to observe differences in the IR
        spectrometer signal response rates when observing an external
        radiance source to differentiate between gain and offset effects
        when using the various subframe modes.  The test was performed by
        scanning the spectrometer across the moon (cross-slit) at multiple
        speeds with various subframe modes while the HRI telescope barrel
        was warm.
 
      EPOCh Earth North Pole Darks:  At the beginning and end of this
        campaign on 27-28 March 2009, HRII dark frames were acquired for
        calibration purposes and included in this dataset.
 
      HRII Lunar Flats and Radiometry:  On 1-2 June 2009, the HRII
        spectrometer acquired a series of east/west scans of the moon along
        the IR slit for flats.  These data were the best obtained to date
        for the purpose of generating flat fields for the IR spectrometer.
        Also three cross-slit north/south scans of the moon were acquired
        for lunar radiometry.  Please note these data have poor
        signal-to-noise at short wavelengths.
 
      HRII Lunar Antisat Filter and Radiometry:  On 9 June 2009, the HRII
        spectrometer imaged the moon using cross-slit north/south scans to
        better characterize the effects of the anti-saturation filter in the
        IR spectra.  These data were also used for radiometry.
 
      HRII Linearity Calibration:  On 18 June 2009, HRII darks were acquired
        to check the linearity of the IR spectrometer.  The sequence was
        identical to the one used during standard cruise calibrations for
        linearity.
 
      EPOCh Earth South Pole #1 Darks (partial):  At the beginning of this
        campaign on 27-28 September 2009, HRII dark frames were acquired
        for calibration purposes and included in this dataset.  However
        the sequence ended prematurely because HRI was turned off by fault
        protection although the spacecraft was fine.  The set of HRII
        darks scheduled for the end of this sequence were never acquired.
 
      Checkout after HRI Turnoff:  Before repeating the Earth South Pole
        observation, a standard imaging checkout of the HRII, HRIV, and MRI
        instruments was performed after HRI was powered up on 30 September
        2009.  The data included HRII spectra of the sky.
 
      EPOCh Earth South Pole #2 Darks (Full):  On 04-05 October 2009, EPOCh
        successfully acquired a full set of observations (24 hours) of Earth
        at high southern latitudes.  At the beginning and end of this
        campaign, HRII dark frames were acquired for calibration purposes
        and included in this dataset.
 
      HRII Radiometric Cal #1 (Beta Hyi):  From 13 October to 24 October
        2009, the HRII spectrometer repeatedly scanned the star Beta Hyi to
        improve the absolute spectral radiometric calibration for that
        instrument.
 
      HRII Dark Subframe Test:  On 20 November 2009, the HRII spectrometer
        acquired dark frames to further characterize the background signal
        of the subframe imaging modes (numbers 2 and 3) versus the
        integration time and the time between IR frames.
 
      EPOCh Mars Obs Darks:  On 20-21 November 2009, EPOCh observed Mars
        for 24 hours with the HRIV CCD and the IR spectrometer.  At the
        beginning and end of this campaign, HRII dark frames were acquired
        for calibration purposes and included in this dataset.
 
      HRII Lunar Flats/Radiometric Cal #1 and #2:  On 05 and 12 December
        2009 as the spacecraft approached Earth, the IR spectrometer made
        north/south cross-slit scans of the moon for radiometry and
        east/west scans along the slit for lunar flats and a radiometric
        calibration.  Please note the flat-field data are very good.
 
      HRII Lunar South Pole Radiometry:  On 18 December 2009, about 10 days
        before the distant flyby of Earth the IR spectrometer made
        north/south cross-slit scans of the lunar south pole for radiometric
        analysis.
 
      Standard Cruise Calibration:  A full, standard cruise calibration
        for HRII, HRIV, and MRI was completed on 16 February 2010.  The
        sequence was very similar to that used for the standard cruise
        calibrations in 2008.
 
      HRII NoSave Flush Test:  On 20 April 2010, an HRII dark frame
        sequence designed to reduce the amount of charge buildup that
        results in abnormally high signals in the first 1 to 4 images of a
        multi-frame IR exposure was tested.  The sequence consisted of
        flushing the IR detector before science imaging by alternating
        between saving frames of one exposure ID for science and not saving
        those from the next exposure (i.e., flush frames).
 
      HRII Radiometric Cal #2 (Beta Hyi):  From 03 May to 17 May 2010, the
        HRII spectrometer repeatedly scanned the star Beta Hyi to improve
        the absolute spectral radiometric calibration for that instrument.
 
      Pre-Encounter Standard Cruise Calibration:  A full, standard cruise
        calibration for HRII, HRIV, and MRI was performed on 28-29
        September 2010.  The sequence was very similar to that used
        earlier in 2010.
 
      Post-Encounter Standard Cruise Calibration:  A full post-encounter
        standard cruise calibration for HRII, HRIV, and MRI was performed
        on 27-28 November 2010.  The sequence was nearly identical to the
        pre-encounter calibration performed in September.
 
      HRII 50-Frame Extended Linearity Calibration:   From 05 to 06 February
        2011, the HRII spectrometer took 50 dark frames for a set of
        integration times and for each imaging mode to gather enough data
        to perform a thorough analysis of the linearity of each active
        pixel in the IR focal plane array.
 
 
    Required Reading
    ---------------
      The documents listed below are essential for the understanding and
      interpretation of this dataset.  Although a copy of each document is
      provided in the DOCUMENT directory of this dataset, the most recent
      version is archived in the Deep Impact and EPOXI documentation set,
      DI-C-HRII/HRIV/MRI/ITS-6-DOC-SET-V3.0, available online at
      http://pds.nasa.gov.
 
      EPOXI_SIS.PDF
        - The Archive Volume and Data Product Software Interface
          Specifications document (SIS) describes the EPOXI datasets, the
          science data products, and defines keywords in the PDS labels.
 
      HARTLEY2_CAL_PIPELINE_SUMM.PDF
        - The EPOXI Hartley 2 Calibration Pipeline Summary provides an
          overview the calibration pipeline as of June 2011 used for
          processing data acquired during the Hartley 2 Encounter.
 
      EPOXI_INFLIGHT_CAL_SUMMARY.PDF
        - The EPOXI In-Flight Calibrations Summary provides an overview of
          the instrument calibrations performed during the entire EPOXI
          mission.
 
      INSTRUMENTS_HAMPTON.PDF
        - The Deep Impact instruments paper by Hampton, et al. (2005)
          [HAMPTONETAL2005] provides very detailed descriptions of the
          instruments.
 
      HRII_2_EPOXI_CALIBRATIONS.TAB
        - This ASCII table provides image parameters such as the mid-obs
          Julian date, exposure time, mission activity type, and
          description or purpose for each observation (i.e., data product)
          in this dataset.  This file is very useful for determining which
          data files to work with.
 
 
    Related Data Sets
    -----------------
      The following PDS datasets are related to this one and may be useful
      for calibration purposes:
 
      DIF-E-HRII-2-EPOXI-EARTH-V1.0
      DIF-E-HRII-3/4-EPOXI-EARTH-V1.0
        - Raw and calibrated HRII Earth observations
 
      DIF-M-HRII-2-EPOXI-MARS-V1.0
      DIF-M-HRII-3/4-EPOXI-MARS-V1.0
        - Raw and calibrated HRII Mars observations
 
      DIF-C-HRII-2-EPOXI-HARTLEY2-V1.0
      DIF-C-HRII-3/4-EPOXI-HARTLEY2-V1.0
        - Raw and calibrated HRII comet Hartley 2 observations
 
      DI-C-HRII/HRIV/MRI/ITS-6-DOC-SET-V3.0
        - Deep Impact and EPOXI documentation set including a draft of the
          Deep Impact instrument calibration paper by Klaasen, et al. (2008)
          [KLAASENETAL2006]
 
      DIF-C/E/X-SPICE-6-V1.0
        - EPOXI SPICE kernels
 
      DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV/MRI-6-EPOXI-TEMPS-V2.0
        - HRII, HRIV, and MRI instrument thermal telemetry data for EPOXI
          which may be useful for determining how temperature fluctuations
          affect the science instruments, in particular the IR spectrometer
 
      DIF-CAL-HRII-2-9P-CRUISE-V1.0
      DIF-CAL-HRII-2-9P-ENCOUNTER-V1.0
        - Deep Impact raw HRII calibrations datasets from 2005
 
      DIF-CAL-HRII-2-GROUND-TV1-V1.0
      DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV-2-GROUND-TV2-V1.0
      DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV/MRI-2-GROUND-TV4-V1.0
        - Deep Impact raw HRII pre-launch calibrations from 2002 and 2003
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The raw two-dimensional (wavelength and spatial/along-slit) FITS
    spectral images and PDS labels in this dataset were generated by the
    Deep Impact/EPOXI data pipeline, maintained by the project&apos;s Science
    Data Center (SDC) at Cornell University.  The FITS data were assembled
    from raw telemetry packets sent down by the flyby spacecraft.
    Information from the embedded spacecraft header (the first 100 bytes of
    quadrant A image data) was extracted and stored in the primary FITS
    header.  Geometric parameters were computed using the best available
    SPICE kernels and the results were also stored in the FITS header.  If
    telemetry packets were missing, the corresponding pixels were flagged
    as missing in the quality map included as a FITS image extension.  The
    quadrant nomenclature and the image quality map are described in the
    EPOXI SIS document.  The SDC did not apply any type of correction or
    decompression algorithm to the raw data.
 
 
  Data
  ====
 
    FITS Images and PDS Labels
    --------------------------
      Each raw spectral image is stored as FITS.  The primary data unit
      contains the two-dimensional spectral image, with the fastest
      varying axis corresponding to increasing wavelengths from about
      1.05 to 4.8 microns and the slowest varying axis corresponding to
      the spatial or along-slit dimension.  The primary array is
      followed by one image extension that contains a two-dimensional
      pixel-by-pixel quality map.  This extension uses one byte of eight
      bit flags to indicate the quality of each pixel in the primary
      image.  The data label provides a short description of each bit.
      For more information about the FITS primary image and its
      extension or for examples of how to access and use the quality
      flags, refer to the EPOXI SIS document.
 
      Each FITS file is accompanied by a detached PDS data label.  The
      EPOXI SIS document provides definitions for the keywords found in
      a PDS data label.  Many values in a label were extracted from
      FITS image header keywords which are defined in the document
      EPOXI_FITS_KEYWORD_DESC.ASC found in the Deep Impact and EPOXI
      documentation dataset, DI-C-HRII/HRIV/MRI/ITS-6-DOC-SET-V3.0.
 
 
    File Naming Convention
    ----------------------
      The naming convention for the raw data labels and FITS files is
      HIyymmddhh_eeeeeee_nnn.LBL or FIT where &apos;HI&apos; identifies the HRII
      instrument, yymmddhh provides the UTC year, month, day, and hour at
      the mid-point of the observation, eeeeeee is the exposure ID
      (OBSERVATION_ID in data labels), and nnn provides the image number
      (IMAGE_NUMBER in the data labels) within the exposure ID.
 
      Up to 999 individual images can be commanded for one exposure ID.
      Spectral scans often had 32 or more frames for one specific exposure.
      Therefore, nnn in the file name provides the sequentially increasing
      frame number within an exposure ID and corresponds to IMAGE_NUMBER in
      the data labels.  For example, if 32 frames were commanded for a scan
      with an exposure ID of 1000001, the first FITS file name would be
      HI08060416_1000001_001.FIT and the last would be
      HI08060416_1000001_032.FIT.
 
 
    Image Compression
    -----------------
      Although raw data numbers for HRII frames could be compressed on
      board the flyby spacecraft by use of a lookup table then downlinked,
      processed, and archived in the same format, all calibration-related
      spectra acquired during the time period covered by this dataset
      were never compressed.
 
 
    Image Orientation
    -----------------
      A true-sky &apos;as seen by the observer&apos; view is achieved by displaying
      the image using the standard FITS convention:  the fastest-varying
      axis (samples or wavelength) increasing to the right in the display
      window and the slowest-varying axis (lines or spatial/along-slit)
      increasing to the top.  This convention is identified in the data
      labels:  the SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION keyword is set to RIGHT and
      LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION to UP.
 
      The direction to celestial north, ecliptic north, and the Sun is
      provided in data labels by CELESTIAL_NORTH_CLOCK_ANGLE,
      ECLIPTIC_NORTH_CLOCK_ANGLE, and SUN_DIRECTION_CLOCK_ANGLE keywords
      and are measured clockwise from the top of the image when is
      displayed in the correct orientation as defined by
      SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION and LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION.  Please note
      the aspect of the North celestial pole in an image can be computed
      by adding 90 degrees to the boresight declination given by
      DECLINATION in the data labels.
 
      For a comparison of the orientation FITS image data from the three
      science instruments, see the quadrant nomenclature section of the
      the EPOXI SIS document.
 
 
    IR Slit Location
    ----------------
      For a comparison of the relative locations of the IR slit with
      respect to the fields of view of the Medium Resolution Instrument
      Visible CCD (MRI) and the High Resolution Instrument Visible CCD
      (HRIV), see the instrument alignment section of the EPOXI SIS
      document or Klaasen, et al. (2011) [KLAASENETAL2011].
 
 
    Timing for Spectra
    ------------------
      It is important to note that the readout order of the IR detector
      affects the timing of the spectra.  When a HRII spectral image is
      displayed using the true-sky convention, the wavelength increases
      horizontally to the right and the spatial or along-slit direction is
      vertical.  In this orientation, the IR detector was read out from the
      left and right edges and toward the center and starting with the
      first row at the bottom and ending with the last row at the top of
      the display.  Since the detector is reset and read out on a
      pixel-by-pixel basis, the read out order affects the time at which
      each pixel is exposed although each pixel has the same exposure
      duration -- except for the ALTFF mode that has different read and
      reset causing the effective exposure time to vary with line number,
      i.e., along the slit in the spatial direction.  Additionally, the end
      of the spectrometer slit that always points roughly towards the sun
      is the first line to be readout and the last line to be read out is
      furthest from the sun, assuming the spacecraft is in its usual
      orientation with the solar panels pointing roughly toward the sun.
      For more information about the timing of the spectra, see the zero
      exposure background section of the EPOXI instrument calibration paper
      by Klaasen, et al. (2011) [KLAASENETAL2011].  A brief discussion
      about how the calibration pipeline handles the ALTFF mode is included
      in the EPOXI Hartley 2 Calibration Pipeline Summary document.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
    Data Units
    ----------
      Raw image data are in units of raw data numbers.
 
 
    Target Name and Description
    ---------------------------
      The TARGET_NAME keyword in the data labels is set to the intended
      target, &apos;CALIBRATION&apos;, for each observation in this dataset. The
      TARGET_DESC keyword provides the name of the specific calibration
      target, such as &apos;DARK&apos; or &apos;VEGA&apos;.
 
 
    Imaging Modes
    -------------
      A summary of the imaging modes is provided here.  For more
      information see the EPOXI SIS and EPOXI Hartley 2 Calibration
      Pipeline Summary documents, Hampton, et al. (2005) [HAMPTONETAL2005]
      and Klaasen, et al. (2011) [KLAASENETAL2011].  In the table below,
      X-Size is the spectral dimension and Y-Size is the spatial
      dimension.
 
                    X-Size  Y-Size  Bin
        Mode Name   (pix)   (pix)  Type  Comments
        ---- ------ ------  -----  ----- ------------------------------------
          1  BINFF    512     256   2x2  Binned full frame
          2  BINSF1   512     126   2x2  Binned sub-frame
          3  BINSF2   512      64   2x2  Binned sub-frame
          4  UBFF    1024     512   1x1  Unbinned full frame
          5  ALTFF    512     256   2x2  Alternate mode 1 (min. exposure
                                         time is 1/2 of mode 1)
          6  DIAG    1024     512   1x1  Diagnostic, one reset frame followed
                                         by a separatly-stored read frame
                                         such that odd IMAGE_NUMBERs are
                                         reset frames and even IMAGE_NUMBERs
                                         are read frames
          7  MEMCK   1024     512   1x1  Memory Check
 
      Note the subframe modes are binned (2x2), reduce the spatial (LINE)
      extent of the image FOV, and have a shorter readout time which reduces
      the exposure time for bright objects and keeps the detector from
      saturating.
 
 
    Time- and Geometry-Related Keywords
    -----------------------------------
      All time-related keywords in the data labels, except
      EARTH_OBSERVER_MID_TIME, are based on the clock on board the flyby
      spacecraft.  EARTH_OBSERVER_MID_TIME provides the UTC when an
      Earth-based observer should have been able to see an event recorded
      by the instrument.
 
      The SDC pipeline was not able to automatically determine the proper
      geometric information for the target of choice in some cases.  When
      these parameters could not be computed, the corresponding keywords
      in the data labels are set to a value of unknown, &apos;UNK&apos;.  Also if
      GEOMETRY_QUALITY_FLAG is set to &apos;BAD&apos; or GEOMETRY_TYPE is set to
      &apos;PREDICTED&apos; in the PDS labels, then this indicates the geometry
      values may not be accurate and should be used with caution.  The
      value &apos;N/A&apos; is used for some geometry-related keywords in the data
      labels because these parameters are not applicable for certain
      calibration targets.
 
      Observational geometry parameters provided in the data labels were
      computed at the epoch specified by the mid-obs UTC, IMAGE_MID_TIME,
      in the data labels.  The exceptions are the target-to-sun values
      evaluated at the time light left the target that reached the
      spacecraft at mid-obs time and the earth-observer-to-target values
      evaluated at the time the light that left the target, which reached
      the spacecraft at mid-obs time, reached Earth.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    The geometric parameters included in the data labels and FITS headers
    were computed using the best available SPICE kernels at the time the
    data products were generated.  The kernels are archived in the
    EPOXI SPICE dataset, DIF-C/E/X-SPICE-6-V1.0.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    Earth Mean Equator and Vernal Equinox of J2000 (EME J2000) is the
    inertial reference system used to specify observational geometry
    parameters in the data labels.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The observations in this dataset are in standard FITS format with PDS
    labels, and can be viewed by a number of PDS-provided and commercial
    programs.  For this reason no special software is provided with this
    dataset.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The FITS files in this dataset were reviewed internally by the EPOXI
    project and were used extensively by the science teams to improve
    the calibration of instrument.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    This dataset, Version 2.0, was peer reviewed and certified for
    scientific use on 15 August 2011.  It supersedes Version 1.0
    which contained data only from October 2007 through May 2010.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    There are no unexpected gaps in this dataset.  All calibration
    observations received on the ground were processed and included in this
    dataset.
 
    Horizontal striping through some images indicates missing data.  The
    image quality map extension identifies where pixels are missing.  If
    the second most-significant bit of a pixel in the image quality map is
    turned on, then data for the corresponding image pixel is missing.  For
    more information, refer to the EPOXI SIS document.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
 
    Timing
    ------
      The flyby spacecraft clock SPICE kernels (SCLK) used to convert to
      UTC and to calculate geometry-related parameters for this dataset
      have a known accuracy of no better than 0.5 seconds.  However the
      latest SCLK (science version 84) applied to the Hartley 2 encounter
      data is good to within 0.01 seconds for converting the spacecraft
      timestamps to ephemeris time for observations acquired around
      closest approach.  Please note that the SCLK (version 65) used to
      compute UTC values and geometry for calibration data acquired from
      January 2009 through July 2010 has known discontinuities of up to a
      second.  Those discontinuities have been corrected in the latest
      SCLK, science version 84, applied to Hartley data.
 
      The mission operations team has figured out how to correct raw clock
      correlation data for the Deep Impact flyby spacecraft to allow
      timing fits that are accurate to well under the sub-second level as
      evidenced by the 0.01-second accuracy around the time the Hartley 2
      encounter.  The EPOXI project plans to use this method to generate a
      complete and highly accurate set of UTC correlations for the flyby
      spacecraft since the launch, resulting in a future version of a SCLK
      kernel that will retroactively change correlation for **all** Deep
      Impact and EPOXI data.  When this kernel is available, it will be
      added to the SPICE datasets for the two missions and posted on the
      NAIF/SPICE web site at http://naif.jpl.nasa.gov/naif/.  The EPOXI
      project will provide more precise times for archived data as time
      and funding permit.
 
 
    HRI Telescope Focus
    -------------------
      Images of stars acquired early during the Deep Impact mission in 2005
      indicated the HRI telescope was out of focus.  However, this focus
      problem does not significantly affect the HRII instrument.  For more
      details please see the Deep Impact instrument calibration paper by
      Klaasen, et al. (2008) [KLAASENETAL2006].
 
 
    Displaying Images
    -----------------
      Flight software writes an image header over the first 100 bytes of
      quadrant A.  These image header pixels were included in the raw FITS
      images.  Since the values in these pixels vary dramatically, it is
      recommended that the values of the MINIMUM and MAXIMUM keywords in
      the data label (or the MINPVAL and MAXPVAL in the FITS header) be
      used to scale an image for display because these values exclude the
      header bytes as well as the reference rows and columns located around
      the edge of the spectral image.  For more information, see the
      quadrant nomenclature section of the EPOXI SIS document.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

