<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ear-a-i0688-5-cmormetorb-v2.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CMOR METEOROID STREAM SURVEY V2.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.support_archives::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.obs3340t1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:i0688.obs3340t1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:meteoroid.meteoroid::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-a-i0688-5-cmormetorb-v2.0__browserp_ear-a-i0688-5-cmormetorb-v2.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Brown, P., R.J. Weryk, D.K. Wong, and J. Jones, A meteoroid stream survey using
                   the Canadian Meteor Orbit Radar I. Methodology and radiant catalog, Icarus 195,
                   317-339, 2008.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BROWNETAL2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Brown, P., D.K. Wong, R.J. Weryk, and P. Wiegert, A meteoroid stream survey
                   using the Canadian Meteor Orbit Radar II: Identification of minor showers using
                   a 3D wavelet transform. Icarus 207, 66-81, 2010.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BROWNETAL2010</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>EAR-A-I0688-5-CMORMETORB-V2.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CMOR METEOROID STREAM SURVEY V2.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2011-05-31</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2002-01-01</start_time>
        <stop_time>2008-12-31</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>CAROL NEESE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Brown, P., Weryk, R.J., Wong, D.K., and Jones, J., CMOR Meteoroid
            Stream Survey V2.0. EAR-A-I0688-5-CMORMETORB-V2.0. NASA Planetary
            Data System, 2011.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Survey of meteoroid streams by the Canadian Meteoroid Orbit Radar
            (CMOR), published in Brown et al. (2008, 2010).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            A seven-year radar survey of meteor showers has been carried out
            with the Canadian Meteor Orbit Radar (CMOR) from 2002-2008 (Brown
            et al. 2008, 2010). This survey resulted in the unambiguous
            detection and orbital characterization of 109 major and minor
            meteor showers. This data set includes a list of the detected
            meteor showers along with their orbital parameters.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The Canadian Meteor Orbit Radar, (CMOR), located near Tavistock, Ontario
    and operated by the University of Western Ontario, initially carried out a
    survey of meteor showers over the period 2002-2006, the results of which
    were published in Brown et al. (2008) and which were archived in PDS in
    version 1.0 of this data set.  The survey was subsequently extended
    through 2008, and the extended results published in Brown et al. (2010).
    In the following description, Survey I refers to the initial 2002-2006
    reconnaissance survey, and Survey II refers to the combined data from the
    full 2002-2008 survey.  This version (2.0) of the data set contains the
    full results from Survey II.
 
    A total of just over 3 million meteoroids were detected in survey II, and
    their orbits determined.  From these data, an automated stream search
    algorithm identified 117 meteor showers, including 42 of the 45 streams
    previously identified in survey I.  Removing possible duplicate showers
    from the results leaves a total of 109 distinct meteor showers.  This data
    set presents the orbital parameters measured for the 117 major and minor
    meteor streams which were detected during survey II.  Tables showing
    linkages between the streams, possible parent bodies, and grouping of the
    streams into complexes are also included.
 
 
    Data Files and Parameters
    =========================
 
    radiants.tab - Contains information about the radiants of the 117 detected
    showers, including the time of maximum, duration, geocentric radiant
    coordinates, and velocity at time of maximum, as well as radiant drift and
    associated error.  Reproduces the content of Table 1 of the paper.
 
    orbits.tab - Contains information about the shower mean orbits, computed
    using the radiant and velocity observed at shower maximum.  Included are
    orbital elements and the number of orbits used to compute the mean stream
    orbit.  Reproduces the content of Table 2 of the paper.
 
    complexes.tab - Groups the detected streams into seven major stream
    complexes.  Reproduces the content of Table 3 of the paper.
 
    linkages.tab - Lists possible interstream linkages, along with possible
    parent bodies.  Reproduces the content of Table 4 of the paper.
 
    For a full description of the survey and derivations, and a discussion of
    the results, see the original papers, Brown et al. (2008, 2010).
 
 
    References
    ==========
 
    Brown, P., R.J. Weryk, D.K. Wong, and J. Jones, A meteoroid stream survey
    using the Canadian Meteor Orbit Radar I. Methodology and radiant catalog,
    Icarus 195, 317-339, 2008.
 
    Brown, P., D.K. Wong, R.J. Weryk, and P. Wiegert, A meteoroid stream
    survey using the Canadian Meteor Orbit Radar II:  Identification of minor
    showers using a 3D wavelet transform.  Icarus 207, 66-81, 2010.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    For further discussion of the survey data and analysis, see Brown et al.
    (2008, 2010).
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

