<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lro-l-lamp-2-edr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LRO MOON LAMP 2 EXPERIMENT DATA RECORD V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:lamp.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-lamp-2-edr-v1.0__browserp_lro-l-lamp-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-lamp-2-edr-v1.0__dvo_imaging_lro-l-lamp-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-lamp-2-edr-v1.0__pds.geo.lro.orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Gladstone, G.R., S.A. Stern, K.D. Retherford, R.K. Black, D.C. Slater, M.W.
                   Davis, M.H. Versteeg, K.B. Persson, J.Wm. Parker, D.E. Kaufmann, A.F. Egan,
                   T.K. Greathouse, P.D. Feldman, D. Crider, W.R. Pryor, and A.R. Hendrix, LAMP:
                   The Lyman Alpha Mapping Project on NASA&apos;s Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter Mission,
                   Space Sci. Rev., submitted (2008).
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GLADSTONEETAL2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LRO-L-LAMP-2-EDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LRO MOON LAMP 2 EXPERIMENT DATA RECORD V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2010-03-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2009-01-01</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID E. KAUFMANN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Kaufmann, D.E., LRO L LAMP EXPERIMENT DATA RECORD V1.0,
            LRO-L-LAMP-2-EDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2009.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter (LRO) Lyman Alpha Mapping
            Project (LAMP) CODMAC Level 2 Experiment Data Record is a
            collection of the far ultraviolet photon detections obtained by
            the LAMP instrument, in raw form.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter (LRO) Lyman Alpha Mapping
            Project (LAMP) CODMAC Level 2 Experiment Data Record is a
            collection of the far ultraviolet photon detections obtained by
            the LAMP instrument, in raw form. As such, it constitutes the
            permanent record of the raw LAMP data. These data include both
            the instrument science and housekeeping data, organized into
            extensions within files formatted according to the Flexible Image
            Transport System (FITS) standard, version 2.1b. The LAMP EDR
            archive enables reprocessing of the raw science data as
            radiometric and geometric calibration processing routines
            improve. Investigators interested in applying advanced
            calibration methods or needing to understand the properties of
            the raw data will find the EDR products useful. Most
            investigators, however, will be interested in using either the
            LAMP data products contained in the CODMAC Level 3 Reduced Data
            Record, as radiometric and geometric calibration processing has
            already been done for these products, or the LAMP CODMAC Level 5
            far ultraviolet map products.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  DATA SET OVERVIEW
  =================
    The Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter (LRO) Lyman Alpha Mapping Project (LAMP)
    CODMAC Level 2 Experiment Data Record is a collection of the far
    ultraviolet photon detections obtained by the LAMP instrument, in raw
    form. As such, it constitutes the permanent record of the raw LAMP data.
    These data include both the instrument science and housekeeping data,
    organized into extensions within files formatted according to the Flexible
    Image Transport System (FITS) standard, version 2.1b.  The LAMP EDR
    archive enables reprocessing of the raw science data as radiometric and
    geometric calibration processing routines improve.  Investigators
    interested in applying advanced calibration methods or needing to
    understand the properties of the raw data will find the EDR products
    useful.  Most investigators, however, will be interested in using either
    the LAMP data products contained in the CODMAC Level 3 Reduced Data
    Record, as radiometric and geometric calibration processing has already
    been done for these products, or the LAMP CODMAC Level 5 far ultraviolet
    map products.
 
 
  PARAMETERS
  ==========
    The fundamental measured parameters contained in the LAMP EDR data set are
    the nearest time markers and the spatial and spectral locations on the
    LAMP detector for each of the recorded far ultraviolet photon detection
    events. From these values raw calculated count rates (counts/sec)
    integrated over all spatial and spectral bins are also derived.  The
    sampling interval for the derived count rate values is determined by the
    commanded rate at which the time markers are inserted into the data
    stream.  This value will normally be set to 250 Hz.
 
 
  PROCESSING
  ==========
    LAMP EDR data products will be generated at the LAMP Science Operations
    Center (SOC), located at the Southwest Research Institute in Boulder,
    Colorado.  The products will be generated by an automated pipeline
    process. The LAMP instrument will nominally generate one housekeeping
    telemetry file and one science data file per orbit.  Once per day these
    LAMP-generated files will be retrieved from the LRO spacecraft by the LRO
    Mission Operations Center (MOC) and then transferred by the MOC to the
    LAMP SOC. The automated LAMP SOC pipeline will ingest these files and
    invoke software to process them, in pairwise fashion (one housekeeping and
    one science data file at a time), into EDR data product files.  No
    calibration of the science data will be done at this time.  Raw
    housekeeping telemetry values will be converted to engineering units,
    where applicable, and these converted values will be included in the EDR
    data product files.
 
 
  DATA
  ====
    The LAMP EDR data product file will contain the following seven types of
    data:
 
    1) Spectral Image (Aperture Door Open) - This is a reconstructed histogram
    generated from the pixel list data in the science data file.  Using
    information from the housekeeping data, only the pixel list data acquired
    when the aperture door was open are included in this dataset.  If
    housekeeping data are unavailable, all pixel list data are included in
    this histogram.  If the science data file contains only data acquired with
    LAMP operating in histogram mode, this dataset will contain a copy of the
    first histogram image.  This summary image is used as a &apos;quick-look&apos; check
    on data quality.  [Extension 0, primary FITS header and data unit (HDU)]
 
    2) Spectral Image (Aperture Door Closed) - This is similar to the first
    dataset above, but the reconstructed histogram here is generated from
    pixel list data acquired when the aperture door was closed.  If
    housekeeping data are unavailable, this dataset will be empty.  If the
    science data file contains only data acquired in histogram mode, this
    dataset will contain a copy of the second histogram image in the file.
    This summary image is used as a &apos;quick-look&apos; check on data quality.
    [Extension 1]
 
    3) Acquisition List - This dataset contains a list of the generated frame
    acquisitions as determined from the housekeeping data file.  The list
    includes, for each frame, the instrument frame sequence number, start and
    stop times, mode type, aperture door and other instrument state
    information.  The frame acquisition times and instrument state data
    contained in this list are used to cross-reference with the pixel list
    mode data for purposes of selecting data and checking timing consistency.
    [Extension 2]
 
    4) Raw Frame Data - This dataset contains all of the raw data from the
    science data file except for the file header.  [Extension 3]
 
    5) Calculated Count Rate - This dataset contains a high-resolution
    sequence of UV photon count rates computed from the pixel list data for
    each acquisition (nominally the whole orbit).  The resolution of this
    count rate sequence depends on the commanded &apos;hack time&apos; interval.  If no
    consecutive pixel list science data are available, e.g., if data are
    acquired only in histogram mode, then this dataset will contain the lower
    resolution (1-Hz) count rate data that are available from the housekeeping
    data file. [Extension 4]
 
    6) LTS Data - LAMP housekeeping data contain up to 10 values per second of
    gain     and offset corrected measurement values from each of the two LAMP
    Lunar Terminator Sensors (LTS).  This dataset provides the full 10-Hz LTS
    dataset. These coincident LTS data will be used with the count rate
    sequence in Extension 4 to confirm that LAMP is viewing the appropriate
    day/night/shadow scenes.  (Raw 14-bit LTS data sampled at the 1-Hz HK rate
    is included together with this 10-Hz gain and offset corrected LTS dataset
    in the housekeeping data Extension 6.)  [Extension 5]
 
    7) Housekeeping Data - This dataset contains the complete housekeeping
    dataset, both in raw format and, where applicable, in calibrated
    engineering units.  HK data are included here to assist with joint
    instrument and data quality trending analyses (foreseen and unforeseen).
    [Extension 6]
 
 
  ANCILLARY DATA
  ==============
    Ancillary data used in the generation of the LAMP EDR data set include
    those values required to convert instrumental engineering quantities
    contained in the housekeeping data from raw values to physical units.
    These data have been obtained from the LAMP engineers at the Southwest
    Research Institute in San Antonio, Texas.
 
 
  COORDINATE SYSTEM
  =================
    The LAMP EDR data product is a CODMAC Level 2 product. As such, the
    science data contained therein have not been corrected for instrumental
    effects, calibrated, or located in space.  The data are reported according
    to the two-dimensional detector coordinate system in X and Y (1024 x 32,
    respectively).
 
 
  SOFTWARE
  ========
    Because the LAMP EDR data product files adhere to version 2.1b of the FITS
    standard, all FITS readers up to this standard should be able to
    successfully read these files.  There are many such FITS readers freely
    available in the public domain.
 
 
  MEDIA/FORMAT
  ============
    The LAMP EDR data product files are written in FITS format, and the format
    of each file is described in an accompanying detached PDS label.  The EDR
    archive itself will be written on DVD-R media and physically delivered
    from the LAMP SOC to the PDS Imaging Node, where it will be made generally
    available via the World Wide Web.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence level information will be provided after more thorough analysis
  of the data.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

