<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mgs-m-mola-1-aedr-l0-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MOLA AGGREGATED EXPERIMENT DATA RECORD</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_global_surveyor::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mgs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mola.mgs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-mola-1-aedr-l0-v1.0__browserp_geo_mgs-m-mola-1-aedr-l0-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-mola-1-aedr-l0-v1.0__dvo_geo_mgs-m-mola-1-aedr-l0-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mars Orbiter Laser Altimeter Aggregated Experiment Data Record Software
                   Interface Specification, Version 2.1, NASA/Goddard Space Flight Center,
                   September 24, 1998.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MOLAAEDRSIS1998</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MGS-M-MOLA-1-AEDR-L0-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MOLA AGGREGATED EXPERIMENT DATA RECORD</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1998-10-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1997-07-31T19:10Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID E. SMITH</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Smith, D., G. Neumann, P. Ford, E. A. Guinness, and S. Slavney,
            Mars Global Surveyor Laser Altimeter Aggregated Experiment Data
            Record, NASA Planetary Data System, MGS-M-MOLA-1-AEDR-L0-V1.0,
            1999.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Aggregated Experiment Data Record (AEDR) archive contains raw
            altimetry profile data acquired by the Mars Orbiter Laser
            Altimeter (MOLA) during the Mars Global Surveyor (MGS) mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The MOLA AEDR data set contains the raw altimetry measurements
            acquired by the Mars Orbiter Laser Altimeter on the Mars Global
            Surveyor spacecraft. The AEDR data are used as input to the MOLA
            Precision Experiment Data Record (PEDR) data set, in which the
            altimetry data have been corrected according to precise
            measurements of the orbit. The PEDR data set is preferred for
            science analysis.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The Mars Global Surveyor spacecraft included a laser altimeter
    instrument.  The primary objective of the Mars Orbiter Laser
    Altimeter (MOLA) is to determine globally the topography of Mars
    at a level suitable for addressing problems in geology and
    geophysics.
 
    The Aggregated Experiment Data Record (AEDR) is an aggregation of
    MOLA telemetry packets (raw data).  AEDR products generated
    during the Orbit Insertion phase of the mission are aggregated by
    orbit.  AEDR products generated during the Mapping Phase are
    aggregated by sol (Martian day).  The raw AEDR products are
    truncated and used to create the PEDRs.
 
    The process to create the AEDR data product is performed as part
    of MOLA mission operations.  The telemetry packets are aggregated
    on a Mars Global Surveyor mapping orbit basis.  There are
    approximately 12 orbits per day with each orbit taking 117
    minutes 39 seconds to complete.  The mapping mission will last
    for one Martian year, which is 687 Earth days.
 
    The AEDR data products will be produced continuously for the life
    of the mission (687 days).  Each product will contain
    approximately 7000 seconds of data.
 
    A complete listing of all parameters contained in an AEDR can be
    found in Tables 1 and 2 of the AEDR Software Interface
    Specification (SIS) document [MOLAAEDRSIS1998].  Additionally,
    the AEDR format and contents are described in the AEDR Data
    Dictionary in Appendices A and B of the SIS.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The AEDR files are in binary format with attached PDS labels.
    The SIS document describing this standard product is included on
    this volume.
 
    The AEDRs contain essentially all the data contained in the
    PEDRs.  Everything in the AEDR is archived in the PEDR after
    scaling.  The AEDRs usually contain engineering data during
    instrument warm-up.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The MOLA instrument measures the round-trip time of flight of
    infrared laser pulses transmitted from the MGS spacecraft to the
    Martian surface.  The instrument normally operates in a single
    autonomous mode, in which it produces ranging measurements.
    Surface topography estimates can be derived from these data,
    given appropriate corrections for the position and attitude of
    the spacecraft.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The AEDR raw telemetry data are truncated to create PEDRs.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    N/A
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    N/A
 
 
  Software
  ========
    N/A
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    The MGS MOLA PEDR dataset will be available on CD-ROM and
    electronically via the PDS Geosciences Node web site at
    http://wwwpds.wustl.edu and the MOLA Science Team web site at
    http://ltpwww.gsfc.nasa.gov/tharsis/mola.html.  Formats will be
    based on standards established by the Planetary Data System
    (PDS).
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The resolution of the data is about 40 cm vertically, and about
    330 m along-track, limited by the 10 Hz firing rate of the laser.
    The absolute, long-wavelength radial orbit error is estimated to
    be about 30 m.  The uncertainty in absolute ground spot location
    is limited by the attitude knowledge of the spacecraft, and is
    estimated to be about 400 m at a nominal range of 400 km.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    MOLA AEDR and PEDR archive volumes are reviewed by MGS mission
    scientists and by PDS.
 
 
  Data Coverage/Quality
  =====================
    On May 26, 1998, the Mars Global Surveyor (MGS) spacecraft
    entered into Phase 2 of the Science Phasing Orbit (SPO-2).  SPO
    is a near-polar (92.869 degrees) inclination orbit with a period
    of 11.6 hours and a periapsis altitude of about 170 km.  During
    SPO-2 MOLA will collect observations of Mars&apos; northern
    hemisphere, with emphasis on detailed mapping of the north polar
    ice cap.  Late June and early July 1998 is expected to be the
    period of maximum ice loading for the northern cap for the
    current Martian year and thus represents an especially exciting
    and crucial time for MOLA observations.  We anticipate that the
    observations collected during this period will contribute
    significantly towards understanding the present-day Martian
    volatile budget.  We have just completed a two-week period where
    the MGS spacecraft was tilted on alternating orbits so that MOLA
    could fill in the 2 degree coverage gap at the north pole that
    occurred because the spacecraft orbital inclination is not
    exactly 90 degrees.
 
    MOLA collected 61 topographic profiles of Mars&apos; northern
    hemisphere during the first phase of the MGS Science Phasing
    Orbit (SPO-1) that spanned the period from March 26, 1998 until
    April 28, 1998.  All of the MOLA data collected during SPO-1 were
    presented in thirteen talks and posters during the week of May
    26, 1998 at the Spring Meeting of the American Geophysical Union
    in Boston.
 
    MOLA&apos;s SPO-1 observations were collected during orbital passes in
    which targeted imaging of surface features was not being
    attempted.  Collection of images of target sites (Viking 1 &amp; 2
    and Pathfinder landing sites and Cydonia) resulted in a loss of
    about 25% of the data that MOLA could have been collected during
    that period.
 
    SPO-1 ended in mid-May, just before solar conjunction.  During
    conjunction the sun is in the line of sight of the spacecraft,
    which interferes with communication, so commanding of the
    spacecraft is minimized.
 
    The Science Phasing Orbit represents a hiatus from aerobraking
    that is needed so that the spacecraft will achieve the desired
    local time for the mapping orbit that will be entered next
    spring.  SPO will last until September 11, 1998, after which time
    MGS will resume aerobraking to circularize its current elliptical
    orbit.  During aerobraking passes, the MOLA instrument does not
    collect data because the instrument is not pointed at the surface
    during the period of time when the spacecraft is within ranging
    distance.
 
    Previous MOLA data was collected during the capture orbit phase
    of the MGS mission shortly after orbit insertion on September 15,
    1997.  A further 17 passes were collected between October 14 and
    November 6, 1997, during a hiatus in the aerobraking phase
    necessitated by a study of the integrity of a solar panel that
    was slightly damaged after launch.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    Our current understanding of the Martian environment, the
    capabilities of MGS, and its suite of instruments is changing
    rapidly.  MOLA has met or exceeded its design expectations.  It
    has demonstrated a measurement precision of 30 centimeters over
    flat terrain.  While designed for nadir-looking operation in a
    circular, 365- to 445-km- high orbit, MOLA has ranged
    successfully to Mars at distances from 170 to 786 km, and to
    surface slopes up to 60 degrees.  MOLA has ranged to the surfaces
    of clouds lying at elevations of a few hundred meters above the
    surface, to over 15 km high, and returned measurements of
    atmospheric opacity greater than 2 during dust storms.  MOLA
    returned 628 ranges to the moon Phobos in an orbital fast-flyby.
    The planetary range detection rate in clear atmosphere has
    exceeded 99% over smooth and rough terrain.
 
    The MOLA ranges and precision orbit data are preliminary, and
    will be revised as our knowledge of the spacecraft and the
    Martian gravity field improves.  Important details of the
    instrument design and the progress of the mission are found in
    the files INST.CAT and MISSION.CAT.  The orbital, atmospheric and
    thermal environment of the Orbit Insertion phase has introduced
    uncertainties in the data quality.  The eccentric orbits and
    frequent off-nadir pointing during ranging cause a greater
    sensitivity to errors in spacecraft timing and attitude knowledge
    than expected in mapping orbit.
 
    Orbital location is derived from radio observations and a host of
    dynamic variables, most important of which is the gravitational
    attraction of Mars.  Improvements in the gravity field are best
    obtained from tracking at low elevations, now being obtained from
    MGS.  The gravity model used to calculate the orbits is an
    interim solution, internally designated mgm0827e, derived from
    Goddard Mars Model 1.  This model is given in the software
    directory as GMM1.2 for the purpose of defining an equipotential
    topographic reference surface.  GMM1.2 is necessarily constrained
    and lacks detailed resolution of the polar regions, so that
    unmodeled orbital perturbations accumulate.  At the same time,
    the areoid reference surface may vary by tens of meters depending
    on the choice of gravity model.  The altimetric error budget is
    currently dominated by orbital uncertainty, and does not yet meet
    our goal of 30 m accuracy.
 
    The spacecraft radial distance from Mars may change up to 1.6
    meters in a millisecond due to orbital eccentricity, and up to 8
    meters between the time the pulse is fired and it is received.
    Altimetric processing therefore depends strongly on timing
    accuracy and knowledge of the direction in which the laser is
    fired.  MOLA data are time-tagged once per packet with a
    spacecraft time code, calibrated to ground time.  An instrument
    clock synchronized to the Payload Data System provides 1/256
    second resolution timing.  The PEDRs contain interpolated laser
    transmit time to a precision of a tenth of a millisecond.
 
    Altimetric crossovers are being used to assess the accuracy of
    the data.  It has been determined that the observations have a
    systematic timing bias, further, that the attitude knowledge of
    the spacecraft is offset.  The range observations have been
    registered with orbital position by assuming that the time tag of
    the MOLA range, as derived from the spacecraft clock, is 113
    milliseconds earlier than the actual transmit time.  In addition
    it is assumed that the time tag of the attitude kernel provided
    by the MGS Project is one second later than the time of the
    spacecraft attitude sensor readings, due to a software filter
    delay.  The precise causes and amounts of offset are under
    investigation.
 
    Range measurements are affected by the counting frequency
    standard, electronic delays, and spreading of the returned pulse
    due to ground slope and detector characteristics.  The MOLA
    timing interval unit has a an accuracy of ~2.5 nanoseconds, its
    precision being extended from the 10 ns clock rate by two
    interpolator bits.  However, &apos;range walk&apos; due to variable
    threshold settings, pulse amplitude and shape, can be many times
    greater than measurement precision, especially over rough
    terrain.  The MOLA instrument records the pulse width and
    amplitude during the time that the signal exceeds a
    software-controlled threshold.  Shot ranges are corrected in
    processing via a mathematical receiver model [ABSHIRE&amp;SUN1998],
    assuming linear instrument behavior.  Flat and highly reflective
    terrain, short ranges, and abnormal atmospheric conditions can
    drive the electronics into saturation, increasing detected pulse
    width and invalidating the instrument model.  The range
    corrections for saturated returns are limited to their
    equivalents for terrain with a slope of one in sixteen.
    Meter-level changes in topography must be interpreted in the
    context of the range correction values in the PEDR files.
 
    The returned-optical-pulse-width and energy measurements must
    also be interpreted with caution, in view of the above-mentioned
    effects.  Moreover, the detectors were not calibrated for the
    unusually cold conditions experienced during Orbit Insertion.
    Energy values are slightly higher than measured by test equipment
    under optimal conditions.  The unsaturated return energy and
    reflectivity measurements were only designed for 5% accuracy in
    any case.
 
    Lastly, the presence of highly reflective clouds, and a level of
    noise returns consistent with instrument tradeoffs, has
    necessitated an empirical classification of shots as to their
    origin.  The first shot of every 140 is likely to be triggered by
    an internal test source, but may be a valid ground return, while
    0.5% of the shots result from detector noise exceeding the
    triggering threshold.  The probable ground returns have been
    flagged based on a combination of measurements and a stochastic
    model of topographic variability.  An unambiguous classification
    is often impossible, given clouds that often follow the surface,
    and the dramatic variability of Martian terrain.  The
    classification should be used only as a guide.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>96-062A-03A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

