<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.go-j-pls-3-rdr-fullres-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GALILEO JUPITER RDR FULL RESOLUTION PLASMA DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.galileo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:pls.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.callisto::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.europa::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.ganymede::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.io::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-j-pls-3-rdr-fullres-v1.0__browserp_go-j-pls-3-rdr-fullres-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Frank, L. A., K. L. Ackerson, J. A. Lee, M. R. English, and G. L. Pickett, The
                   Plasma Instrumentation for the Galileo Mission, Sp. Sci. Rev., 60, 283-307,
                   1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FRANKETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GO-J-PLS-3-RDR-FULLRES-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GALILEO JUPITER RDR FULL RESOLUTION PLASMA DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2003-11-21</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1995-12-07T15:30Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2003-09-21T18:45Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. KENT ACKERSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Frank, L.A., Paterson, W.R., Ackerson, K.L., GALILEO JUPITER RDR
            FULL RESOLUTION PLASMA DATA V1.0, GO-J-PLS-3-RDR-FULLRES-V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 2000.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains raw data from the Plasma Science
            instrument (PLS) on the Galileo spacecraft for all Jupiter
            orbits. These data have been reformatted into ASCII tables to
            facilitate data processing and analysis.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains raw data from the Plasma Science
            instrument (PLS) on the Galileo spacecraft for all Jupiter
            orbits. These data have been reformatted into ASCII tables to
            facilitate data processing and analysis.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Overview:
    =========
 
    This data set contains data from the Plasma Science instrument
    (PLS) onboard the Galileo spacecraft during the Jupiter orbital
    operations phase (December 1995 to end of mission). These data have
    been edited and reformatted from the raw telemetry packets into a
    simple ASCII tabular structure to facilitate processing and analysis.
 
 
    Parameters:
    ===========
 
    This data set includes both high time resolution (LPW) data recorded
    during targeted encounters and real-time science (RTS) data acquired
    during the magnetospheric survey when telemetry was available. The
    Plasma instrument can collect either RTS data or LPW data but not
    both simultaneously.
 
    The basic data set parameters are the detector count rates in units
    of counts per second. Data are provided at the full instrument
    sampling rate in all sampling parameters (time, detector, E/Q, M/Q).
    The instrument has twenty (20) detectors (seven ion, seven electron,
    six mass spectrometer) and can sample E/Q or M/Q (mass spectrometer
    detectors only) in sixty-four (64) steps for each detector.
 
 
    Processing:
    ===========
 
    The final instrument packet files (IPF&apos;s) have been processed to
    decommutate the PLS telemetry into individual instrument modes. Each mode
    generally covers one spacecraft rotation and contains a number of energy
    spectra (or mass spectra) at a number of angles.
 
    In LPW mode an instrument cycle spans an interval of 4 RIM&apos;s (242.67
    seconds). During this interval the instrument collects approximately
    28 individual modes of data. In RTS operation the cycle is different,
    and longer, due to the severely reduced telemetry rates. The
    energies, accumulation times, and sectoring schemes all vary from
    mode to mode, as with the LPW data.
 
    A major accomplishment of the RDR processing is to recast the PLS
    data in a format that is independent of the details of the operating
    modes. The resulting RDR data records are much easier to use.
 
    The PLS telemetry system is sensitive to data gaps. Repairing data
    due to embedded data gaps cannot be automated.  Consequently
    measurements with gaps in the middle of an individual modes are not
    included in the RDR file. Fortunately, such gaps occurred
    infrequently.  The recovery of LPW data was generally good. Multiple
    playbacks were made on each LPW recording to fill gaps.
 
    Please refer to the calibration document (CALIB.TXT) contained on the
    PDS archive volume for a discussion of pitfalls and problems in using
    the RDR files. This document is located on the PDS archive volumes in
    the DOCUMENT/PLS directory.
 
 
    Ancillary Data:
    ===============
 
    Several ancillary files are provided with these data: calibration
    tables, a calibration document, and a spacecraft events file.
 
 
    Calibration:
 
      PLSCALIB.TXT  Describes the calibration algorithm and pitfalls.
      PLS_DETS.TAB  maps detector numbers to detector names/functions
      E_STEP_1.TAB  E-steps for electron detectors 14,16,18, and 20.
      E_STEP_2.TAB  E-steps for ion dets 3,5,9,11 and mass spec dets 6,7
      E_STEP_3.TAB  E-steps for electron detectors 15,17, and 19.
      E_STEP_4.TAB  E-steps for ion dets 4,8,10 and mass spec dets
      1,2,12,13 M_STEP_1.TAB  M-steps for the mass spectrometer channels
      SECTOR.TAB    AACS sector angles
      CALIB_1.TAB   Calibration factors to convert count rates to
                    differential flux for electron detectors 14,16,18,
                    and 20 CALIB_2.TAB   Calibration factors to convert
                    count rates to differential flux for ion detectors
                    3,5,9,11 and mass spec detectors 6 and 7.
      CALIB_3.TAB   Calibration factors to convert count rates to
                    differential flux for electron detectors 15,17, and
                    19. CALIB_4.TAB   Calibration factors to convert
                    count rates to differential flux for ion detectors
                    4,8,10 and mass spec detectors 1,2,12 and 13.
 
    Spacecraft Events:
 
    xxx_SEF.TXT   A time ordered file extracted from the As-Run
    Spacecraft Events Files (ARSEF) that provides the timing of events
    that are significant to the plasma experiment. These  events include
    whether or not the instrument is &apos;on&apos;, which type of data are being
    acquired (RTS or  LPW), the time of thruster firings, etc. The &apos;xxx&apos;
    in the file name is the orbit name (i.e. G01 for orbit Ganymede 1).
 
 
    Coordinate System:
    ==================
 
    Data are provided in PLS instrument coordinates. Please refer to the
    instrument description paper [FRANKETAL1992] for a description of the
    instrument mounting, detector fields of view, and spin phase
    sectoring. See also the SECTOR.TAB file in the ancillary data files.
 
 
    Software:
    =========
 
    There is no software provided with this archive.
 
 
    Media/Format:
    =============
 
 
    These data are archived on either CDROM or DVDROM media. The data
    files are stored in a simple ASCII table form that is described by a
    detached PDS label (Table Object). Each table has the following
    structure:
 
    Col#    Name  Format   Description
-----------------------------------------------------------------------
    1       Time    A24      Spacecraft event time (UTC)
    2       SCLK    A11      Spacecraft clock counter (RIM:mf)
    3       Rate    1PE8.2   Count rate (counts/sec)
    4       DetId   I2       Detector Id (1-20)
    5       E-Step  I2       E/Q analyzer step (0-63)
    6       M-Step  I2       M/Q analyzer step (0-63)
    7       Sector  I3       AACS rotor spin angle (0-255 =2 PI).
    8       Sample  I2       Sample number
    9       Accum   F6.4     Accumulation time in seconds
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Data Coverage/Quality:
    ======================
 
    This data set contains gaps in coverage. Many of these gaps were
    planned (insufficient telemetry coverage to provide continuous data)
    and others were not (telemetry dropouts, station outages, etc.).
 
    Some files may not be completely continuous in time.  This is a result
    of how the data is transmitted and received:
 
    &apos;The PLS instrument has two analyzers: A and B.  Each analyzer has its own
    sensors, high voltage supplies, analyzer plates, and data paths.  The two
    analyzers normally start a spin-mode at the same time.  And they normally
    end a spin-mode at the same time.  Both data streams are buffered
    internally by the PLS data system and sent out to the spacecraft in a
    packetized telemetry scheme.  Generally, the two streams are interleaved
    on a minor-frame-by-minor-frame basis, but if one analyzer does not have
    data ready and the other does then the telemetry that is ready is sent.
    (Note that the two analyzers have different numbers of sensors and create
    different quantities of data.)
 
    On the ground, the PLS telemetry stream is decommutated and separated into
    A and B data-sets for each spin-mode.  The time tag attached to each
    A-data-set and each B-data-set is the time of the first telemetry packet
    containing some of that data.  As soon as a complete data set has been
    decommutated on the ground it is written to the output file.  And this is
    the key to understanding what is happening.  Sometimes the first data-set
    to appear in the telemetry stream is also the first one to be completed.
    And sometimes the first data-set to appear in the telemetry is the last to
    be completed.  It is essentially a random thing.
 
    It is crucial to note that PLS takes all of its data in a spin-
    synchronized fashion, not in a SCLK-synchronized fashion.  We went to
    great pains to ensure that the data were obtained in well-defined spin
    sectors and in repeatable directions.  Differences of a couple of
    minor-frames are not significant.  The spin-phase angles are the
    quantities of importance.&apos;
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

