<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lro-l-dlre-5-gdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LRO DLRE 5 GRIDDED DATA RECORDS</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:dlre.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-dlre-5-gdr-v1.0__browserp_lro-l-dlre-5-gdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-dlre-5-gdr-v1.0__dvo_geo_lro-l-dlre-5-gdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-dlre-5-gdr-v1.0__pds.geo.lro.orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Paige, D.A., et al., The Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter Diviner Lunar Radiometer
                   Experiment, Space Sci. Rev., doi: 10.1007/s11214-009-9529-2, 2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PAIGEETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LRO-L-DLRE-5-GDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LRO DLRE 5 GRIDDED DATA RECORDS</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2013-03-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2009-07-05T16:50:26.195Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2012-09-15T22:00:00.000Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID PAIGE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Paige et al., LRO DLRE LEVEL 5 GDR V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, LRO-L-DLRE-5-GDR-V1.0, 2011.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            LRO DLRE GDR, Averaged reflectances, temperatures, and derived
            values.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set consists of the Diviner Lunar Radiometer Experiment
            Gridded Data Records also known as GDRs. The DLRE is a surface
            pushbroom mapper that measures emitted thermal radiation and
            reflected solar radiation from the surface of the moon. Two
            Diviner solar channels measure 0.3-3 micrometers reflected solar
            radiation. Three Diviner channels near 8 micrometers classify
            regolith mineralogy by mapping the location of the Christiansen
            feature. The remaining four Diviner channels measure surface
            temperature in four spectral bands ranging from 12.5 micrometers
            to beyond 200 micrometers.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
-------------------------------------------------------------------------+
 
Data Product Overview
=====================
 
Level 2 GDR
 
The Diviner GDR data products are derived directly from the RDR
data product.  They directly mimic the format and intent of the
Lunar Orbiter Laser Altimeter (LOLA) GDR data product for
maximum compatibility with LOLA and other products.
 
NASA Level 2 Diviner GDR products include solar reflectances,
brightness temperatures, and time-related values such as local time
and Julian Date that are binned and averaged according to 27-day
LRO mapping cycles.   Each averaged product is further split into
daytime (local time 06:00 to 18:00) and nighttime (local time 18:00
to 06:00) data products.
 
For each averaged gridded product, an analogous pair of count and error
estimate products will be created.  Count files will simply contain the
number of measurements in each bin.  The purpose of the error estimate
products is to provide the end user with information regarding the
uncertainties in the gridded quantities based on the signal to noise
ratios of the Diviner channels, and the number of observations in each
bin.  Error estimates in local time and Julian Date will be determined by
computing the standard deviation in these quantities.
 
Unlike the LOLA GDR data products, which use interpolation to create
continuous global grids, Diviner GDR data products will include data gaps
in grid cells where no observations were acquired.
 
The Level 2 GDR data products are gridded in cylindrical longitude and
latitudinal space and in polar stereographic space (to +/- 75 degrees
latitude) at varying resolutions.   The master resolution for both types
of projections will be 128 pixels per degree (ppd).
Only nadir-pointing data will
be used in these datasets (RDR activity flag = 110: on moon, standard nadir).
The thermal channel data was further constrained to brightness temperature
values of 10 to 450 K as anything outside this range contains bad data.
Observations with excessive noise were also culled.  The finite field
of view of the Diviner footprints will be taken into account to produce the
master maps, which will avoid resolution aliasing problems at higher
latitudes.  All footprints will be projected by locating the fields of
view in three dimensions onto a LOLA 128 ppd digital elevation
model of the Moon.
 
In addition to the 128 ppd master resolution maps, a series of
lower-resolution maps will also be produced, for both cylindrical and
polar projections, at 64, 16, 4, and 1 ppd resolution.
This last resolution value produces global lon/lat maps during the LRO
primary mission with minimal low-latitude gores.
 
Level 3 GDR
 
NASA Level 3 Diviner GDR products include Christiansen Feature (CF)
position, Rock Abundance, Soil Temperature, and Root Mean Square (RMS)
fitting errors between measured and modeled radiances..
 
The CF position is the wavelength of a major mid-infrared emissivity
peak near 8-microns.  It is a measure of silicate composition and
shifts to shorter wavelengths for feldspathic lithologies
(e.g. highlands) and longer wavelengths for mafic lithologies
(e.g. maria).  The CF position is also correlated with geochemical
composition (generally shorter CF position for higher Si, Na, Ca
and longer for higher Fe, Mg).  The CF position is calculated from
Diviner channels 3, 4, and 5 radiances.  Each radiance is binned and
averaged and then converted to brightness temperature.  The three
point brightness temperature spectrum is solved quadratically to
determine the maximum brightness temperature.  Emissivity values are
then calculated for channels 3, 4, and 5.  The emissivity spectrum is
solved quadratically to determine the CF position.
 
Two types of CF maps will be created:
 
(1) Standard CF: CF calculated using a quadratic fit to the three
8-micron channels to determine the wavelength location of the
emissivity peak.  This map will include the best TOD data available
for each longitude.
 
(2) Normalized to Equatorial Noon (NEN) CF: Standard CF
normalized to equatorial noon by the &apos;best effort&apos; of the
Diviner science team.
 
Rock Abundance and Soil Temperature are derived from nighttime
Diviner Channel 6, 7, and 8 observations.  The maps were derived
by fitting the measured radiances to a two-component model that
assumes that the observed scene consists of an unknown mixture of
soil and rock. The temperature of the rock component taken from
thermal model results assumes a semi-infinite rock thermal inertia
of 1000 (MKS units) and the rock fractional coverage and the soil
temperature are fitted parameters.
 
RMS fitting errors are with respect to measured and modeled Diviner
radiance in channels 6, 7, and 8 using the rock abundance and soil
temperature determination technique described in
Bandfield et al. (2011).
 
For CF and NEN_CF, a single map for each will be produced. For
Rock Abundance, Soil Temperature, and RMS fitting error,
ten lunar-hourly maps spanning the local time range of
19:30 to 5:30 will be produced.  There will also be a single
map averaging all hours together for Rock Abundance, Soil Temperature,
and Soil Temperature Normalized to Remove Latitudinal Dependencies
(STN).  All maps will be simple cylindrical projections covering the
latitude range -60 to 60 degrees at 32 ppd resolution.
 
 
Data Processing Level
=====================
 
The Diviner GDR data products are derived directly from the
Diviner Reduced Data Record (RDR) data products.
GDRs are CODMAC Level 5 (NASA Level 4).
 
 
Data Product Generation
=======================
 
The Diviner GDR data products and labels are generated by the
Diviner Science Team at UCLA.
 
Data Flow
=========
 
The Diviner GDRs will be made available via a data release
on March 15, 2011, six months after the end of the first year
of mapping orbit.
 
For more information please see the document DP_SIS.HTM
(HTML format) or DP_SIS.PDF (Adobe Acrobat format) located
in the DOCUMENT directory of this archive.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
Review
======
 
This archival data set was examined by a peer review panel prior to
its acceptance by the Planetary Data System (PDS). The peer review
was conducted in accordance with PDS procedures.
 
Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data set,
key elements of the archive were distributed for preliminary
review.  These included electronic versions of example PDS labels,
CATALOG files, and Software Interface Specifications (SISs).
These materials were distributed to PDS personnel, the experiment
investigator, and others, as appropriate.
 
Data Coverage and Quality
=========================
 
See the section &apos;Data Coverage and Quality&apos; in RDRDS.CAT.
 
Limitations
===========
 
Data seen immediately after the instrument is powered on or after
a restart is suspect for a few seconds to a few minutes.  The pointing
information is typically incorrect or missing.
 
Known Issues
============
 
None.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>IN_QUEUE</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

