<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ear-a-compil-5-binmp-v2.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>BINARY MINOR PLANETS V2.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.support_archives::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.publit::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:compil.publit::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.asteroid::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-a-compil-5-binmp-v2.0__browserp_ear-a-compil-5-binmp-v2.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Descamps, P., and F. Marchis, Angular momentum of binary asteroids:
                   Implications for their possible origin, Icarus, 193,74-84, 2008
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DESCAMPS-MARCHIS2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Merline, W.J., S.J. Weidenschilling, D.D. Durda, J.-L. Margot, P. Pravec, and
                   A.D. Storrs, Asteroids do have Satellites, in Asteroids III, W. F. Bottke Jr.,
                   A. Cellino, P. Paolicchi, and R. P. Binzel (eds.), Univ. of Arizona Press,
                   Tucson, 289-312, 2003.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MERLINEETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Noll, K.S., Solar system binaries, in Asteroids, Comets, Meteors, Proceedings
                   of the 229th Symposium of the International Astronomical Union, L. Daniela et
                   al. (eds.), Cambridge Univ. Press, Cambridge, 301-318, 2006.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NOLL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Noll, K.S., W.M. Grundy, E.I. Chiang, J.-L. Margot, and S.D. Kern, Binaries in
                   the Kuiper Belt, in The Solar System Beyond Neptune, M. A. Barucci, H.
                   Boehnhardt, D. P. Cruikshank, and A. Morbidelli (eds.), Univ. of Arizona Press,
                   Tucson, 345-363, 2008.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NOLLETAL2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Pravec, P., and A.W. Harris, Binary asteroid population: 1. Angular momentum
                   content, Icarus, 190, 250-259, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PRAVEC-HARRIS2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Pravec, P., P. Scheirich, P. Kusnirak, L. Sarounova, S. Mottola, and 52 others,
                   Photometric survey of binary near-Earth asteroids, Icarus 181, 63-69, 2006.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PRAVECETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Richardson, D.C., Walsh, K.J. 2006. Binary minor planets, Annu. Rev. Earth
                   Planet. Sci. 34, 47-81, 2006.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.RICHARDSON-WALSH2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>EAR-A-COMPIL-5-BINMP-V2.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>BINARY MINOR PLANETS V2.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2009-06-03</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1978-08-01</start_time>
        <stop_time>2009-05-01</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>KEVIN WALSH</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Johnston, W.R., Richardson, D.C., and Walsh, K.J., Binary Minor
            Planets V2.0. EAR-A-COMPIL-5-BINMP-V2.0. NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2009.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            A summary of binary minor planets with their properties, updated
            as of May 2009, compiled by Johnson, Richardson and Walsh.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            We present data tables giving basic orbital and physical
            parameters for well-observed or suspected binary/multiple minor
            planets and the Pluto system, based on a literature review. In
            total 173 companions in 165 systems are included. Listed data
            include: minor planet number, name, and provisional designation,
            dynamical type, and heliocentric semimajor axis and eccentricity;
            primary and secondary diameter; primary spin period and albedo;
            companion semimajor axis and orbital period; system mass and
            density; secondary designation; discovery method and year of
            announcement. This data set is complete for binary/multiple
            components reported through 10 March 2009, with some additional
            data through 4 May 2009.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    OVERVIEW
 
  The data set lists orbital and physical properties for well-observed or
  suspected binary/multiple minor planets and the Pluto system, as inspired by
  Richardson and Walsh (2006) and similar reviews (Merline et al., 2003; Noll,
  2006; Pravec et al., 2006; Pravec and Harris, 2007; Descamps and Marchis,
  2008; Noll et al., 2008).  In total 173 companions in 165 systems are
  included.  Data are presented in two tables, one for orbital and physical
  properties and one for companion designations, discovery information, and
  reference codes for data values.  Data are ordered by asteroid number, then
  provisional designation.  This data set is complete for binary/multiple
  components reported through 10 March 2009, with some additional data through
  4 May 2009.
 
    ORBITAL/PHYSICAL PROPERTIES TABLE
 
  The first table (binarytable2) lists orbital and physical properties of
  binary/multiple minor planets, with the following data:
 
    * minor planet number, name, and provisional designation;
    * minor planet dynamical type (from Minor Planet Center classifications);
    * minor planet heliocentric semimajor axis (AU) and eccentricity;
    * primary diameter (km) with uncertainty and note code;
    * primary spin period (h) with uncertainty and note code;
    * companion semimajor axis (km) with uncertainty and note code;
    * companion diameter (km) with uncertainty and note code;
    * companion orbital period (d) with uncertainty and note code;
    * primary geometric albedo with uncertainty and note code;
    * system mass (kg) with uncertainty and note code;
    * and system density (g/cm^3) with uncertainty and note code.
 
  Dynamical type codes are as follows: AMO = Amor, APO = Apollo, ATE =
  Aten, MC = Mars crosser, MB = Main Belt asteroid, JL4 = Jupiter L4 Trojan,
  JL5 = Jupiter L5 Trojan, CUB = Cubewano, PLU = Plutino, 1:2 = Neptune 1:2
  resonance object, 2:5 = Neptune 2:5 resonance object,
  4:7 = Neptune 4:7 resonance object, SDO = scattered disk object, and
  TNO = other trans- Neptunian object.
 
 
    Note codes indicate comments on data values as follows:
         A = assumed value;
         D = derived from published measurements;
         E = estimated based on assumed values;
         G = greater than;
         H = (for spin period) spin period of one-half the stated value also
  possible;
         L = less than;
         Q = (for spin period) multiple periods exist, with association of
  period with primary inconclusive;
         R = (for primary geometric albedo) red albedo;
         S = (for binary semimajor axis) projected separation distance.
 
  Dashes or invalid inputs (usually -9.99) indicate unassigned or unknown
  values.  Unmeasured primary diameters are estimated based on JPL-reported
  absolute magnitude values (H) generally assuming albedos of 0.16 for
  NEAs/main belt asteroids or 0.09 for trans-Neptunian objects.  Some
  secondary diameters are derived from measured ratios of companion diameter
  to primary diameter, or from the magnitude difference between components
  assuming equal albedos.  For some objects with unknown binary semimajor axis
  values, the projected separation distance is provided.  Estimated values of
  semimajor axis and/or orbital period are order-of-magnitude figures only,
  based on assumed values of density and/or albedo and (in some cases)
  assuming the binary semimajor axis is the same as the projected separation.
  If unmeasured, system densities are assumed to be 1.6 g/cm^3 for NEAs/main
  belt asteroids or 1.0 g/cm^3 for trans-Neptunian objects.  Regarding
  uncertainties on measured values, readers are referred to the respective
  references.
 
 
    COMPANION DESIGNATIONS/DISCOVERY INFORMATION/REFERENCES TABLE
 
  The second table (binaryothref2) includes companion designations (either
  permanent or provisional), discovery information, and reference codes for
  for data values listed in the orbital and physical properties table, as
  follows:
 
    * minor planet number, name, and provisional designation;
    * code for discovery detection method;
    * year of announcement of the discovery;
    * and reference codes.
 
  Discovery method codes are as follows:  A = adaptive optics telescope
  imaging, C = combined radar/lightcurve observations, H = Hubble Space
  Telescope imaging, I = imaging, other or unspecified, L = photometric
  lightcurve observations, R = radar observations, S = spacecraft imaging.
  Reference codes are given for each orbital or physical property value, with
  codes referring to complete references listed in a separate file. Dashes or
  spaces indicate unassigned values.
 
 
    MODIFICATION HISTORY
 
  Differences between the current database version and the previous
  version (2006) are:
 
    * The current version includes data on 173 components in 165 systems, or
  113 more components and 105 more systems than the previous release.  New or
  revised parameters are reported for 53 of the 60 binaries included in the
  previous release.
    * Entries are now provided for all components in systems with more than
  two components.
    * In addition to parameters listed in the previous release, the current
  release also includes data on geometric albedo, discovery method, date of
  discovery announcement, and secondary designation.
    * Dynamical types are more specific, differentiating types of NEOs,
  Jupiter Trojans, and KBOs.
    * Codes have been added for parameter values, indicating derived/assumed
  values and other notes.
    * If assumed values of density and/or albedo are used to estimate other
  parameters, the assumed values are listed with an appropriate note code.
    * References are identified for each parameter individually, rather than
  collectively for each object.
 
  ADDITIONAL INFORMATION
 
  This data set is intended to provide a quick overview of data on asteroids
  and trans-Neptunian objects with companions.  Readers should refer to the
  original works regarding cited data and for additional details.  Also, there
  currently exists a number of electronic databases on minor planets with more
  extensive information, some of which we note:
 
    * Johnston, W. R., Asteroids with Satellites
    [http://www.johnstonsarchive.net/astro/asteroidmoons.html].
    * Richardson, D. C., K. Walsh, N. Vogel, and D. Bettis, Minor Planet
  Satellite Database [http://borg.astro.umd.edu/~dwb/asteroid/].
    * Marchis, F., et al., Virtual Observatory Binary Asteroids Database
    [http://cilaos.berkeley.edu/PHP_scripts/VOBAD/VOBAD_portal.html].
    * Warner, B. D., A. W. Harris, and P. Pravec, Lightcurve Parameters
  [http://www.minorplanetobserver.com/astlc/LightcurveParameters.htm].
 
  The NASA Astrophysics Data System (ADS) was used in compiling the data
  presented.
 
 
    REFERENCES
 
    Descamps, P., and F. Marchis, 2008, Angular momentum of binary asteroids:
  Implications for their possible origin, Icarus, 193:74-84.
 
    Merline, W. J., S. J. Weidenschilling, D. D. Durda, J.-L. Margot, P.
  Pravec, and A. D. Storrs, 2003, Asteroids do have Satellites, in Asteroids
  III, W. F. Bottke Jr., A. Cellino, P. Paolicchi, and R. P. Binzel (eds.),
  Univ. of Arizona Press, Tucson, 289-312.
 
    Noll, K. S., 2006, Solar system binaries, in Asteroids, Comets, Meteors,
  Proceedings of the 229th Symposium of the International Astronomical Union,
  L. Daniela et al. (eds.), Cambridge Univ. Press, Cambridge, 301-318.
 
    Noll, K. S., W. M. Grundy, E. I. Chiang, J.-L. Margot, and S. D. Kern,
  2008, Binaries in the Kuiper Belt, in The Solar System Beyond Neptune, M. A.
  Barucci, H. Boehnhardt, D. P. Cruikshank, and A. Morbidelli (eds.), Univ. of
  Arizona Press, Tucson, 345-363.
 
    Pravec, P., and A. W. Harris, 2007, Binary asteroid population: 1. Angular
  momentum content, Icarus, 190:250-259.
 
    Pravec, P., et al., 2006, Photometric survey of binary near-Earth
  asteroids, Icarus, 181:63-93.
 
    Richardson, D. C., and K. J. Walsh, 2006, Binary minor planets, Annu. Rev.
  Earth Planet. Sci., 34:47-81.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The Astrophysics Data System (ADS) was used to collect the data presented
    in the table.  Users are referred to the individual papers in the
    ancillary document for the confidence level of each item.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SUPERSEDED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

