<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.hay-a-spice-6-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>HAYABUSA SPICE KERNELS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.hayabusa::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.hay::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.hay::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.25143_itokawa::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.hay-a-spice-6-v1.0__browserp_hay-a-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.hay-a-spice-6-v1.0__browser_hay-a-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.hay-a-spice-6-v1.0__browser_wgc_hay-a-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.naif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>HAY-A-SPICE-6-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>HAYABUSA SPICE KERNELS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2009-12-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2005-09-11T05:51:38Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2005-11-19T23:54:03Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>BORIS V. SEMENOV</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Semenov, B.V., N. Hirata, R. Nakamura, Y. Yamamoto, O.S.
            Barnouin-Jha, D.K. Yeomans, and C.H. Acton, HAYABUSA SPICE
            KERNELS V1.0, HAY-A-SPICE-6-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2009.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Navigation and ancillary data in the form of SPICE System kernel
            files for the Hayabusa mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set includes the complete set of Hayabusa SPICE data
            files (``kernel files&apos;&apos;) for the surveying and
            collection phases of the mission. The SPICE data files, which can
            be accessed using SPICE software, contain geometric and other
            ancillary information needed to recover the full value of the
            science instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide
            spacecraft and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting
            alignments, spacecraft orientation, spacecraft sequences of
            events, and data needed for relevant time conversions.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
 
      This data set includes the complete set of Hayabusa SPICE data
      files (``kernel files&apos;&apos;) for the surveying and collection phase
      of the mission. The SPICE data files, which can be accessed using
      SPICE software, contain geometric and other ancillary information
      needed to recover the full value of the science instrument data.
      In particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft and planetary
      ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments, spacecraft
      orientation, spacecraft sequences of events, and data needed for
      relevant time conversions.
 
 
      Data Types (SPICE kernel types)
      ===============================
 
      SPK kernels contain ephemerides for spacecraft, planets,
      satellites, comets and asteroids as well as for moving or fixed
      spacecraft and instrument structures. They provide position and
      velocity, given in a Cartesian reference frame. SPK files are
      located under the ``data/spk&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      PCK kernels contain certain physical, dynamical and
      cartographic constants for target bodies, such as size and shape
      specifications, and the orientation of the spin axis and prime
      meridian. PCK files are located under the ``data/pck&apos;&apos; directory
      of this data set.
 
      IK kernels (Instrument description kernels) give descriptive and
      operational data peculiar to a particular scientific instrument,
      such as internal timing relative to the spacecraft clock and
      field-of-view model parameters. IK files are located under the
      ``data/ik&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      CK kernels describe pointing, containing a transformation
      traditionally called the C-matrix which is used to determine
      time-tagged pointing (orientation) angles for a spacecraft
      structure upon which science instruments are mounted. CK files
      are located under the ``data/ck&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      EK (Events) kernels are derived from the integrated sequence of
      events used to produce actual spacecraft commands. In some cases
      EK files are used to storing database-type information such as
      parameter value tables, triangular shape model data, etc. EK
      files are located under the ``data/ek&apos;&apos; directory of this data
      set.
 
      LSK (Leapseconds) kernels contain the leapseconds and the values
      of other constants required to perform a transformation between
      Universal Time Coordinated (UTC) and Ephemeris time (ET). LSK
      files are located under the ``data/lsk&apos;&apos; directory of this data
      set.
 
      SCLK (Spacecraft Clock) kernels contain on-board clock calibration
      data required to perform a mapping between Ephemeris time (ET)
      and spacecraft on-board time (SCLK.) SCLK files are located under
      the ``data/sclk&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      FK (Frame Definitions) kernels contain information required to
      define reference frames, sources of frame orientation data and
      inter-connections between these frames and other frames supported
      within the SPICE system. This includes mounting alignment
      information for each instrument. FK files are located under
      the ``data/fk&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
 
      Kernel File Details
      ===================
 
      A brief overview of the different types of Hayabusa kernels included
      in this data set is provided in the CONFIDENCE_LEVEL_NOTE section
      of this file while details specific to individual files are found
      in the ``*info.txt&apos;&apos; files in the corresponding data directory.
      The most detailed description of the data in each file is
      provided in metadata included inside the file -- in the
      description area of text kernels or in the comment area of binary
      kernels.
 
 
      Software
      ========
 
      The SPICE Toolkit contains software modules needed to read
      SPICE kernel files. SPICELIB software is highly documented
      via internal headers. Additional documentation is available
      in separate ASCII text files called Required Reading files.
      For example, the S- and P- Kernel (SPK) Required Reading File,
      named SPK.REQ, describes use of the SPK kernel file readers
      and contains sample programs.
 
      The latest SPICE Toolkit for a variety of computer platforms such
      as PC, Mac, SUN, etc. is available at the NAIF Node of PDS
      electronically (via anonymous FTP and WWW servers). Refer to
      information in ``software/softinfo.txt&apos;&apos; for details regarding
      obtaining this software. Each version of the Toolkit is also
      archived at the NASA National Space Science Data Center.
 
 
      Loading Kernel Files into a SPICE-based Application
      ===================================================
 
      The easiest way to make data from a collection of SPICE kernels
      available to a SPICE-based application is to list these kernels
      in a meta-kernel and load it into the program using the high
      level SPICE data loader routine FURNSH. This data set provides
      such meta-kernel(s) under the ``extras/mk&apos;&apos; directory. For more
      information about the Hayabusa meta-kernel(s), see the file
      ``extras/mk/mkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      This data set contains SPICE kernel files created during mission
      operations and post mission data reconstruction and analysis.
      Some general information about this collection follows here, but
      the prospective user is also referred to extensive descriptions
      (metadata) about each file that are stored inside each kernel
      file. Those metadata provide detailed information regarding the
      information source from which the data were derived, the type of
      processing applied to the source data, applicability of the data,
      etc. Metadata are located in the ``comment area&apos;&apos; for binary
      kernel types (SPK, CK, DBK), accessible using either the COMMNT
      or SPACIT utility program found in the NAIF Toolkit. Metadata are
      located after ``\begintext&apos;&apos; markers within the text kernel types
      (PCK, IK, FK, LSK, SCLK), accessible by using any available text
      file display tool such as a word processor, text editor, or the
      unix ``more&apos;&apos; or ``cat&apos;&apos; commands.
 
      In some cases data accuracy information does not exist because
      it could not be estimated even after mission completion.
 
      Where there are questions about data accuracy or ``confidence&apos;&apos;
      not addressed herein the reader is invited to examine subsequent
      SPICE archive releases associated with this data set (if such
      exist), or to contact the NAIF node of the Planetary Data System
      for possible further information.
 
 
      SPK Files
      =========
 
      The SPK files included in this dataset provide reconstructed
      trajectory of the Hayabusa spacecraft, ephemeris data for the
      mission target asteroid Itokawa, Solar System planets, and the
      Sun.
 
      The spacecraft trajectory SPK files provided in this data set
      include SPKs created by the Hayabusa Joint Science Team (HJST),
      Dr. Olivier S. Barnouin-Jha, and NAIF.
 
      The HJST&apos;s set of spacecraft trajectory SPKs includes a few dozen
      short-coverage SPKs (``hayabusa_YYYYMMDD_YYYYMMDD_v01.bsp&apos;&apos;)
      produced during operations near the asteroid and one
      long-coverage SPK (``hayabusa_itokawarendezvous_v01.bsp&apos;&apos;)
      produced at the end of operations near the asteroid. These files
      were created by HJST using the Hayabusa position and velocity
      data relative to Itokawa determined by the spacecraft on-board
      software. The long-coverage SPK supersedes all short coverage
      SPKs.
 
      Dr. Barnouin-Jha&apos;s SPK (``hay_osbj_050911_051118_v1.bsp&apos;&apos;)
      was created from the Hayabusa position data determined by joint
      processing of LIDAR, WAC, and Itokawa shape data.
 
      In an attempt to resolve some of the issues found in both HJST&apos;s
      and Dr. Barnouin-Jha&apos;s SPKs at the time of the archive
      preparation NAIF created the ``touched-up&apos;&apos; versions of the
      long-coverage HJST&apos;s SPK and Dr. Barnouin-Jha&apos;s SPK. These SPKs
      are named ``hay_jaxa_050916_051119_v1n.bsp&apos;&apos; and
      ``hay_osbj_050911_051118_v1n.bsp&apos;&apos;. For more information about
      issues with the original SPKs and what was done to make the
      ``touched-up&apos;&apos; SPKs see the ``hayspice.htm&apos;&apos; document provided
      under the ``document&apos;&apos; directory of the data set.
 
      The asteroid Itokawa ephemeris SPK files provided in this data
      set include two files created by JPL&apos;s Solar System Dynamics
      (SSD) group. The first SPK, ``sb_25143_140.bsp&apos;&apos;, was officially
      delivered to the project by SSD three months before the start of
      operations near Itokawa. The second SPK,
      ``itokawa_1989_2010.bsp&apos;&apos;, was created by HJST using SSD&apos;s
      HORIZONS service during operations near Itokawa. Although both
      files were created using the same initial conditions and models,
      the asteroid ephemerides provided by them differ by about a
      hundred meters, which is less than 2% of the 6.9 km 1-sigma
      formal uncertainty of the initial conditions. This difference was
      introduced in the second SPK due to integrating over a longer
      time-span (1989-2010).
 
      The planetary ephemeris SPK file included in this data set
      (``de403s.bsp&apos;&apos;) is the DE-403 ephemeris used to integrate the
      Itokawa trajectory provided in the Itokawa SPKs.
 
      Additional information about SPK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/spk/spkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      CK Files
      ========
 
      The CK files included in this dataset provide the orientation of
      the Hayabusa spacecraft bus. All these CK files were produced
      from engineering telemetry downlinked from the spacecraft. As is
      often the case with spacecraft engineering telemetry-based
      measurements, considerable uncertainty exists as to the accuracy
      of such measurements, and, data quality (accuracy and
      completeness) can vary significantly.
 
      The spacecraft orientation CK files provided in this data set
      include CKs created by HJST and NAIF.
 
      The HJST&apos;s set of spacecraft orientation CKs includes a few dozen
      short-coverage CKs (``hayabusa_YYYYMMDD_YYYYMMDD_v01.bc&apos;&apos;)
      produced during operations near the asteroid and two
      long-coverage CKs (``hayabusa_itokawarendezvous_v01.bc&apos;&apos; and
      ``hayabusa_itokawarendezvous_v02.bc&apos;&apos;) produced at the end of
      operations near the asteroid. These files were created from the
      Hayabusa orientation determined by the spacecraft&apos;s on-board
      software. The ``v02&apos;&apos; long-coverage CK supersedes all short
      coverage CKs and the ``v01&apos;&apos; long-coverage CK.
 
      In an attempt to resolve some of the issues found in HJST&apos;s CKs
      at the time of the archive preparation NAIF created the
      ``touched-up&apos;&apos; version of the ``v02&apos;&apos; CK. This CK is named
      ``hayabusa_itokawarendezvous_v02n.bc&apos;&apos;. For more information
      about issues with the original CKs and what was done to make the
      ``touched-up&apos;&apos; CK see the ``hayspice.htm&apos;&apos; document provided
      under the ``document&apos;&apos; directory of the data set.
 
      Additional information about CK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/ck/ckinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      PCK Files
      =========
 
      The PCK files included in this data set provide size, shape and
      orientation data for the mission target, asteroid Itokawa, and
      for the Solar System planets and satellites. A description of
      these data items and reference to their source is provided inside
      the PCK files, which are simple text files that can be viewed
      using any word processor, text editor or text display utility.
 
      The Itokawa PCK files provided in this data set include a PCK
      file with Itokawa rotation constants derived by the Hayabusa
      Team of University of Aizu (``itokawa_aizu504.tpc&apos;&apos;) and and two
      PCK files with the Itokawa rotation constants derived by Dr.
      Robert W. Gaskell, Planetary Science Institute (PSI)
      (``itokawa_gaskell.tpc&apos;&apos; and ``itokawa_gaskell_n3.tpc&apos;&apos;). The
      Aizu PCK and the first Gaskell PCK are consistent with the
      Itokawa shape models stored in the EK files included in this data
      set. The second Gaskell&apos;s PCK (``_n3&apos;&apos;) is consistent with the
      Itokawa shape models archived in the PDS data set
      HAY-A-AMICA-5-ITOKAWASHAPE-V1.0.
 
      The generic PCK file (``pck00008.tpc&apos;&apos;) provided in this data set
      contains constants for the Solar System planets and satellites
      taken from the official IAU/IAG/COSPAR report published in 2000.
 
      Additional information about PCK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/pck/pckinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      FK Files
      ========
 
      The FK files included in this data set provide definitions for
      the Hayabusa spacecraft frames, mission-specific dynamic frames,
      and the asteroid Itokawa body-fixed frame. Comments in the FK
      files provide the frame specifications, descriptions of the frame
      relationships, the source of and accuracy of the mounting
      alignment information, etc.
 
      The ``hayabusa_hp.tf&apos;&apos; FK defines the Hayabusa spacecraft frame
      and the dynamic frame used as the reference in the HJST-produced
      SPKs, as well as a few other dynamic frames intended to represent
      the nominal pointing of the spacecraft for different attitude
      modes. For historic reasons the Hayabusa instrument frame
      definitions are not provided in this FK file; instead all frames
      defined for a given instrument are included in the IK file for
      that instrument.
 
      The ``itokawa_fixed.tf&apos;&apos; FK defines the body-fixed frame for
      asteroid Itokawa.
 
      Both FK files were created by HJST.
 
      Additional information about FK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/fk/fkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      IK Files
      ========
 
      The IK files included in this data set provide specifications for
      the optical and physical instrument parameters and -- where
      applicable -- field-of-view size, shape and orientation for the
      Hayabusa instruments. In addition to these parameters, for
      historic reasons, the Hayabusa IK files also contain the
      instrument frame definitions that are normally found in the FK
      files. Each IK file contains comments providing descriptions of
      the included parameters and FOV and frame specifications.
 
      All IK files provided in the data set were created by HJST. There
      is one IK for each instrument (``amica31.ti&apos;&apos;, ``nirs10.ti&apos;&apos;,
      ``xrs10.ti&apos;&apos;) except for LIDAR, for which there are two IK files
      (``lidar10.ti&apos;&apos;, defining a 0.1 by 0.1 degrees FOV, and
      ``lidar_v1.ti&apos;&apos;, defining a 0.0566 by 0.0566 degree FOV).
 
      Additional information about IK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/ik/ikinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      SCLK Files
      ==========
 
      The SCLK file included in this data set provides a tabulation of
      data needed to convert time measurements between ephemeris time
      (ET) and Hayabusa spacecraft clock time (SCLK). This file was
      created by HJST and is named ``hayabusa.tsc&apos;&apos;. The accuracy of
      and issues with the correlation provided by this file are
      discussed in the ``hayspice.htm&apos;&apos; document provided under the
      ``document&apos;&apos; directory of the data set.
 
      Additional information about SCLK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/sclk/sclkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      LSK Files
      =========
 
      The LSK file included in this data set provides the most current
      tabulation of ``leapseconds&apos;&apos; and other terms used in converting
      time measurements between ephemeris time (ET) and Universal Time
      (UTC) at the time when this data set was assembled (October
      2009).
 
      Metadata describing how the LSK data are obtained or computed is
      contained inside the LSK text file. The time conversion provided
      by SPICE LSK files is accurate to approximately 0.000030 seconds.
 
      Additional information about LSK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/lsk/lskinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      EK Files
      ========
 
      The EK files included in this data set provide tessellated
      triangular plate data describing the shape of the asteroid
      Itokawa. These files store plate data in the format used by the
      SPICE PLATELIB package informally provided by NAIF to a number of
      customers, including HJST, between 1997 and 2005. While NAIF
      discontinued support for this package in 2006, the basic data
      stored in the file -- vertex coordinates and plate-vertex
      associations -- can still be accessed via either SPICE EK APIs or
      using the INSPEKT utility program.
 
      This data set includes two plate model EK files:
      ``itokawa_aizu504.bdb&apos;&apos; containing data derived by the Hayabusa
      Team of University of Aizu and ``itokawa_gaskell070104.bdb&apos;&apos;
      containing data derived by Dr. Robert W. Gaskell, PSI. Both files
      were created by HJST; the Aizu EK providing lower resolution data
      was created at the end of operations near Itokawa while Gaskell&apos;s
      file providing higher resolution data was created in 2007.
 
      Additional information about EK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/ek/ekinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      Kernel Files Obtained from ISAS/JAXA Hayabusa Archive
      =====================================================
 
      Most kernels included in the archive were copied from the
      Hayabusa Project Science Data Archive Information System
      (http://hayabusa.sci.isas.jaxa.jp). Some of the kernels had names
      that were not PDS-compliant and/or consistent with the naming
      conventions used in other SPICE archives; these kernels were
      renamed before inclusion in the archive as shown in this table:
 
        Original Name                       Name in the Archived Data Set
        ---------------------------------   -----------------------------
        hayabusa_YYYYMMDD_YYYYMMDD_v01.bc   -
        hayabusa_itokawarendezvous_v01.bc   -
        itokawa_aizu504.bpl                 itokawa_aizu504.bdb
        itokawa_gaskell070104.bpl           itokawa_gaskell070104.bdb
        HAYABUSA_HP.TF                      hayabusa_hp.tf
        itokawa_fixed.tf                    -
        amica30.ti                          -
        lidar10.ti                          -
        nirs10.ti                           -
        xrs10.ti                            -
        itokawa_aizu504.tpc                 -
        itokawa_gaskell.tpc                 -
        hayabusa.tsc                        -
        hayabusa_YYYYMMDD_YYYYMMDD_v01.bsp  -
        hayabusa_itokawarendezvous_v01.bsp  -
        itokawa_1989-2010.bsp               itokawa_1989_2010.bsp
 
      (A ``-&apos;&apos; in the right column means that the file was archived
      with its original name. YYYYMMDD in the daily CK and SPK files
      names stands for the coverage begin and end dates.)
 
 
      Kernel Files Provided by Dr. Olivier S. Barnouin-Jha
      ====================================================
 
      Four kernels included in the archive were provided by Dr. Olivier
      S. Barnouin-Jha. Some of these kernels had non PDS-compliant
      names and had to be renamed before inclusion in the archive. This
      table lists the original and new file names:
 
        Original Name              Name in the Archived Data Set
        ------------------------   ---------------------------------
        lidar_v1.ti                -
        Sept-Nov_SPK.bsp           hay_osbj_050911_051118_v1.bsp
        Itokawa_Gaskell_n3.tpc     itokawa_gaskell_n3.tpc
        20050902-20051126_att.bc   hayabusa_itokawarendezvous_v02.bc
 
      (A ``-&apos;&apos; in the right column means that the file was archived
      with its original name.)
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

