<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.hay-a-nirs-3-nirscal-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>HAYABUSA NIRS CALIBRATED SPECTRA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.hayabusa::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.hay::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:nirs.hay::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.25143_itokawa::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.asteroid::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.hay-a-nirs-3-nirscal-v1.0__browserp_hay-a-nirs-3-nirscal-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kitazato, K., B.E. Clark, M. Abe, S. Abe, Y. Takagi, T. Hiroi, O.S.
                   Barnouin-Jha, P.A. Abell, S.M. Lederer, F. Vilas, Near-infrared
                   spectrophotometry of Asteroid 25143 ltokawa from NIRS on the Hayabusa
                   spacecraft, Icarus 194, 137-145, 2008.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KITAZATOETAL2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>HAY-A-NIRS-3-NIRSCAL-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>HAYABUSA NIRS CALIBRATED SPECTRA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2010-06-07</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2005-08-31</start_time>
        <stop_time>2005-11-24</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>CAROL NEESE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Abe, M., Takagi, Y., Abe, S., and Kitazato, K., Hayabusa NIRS
            Calibrated Spectra V1.0. HAY-A-NIRS-3-NIRSCAL-V1.0. NASA
            Planetary Data System, 2011.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Hayabusa NIRS calibrated spectra including all Itokawa spectra
            taken by the mission, from Aug. 31 through Nov. 24, 2005.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set includes the 111,226 calibrated spectra of asteroid
            25143 Itokawa returned by the Near-Infrared Spectrometer (NIRS)
            instrument of the Hayabusa mission. The data cover the Itokawa
            encounter phases of the mission, from Aug. 31 through November
            24, 2005.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The Hayabusa spacecraft launched on May 9, 2003, performed an Earth flyby
    on May 19, 2004, and reached the asteroid 25143 Itokawa in September 2005,
    spending September through November 2005 at the asteroid.  During the
    mission the Hayabusa Near-Infrared Spectrometer (NIRS) returned 117,937
    spectra, including over 80,000 of the asteroid Itokawa.  This data set
    contains the calibrated spectra of Itokawa, including 111,226 spectra.
    For the NIRS raw spectra, see the PDS data set HAY-A-NIRS-2-NIRSRAW-V1.0.
 
    For 83,320 of the spectra, the data labels include the footprint
    coordinates indicating by asteroid latitude and longitude the specific
    area on the asteroid surface covered by each spectrum. The footprint
    information, illumination angles, and range for each of these spectra are
    also collected in a parameter table.
 
    NIRS is a grating infrared spectrometer  with a 64-element
    indium-gallium-arsenide  (InGaAs) linear detector array that covers the
    wavelength range of 750 - 2250 nm in increments of 24 nm.  NIRS carries
    two types of onboard calibration targets, an incandescent halogen lamp and
    a light-emitting diode (LED).  The basic unit of spectral data for the raw
    NIRS spectra is the digital number (DN), showing the integrated photon
    counts during a time-exposure interval.  The raw data are originally
    sampled with 14 bits per channel (0 - 16383 DNs).  A DN has a value of
    approximately 0.565 mV output from the detector preamplifiers when at a
    gain of 1.08.
 
    NIRS data are taken by stacking a number of sequential sets of light and
    dark frames at a single spectral measurement.  Dark subtraction and data
    averaging are carried out with the on-board software, and only the
    dark-subtracted average, standard deviation, minimum, and maximum values
    for each channel are returned via telemetry.  These are included in the
    FITS spectral tables as four separate columns within a single FITS file.
    The number of stacked frames is indicated by the STACK_COUNT keyword in
    the data labels, and also by the keyword STACK in the FITS header.
    STACK_COUNT, the number of stacked frames, is equal to two to the power of
    STACK.
 
    For further information about the NIRS instrument and its  calibration,
    see Abe et al. (Unpublished). For a complete description of the processing
    of the calibrated spectra, see Kitazato et al. (2008).
 
    Data Organization and File Naming
    =================================
 
    Within the data/spectra directory, the data are organized into directories
    by mission phase (Approach, Gatepoint, Home Position, and Touchdown).  In
    addition there are two calibration directories.  Within these directories,
    the data files are in subdirectories by date.  The filenames follow the
    convention nnnnnnnnnn_lvl3_0.fit, where nnnnnnnnnn is the spacecraft time
    of the image, and lvl3 indicates calibrated data with footprint
    information.
 
    The NIRS calibration procedure uses the ASCII table files
    (nirs_vol2rad_pls.tab for point light source and nirs_vol2rad_als.tab for
    area light source) to convert from raw NIRS output (Voltage) to radiance
    and the file nirs_solar_spc.tab to convert to I/F.  These files are
    located in the data/calib directory.
 
    References
    ==========
 
    Abe, M., Y. Takagi, S. Abe, and K. Kitazato, Instrument calibration of the
    Hayabusa near-infrared spectrometer, Unpublished. (Included in the
    document directory of this data set.)
 
    Kitazato, K., B.E. Clark, M. Abe, S. Abe, Y. Takagi, T. Hiroi, O.S.
    Barnouin-Jha, P.A. Abell, S.M. Lederer, and F. Vilas, Near-infrared
    spectrophotometry of asteroid 25143 Itokawa from NIRS on the  Hayabusa
    spacecraft, Icarus 194, 137-145, 2008.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The highest quality spectra in this data set are those taken during the
    Gate Position phase of September 12-29, 2005, in which the accuracy of the
    NIRS footprint estimate is relatively high.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

