<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dawn-m-a-spice-6-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DAWN SPICE KERNELS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.dawn_mission_to_vesta_and_ceres::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.1_ceres::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.4_vesta::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dawn-m-a-spice-6-v1.0__browserp_dawn-m-a-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dawn-m-a-spice-6-v1.0__browser_dawn-m-a-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dawn-m-a-spice-6-v1.0__browser_wgc_dawn-m-a-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.naif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Acton, C.H., The SPICE System - A Brief Overview, Navigation and Ancillary
                   Information Facility, JPL, 1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ACTON1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DAWN-M/A-SPICE-6-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DAWN SPICE KERNELS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2012-09-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2007-09-27T12:40:49.832Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2012-09-13T07:58:52.817Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>SAMANTHA C. KRENING</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Krening, S.C., B.V. Semenov, and C.H. Acton, DAWN SPICE KERNELS
            V1.0, DAWN-M/A-SPICE-6-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2012.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Navigation and ancillary data in the form of SPICE System kernel
            files for the DAWN spacecraft.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set includes the complete set of DAWN SPICE data files
            (``kernel files&apos;&apos;), which can be accessed using SPICE
            software. The SPICE data contain geometric and other ancillary
            information needed to recover the full value of science
            instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft
            and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments,
            spacecraft orientation, and data needed for relevant time
            conversions.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
 
      This data set includes the complete set of DAWN SPICE data files
      (``kernel files&apos;&apos;), which can be accessed using SPICE software.
      The SPICE data contain geometric and other ancillary information
      needed to recover the full value of science instrument data. In
      particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft and planetary
      ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments, spacecraft
      orientation, and data needed for relevant time conversions.
 
      This data set is contained on a single virtual volume,
      DAWNSP_1000, including data from all mission phases and covering
      from launch, 2007-09-27T12:40:49.832, through the end time of the
      latest spacecraft trajectory file supplied in the data set. Until
      the end of the spacecraft lifespan this data set is accumulating
      with new data added approximately every three to six months.
 
      Data Types (SPICE kernel types)
      ===============================
 
      SPK kernels contain ephemerides for spacecraft, planets,
      satellites, comets and asteroids as well as for moving or fixed
      spacecraft and instrument structures. They provide position and
      velocity, given in a Cartesian reference frame. SPK files are
      located under the ``data/spk&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      PCK kernels contain certain physical, dynamical and cartographic
      constants for target bodies, such as size and shape
      specifications, and orientation of the spin axis and prime
      meridian. PCK files are located under the ``data/pck&apos;&apos; directory
      of this data set.
 
      IK kernels (Instrument description kernels) give descriptive and
      operational data peculiar to a particular scientific instrument,
      such as internal timing relative to the spacecraft clock and
      field-of-view model parameters. IK files are located under the
      ``data/ik&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      CK kernels describe pointing, containing a transformation
      traditionally called the C-matrix which is used to determine
      time-tagged pointing (orientation) angles for a spacecraft
      structure upon which science instruments are mounted. CK files
      are located under the ``data/ck&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      EK (Events) kernels are derived from the integrated sequence of
      events used to produce actual spacecraft commands. EK files are
      located under the ``data/ek&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      LSK (Leapseconds) kernels contain the leapseconds and the values
      of other constants required to perform a transformation between
      Universal Time Coordinated (UTC) and Ephemeris time (ET). LSK
      files are located under the ``data/lsk&apos;&apos; directory of this data
      set.
 
      SCLK (Spacecraft Clock) kernels contain on-board clock
      calibration data required to perform a mapping between Ephemeris
      time (ET) and spacecraft on-board time (SCLK). SCLK files are
      located under the ``data/sclk&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      FK (Frame Definitions) kernels contain information required to
      define reference frames, sources of frame orientation data and
      connections between these frames and other frames supported
      within the SPICE system. This includes mounting alignment
      information for each instrument. FK files are located under the
      ``data/fk&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
 
      Kernel File Details
      ===================
 
      A brief overview of the different types of DAWN kernels included
      in this data set is provided in the CONFIDENCE_LEVEL_NOTE section
      of this file while details specific to individual files are found
      in the ``*info.txt&apos;&apos; files in the corresponding data directory.
      The most detailed description of the data in each file is
      provided in metadata included inside the file -- in the
      description area of text kernels or in the comment area of binary
      kernels.
 
 
      Software
      ========
 
      The SPICE Toolkit contains software modules needed to read SPICE
      kernel files. SPICE software is highly documented via internal
      headers. Additional documentation is available in separate ASCII
      text files called Required Reading files. For example, the S- and
      P- Kernel (SPK) Required Reading File, named SPK.REQ, describes
      use of the SPK kernel file readers and contains sample programs.
 
      The latest SPICE Toolkit for a variety of computer platforms such
      as PC, Mac, SUN, etc. is available at the NAIF Node of PDS
      electronically (via anonymous FTP and WWW servers). Refer to
      information in ``software/softinfo.txt&apos;&apos; for details regarding
      obtaining this software. Each version of the Toolkit is also
      archived at the NASA National Space Science Data Center.
 
 
      Loading Kernel Files into a SPICE-based Application
      ===================================================
 
      The easiest way to make data from a collection of SPICE kernels
      available to a SPICE-based application is to list these kernels
      in a meta-kernel and load it into the program using the high
      level SPICE data loader routine FURNSH. This data set provides
      such meta-kernel(s) under the ``extras/mk&apos;&apos; directory. For more
      information about the DAWN meta-kernel(s), see the file
      ``extras/mk/mkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      This data set contains SPICE kernel files created during mission
      operations and after mission data reconstruction and analysis.
      Some general information about this collection follows here, but
      the prospective user is also referred to extensive descriptions
      about each file that are stored inside each kernel file. These
      metadata provide detailed information regarding the information
      source from which the data were derived, the type of processing
      applied to the source data, applicability of the data, etc.
      Metadata are located in the ``comment area&apos;&apos; for binary kernel
      types (SPK, CK, ESQ), accessible using either the COMMNT or
      SPACIT utility program found in the NAIF Toolkit. Metadata are
      located after ``\begintext&apos;&apos; markers within the text kernel types
      (PCK, IK, FK, LSK, SCLK, MK), accessible by using any available
      text file display tool such as a word processor, text editor, or
      the unix ``more&apos;&apos; or ``cat&apos;&apos; commands.
 
      Where there are questions about data accuracy or ``confidence&apos;&apos;
      not addressed herein the reader is invited to contact the NAIF
      node of the Planetary Data System for possible further
      information.
 
      SPK Files
      =========
 
      Three kinds of SPK files are provided in this archive: SPK files
      for the spacecraft orbit, SPK files for the Solar System planets
      and asteroids, and SPK files for the relative locations of
      selected spacecraft structures. Each kind of file is briefly
      described below; more information is available in the file
      ``data/spk/spkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
      The spacecraft orbit SPK files contain the reconstructed
      spacecraft trajectory determined by the DAWN Navigation (NAV)
      Team, JPL. The informal 1-sigma uncertainty for the DAWN
      spacecraft reconstruction during the Survey from 2011-08-02 to
      2011-08-31 was 700 m along track, 40 m radial, and 70 m
      crosstrack. During HAMO from 2011-09-28 to 2011-11-02, the
      informal 1-sigma estimate was 70 m along track, 7 m radial, and 8
      m crosstrack. During LAMO from 2011-12-10 to 2012-05-01, the
      informal 1-sigma uncertainty was 3 m in the along track, radial,
      and crosstrack directions.
 
      This data set also includes the orbit number files generated
      during the mission using the NAIF&apos;s ORBNUM utility program. These
      files are not SPICE kernels; for this reason they are provided in
      the ``extras/orbnum&apos;&apos; directory. For more information about the
      DAWN orbit number files, see the file
      ``extras/orbnum/orbinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
      The DE421 planetary ephemeris SPK file included in this data set
      contains ephemeris data for the Solar System planet barycenters,
      Sun, Mercury, Venus, Earth, Moon, and Mars. This version of
      ephemerides was officially used by the project during mission
      operations. The internal comments included this SPK file provide
      detailed accuracy information.
 
      The asteroid SPK files included in this data set contain
      ephemeris data for Vesta and Ceres. The informal 1-sigma
      uncertainty of the Vesta reconstruction from 2011-08-01 to
      2012-06-28 was 1.5 km in the along track and radial directions
      and 5.0 km in the crosstrack direction.
 
      The DAWN structures SPK file included in this archive provides
      relative locations of the High Gain Antenna (HGA) and Solar Array
      (SA) components. The data included in the file are based of the
      dimensions from the spacecraft engineering drawings.
 
 
      CK Files
      ========
 
      Three kinds of C-kernel files are provided in this archive: the
      spacecraft bus (SC) orientation CKs (reconstructed from TLM,
      reconstructed from image processing, and predicted), the solar
      array (SA) orientation CKs (reconstructed), and the VIR
      Spectrometer (VIR) orientation CKs (reconstructed). The
      reconstructed CK files were produced from engineering telemetry
      downlinked from the spacecraft. The predicted CKs included in
      this data set are intended to be used to fill gaps with nominal
      orientation by loading these predicted files simultaneously with
      (but with lower priority than) the reconstructed files.
 
      The reconstructed spacecraft bus (SC) CK files based on telemetry
      (TLM) were created by NAIF at JPL; the reconstructed SC CK files
      based on FC images were created by the FC Team at DLR; and the
      predicted spacecraft bus CK files were produced by the DAWN
      Spacecraft Team (SCT). The image-based and predicted SC CKs are
      included in the archive only for the periods when TLM-based SC
      CKs have gaps.
 
      The system pointing budget summary, in milliradians, from
      Orbital Sciences&apos; pre-launch analysis, provided by the DAWN ACS
      team as an indicator of the reconstructed TLM-based CK accuracy, is:
 
         -----------------  ----  ----  ----
                             X     Y     Z
         -----------------  ----  ----  ----
         FC Estimate        0.20  0.13  0.07
         FC Requirement     0.25  0.25  0.25
 
         VIR Estimate       0.21  0.14  0.08
         VIR Requirement    0.25  0.25  0.25
         -----------------  ----  ----  ----
 
      An informal, one-sigma accuracy estimate for the spacecraft bus
      attitude provided in the reconstructed CK files, reported by the
      DAWN OPNAV team based on the star field calibration data taken
      during approach to Vesta, is approximately 85 microradians.
 
      The reconstructed solar array (SA) CK files were created by NAIF
      at JPL.
 
      The reconstructed VIR Spectrometer CK files were created by the
      VIR Team at INAF.
 
      More information about DAWN CK files is available in the file
      ``data/ck/ckinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      PCK Files
      =========
 
      PCK files provide size, shape and orientation data for ``target&apos;&apos;
      bodies such as Vesta, Ceres, Mars, and Earth. A description of
      these data items and reference to their source is provided inside
      the PCK file, which is a simple text file that can be viewed
      using any word processor, text editor or text display utility.
 
      The set of Vesta PCK files provided in this data set includes the
      current PCK containing Vesta rotation constants for the ``Claudia
      Double-Prime&apos;&apos; coordinate system, which was used in products
      archived in the DAWN Vesta mission science data sets, and two
      obsolete PCKs containing Vesta rotation constants for the
      ``DAWN-Claudia&apos;&apos; and ``Claudia Prime&apos;&apos; coordinate systems used
      during project operations and for pre-peer-review archive
      deliveries. The two obsolete PCKs are superseded by the current
      PCK and are included in the data set only for the record.
 
      The generic PCK file included in this data set is based on the
      IAU/IAG/COSPAR values accepted in 2000. This PCK also provides
      Vesta rotation constants for the ``IAU-2000&apos;&apos; Vesta coordinate
      system, that are obsolete and superseded by the ``Claudia
      Double-Prime&apos;&apos; constants from the current Vesta PCK.
 
      The Ceres PCK file provided in this data set contains the best
      constants available in 2012; this is planned to be updated
      before arrival to Ceres.
 
      More information about the PCK files included in this data set is
      available in the file ``data/pck/pckinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      FK Files
      ========
 
      Frames kernel files provide specifications for how one reference
      frame is defined relative to another frame. The DAWN FK provided
      in this data set contains the complete set of frame definitions
      for the spacecraft, its structures such as solar array and
      antennas, and all of its science instruments. Meta information
      provided in the comments included in this file consists of the
      frame definitions, description of the frame relationships, source
      of and accuracy of the mounting alignment information, etc.
 
      This data set also includes Vesta- and Ceres-specific frames
      kernels. Each kernel contains the definition of the body-fixed
      frame for the respective asteroid.
 
      More information about the DAWN FK files is available in the file
      ``data/fk/fkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      IK Files
      ========
 
      Instrument kernel files provide specifications for geometric
      parameters and--where applicable--field-of-view size, shape and
      orientation for the named instruments. Metadata describing these
      estimates are provided in each IK file included in this archive.
      Parameter values were determined from pre-launch measurements,
      instrument parameters specification documents, and in some cases
      from analysis of in-flight calibration data. The accuracy
      estimates for these data vary from instrument to instrument and,
      where available, are included in the IK internal comments.
 
      This data set includes IK files for instruments on the DAWN
      spacecraft, including the Framing Camera, the Gamma Ray and
      Neutron Detector (GRaND), the Visible and Infrared Mapping
      Spectrometer (VIR), antennas, star trackers, and other
      structures.
 
      Because the sets of geometric parameters included in the IKs vary
      from instrument to instrument users are encouraged to carefully
      examine the IKs before using them.
 
      More information about DAWN IK files is available in the file
      ``data/ik/ikinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      SCLK Files
      ==========
 
      Spacecraft Clock kernel files provide a tabulation of data needed
      for converting time measurements between ephemeris time (ET) and
      spacecraft clock time (SCLK). The DAWN SPICE SCLK files were made
      from similar files--SCLK/SCET files, or SCLKvSCET files--produced
      by another mission entity. Each newly made SCLK file fully
      replaces the previous SCLK file.
 
      For DAWN, the time correlation accuracy provided in the SCLK
      kernel files for the Vesta orbital operations time period is
      informally reported to be better than 20 milliseconds, while the
      accuracy for the cruise to Vesta time period is significantly
      worse, with errors occasionally growing to 200-300 milliseconds.
 
      SPICE software does not prohibit an SCLK file from being used for
      time conversions occurring for ``future times&apos;&apos; (or more
      accurately, for epochs that occur later than the epoch of the
      last telemetry data used in producing the last correlation
      coefficients found in the SCLK file). Such ``predict&apos;&apos; time
      conversions are likely to be inaccurate (changed somewhat) once
      the epoch of interest has been passed.
 
      More information about the DAWN SCLK files is available in the
      file ``data/sclk/sclkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      LSK Files
      =========
 
      Leapseconds kernel files provide a tabulation of ``leapseconds&apos;&apos;
      and some other terms used in converting time measurements between
      ephemeris time (ET) and Universal Time (UTC). ``Spacecraft Event
      Time&apos;&apos; (SCET) is the commonly used name for UTC events measured
      at the spacecraft.
 
      Metadata describing how the LSK data are obtained or computed is
      contained inside the LSK text file. The time conversion provided
      by SPICE LSK files is accurate to approximately 0.000030 seconds.
 
      More information about the LSK files is available in the file
      ``data/lsk/lskinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
      EK Files
      ========
 
      The DAWN project did not produce any EK files; therefore, no EKs
      are included in this data set.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

