<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mpfr-m-rvrcam-5-midr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MPFR MARS ROVER CAMERA 5 MOSAICKED IMAGE DATA RECORD V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_pathfinder::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mpfr::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rcrr.mpfr::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:unk.unk::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mpfr-m-rvrcam-5-midr-v1.0__browserp_mpfr-m-rvrcam-5-midr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Golombek, M.P., R.A. Cook, T. Economou, W.M. Folkner, A.F.C. Haldemann,
                   P.H. Kallemeyn, J.M. Knudsen, R.M. Manning, H.J. Moore, T.J. Parker, R.
                   Rieder, J.T. Schofield, P.H. Smith, and R.M. Vaughan, Overview of the Mars
                   Pathfinder Mission and Assessment of Landing Site Predictions, Science,
                   278, 1743-1748, 1997.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GOLOMBEKETAL1997B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Matijevic, J., Microrover Flight Experiment Requirements, Architecture and
                   Verification Document, JPL Document 10925, PF-R00-5.0-02, Rev B, 68 pp.,
                   April 15, 1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MATIJEVIC1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Matijevic, J.R., L.W. Avril, R.S. Banes, D.B. Bickler, R.S. Blomquist, G.S.
                   Bolotin, D.F. Braun, D.R. Burger, B.K. Cooper, J. Crisp, F. Deligiannis,
                   W.C. Dias, H.J. Eisen, D. Ferguson, B.H. Fujiwara, R.D. Galletly, G.S.
                   Hickey, P. Jenkins, K.A. Jewett, E.J. Jorgensen, J. Kilecki, H.A. Kubo,
                   G.A. Landis, W.E. Layman, L.H. Matthies, D.P. McQuarie, R.J. Menke, A.H.
                   Mishkin, D.S. Mittman, H.J. Moore, J.C. Morrison, T.T. Nguyen, D.E. Noon,
                   L. Oberle, T.R. Ohm, G.M. Shinn, D.L. Shirley, A.R. Sirota, C.B. Stell, S.
                   Stevenson, H.W. Stone, L.F. Sword, H.C. Ta, A.D. Thompson, L.M. van
                   Nieuwstadt, M.T. Wallace, L. -C. Wen, B.H. Wilcox, and Y.C. Wu, The
                   Pathfinder Microrover, J. Geophys. Res., 102, 3989-4001, 1997.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MATIJEVICETAL1997A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Matijevic, J.R., J. Crisp, R.S. Banes, D.B. Bickler, B.K. Cooper, H.J.
                   Eisen, D. Ferguson, J. Gensler, A. Haldemann, F. Hartman, P. Jenkins, K.A.
                   Jewett, J. Kolecki, G.A. Landis, S.L. Laubach, L.H. Matthies, A.H. Mishkin,
                   H.J. Moore, J.C. Morrison, T.T. Nguyen, A.R. Sirota, H.W. Stone, S. Stride,
                   L.F. Sword, J.A. Tarsala, A.D. Thompson, M.T. Wallace, R. Welch, E.
                   Wellman, B.H. Wilcox, and D. Wilt, Characterization of the Martian Surface
                   Deposits by the Mars Pathfinder Rover, Sojourner, Science, 278, 1765-1768,
                   1997.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MATIJEVICETAL1997B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mellstrom, J. and K. Lau, Mars Pathfinder AIM Phasing and Coordinate Frame
                   Document, JPL Document 12103, PF-300-4.0-04, 38 pp., 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MELLSTROM-LAU1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Vaughan, R., Mars Pathfinder Project Planetary Constants and Models, JPL
                   Document 12947, PF-100-PMC-01, 136 pp., December, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.VAUGHAN1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Wellman, J.B., Imager for Mars Pathfinder Coordinate Systems and Imaging
                   Transformations, JPL Document 15212, PF-400-9.0, 16 pp., July 25, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.WELLMAN1996B</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MPFR-M-RVRCAM-5-MIDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MPFR MARS ROVER CAMERA 5 MOSAICKED IMAGE DATA RECORD V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1998-01-04</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1997-07-05T02:18:30.266Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1997-09-25T04:52:07.936Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>ALLAN J. RUNKLE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Runkle, A. J., MPFR MARS ROVER CAMERA 5 MOSAICKED IMAGE DATA
            RECORD V1.0, MPFR-M-RVRCAM-5-MIDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 1998
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Mars Pathfinder bounced down and rolled to a stop on the surface
            of Mars on July 4, 1997.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Mars Pathfinder bounced down and rolled to a stop on the surface
            of Mars on July 4, 1997. After a slight delay in deployment due
            to airbags draped over one of the lander&apos;s petals, the Rover
            rolled down onto the surface of Mars at 5:37am, July 6, 1997
            (UTC).
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    Mars Pathfinder bounced down and rolled to a stop on the surface
    of Mars on July 4, 1997.  After a slight delay in deployment due
    to airbags draped over one of the lander&apos;s petals, the Rover
    rolled down onto the surface of Mars at 5:37am, July 6, 1997
    (UTC).
 
    627 images were collected by the three cameras mounted on the
    Microrover Flight Experiment (also known as the Mars Pathfinder
    Rover or Sojourner).  The rover had two monochromatic cameras
    mounted in front which provided stereo viewing, and a separate
    &apos;color&apos; camera mounted in the rear.  The rear camera obtained
    color pictures through the use of red, green, and blue pixels
    arranged in a &apos;field-staggered 3G&apos; mosaic filter pattern on the
    CCD.
 
    The Rover Camera MIDR data set is composed of four different
    kinds of products: uncorrected black and white mosaics,
    uncorrected color mosaics, CAHV-corrected color mosaics, and
    stereo anaglyphs.  The &apos;uncorrected&apos; mosaics have had some
    limited radiometric corrections applied to them but no geometric
    corrections.  The CAHV-corrected mosaics have had both
    corrections applied.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The Rover Camera MIDRs are images; the main parameter is light,
    measured in units of data numbers or DNs.  Each CCD pixel
    (picture element) is represented by a byte value ranging from 0
    (dark) to 255 (saturated).  The wavelength sensitivity of the
    front (black and white) cameras was 830 to 890 nm; the aft
    (color) camera sensitivity was 500 to 900 nm.  Since the MIDRs
    combine multiple EDRs acquired at varying light levels and
    exposure durations, the MIDR pixels can have light levels greater
    than 255.  (See the more detailed explanation in the &apos;Processing&apos;
    section below.)
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The input products used to generate the Rover Camera Mosaicked
    Image Data Records (MIDRs) were the Rover Camera Experiment Data
    Records (EDRs), (data set id MPFR-M-RVRCAM-2-EDR-V1.0), also
    archived on this CD.  The identity of individual EDRs used as
    input to a specific MIDR can be determined using the
    COMMAND_SEQUENCE_NUMBER item in the PDS label of each MIDR.
 
    The Rover Camera MIDRs consist of the reconstruction of multiple
    subframes acquired at approximately the same time, from the same
    physical location.  In other words, there was no movement of the
    rover between subframes; there were radiometric but no spatial
    changes from one subframe to another.  The purpose of subframing
    was to optimize the exposure times in different portions of a
    reconstructed image, while utilizing the full dynamic range of
    the CCD.  For example, the top half of a Rover image may have
    received significantly more light than the shadowed lower half,
    and would therefore benefit from a shorter exposure time.
 
    The lowest level MIDR products are the black and white
    uncorrected mosaics.  These products were created using the VICAR
    (Video Image Communication and Retrieval) program MPFRVRMOS.
    MPFRVRMOS mosaicked multiple rover subframes from one image.  It
    applied rudimentary dark current and exposure corrections to the
    mosaic.  It did this first by subtracting a dark level from the
    DN values of all component frames.  (This value is indicated by
    the DARK_LEVEL_CORRECTION keyword in the labels.) It then
    synthetically generated an &apos;output&apos; exposure duration equal to
    the longest exposure duration of any input subframe.  It
    equalized the exposures of the various subframes by multiplying
    the DN values in each input frame by the ratio of the
    synthetically generated exposure duration over the input exposure
    duration.  The entire DN range of every input frame was retained
    by converting the byte data to half word data at this stage.
    Finally, the program applied a dark current correction to the
    mosaic.  This could be done in one of two ways indicated by the
    DARK_CURRENT_CORRECTION_TYPE keyword in the PDS labels.  The
    valid types of correction were PRIME and BOTH; PRIME applied only
    a vertical correction on the front camera images, or only a
    horizontal correction on the rear camera images.  BOTH meant that
    both a vertical and a horizontal correction were applied.
 
    The products generated by this process were the &apos;.HAF&apos; images in
    the RVR_MIDR/RVR_MOS/ directory.  These images were then
    converted back to byte data using the VICAR program CFORM.  This
    resulted in the &apos;.IMG&apos; images in the same directory.
 
    The next level of MIDR products are the color uncorrected
    mosaics, produced from EDRs acquired by the rear rover camera.
    These products were essentially created through the same process
    as the black and white mosaics, except that after the mosaic had
    been radiometrically corrected, it was run through the program
    MPFRVRCLR, which generated three separate color bands from the
    single input band.  (In one case only, for image
    RVR_MIDR_CLR-1253414310-S076054-REAR-B, the image was split into
    three separate bands before being radiometrically corrected.) As
    described elsewhere (see RCRRINST.CAT on this CD), the rear
    camera CCD contained pixels sensitive to different wavelengths of
    light, enabling it to obtain a &apos;color&apos; picture with a single
    exposure.  This single band was split up by using a color map,
    and applying bilinear spatial interpolation to fill in the
    &apos;missing&apos; pixels.
 
    This step of the process also resulted in both half word and byte
    data files, stored in the directory RVR_MIDR/RVR_CLR/ on the CD.
    (Technically, since the CFORM program only worked on
    single-banded files, the images were split into three separate
    red, green, and blue files using COPY, converted to byte using
    CFORM, and recombined into a single file using MPFCOMBO.)
 
    The next step of process involved the application of a geometric
    correction to the mosaics using the CAHV camera model.  This step
    was applied to both the black and white and the color mosaics.
    The half word data files were used as input.  This step was
    accomplished using the VICAR program MPFCAHV.  This program
    converted the images from distorted (CAHVOR) to linear (CAHV)
    coordinates.  The coordinates of each pixel in the output image
    were transferred from CAHV to CAHVOR space.  If the pixel fell
    within the input image, its DN value was bilinearly interpolated
    and placed within the output image.  A full output image was
    created even if the input image was only a subframe.  The output
    image was converted to byte data by the MPFCAHV program.  These
    images are stored in the RVR_MIDR/RVR_CAHV/ directory on the CD.
 
    All of the above products were generated at the Multimission
    Imaging Processing Laboratory, at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory.
    The highest level of MIDR products, the stereo anaglyphs, were
    generated by the Microrover Flight Experiment Team, also at JPL.
 
    The Sojourner Rover anaglyphs were created using the left and
    right images captured by the rover on Mars.  The following text,
    provided by Tam Nguyen of the MFEX Team, describes the conversion
    process which involved two platforms: a Sun Sparc20 and a Mac
    PowerPC.
 
    A. The Sun Sparc20 process:
 
      1. The input left and right images had been previously camera
         corrected by MIPL, applying the CAHV camera model.
 
      2. These CAHV image files were then converted to PIC format using
         the &apos;cahv2pic&apos; command (developed by Todd Litwin for the Mars
         Pathfinder Project).  The &apos;fisheye&apos; warping effect caused by
         the rover cameras&apos; wide angle lenses was corrected using the
         &apos;dowarp&apos; command (also developed by Todd Litwin).
 
      3. The unwarped images were then converted to GIF format using the
         &apos;pic2gif&apos; command (again developed by Todd Litwin) for
         compatability with Adobe PhotoShop format constraints.
 
    B. The Mac PowerPC process:
 
      The creation of the rover anaglyph was performed using the Adobe
      PhotoShop Version 3.0 program on a Mac PowerPC, employing the
      following steps:
 
      1. A pair of left and right rover images in GIF format were
         opened. The right image was converted to RGB format by
         selecting &apos;Mode: RGB image&apos;.
 
      2. The &apos;FrameImage&apos; (a dashed box) in the top left corner Tool
         palmlet was selected, then used to frame the left image by
         holding down the left mouse button and dragging the mouse to
         identify the selected area of the image.
 
      3. The &apos;Edit: Copy&apos; menu item was selected to copy the selected
         image to a buffer.
 
      4. The right image was selected by clicking on it.
 
      5. The Layers/Channels/Paths palmlet was opened by selecting
         &apos;Windows: Show Channels&apos;.
 
      6. The &apos;Channels&apos; option in the Layers/Channels/Paths palmlet was
         selected, then the &apos;Red&apos; channel only was selected (identified
         by an eye in the left hand side box).  The &apos;Edit: Paste&apos;
         command was used to paste the left image (in the buffer) into
         the &apos;Red&apos; channel of the right image.
 
      7. The &apos;Green&apos; and &apos;Blue&apos; channels of the Layers/Channels/Paths
         palmlet, identified by the eyes in the left hand side boxes,
         were selected to bring the green and blue colors of the right
         image back.
 
      8. Wearing red and blue stereo viewing goggles, the &apos;Move&apos; icon
         (a hand in the top left corner of the Tool palmlet) was
         selected.  The arrow cursor then became a hand cursor.  The
         cursor was moved into the selected red image area, then the
         left mouse button was held down.  The red image was dragged
         until the anaglyph showed the desired results, then the left
         mouse button was released.
 
      9. The &apos;FrameImage&apos; feature was used to eliminate the unwanted
         area of the anaglyph, and then the image was saved.
 
    The anaglyph PDS labels were created using the PDS information
    from the CAHV files.  The &apos;cahvlbl&apos; command (developed by Todd
    Litwin) extracted the PDS information from the the CAHV files,
    which was then converted into the correct PDS format using the
    &apos;greppds&apos; command (developed in the Tcl language by Tam Nguyen
    for the Mars Pathfinder Project).
 
    Since the process of creating an anaglyph required the left and
    right images, the PDS label of an analyph could contain the
    information from either the left or the right image, but not
    both.  The unwarping and anaglyph creation processes resulted in
    anaglyphs with image sizes smaller than their original images.
    The rover camera models of all of the pds labels were the same.
 
    The anaglyph creation technique described above was developed by
    Tim Parker for the Mars Pathfinder Project.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The Rover images on this CD are uncompressed, 8- and 16-bit
    files, labelled in conformance with PDS standards.  Both black
    and white and color images are present in the data set.  The
    color images are stored as three separate bands in a single file.
 
    The Rover Camera MIDRs are contained in the RVR_MIDR/ directory
    on the CD.  The uncorrected black and white mosaics are stored in
    the RVR_MIDR/RVR_MOS/ subdirectory, the uncorrected color mosaics
    are stored in the RVR_MIDR/RVR_CLR/ subdirectory, the
    CAHV-corrected mosaics are stored in the RVR_MIDR/RVR_CAHV/
    subdirectory, and the stereo anaglyphs are stored in the
    RVR_MIDR/RVR_GLYF/ subdirectory.
 
    Individual filenames consist of the instrument identifier &apos;R&apos;,
    followed by a five digit command sequence number, followed by a
    single letter, used as a counter.  The command sequence number
    used in each mosaic filename is the lowest of the command
    sequence numbers from the input EDRs which make up that mosaic.
    (For the stereo anaglyphs, this is the lowest of the EDRs in the
    RIGHT frame.) The counter is used to distinguish between multiple
    mosaics which have identical command sequence numbers.  (The only
    time this occurrs is for command sequence &apos;0&apos;, used when the
    rover acquired images autonomously while in an emergency mode,
    and for command sequence numbers in the 55xx range, which were
    erroneously repeated.)
 
    For all but the anaglyph images, the filename then contains one
    of &apos;L&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, or &apos;R&apos;, indicating a LEFT, RIGHT, or COLOR image.
    (The anaglyphs, obviously, are combinations of both LEFT and
    RIGHT images.)
 
    Finally, this is followed by one of the two file extensions,
    &apos;.IMG&apos; or &apos;.HAF&apos;.  The &apos;.IMG&apos; extension is used for byte (8-bit)
    data, and the &apos;.HAF&apos; extension is used for half-word (16-bit)
    data.
 
    Note that the Rover Team delivered the stereo anaglyphs with
    different filenames that what have been used on the CD.  The
    files were renamed partly to comply with PDS file naming
    guidelines, and partly to provide correspondance between these
    images and the other MIDRs on the CD.  A mapping between the old
    and new names is provided here for reference:
 
        005101-BOTH.{jpg,pds} --&gt; R05101A.{JPG,IMG}
        05524A-BOTH.{jpg,pds} --&gt; R05524A.{JPG,IMG}
        05524B-BOTH.{jpg,pds} --&gt; R05524B.{JPG,IMG}
        14099-BOTH.{jpg,pds}  --&gt; R14094A.{JPG,IMG}
        15130-BOTH.{jpg,pds}  --&gt; R15130A.{JPG,IMG}
        24057-BOTH.{jpg,pds}  --&gt; R24057A.{JPG,IMG}
        27093-BOTH.{jpg,pds}  --&gt; R27093A.{JPG,IMG}
        32092-BOTH.{jpg,pds}  --&gt; R32092A.{JPG,IMG}
        37082-BOTH.{jpg,pds}  --&gt; R37082A.{JPG,IMG}
 
    (The JPEG versions of the above files have been placed in the
    BROWSE directory of the CD.)
 
    The filenames can be used to correlate the different kinds of
    MIDRs.  In other words, files in different directories of the CD
    which have identical filenames, are related.  For example:
 
        RVR_MOS/R24057AR.HAF  - half-word version of uncorrected black
                                and white mosaic of EDRs in the command
                                sequence number range of 24057 - 24060
        RVR_MOS/R24057AR.IMG  - byte version of the same mosaic
        RVR_CAHV/R24057AR.IMG - CAHV-corrected version of the same
                                mosaic
        RVR_GLYF/R24057A.IMG  - stereo anaglyph version of the same
                                mosaic; note that this RIGHT frame
                                mosaic is combined with the LEFT frame
                                mosaic of EDRs in the range of
                                24053 - 24056
 
    (Note that there is NO correspondence between R00000AL.IMG and
    R00000AR.IMG.) For all of the MIDRs, the command sequence numbers
    of the input EDRs are included in the PDS label.  These values
    can be used to backtrack to the raw products which make up a
    mosaic.
 
    For all MIDRs, the SPACECRAFT_CLOCK_STOP_COUNT shown in the label
    is the SPACECRAFT_CLOCK_START_COUNT from the latest input EDR
    used in the mosaic.
 
    Note that the EXPOSURE_DURATION used in the MIDR labels has a
    different meaning than that used in the EDR labels; it is a
    synthetically generated value as described above in the
    &apos;Processing&apos; section.
 
    Some of the keyword values shown in the labels of the anaglyph
    images are the values for the right frame of the mosaic; the
    values for the left frame are not included.  (However, the
    COMMAND_SEQUENCE_NUMBER can be used to determine all the input
    EDRs, and therefore the missing values.)
 
    The best way to identify rover images that can be used as stereo
    pairs is to find left and right images that have the same values
    for the ROVER_HEADING and ROVER_POSITION.  The &apos;Flight Rover
    Image Status Report&apos;, put together by the Rover Team, may also be
    of assistance.  This report is contained in the
    DOCUMENT/ROVERDOC/DOWNLINK/TABLIMAG.HTM file on this CD.
 
    All image files are stored with a fixed length record format.
    There is an attached PDS label at the beginning of each image
    file that describes the content and format of the image.  If the
    PDS label size is not an exact multiple of the file record
    length, padding is added after the end of the PDS label.  Thus,
    the image object always starts on a record boundary.
 
    PDS labels are object-oriented.  The object to which the label
    refers (e.g., IMAGE, TABLE, etc.) is denoted by a statement of
    the form:
 
        ^object = location
 
    in which the carat character (&apos;^&apos;, also called a pointer in this
    context) indicates that the object starts at the given location.
    For an object in the same file as the label (as is the case for
    the Rover MIDRs), the location is an integer representing the
    starting record number of the object (the first record in the
    file is record 1).  For example:
 
        ^IMAGE = 22
 
    indicates that the IMAGE object begins at record 22 of the file.
 
    A complete description of the PDS file format is available from
    the Planetary Data System.  (Complete contact information for the
    PDS is available in the AAREADME file in the root directory of
    this CD.)
 
 
  Coordinate Systems and Image Geometry
  =====================================
    The Rover heading and position are measured in the Martian Local
    Level coordinate frame.  The heading is measured clockwise from
    north in units of BAMs (Binary Angle Measurements), where 2**16
    BAMs equals one revolution.  The position is provided as x and y
    offsets in meters north and east, respectively, of the Lander.
 
    The Martian Local Level Coordinate Frame is a right handed,
    orthogonal, frame whose origin is co-incident with the origin of
    the Lander Coordinate Frame.  The XM axis points north, the YM
    axis points east, and the ZM axis points down.  This sytem is
    defined relative to the Mars areocentric coordinate system.
 
    For more information on Mars Pathfinder coordinate systems, see
    the [MELLSTROM&amp;LAU1996], [WELLMAN1996B], and [VAUGHAN1995]
    references.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The Rover MIDR images can be displayed on UNIX, Macintosh, and PC
    platforms using the PDS developed program, NASAView.  This
    software is freely available from the PDS Central Node and may be
    obtained from their web site at http://pds.nasa.gov/.  For
    more information or help in obtaining the software, contact the
    PDS operator at the following address:
 
    Address:     Planetary Data System, PDS Operator
                 Jet Propulsion Laboratory
                 4800 Oak Grove Drive
                 Pasadena, CA 91109
 
    Phone:       (818) 354-4321
    Email:       pds_operator@jpl.nasa.gov
    WWW URL:     http://pds.nasa.gov/
 
    The real time processing of the VICAR-formatted Rover data was
    done using the VICAR suite of image processing programs.  The
    latest version of the VICAR program XVD may also be used for
    displaying PDS formatted images.  For information on obtaining
    VICAR, please contact:
 
    Address:     Danika Jensen
                 M/S 168-414
                 Jet Propulsion Laboratory
                 4800 Oak Grove Drive
                 Pasadena, CA 91109
 
    Phone:       (818) 354-6269
    Email:       Danika.Jensen@jpl.nasa.gov
    WWW URL:     http://www-mipl.jpl.nasa.gov/vicar.html
 
 
  Media / Format
  ==============
    The Rover Camera MIDR data are stored on compact disc-read only
    memory (CD-ROM) media.  The CD is formatted according to ISO-9660
    and PDS standards.  The data files do not include extended
    attribute records (XARs), and are therefore not readable on some
    older VMS operating systems.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    Since the cameras were not adequately calibrated, some dark
    current and dark level corrections were done for a &apos;best
    appearance&apos;, rather for strict scientific purposes, although
    attempts to minimize data loss were important in the process.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    Prior to release, the data will be reviewed by the Rover
    instrument team and the Planetary Data System.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    Given that these products were generated from the Rover Camera
    EDRs, all quality issues affecting the EDRs were inherited by the
    MIDRs.  Most noticeably, the products with command sequence
    numbers 45054, 49083, and 75077 are all missing values in their
    labels, since those values were not present in the EDR labels.
    Full details are provided in the ERRATA.TXT file in the root
    directory of this CD.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>IN_QUEUE</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

