<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-e-v-h-mdis-6-ddr-geomdata-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER MDIS DERIVED DATA RECORDS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mdis-nac.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mdis-6-ddr-geomdata-v1.0__browserp_mess-e-v-h-mdis-6-ddr-geomdata-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mdis-6-ddr-geomdata-v1.0__browser_geo_mercury_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mdis-6-ddr-geomdata-v1.0__browser_mess-e-v-h-mdis-6-ddr-geomdata-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mdis-6-ddr-geomdata-v1.0__dvo_imaging_mess-e-v-h-mdis-6-ddr-geomdata-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hawkins, S.E., III, J. Boldt, E.H. Darlington, R. Espiritu, R.E. Gold, B.
                   Gotwols, M. Grey, C. Hash, J. Hayes, S. Jaskulek, C. Kardian, M. Keller, E.
                   Malaret, S.L. Murchie, P. Murphy, K. Peacock, L. Prockter, A. Reiter, M.S.
                   Robinson, E. Schaefer, R. Shelton, R. Sterner, H. Taylor, T. Watters, and B.
                   Williams, The Mercury Dual Imaging System on the MESSENGER spacecraft, Space
                   Science Reviews, 131, 247-338, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAWKINSETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hawkins, S.E., III, S.L. Murchie, K.J. Becker, C.M. Selby, F.S. Turner, M.W.
                   Noble, N.L. Chabot, T.H. Choo, E.H. Darlington, B.W. Denevi, D.L. Domingue,
                   C.M. Ernst, G.M. Holsclaw, N.R. Laslo, W.E. McClintock, L.M. Prockter, M.S.
                   Robinson, S.C. Solomon, and R.E. Sterner, II, In-flight performance of
                   MESSENGER&apos;s Mercury Dual Imaging System, Proceedings of the SPIE, Volume 7441,
                   pp. 74410Z-74410Z-12, 2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAWKINSETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-E/V/H-MDIS-6-DDR-GEOMDATA-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESSENGER MDIS DERIVED DATA RECORDS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-05-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-08-19T18:01:23Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-04-30T11:07:43Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>CHRISTOPHER HASH</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            C. Hash, MESSENGER MDIS MAP PROJECTED MULTISPECTRAL RDR V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 2013
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Derived data records of geometrical information for the
            wide-angle and narrow-angle MDIS cameras on MESSENGER.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== The Mercury Dual Imaging System (MDIS) consists
            of two cameras, a Wide Angle Camera (WAC) and a Narrow Angle
            Camera (NAC), mounted on a common pivot platform. This dataset
            includes Derived Data Records of geometric information for each
            image pixel, for the WAC and NAC. The are 5 image planes for
            information for each pixel: planetocentric longitude, positive
            east; planetocentric latitude; solar incidence angle; emission
            angle; and phase angle.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Mercury Dual Imaging System (MDIS) consists of two cameras, a
      Wide Angle Camera (WAC) and a Narrow Angle Camera (NAC), mounted on
      a common pivot platform. This dataset includes the Derived Data
      Record (DDR) information for all valid, calibratible images acquired
      during flybys and orbit around Mercury, for which the target is
      Mercury and at least part of the image falls on the surface
      of the planet. These conditions represent a subset of all the
      images in the Calibrated Data Record or CDR dataset. The filename
      parallels that of the corresponding CDR, where:
 
      &apos;pcrnnnnnnnnnf_tt_v&apos;, where
 
         p = product type = D derived
         c = camera (W WAC or N NAC)
         r = spacecraft-clock-partition-number minus 1 [0, 1]
             for pre- or post-spacecraft-clock-reset
         nnnnnnnnn  = Mission Elapsed Time (MET) counter taken from the
                      image header (and same as original compressed
                      filename from SSR).
         f = Filter wheel position (A, B, C, D, E, F, G, H, I, J, K, L, U)
             for the WAC.  It is M for the NAC, which has no filter wheel.
         tt = data type (DE derived)
         v = version number
 
      The data exist in a format paralleling that of the raw or
      calibrated data: images have the same line and sample dimensions,
      and information in attached PDS labels is updated to convey
      differences in units and processing history. This dataset also
      includes ancillary data files that tabulate the contents of the
      volume and documentation files.
 
      For more information on the contents and organization of the volume
      set refer to the aareadme.txt file located in the root directory of
      the data volumes.
 
 
    Versions
    ========
 
      Version numbers of DDRs increment on reprocessing or updates to
      pointing information used to create the products.
 
      In version 0 DDRs, latitude and longitude are calculated using the
      best-determined spacecraft and instrument pointing values,
      spacecraft position, and camera model recorded in SPICE kernels,
      and an ellipsoidal model of the planet surface. For version 1 DDRs,
      c-smithed kernels and a global digital elevation model (DEM) are
      used, with the DEM derived using a least-squares bundle adjustment
      of common features, measured as tie point coordinates in overlapping
      NAC and WAC-G filter images.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      MDIS observing variables pertaining to the DDRs are as follows.
 
      Pixel Binning: Some images are unbinned and 1024x1024 pixels.
      Some images are 2x2 pixel binned in the focal plane hardware
      (also known as &apos;on-chip&apos; binning), resulting in 512 x 512
      images. Images can be further compressed 2x2 using the MP,
      in addition to DPU binning, yielding 256x256 images. The dimensions
      of the DDR are controlled by the types of pixel binning applied to
      the source image.
 
      Pointing: The MDIS imagers are mounted on a pivot platform, which
      is itself mounted to the MESSENGER spacecraft deck. The pivot
      platform is controlled by a stepper motor, which is controlled by
      the Data Processing Unit (DPU). The pivot platform can move in
      either direction. The total range of motion is 240 degrees, limited
      by mechanical &apos;hard&apos; stops, and is further constrained by &apos;soft&apos;
      stops applied by the software. The nominal pointing position for
      MDIS is defined as 0 degrees, aligned with the spacecraft +Z axis
      and the boresight for several other instruments. The range of the
      soft stops is set to 40 degrees in the spacecraft -Y direction
      (toward the MESSENGER sunshade) and +50 degrees in the +Y direction
      (away from the sunshade). The pivot position can be commanded in
      intervals of 0.01 degrees within this range. The position of the
      pivot is a key input to calculation of values in the DDR image
      planes.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      A Derived Data Record (DDR) consists of a multiband image whose
      line and sample dimensions correspond one-for-one with those of
      a CDR. It has 5 bands of data used to help create map- projected
      products, including for every image pixel: (a) latitude,
      (b) longitude, (c) solar incidence angle, (d) emission
      angle, and (e) phase angle. The focal lengths and optical
      distortions that control the static field of view of each of
      the WAC and NAC are recorded in the instrument (I) kernel. Pivot
      positions are extracted from the spacecraft housekeeping and
      formatted as a pivot C kernel. Spacecraft attitude is formatted
      as a spacecraft C kernel. Spacecraft position is recorded in an
      SP kernel. Planetary constants including orbital elements are
      recorded in the PC kernel. Using these kernels and SPICE software,
      the surface intercept on a shape model of Mercury is calculated
      for each spatial pixel. The angles between a vector from the center
      of the planet to the pixel&apos;s surface intercept and either the
      equatorial plane or reference longitude constitute the latitude
      and longitude of the pixel, respectively. For that latitude and
      longitude, solar incidence, emission, and phase angles are
      evaluated for the time that the image was taken. For calculation
      of the photometric angles, it is assumed that locally the surface
      is a part of a spherical shell.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      There is one data type associated with this volume, DDRs consisting
      of 5 image planes describing the latitude, longitude, and photometric
      geometries of each pixel in MDIS WAC and NAC images of the planet
      Mercury.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
 
      There are no ancillary data provided with this dataset.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
 
      The cartographic coordinate system used for the MDIS data products
      conforms to the J2000 celestial reference frame for star imaging,
      and the IAU planetocentric system with East longitudes being
      positive for planetary surfaces. A Mercury radius of 2440.0 km was
      used for data products delivered prior to delivery 15. In delivery
      15, that value is updated to 2439.4 km.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
 
      The MDIS archive is organized and stored in the directory
      structure described in the Mercury Dual Imaging System (MDIS)
      Calibrated Data Record (CDR) and Reduced Data Record (RDR)
      Software Interface Specification (SIS). The contents of the
      archive, along with fiduciary checksums, are compressed into
      a single &apos;zip archive&apos; file for transmittal to the PDS Imaging
      node.  The zip archive preserves the directory structure
      internally so that when it is decompressed the original
      directory structure is recreated at the PDS Imaging node.
      The zip archive is transmitted to the PDS Imaging node via
      FTP to the URL specified by the node for receiving it.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      Known issues of concern are described below.
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set will be examined by a peer review panel
      prior to its acceptance by the Planetary Data System (PDS).  The
      peer review will be conducted in accordance with PDS procedures.
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
 
      Only a subset of raw EDR data are calibrated to CDRs and then
      DDRs generated for the image. Briefly, the following criteria
      are met:
 
      (a) The data represent a scene and not the instrument test
      pattern, as indicated by Data Quality Index (DQI) byte 0.
 
      (b) The exposure time is greater than zero (zero exposures
      occur in some images due to software features), as indicated
      by DQI byte 1.
 
      (c) Less than 20 percent of the image is saturated (empirically
      this is a threshold dividing wholly corrupted images from
      everything else).
 
      (d) The target of the image is MERCURY.
 
      (e) Mercury occupies at least part of the image.
 
      The information in DDRs has systematic errors resulting from the
      following issues.
 
      (1) TIME VARIATIONS IN MDIS ATTITUDE. The orientation of MDIS
      relative to the spacecraft reference frame was determined inflight
      using star calibrations to solve for WAC-NAC coalignment, the
      orientation of the pivot plane, and the origin of the reported
      pivot position within the plane. However these alignments can be
      affected by thermal state of the spacecraft, or by any other
      events that potentially shift the position of the MDIS base
      relative to the spacecraft star cameras that generate the attitude
      measurements. Mercury and Venus flybys are thermally benign.
      However in Mercury orbit there are thermal perturbations from which
      errors in reported MDIS attitude of up to 350 microradians might be
      expected. Regular star calibrations are conducted in orbit and
      indicate up to two or more types of time variation in attitude of an
      image relative to a given reported pivot position: (a) A one-time
      shift of WAC and NAC image alignment occurred near the time of
      Mercury orbit insertion, several hundred microradians in magnitude.
      This is being addressed in an updated frames kernel. The shift for
      the WAC was first describe in a frames kernel released in
      conjunction with release 9. The frames kernel in conjunction with
      release 11 and the first release of DDRs also includes the shift of
      NAC image alignment near the time of orbit insertion.
      (b) In addition to the shift of WAC and NAC image orientation near
      the time of orbit insertion, subsequent gradual drift is observed
      in the WAC from star calibration images. That is addressed by
      modifications to the pivot C kernel that incorporate that drift
      as part of the pivot attitude, for simplicity. Limited star
      calibrations that determine the relative alignments of the WAC and
      NAC during the orbital phase of the mission indicate that the two
      fields of view drift together, so a single modified pivot C kernel
      is used to describe the pointing for both cameras.
 
      (2) POINTING UNCERTAINTY. MDIS pivot C-kernels generated prior
      to September 2009 were based on counting steps of the pivot motor.
      There is periodicity at the scale of 3 degrees of pivot rotation
      in the relationship between pivot step size and physical angle,
      leading to reported pivot geometries being in error by up to 350
      microradians in early versions of the pivot C kernel. Inflight
      tests during 2009 supported development of an alternative
      calculation of pivot angle using the pivot position resolver;
      this approach is included in MDIS pivot C kernels since MDIS
      release 5 (images through Mercury flyby 3). The uncertainties
      in pivot attitude in latter kernels are of the order of
      35 microradians.
 
      Uncertainty in spacecraft pointing is by requirement less than 350
      microradians, but unofficial estimates from the guidance and
      control team suggest a more typical value near 70 microradians.
      When convolved with error in pivot pointing, this results in the
      majority of error in knowledge of image pointing (exclusive of
      thermal distortion or time variations that can be calibrated out).
 
      An additional and generally larger source of error in map
      projection of MDIS images acquired during Mercury orbit may be
      uncertainty in spacecraft position. At low altitudes that source
      of error dominates, whereas at high altitudes pointing error
      dominates, such that in either case typical errors in map
      projection from the best reconstructed spacecraft position are
      expected to be smaller than 1 km.
 
      In the end-of-mission delivery 15 of SPICE files and version 1 DDRs,
      these errors are reduced by controlling images using c-smithed
      kernels and a global digital elevation model (DEM), both
      derived using a least-squares bundle adjustment of common
      features, measured as tie point coordinates in overlapping NAC and
      WAC-G filter images of Mercury at favorable solar incidence and
      emission angles.
 
      (3) TEMPERATURE-DEPENDENCE OF WAC and NAC FOCAL LENGTH. The
      star calibrations used to track the position of the MDIS pivot
      base, augmented by special calibrations using fields with high
      spatial densities of stars, sample much of the range of thermal
      environments experienced in orbit. Analyses of these data showed
      that focal length of each camera is correlated with temperature
      of the focal plane housing &apos;FOCAL_PLANE_TEMPERATURE&apos;, and that
      focal length varies over the cameras&apos; operating temperature range
      by several parts in 10,000. This dependence is included in an
      updated delivery of the instrument kernel associated with PDS
      release 11.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      None
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

