<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.clem1-l-u-5-dim-uvvis-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CLEMENTINE UVVIS DIGITAL IMAGE MODEL</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_space_program_science_experiment::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.clem1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:uvvis.clem1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-u-5-dim-uvvis-v1.0__browserc_clem1-l-u-5-dim-uvvis-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-u-5-dim-uvvis-v1.0__browserp_clem1-l-u-5-dim-uvvis-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-u-5-dim-uvvis-v1.0__dvo_imaging_clem1-l-u-5-dim-uvvis-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Planetary Data System Standards Reference, Jet Propulsion Laboratory Document
                   D-7669, Part 2, 20 November 1992
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PDSSR1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CLEM1-L-U-5-DIM-UVVIS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CLEMENTINE UVVIS DIGITAL IMAGE MODEL</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1999-03-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1994-01-25T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1994-05-07T00:00:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>ERIC M. ELIASON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Clementine Imaging (UVVIS) Lunar Full Resolution Global Mosaic
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Clementine UVVIS DIM Mosaic is a full-resolution (100 meters
            per pixel) global mosaic produced by the U.S. Geological Survey
            from Clementine EDR Data. Imaging data acquired by the
            Ultraviolet/Visible Camera were used to create the multi-band
            mosaic.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The Clementine UVVIS DIM Mosaic is a full-resolution (100 meters
    per pixel) global mosaic produced by the U.S.  Geological Survey
    from Clementine EDR Data.  Imaging data acquired by the
    Ultraviolet/Visible Camera were used to create the multi-band
    mosaic.
 
    The Clementine UVVIS DIM Mosaic is partitioned on the CD
    collection in the Sinusoidal Equal-Area Projection in
    cartographic format indentical to that of the previously released
    750-nm UVVIS basemap (PDS CD volumes CL_3001 through CL_3015).
    The 30 degree zone of the single band mosaic is now divided into
    six sets of quadrangles such that each set completes a 650
    megabyte CD volume.  This results in a 78 CD volume set.
    Additional CD volumes, containing reduced- resolution planetwide
    coverage at 0.5, 2.5, and 12.5 km/pixel and other ancillary data,
    and a final volume containing various ancillary data and
    information complete the archive collection.  For each full- and
    reduced- resolution image product, subsampled enhanced color and
    comparative ratio &apos;browse&apos; images are provided in Joint
    Photographic Experts Group (JPEG) format.
 
    In general, this design consists of rectangular tiles that are
    roughly 2100 pixels on a side.  The actual tile size varies with
    latitude.  Near the equator, each tile covers 7 degrees of
    latitude and 6 degrees of longitude.  A typical full-resolution
    5-band tile requires ~48 megabytes of digital storage.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    N/A
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The Integrated Software for Imagers and Spectrometers (ISIS)
    processing system, developed by the U.S.  Geological Survey was
    used to generate the UVVIS mosaic.  Processing within ISIS
    includes radiometric and geometric correction, spectral
    registration, photometric normalization, and image mosaicking.
    Radiometric correction applies &apos;flat fielding&apos;, dark current
    subtraction, non-linearity correction, and conversion to
    radiometric units.  Geometric transformations tie each raw image
    with a ground control network and convert from raw image
    coordinates to the Sinusoidal Equal-Area projection.  Photometric
    normalization is applied to balance brightness variations due to
    illumination differences among the images in a mosaic.  Images
    are then mosaicked together to form a global map of continuous
    image coverage for the entire planet.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    The Clementine UVVIS mosaic is delivered to the Planetary Data
    System using CD media.  Formats are based on standards for such
    products established by the Planetary Data System (PDS)
    [PDSSR1992].
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The Clementine UVVIS DIM Mosaic is the result of an exhaustive
    Lunar cartography project based on data from the Clementine EDR
    image collection.  Systematic calibration and processing enable
    global, full-resolution scientific analysis of the Clementine
    Datasets.  A first major step in the systematic processing of the
    imaging data is the production of an accurate basemap to which
    all products are geometrically registered.  Previous maps and
    ground control points of the Moon were not sufficiently accurate.
    The previous RAND control network is accurate to 500 meters in
    the area covered by the Apollo mapping frames (15% of the Moon&apos;s
    surface), and is accurate to about 1-2 kilometers for regions
    covered by telescopic, Galileo, and Mariner 10 observations.
    However, most of the far side is not included in the network, and
    the only other positional data for these regions contain errors
    as large as tens of kilometers.  Based on best effort
    measurements of the spacecraft orbit and pointing, UVVIS
    geometric distortions, and time tags for each observation, the
    SPICE data alone provides positional accuracies better than 1
    kilometer over most of the Moon.  With residuals primarily small
    random pointing errors, then accuracies approaching the UVVIS
    scale becomes achievable.
 
    The Clementine UVVIS mosaic was geometrically controlled to the
    previously published Clementine Basemap Mosaic by tying
    individual UVVIS images that make up a color set to the
    corresponding image in the color set that was used to produce the
    basemap mosaic.  A description of the method for controlling the
    basemap mosaic follows:
 
    The goal of the basemap mosaic is for 99% of the Moon (excluding
    the oblique observation gap fills) to be better than 0.5 km/pixel
    absolute positional accuracy and to adjust the camera angles so
    that all frames match neighboring frames to within an accuracy of
    2 pixels.  To achieve these goals we required camera alignment
    and pointing data accurate to a few hundredths of a degree.  We
    determined the absolute alignment of the UVVIS with respect to
    spacecraft-fixed axes (A and B Star Tracker Camera quaternions)
    by analyzing a major subset of the over 17,000 images of Vega,
    over 6,000 images of the Southern Cross and a few hundred images
    of the Pleiades, taken during the approach to the Moon and
    throughout the lunar mapping mission phase.  Multiple star images
    within a single picture were used to determine the UVVIS focal
    length and optical distortion parameter values.
 
    Approximately 265,000 match points were collected at the USGS
    from ~43,000 UVVIS images providing global coverage.  About 80%
    of these points were collected via autonomous procedures, whereas
    the 20% required the more time consuming but highly accurate
    pattern-recognition capability of the human eye-brain.  We also
    developed streamlined procedures for the supervised collection of
    match points.  The new procedures saved several person-years of
    effort and represents new capabilities useful with other
    planetary datasets.  The automated success rate exceeded 90%
    along each spacecraft orbit track, where the overlap regions of
    successive images are highly correlated, but failed when the
    overlap regions is narrow and/or nearly featureless.  (&apos;Failure&apos;
    is defined as less than 3 points per image with correlation
    coefficients grater than 0.85; thus, many good match points were
    rejected because we could not be certain that the matches were
    valid without verification.) Across-track matching was more
    difficult due to changes in scale and illumination angle, but a
    fair success rate (~60%) was nevertheless achieved via the use of
    &apos;window-shaping&apos; (local geometric reprojections).  The oblique
    gap-fill images were the most difficult to match, and required
    substantial human intervention.  Matching the polar regions was
    time-consuming because each frame overlaps many other frames.
    most match points were found to a precision of 0.2 pixels.
 
    The USGS match points were sent to RAND corporation for
    analytical triangulations.  Using these match points, control
    points from the Apollo region, and the latest NAIF/SPICE
    information, RAND determined improved camera orientation angles
    for the global set of UVVIS images.  A constant lunar radius of
    1737.4 kilometers was assumed, a significant source of error near
    the oblique gap fills.  The analytical triangulation is a
    least-squares formulation designed to adjust the latitude and
    longitude of the control points and the camera orientation angles
    to best fit the match points.  The triangulation was first
    computed on &apos;packets&apos; of match points (each covering ~1/8-th of
    the Moon), then checked and rechecked at the USGS via plots and
    test mosaics to fix and add match points as needed.  The final
    (global) analytical triangulation required solving ~660,000
    normal equations.  The mean error is less than 1 pixel.  This is
    by far the largest analytical triangulation ever applied to a
    planetary body other than Earth.  The results fully define the
    planimetric geometry of the basemap, to which future systematic
    products will be tied.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>94-004A-01B</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

