<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mgs-m-rss-5-sdp-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MGS RADIO SCIENCE -- SCIENCE DATA PRODUCTS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_global_surveyor::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mgs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.mgs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-rss-5-sdp-v1.0__browserp_geo_mgs-m-rss-5-sdp-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-rss-5-sdp-v1.0__ditdos_mgs-m-rss-5-sdp-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-rss-5-sdp-v1.0__dvo_atmos_mgs-m-rss-5-sdp-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-rss-5-sdp-v1.0__dvo_geo_mgs-m-rss-5-sdp-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Davies, M.E., V.K. Abalakin, A. Brahic, M. Bursa, B.H. Chovitz, J.H. Lieske,
                   P.K. Seidelmann, A.T. Sinclair, and Y.S. Tjuflin, Report of the IAU/IAG/COSPAR
                   Working Group on Cartographic Coordinates and Rotational Elements of the
                   Planets and Satellites: 1991, Celestial Mechanics and Dynamical Astronomy, 53,
                   377-397, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DAVIESETAL1992B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Davies, M.E., V.K. Abalakin, M. Bursa, J.H. Lieske, B. Morando, D. Morrison,
                   P.K. Seidelmann, A.T. Sinclair, B. Yallop, and Y.S. Tjuflin, Report of the
                   IAU/IAG/COSPAR Working Group on Cartographic Coordinates and Rotational
                   Elements of the Planets and Satellites: 1994, Celestial Mechanics and Dynamical
                   Astronomy, 63, 127-148, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DAVIESETAL1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Fjeldbo, G., A.J. Kliore, and V.R. Eshleman, The Neutral Atmosphere of Venus as
                   Studied with the Mariner V Radio Occultation Data, Astron. J., 76, 123-140,
                   1971.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FJELDBOETAL1971</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hinson, D.P., R.A. Simpson, J.D. Twicken, G.L. Tyler, and F.M. Flasar, Initial
                   Results from Radio Occultation Measurements with Mars Global Surveyor, Journal
                   of Geophysical Research, 104, 26997-27012, 1999.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HINSONETAL1999</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hinson, D.P., G.L. Tyler, J.L. Hollingsworth, and R.J. Wilson, Radio
                   Occultation Measurements of Forced Atmospheric Waves on Mars, Journal of
                   Geophysical Research, 106, 1463-1480, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HINSONETAL2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Smith, D.E., W.L. Sjogren, G.L. Tyler, G. Balmino, F.G. Lemoine, and A.S.
                   Konopliv, The Gravity Field of Mars: Results from Mars Global Surveyor,
                   Science, 286, 94-97, 1999.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SMITHETAL1999</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tyler, G.L., G. Balmino, D.P. Hinson, W.L. Sjogren, D.E. Smith, R. Woo, S.W.
                   Asmar, M.J. Connally, C.L. Hamilton, and R.A. Simpson, Radio Science
                   Investigations with Mars Observer, Journal of Geophysical Research, 97,
                   7759-7779, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TYLERETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tyler, G.L., G. Balmino, D.P. Hinson, W.L. Sjogren, D.E. Smith, R.A. Simpson,
                   S.W. Asmar, P. Priest, and J.D. Twicken, Radio science observations with Mars
                   Global Surveyor: Orbit insertion through one Mars year in mapping orbit,
                   Journal of Geophysical Research, 106, 23327-23348, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TYLERETAL2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Yeh, K.C., and C.H. Liu, Theory of Ionospheric Waves, Academic Press, San
                   Diego, 1972.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.YEH-LIU1972</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MGS-M-RSS-5-SDP-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MGS RADIO SCIENCE -- SCIENCE DATA PRODUCTS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2003-06-30</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1997-09-12T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2004-12-22T23:33:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>RICHARD A. SIMPSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Tyler, G.L., G. Balmino, D.P. Hinson, W.L. Sjogren, D.E. Smith,
            R. Woo, J.W. Armstrong, F.M. Flasar, R.A. Simpson, S. Asmar, A.
            Anabtawi, and P. Priest, MGS RST Science Data Products,
            MGS-M-RSS-5-SDP-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2005.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This archive contains reduced radio science data acquired during
            the Mars Global Surveyor (MGS) mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains archival results from radio science
            investigations conducted during the Mars Global Surveyor (MGS)
            mission. Radio measurements were made using the MGS spacecraft
            and Earth-based stations of the NASA Deep Space Network (DSN).
            The data set includes high-resolution spherical harmonic models
            of Mars&apos; gravity field generated by groups at the Jet
            Propulsion Laboratory and Goddard Space Flight Center, covariance
            matrices for some models, and maps for some models; these results
            were derived from raw radio tracking data. Also included are
            profiles of atmospheric temperature and pressure and ionospheric
            electron density, derived from phase measurements collected
            during radio occultations. The data set also includes analyses of
            transient surface echoes observed close to occultations during
            the first few years of MGS operations. The atmospheric and
            surface investigations were conducted by Radio Science Team
            members at Stanford University. The data set also includes 93
            line-of-sight acceleration profiles derived at JPL from radio
            tracking data collected near periapsis while Mars Global Surveyor
            was in its Science Phasing Orbit and below its nominal Mapping
            altitude of 400 km. The data were delivered to PDS in
            approximately chronological order at the rate of one CD-WO volume
            (typically 100 MB) every three months.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Mars Global Surveyor (MGS) Radio Science (RS) Archive Data
      Collection (ADC) of Science Data Products (SDP) includes data
      products generated from radio occultation, gravity, and surface
      reflection investigations conducted by members of the MGS Radio
      Science Team (RST).
 
      The archive includes both Standard Data Products (STDPs) and
      Special Data Products (SPDPs).  STDPs were defined prior to
      Launch; with two exceptions, they were produced routinely
      during the mission.  The two exceptions were not created
      regularly because suitable data were not available.  SPDPs
      were defined after Launch and/or were produced on an irregular
      basis.
 
      Radio occultation STDPs include temperature-pressure (T-p)
      profiles, occultation summary files, and intensity power
      spectra.  T-p profiles were computed with standard vertical
      resolution (approximately 200 m); an option to compute them
      at high resolution (approximately 20 m, after correction for
      diffraction effects) was never exercised.  David Hinson at
      Stanford University created all T-p profiles and occultation
      summary files.  Intensity power spectra were never computed
      because no evidence for scintillations was ever found.
      Richard Woo of the Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) would
      have created the intensity power spectra.
 
      Gravity STDPs include spherical harmonic models, maps or images
      of those models, and line-of-sight acceleration profiles.
      Groups at the Goddard Space Flight Center (GSFC) under the
      direction of David Smith and at JPL under the direction of
      William Sjogren produced spherical harmonic models, maps, and
      images.  Sjogren&apos;s group also produced a small number of
      line-of-sight acceleration profiles from pre-Mapping data
      when periapsis was unusually low.  Data collected during
      Mapping showed little structure that was not captured in the
      spherical harmonic model coefficients.  A group at Centre
      National d&apos;Etudes Spatiales (CNES) under Georges Balmino also
      worked with gravity data; but as of mid-2002 they had not
      generated any gravity STDPs.
 
      For more information on STDPs, see [TYLERETAL1992] and
      [TYLERETAL2001].
 
      Under certain conditions radio occultation data can be processed
      to yield profiles of electron density in the ionosphere.  SPDPs
      include profiles at standard vertical resolution created at
      Stanford University by David Hinson.  An option to produce high
      resolution ionospheric profiles was never exercised.
 
      The surface reflection investigation was developed only after
      the spacecraft was in Mars orbit.  SPDPs include summary tables
      of observing geometry, summary tables of reconstructed antenna
      pointing at the spacecraft, summary tables of signal
      characteristics, and images of signals in time-frequency space.
      These products were generated by Richard Simpson of Stanford
      University.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      Temperature-pressure profiles are tables of atmospheric
      temperature, pressure, and molecular number density versus
      radius from Mars&apos; center of mass.  A header record prepended
      to each table provides information on observing times and
      geometry, surface conditions, and on files used in the data
      processing.  Header records from all of the T-p profiles
      delivered at one time (typically every three months) are
      collected together into a single occultation summary file.
 
      Spherical harmonic models are tables of coefficients GM, Cmn,
      and Smn -- as in equation (1) of [TYLERETAL1992].  These can
      be used to represent gravitational potential of Mars, for
      example.  Both ASCII (data type SHA) and binary (data type
      SHB) formats are defined, with the latter being preferred for
      large files which also include covariance terms.  Each file
      contains up to four tables: a header table containing general
      parameters for the model (gravitational constant, its
      uncertainty, degree and order of the field, normalization
      state, reference longitude, and reference latitude); a names
      table, giving the order in which coefficients appear; a
      coefficients table (degree m, order n, coefficients Cmn and
      Smn, and their uncertainties); and a covariances table giving
      the covariances of CijCmn, SijSmn, CijSmn, and SijCmn.
 
      Radio Science Digital Map files are image representations
      of gravity and other parameters.  Free air gravity, geoid,
      Bouguer anomaly, isostatic anomaly, and topographic values
      may be displayed using this data type.  Data are formatted
      as PDS image objects.
 
      The Line-of-Sight Acceleration Profile Data Record is a pair
      of PDS tables.  The first table contains header information
      such as time and observing geometry, parameters used in
      deriving acceleration from radio tracking measurements, and
      first-order Keplerian orbit elements.  The second table gives
      spacecraft acceleration versus time.  Also included at each
      time is the spacecraft position in planetocentric coordinates.
 
      Electron density profiles are very similar to temperature-
      pressure profiles for the neutral atmosphere.  Each is a
      table of electron density versus radius from Mars&apos; center of
      mass.  A header record prepended to each table provides
      information on observing times and geometry and on files used
      in the data processing.  There is no summary file for the
      electron density profiles delivered together.
 
      Surface Reflection Tables list carrier frequency and power
      and the estimated frequency and power in the surface echo.
      Surface Reflection Images are series of power spectra
      showing the progression of signal characteristics as a
      function of time.
 
      Surface Reflection Geometry tables summarize the observing
      geometry at and near occultations at (typically) 1 second
      intervals.  Quantities include Earth receive time; the
      transmit time (receive time corrected for one-way light time);
      vectors to the spacecraft, Earth receiving station, and
      several points on the surface; angles; and sensitivities of
      some quantities to changes in assumed Mars radius.  The
      surface points include the specular point, the backscatter
      point (the intersection of a line from the receiver through
      the spacecraft to the surface), the raypath closest approach
      point (the point where a line from the Earth to the spacecraft
      is closest to the surface), and a user-defined &apos;target&apos; on
      the surface.  For the surface reflection studies conducted
      with MGS, only the specular point information is of interest.
      The backscatter point is the point on Mars&apos; disk behind the
      spacecraft when viewed from Earth, while the raypath closest
      approach point gives the latitude and longitude of the
      occultation ray closest approach; the backscatter point and
      the raypath closest approach point cannot exist simultaneously.
      The &apos;target&apos; point is meaningful only when a target has been
      selected; it is usually set to a default value of (0.,0.).
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      T-p profiles and ionosphere profiles are derived from raw
      receiver output in several steps.
 
      First, deterministic sources of frequency change are identified
      and removed coherently. These included motion of the spacecraft,
      motion of the Earth receiving station, drift of the UltraStable
      Oscillator (USO), and relativistic effects associated with
      gravity fields of solar system bodies.  This leaves the carrier
      signal at a known frequency except for phase drift associated
      with passage of the radio ray through Mars&apos; atmosphere and/or
      ionosphere.  Drift associated with passage through solar plasma
      or the Earth&apos;s atmosphere or ionosphere is assumed to be
      negligible over the time of a Mars occultation (approximately
      two minutes).
 
      Second, using an accurate reconstruction of the spacecraft
      trajectory, the phase of the signal versus time is converted
      into a measure of refraction angle versus impact parameter --
      the perpendicular distance between the incoming raypath and the
      center of curvature of the atmosphere.
 
      Third, the index of refraction versus radius is obtained using
      an Abel inversion [FJELDBOETAL1971].  From knowledge of the
      composition of the atmosphere and laboratory measurements of
      refractive index for major constituents, index of refraction
      versus radius for the neutral atmosphere is converted to
      vertical distribution of mass density.
 
      Fourth, assuming hydrostatic equilibrium and an ideal gas law,
      the mass density profile is converted to a profile of both
      temperature and pressure for the neutral atmosphere.
 
      For the ionosphere, refractive index versus radius is converted
      to density of free electrons versus radius using a method
      described by [YEH&amp;LIU1972].
 
      Spherical harmonic models, maps, and line-of-sight acceleration
      profiles are derived from raw radio tracking data in several
      steps.
 
      The gravity field coefficients are obtained by solving systems
      of equations with thousands of unknowns.  Radio tracking data in
      long arcs delimited by propulsive maneuvers, occultations, etc.
      are used in solutions which are obtained iteratively and by
      least squares.
 
      Maps of free air gravity and other quantities are generated from
      the spherical harmonic model(s) evaluated at regular grid
      points.
 
      Line-of-sight acceleration profiles are derived from single arcs
      of radio tracking data.  Doppler residuals with respect to a
      specific spherical harmonic model are spline-fitted; the splines
      are then differentiated analytically to obtain accelerations.
 
      See [TYLERETAL1992] and [TYLERETAL2001] and references therein
      for additional details on processing for the products listed
      above.
 
      Surface Reflection Geometry (SRG) tables are summaries of
      observing geometry, typically at one second intervals.  The
      spacecraft-surface-Earth geometry is derived from an SPK (NAIF
      spacecraft and planetary ephemeris) file.
 
      Surface Reflection Antenna (SRA) tables are summaries of
      high-gain antenna (HGA) pointing, typically at 1 second
      intervals.  The HGA pointing in J2000 is computed from
      spacecraft attitude (TCK) and HGA gimbal (AGK) files; that
      vector is then compared with the MGS-Earth vector in the SRG
      file.  Offset is listed as the total angle between the HGA
      boresight and the MGS-Earth vector and in terms of the
      components toward the surface and parallel to the limb.
 
      The Surface Reflection Table (SRT) data are derived as follows.
 
        (1) The occultation is located in time and its sense (ingress
        or egress) is determined from the direction of change in the
        receiver output: if ingress, the output should decrease; if
        egress, the output should increase.
 
        (2) Raw samples of receiver output are passed through
        a digital &apos;equalizing&apos; filter which flattens the output
        spectral response over the central 80 percent of the
        passband.  The output is a string of double-precision
        complex floating point time samples at the Nyquist sampling
        rate (2500/s for data collected through mid-2001, 2000/s for
        data collected starting in late 2001).
 
        (3) 512-point power spectra (approximately 0.2 s each) are
        computed around the transition point (1); approximately 30
        spectra are saved on the occulted side of the transition and
        270 are saved when the carrier is clearly visible (total of
        300 spectra, spaced by 0.2 s and having 5 Hz frequency bins).
 
        (4) A search within each spectrum for the bin with maximum
        signal locates the carrier (when it is present).
 
        (5) A second search within each spectrum for the strongest
        signal at frequencies higher (lower) than the carrier if
        ingress (egress) locates the surface echo.  The surface echo
        is transient, however, so not all results from this search
        are valid.  A predicted frequency curve (straight line) is
        fitted to the DIFFERENCE between the peak echo bin and the
        carrier bin; half of the points are thrown out (the worst
        residuals).  A new straight line is fitted to the remaining
        points, and the single point with the worst residual is
        thrown out.  The process is repeated, tossing out the point
        with the worst residual at each step, until only 10 points
        remain.  The final straight line is taken to be the actual
        drift of the surface echo with respect to the carrier.
 
        (6) An estimate of the noise power is made by averaging 64
        frequency bins from 300 spectra on the side OPPOSITE the
        surface echo and comparing the average with a system
        temperature estimate provided by the DSN Monitor data.
        The noise pedestal is removed and the remaining values are
        scaled to units of watts.
 
        (7) Five bins centered on the carrier are summed to obtain
        the carrier power.
 
        (8) Seven bins centered on the fitted straight line are
        summed to obtain the echo power.
 
        (9) The results are tabulated for each of the 300 spectra
        and stored in the SRT file.
 
        (10) The array of 300 512-point spectra is saved as the
        SRI file.
 
        (11) Fitting of the straight line to the echo trajectory is
        not always successful.  Column 25 in the header of the SRT
        file is set to &apos;0&apos; when the fit is unsatisfactory.  In most
        cases, this results from a very weak surface echo; in a few
        cases, the fitting algorithm simply fails.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      Data are stored on CD-WO volumes approximately in order by the
      time at which they were delivered for archiving.  A CD volume
      of reduced data is prepared approximately every three months
      and forwarded to PDS.
 
      Standard resolution temperature-pressure profiles are stored
      in the TPS directory with file names of the form  ydddhmmC.TPS
      where  y  is the least significant digit of the year,  ddd  is
      the three-digit day number,  h  is one-character which denotes
      the hour, and  mm  is a two-character string denoting the
      minute in which data acquisition began.  h  is  &apos;A&apos; if the
      hour was  00,  &apos;B&apos; if the hour was  01, ... and &apos;X&apos; if the hour
      was 23.  In most cases  mm  is the two-digit minute; but when
      data were collected from two sources and the start time was
      in the same minute, the second digit in  mm  was changed to a
      letter in the second file name (minute  00  becomes  0A,
      01  becomes  0B,  etc.).  C  is a single character indicating
      the version of the file, starting with &apos;A&apos;.
 
      High-resolution temperature-pressure profiles, should they ever
      be produced, will be stored in the TPH directory with file names
      of the form  ydddhmmC.TPH where components in the name are the
      same as for TPS files.
 
      Occultation summary files are stored in the OCS directory if
      derived from TPS data (and in the OCH directory if derived
      from TPH files).  File names are of the form  YMMymmCC.OCS
      and  YMMymmCC.OCH,  respectively, where  Y  is the one-digit
      year of the first entry in the file,  MM  is the two-digit
      month of the first entry,  y  is the one-digit year of the
      last entry, and  mm  is the two-digit month of the last
      entry.  CC  is a two-character string indicating the version
      of the file.
 
      ASCII spherical harmonic models are stored in the SHA directory
      with file names of the form  GTnnnnvv.SHA  where
      G  denotes the generating institution
                    J   for Jet Propulsion Laboratory
                    G   for Goddard Space Flight Center
                    C   for Centre National d&apos;Etudes Spatiales
      T  denotes the type of data represented
                    G   for gravity field
                    T   for topography
                    M   for magnetic field
      nnnn  is a 4-character modifier specified by the data producer
      vv  is a decimal version number, initialized to  &apos;01&apos;  and
      SHA  denotes that this is an ASCII file of spherical harmonic
      coefficients.  The distinction between &apos;nnnn&apos; and &apos;vv&apos; is not
      enforced strictly, however; in some cases, it has been more
      convenient to use all six characters to capture a model name
      and/or number used by the data producer.
 
      Binary spherical harmonic models are stored in the SHB
      directory with file names of the form  GTnnnnvv.SHB  where
      individual name components are as defined above except for the
      SHB suffix.
 
      Radio Science Digital Map products are stored in the IMG
      directory with file names of the form  GTnnnnnn.IMG  where
      G  denotes the generating institution
                    J   for Jet Propulsion Laboratory
                    G   for Goddard Space Flight Center
                    C   for Centre National d&apos;Etudes Spatiales
                    S   for Stanford University
      T  denotes the type of data represented
                    G   for free air gravity field
                    O   for geoid
                    B   for Bouguer anomaly
                    I   for isostatic anomaly
                    T   for topography
                    M   for magnetic field
      nnnnnn  is a 6-character modifier specified by the data
      producer and IMG  denotes that this is a PDS image object.
 
      Line-of-sight acceleration profiles are stored in the LOS
      directory with file names of the form  MOnnnnnC.LOS  where
      nnnnn  is the 5-digit orbit number and  C  is a character
      indicating the version (starting from &apos;A&apos;).
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      When radio occultation data are present on the volume, one
      or more files with names of the form  OCCLOGxx.TAB  may be
      included in the DOCUMENT directory.  These files list
      parameters for each radio occultation data acquisition
      opportunity.  PDS detached labels OCCLOGxx.LBL describe
      the format and contents of the files.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      MGS RST SDP files use a Mars centered body-fixed coordinate
      system with positive east longitude.
 
      Gravity models generally use the IAU 1991 [DAVIESETAL1992B]
      coordinate frame.  Variations are noted in the labels of
      specific gravity products.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      None.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The archival data set was written on CD-WO media using the
      Sun Ultra-5/Yamaha/GEAR CD authoring subsystem provided by
      the MGS Project until June 2002.  Volumes written later than
      June 2002 were written on a Sun Ultra-5/PlexWriter/cdrtoaster
      system.  The CD-WO volumes conform to ISO 9660 standards.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this archive have been reduced as part of mission data
      analysis activities of the MGS Radio Science Team.  Products
      of questionable validity have been flagged or omitted.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was reviewed by the MGS Radio Science
      Team prior to submission to the Planetary Data System (PDS).
      The MGS Science Data Validation Team (SDVT) monitored the
      submissions.
 
      Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data
      set, key elements of the archive were distributed for
      preliminary review.  These included electronic versions of
      example PDS labels, example data files, CATALOG files, and
      Software Interface Specifications.  These materials were
      distributed to PDS personnel, the experiment investigator,
      and others, as appropriate.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
 
      MORS_1001
      ---------
        T-p profiles included in this volume were derived from data
        collected while the spacecraft was at nearly maximum
        Earth-Mars range; the observations ended just a few days
        before solar conjunction.  See [HINSONETAL1999] for
        discussion of results.
 
            Dates:                   1998/01/28 - 1998/04/10
            Number of TPS Files:     88
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress only
            Latitudes:               29N - 64S
            Solar Zenith Angles:     85 - 106
 
        Significant events during this period were:
 
           YY/DDD    Start    Stop    Comments
           ------  -------- --------  ----------------
           98/024  19:15:36 19:32:15  First occultation recording
           98/076  13:19:18 (ET)      Close Phobos approach (380 km)
           98/087  02:44:09           First SPO-1 periapsis gravity
           98/088  01:51:00 02:15:00  First egress recording (LGA)
           98/107  23:01:28 23:18:00  Last good ingress recording
           98/118  15:52:00 16:33:00  Last occultation recording
 
        Quality of data was affected by anomalous conditions during
        data acquisition.  Specifics are given in the OCCLOGA1.TAB
        file in the DOCUMENT directory of MORS_1001; five general
        types of problems dominated:
 
          a) 2-6 dB lower carrier-to-noise level at Madrid antennas
             throughout the occultation period (98/024-98/118), later
             found to be from a weak oscillator in the front end of
             the radio science receiver
          b) &apos;Sawtooth&apos; frequency residuals in approximately 10
             percent of the data (all stations), later found to be
             from an intermittent synchronization error in merging
             two data streams at the DSN station
          c) Amplitude baseline variations more than +/-0.1 dB
             (various)
          d) Spurs (occasional, no consistent pattern)
          e) Unreliable local oscillator tuning (wrong controller
              software) (Madrid antennas, 98/084-98/106)
 
        Gravity models and maps included in this volume were generated
        from Mariner 9 and Viking data.  They do not contain any data
        from the Mars Global Surveyor mission; they do, however, serve
        as the baseline models from which the MGS models evolved.
        Labels for each of the gravity products provide more
        information on how the models were derived.
 
        JGM50C01.SHA is the pre-MGS Mars gravity model produced at the
        Jet Propulsion Laboratory under supervision of Bill Sjogren.
        JGM50C01.IMG is the free-air gravity map corresponding to this
        model. It is defined in IAU 1991 coordinates
        [DAVIESETAL1992B].
 
        GGM50A01.SHA is the pre-MGS Mars gravity model produced at
        Goddard Space Flight Center under supervision of David Smith.
        It is defined in IAU 1994 coordinates [DAVIESETAL1995].
 
        GGM50A02.SHA is a slight variation on this model (a coordinate
        transformation to IAU 1991 coordinates [DAVIESETAL1992B]) used
        by David Hinson in reduction of radio occultation data
        acquired during January-April 1998 and included in this
        volume.
 
      MORS_1002
      ---------
        This volume contains gravity models and maps generated from
        Mariner 9, Viking Orbiter, and MGS data collected through
        mid-September 1998.  The MGS data included tracking results
        from Orbit Insertion subphases Aerobraking 1, Science Phasing
        Orbit 1, and Science Phasing Orbit 2.  Orbit periapsis passed
        near Mars&apos; north pole during the summer of 1998, so the data
        are particularly good in defining the gravity field of the
        north polar region.
 
        GGM0890A.SHA is an ASCII file of coefficients for a 70x70
        degree and order field produced at Goddard Space Flight
        Center.  GGM0890A.IMG is a gridded representation of the
        field.   Derivation of the model is described by a paper in
        both PostScript and LaTeX formats in the DOCUMENT directory
        (see DOCUMENT/AAS99147.LBL for details).
 
        JGM75A01.SHA is an ASCII file of coefficients for a 75x75
        degree and order field produced at the Jet Propulsion
        Laboratory.  JGM75A01.SHB is a binary file of covariances.
 
      MORS_1003
      ---------
        This volume contains gravity models and maps generated from
        Viking Orbiter data and from MGS data collected through March
        1999.  The MGS data include tracking from Orbit Insertion
        subphases Aerobraking 1, Science Phasing Orbit 1, Science
        Phasing Orbit 2, the Gravity Calibration Orbit, and
        approximately the first month of MGS Mapping operations,
        while the high-gain antenna was still not deployed.  Noise
        produced by the control system after HGA deployment corrupted
        the tracking data and several months were required before a
        solution was found.
 
        GGM0964A.SHA is an ASCII file of coefficients for a 70x70
        degree and order field produced at Goddard Space Flight
        Center.  GGM0890A.IMG is a gridded representation of gravity
        anomalies with respect to an evaluation of the Goddard model
        to degree and order 50.  Derivation of the model is
        described by a paper in both PostScript and LaTeX formats in
        the DOCUMENT directory (see DOCUMENT/AAS99328.LBL for
        details).  The Goddard group argues that the MGS data are of
        sufficient quality that historic data (Mariner 9 and Viking
        Orbiter) can be omitted. Their solution is based solely on
        MGS data.
 
        JGM75B01.SHA is an ASCII file of coefficients for a 75x75
        degree and order field produced at the Jet Propulsion
        Laboratory.  JGM75B01.SHB is a binary file of coefficients
        and covariances.  JGD75B50.IMG is a gridded representation
        of gravity anomalies with respect to an evaluation of the
        JPL model to degree and order 50.  The JPL solution
        continues to include Viking Orbiter data.
 
        The Goddard group has also provided a map of uncertainties
        in their gravity anomalies; the JPL group has provided a
        map of geoid height above a reference ellipsoid.
 
        The BRO directory is new with this volume; it contains
        PostScript representations of selected gravity results.
 
        For a discussion of the major conclusions resulting from
        study of the gravity field to this point, see [SMITHETAL1999].
 
        MORS_1003 also contains 36 radio occultation profiles of
        neutral atmosphere temperature and pressure derived from data
        collected in late December 1998.  These observations were
        made while there was no telemetry modulation on the spacecraft
        carrier, providing some of the highest signal-to-noise prior
        to circularization of the orbit (February 1999).   See
        [HINSONETAL2001] for more information.
 
            Dates:                   1998/12/24 - 1998/12/31
            Number of TPS Files:     36
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress only
            Latitudes:               64N - 67N
            Solar Zenith Angles:     78 - 81
 
      MORS_1004
      ---------
        This volume contains a gravity model and maps generated at
        JPL from MGS tracking data collected through early November
        1999.  The MGS data included tracking results from the
        following phases/subphases of the mission:  Science Phasing
        Orbit 1, Science Phasing Orbit 2, Gravity Calibration Orbit,
        Fixed High-Gain Antenna Mapping, and the first seven months
        of Mapping.
 
        JGM75C01.SHA is an ASCII file of coefficients for a 75x75
        degree and order field produced at the Jet Propulsion
        Laboratory.  JGM75C01.SHB is a binary file of coefficients
        and covariances.  JGD75C60.IMG is a gridded representation
        of gravity anomalies with respect to an evaluation of the
        JPL model to degree and order 60.  JOD75C60.IMG is a
        gridded representation of geoid height with respect to
        a reference ellipsoid.
 
        MORS_1004 also contains example files from the Surface
        Reflection investigation.  9133H43A.SRG is a summary table
        of observing geometry for an occultation starting
        1999-133T07:43:00.  9133H43A.SRT is a tabulation of carrier
        and surface echo signal characteristics.  9133H43A.SRI is
        a two-dimensional array showing signal strength as a
        function of both frequency and time around the occultation.
        Surface echo was visible while the specular point moved
        from about (69S, 91W) to about (68S, 83W).
 
      MORS_1005
      ---------
        MORS_1005 contains 97 temperature-pressure profiles from
        radio occultations acquired during March 1999 while the
        spacecraft was in Fixed-High Gain Antenna operations.  The
        analysis was carried out using the JPL MGS75C gravity model
        and associated trajectory reconstructions (see MORS_1004).
 
            Dates:                   1999/03/07 - 1999/03/27
            Number of TPS Files:     97
            Occultation Sense:       48 ingress; 49 egress
            Latitudes:               73N - 68N;  74S - 75S
            Solar Zenith Angles:     76 - 78;    101 - 98
 
        There are also four sets of three files from the surface
        reflection investigation.  The new files accompany a single
        set of three files which appeared on MORS_1004.  All sample
        Mars surface at latitudes 68-69S and longitudes 80-105W.
 
      MORS_1006
      ---------
        MORS_1006 contains 440 temperature-pressure profiles from
        radio occultations acquired during May and June 1999 after
        the spacecraft recovered from the HGA azimuth anomaly and
        resumed Mapping operations.  The analysis was carried out
        using the JPL MGS75C gravity model and associated trajectory
        reconstructions (see MORS_1004).
 
            Dates:                   1999/05/06 - 1999/06/27
            Orbit Numbers:           712 - 1356
            Number of TPS Files:     440
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress only
            Latitudes:               36N - 30S
            Solar Zenith Angles:     98 - 119
 
        This volume contains a gravity model and maps generated at JPL
        from MGS tracking data collected through late March 2000.  The
        model also includes data from Mariner 9 and the two Viking
        Orbiters.
 
        JGM75D01.SHA is an ASCII file of coefficients for the 75x75
        degree and order gravity field produced at JPL.  JGM75D01.SHB
        is a binary file of coefficients and covariances. JGD75D60.IMG
        is a gridded representation of gravity anomalies with respect
        to an evaluation of the JPL model to degree and order 60.
        JOD75D60.IMG is a gridded representation of geoid height with
        respect to a reference ellipsoid.
 
        There are also 105 sets of three files from the surface
        reflection investigation.  The new files were based on data
        collected during March 1999 and sample the surface at
        latitudes 70-75 in both the northern (ingress) and southern
        (egress) hemispheres.
 
      MORS_1007
      ---------
        This volume contains only Special Data Products (SPDPs).
        Included are 32 electron density profiles derived from
        ingress radio occultation data acquired 24-31 December
        1998 (latitude approximately 65N).  Profiles of the neutral
        atmosphere appeared on MORS_1003.
 
        There are also 696 sets of three files from the surface
        reflection investigation.  The new files were derived from
        radio occultations acquired during April-May 1999 and sample
        the surface at latitudes of approximately 15-65N (ingress)
        and 60-70S (egress).
 
      MORS_1008
      ---------
        MORS_1008 contains 442 temperature-pressure profiles from
        egress radio occultations acquired during May and June 1999
        while the spacecraft conducted Mapping operations.  The
        analysis was carried out using the JPL MGS75C gravity model
        and associated trajectory reconstructions (see MORS_1004).
        This set of profiles completes the collection based on the
        first occultation season in MGS Mapping; the next occultations
        were obtained starting in December 1999.
 
            Dates:                   1999/05/06 - 1999/06/27
            Orbit Numbers:           713 - 1348
            Number of TPS Files:     442
            Occultation Sense:       Egress only
            Latitudes:               70S - 67S
            Solar Zenith Angles:     88 - 79
 
        This volume contains the MGM0964C20 gravity model which was
        developed at the Goddard Space Flight Center and which
        provided a reference geoid used extensively by the MOLA
        team in their data analysis.  The model is archived on this
        volume primarily for historical purposes.  File GGM0964B.SHA
        contains ASCII coefficients and uncertainties for the
        spherical harmonic model.
 
        Also on the volume is an 80x80 gravity model developed at
        GSFC and based on MGS radio tracking data collected through
        2000-02-29.  No Viking or Mariner 9 data were used in the
        solution.  File GGM2BC80.SHA contains ASCII coefficients and
        uncertainties for the spherical harmonic model.  Gravity
        anomaly is presented in gridded format in GGM2BA60.IMG at
        1 degree resolution.  GOM2BA60.IMG contains gridded geoid
        values at 0.25 degree resolution.  Also available are
        three grids of error in the gravity anomaly based on
        evaluation of the model using 60x60, 70x70, and 80x80
        terms.
 
        There are also 427 sets of three files from the surface
        reflection investigation.  The new files were based on
        data collected during May-June 1999 and sample the surface
        at latitudes 15S-15N (ingress) and 60-65S (egress).  This
        set of SRX files completes the collection based on the first
        occultation season in MGS Mapping; the next surface
        reflections were obtained starting in December 1999.
 
      MORS_1009
      ---------
        MORS_1009 contains the 75x75 MGS75E gravity model developed
        at JPL and based on MGS radio tracking data collected
        through 2000-09-29.  Both Viking Orbiter and Mariner 9 data
        were also included in the solution.  File JGM75E01.SHA
        contains ASCII coefficients and uncertainties for the
        spherical harmonic model; JGM75E01.SHB is a binary file
        containing both coefficients and covariances.  Gravity
        anomaly is presented as gridded data in JGD75E60.IMG;
        JOD75E60.IMG contains gridded geoid height values.  The
        gridded values were obtained by evaluating the spherical
        harmonic coefficients to degree and order 60.
 
      MORS_1010
      ---------
        MORS_1010 contains 800 atmospheric profiles from radio
        occultations captured during late December 1999 through
        early February 2000.  This was the beginning of the second
        MGS radio occultation season; the set ends when operations
        began in &apos;Beta Supplement&apos; -- a configuration that did not
        allow routine collection of egress occultations.
 
            Dates:                   1999/12/16 - 2000/02/07
            Orbit Numbers:           3458 - 4111
            Number of TPS Files:     800
            Occultation Sense:       389 ingress; 411 egress
            Latitudes:               55N - 63N;   0S - 35S
            Solar Zenith Angles:     112 - 92;    123 - 110
 
        MORS_1010 also contains 43 profiles of electron density in
        the Mars ionosphere.  These were derived from occultations
        captured during the first three weeks of MGS Mapping
        (1999-03-09 through 1999-03-27).  Profiles of the neutral
        atmosphere appeared on MORS_1005.
 
      MORS_1011
      ---------
        MORS_1011 contains 577 atmospheric profiles from ingress
        radio occultations captured during November-December 2000.
        This period included &apos;Campaign F&apos; in mid-December when
        Earth passed through the plane of the MGS orbit and joint
        observations were conducted with TES to compare the two
        atmospheric probing techniques.  MORS_1011 includes 147
        profiles from Campaign F.
 
        The above data were reprocessed and released a second time
        on MORS_1016.  Users should use the results on MORS_1016.
 
        MORS_1011 also includes 134 electron density profiles
        derived from the Campaign F data.  These data were later
        reprocessed; the new results were archived on MORS_1019.
 
      MORS_1012
      ---------
        MORS_1012 contains results from surface reflection analysis
        of 725 radio occultations.  These cover 19 December 1999
        through 31 January 2000, inclusive.  Both ingress and egress
        occultations are included, but few of the egress occultations
        produced detectable surface echoes.
 
      MORS_1013
      ---------
        MORS_1013 contains 826 temperature-pressure profiles derived
        from ingress radio occultation measurements acquired during
        August-October 2000.
 
        The above data were later reprocessed and released a second
        time on MORS_1015.  Users should use the files on MORS_1015.
 
        MORS_1013 also includes 525 sets of three files from the
        surface reflection investigation based on data collected
        during February-March 2000.  Latitudes sampled include
        approximately 32-36S and 48-49S (egress) and 63-68N (ingress).
        Many more ingress occultations were captured during this
        period because of HGA pointing limitations in Beta Supplement
        mode.
 
      MORS_1014
      ---------
        MORS_1014 contains results from surface reflection analysis
        of 793 radio occultations.  These cover January through March
        2001, inclusive.  Both ingress and egress occultations are
        included, but the number of egress occultations is very small
        because of HGA pointing limitations during Beta Supplement
        operations.  Latitudes sampled include approximately 73S
        (egress) and 72-86N (ingress).
 
      MORS_1015
      ---------
        MORS_1015 includes a new 85x85 degree and order solution for
        the gravity field of Mars from the JPL Gravity Science Team
        and a new 80x80 solution from the GSFC gravity group.
 
        ASCII spherical harmonic coefficients for the JPL model are in
        SHA/JGM85F01.SHA; binary coefficients and covariances are in
        SHB/JGM85F01.SHB.  Images of gravity anomalies and the geoid
        are in the IMG directory (files JGD85F60.IMG and JOD85F60.IMG,
        where each has been evaluated from degree 2 up to degree 60.
        The 85F model was derived from Mariner 9, Viking 1/2, and MGS
        data collected through 2001-08-14.
 
        GSFC ASCII spherical harmonic coefficients are in the SHA
        directory (file GGM1025A.SHA).  Images of gravity anomalies
        are in the IMG directory (files GGM1025A.IMG and GGM1025B.IMG,
        where the first was evaluated up to degree 60 and the second
        up to degree 66).  A Postscript file showing gravity anomalies
        is in BRO/GGM1025A.PS1.  The MGM1025 model was derived solely
        from MGS radio tracking data collected through 2001-07-21 and
        from MOLA crossover analyses.
 
        The EDS directory contains 220 ionospheric electron density
        profiles derived from occultation data collected between
        1999/126 and 1999/149.  Latitudes ranged from 64S to 69S,
        while solar zenith angle decreased from 87 to 78 degrees.
        Profiles of the neutral atmosphere appear on MORS_1008.
 
        The TPS directory holds 826 reprocessed atmospheric profiles
        for ingress occultations between August (day 214) and October
        (day 305) in 2000.  The original profiles were released on
        MORS_1013.  The new profiles are more accurate than the
        originals, which contained a small bias caused by motion of
        the spacecraft high-gain antenna.  The old files had names
        of the form ydddHmmA.TPS; the new file names are ydddHmmB.TPS.
        The OCS directory contains an Occultation Summary File
        (008010AB.OCS) for the reprocessed TPS profiles.
 
            Dates:                   2000/08/01 - 2000/10/31
            Orbit Numbers:           6254 - 7379
            Number of TPS Files:     826
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress only
            Latitudes:               67N - 62N
            Solar Zenith Angles:     91 - 86
 
      MORS_1016
      ---------
        The TPS directory contains two sets of atmospheric occultation
        profiles.  First are 125 egress profiles from fixed high-gain
        antenna observations scattered through Beta Supplement
        operations.
 
            Dates:                   2000/05/20 - 2000/05/22
            Orbit Numbers:           5370 - 5393
            Number of TPS Files:     12
            Occultation Sense:       Egress only
            Latitudes:               75S - 77S
            Solar Zenith Angles:     94 - 95
 
            Dates:                   2000/08/08 - 2000/08/09
            Orbit Numbers:           6346 - 6357
            Number of TPS Files:     12
            Occultation Sense:       Egress only
            Latitudes:               73S - 74S
            Solar Zenith Angles:     86 - 87
 
            Dates:                   2000/09/08 - 2000/09/09
            Orbit Numbers:           6726 - 6737
            Number of TPS Files:     4
            Occultation Sense:       Egress only
            Latitudes:               67S - 68S
            Solar Zenith Angles:     86 - 87
 
            Dates:                   2000/10/13 - 2000/10/14
            Orbit Numbers:           7154 - 7165
            Number of TPS Files:     12
            Occultation Sense:       Egress only
            Latitudes:               64S - 65S
            Solar Zenith Angles:     89 - 90
 
            Dates:                   2000/11/17 - 2000/11/20
            Orbit Numbers:           7582 - 7618
            Number of TPS Files:     24
            Occultation Sense:       Egress only
            Latitudes:               65S - 66S
            Solar Zenith Angles:     94 - 95
 
            Dates:                   2000/12/18 - 2000/12/21
            Orbit Numbers:           7961 - 7997
            Number of TPS Files:     25
            Occultation Sense:       Egress only
            Latitudes:               69S - 70S
            Solar Zenith Angles:     99 - 100
 
            Dates:                   2001/01/10 - 2001/01/11
            Orbit Numbers:           8243 - 8254
            Number of TPS Files:     12
            Occultation Sense:       Egress only
            Latitudes:               73S - 74S
            Solar Zenith Angles:     102 - 103
 
            Dates:                   2001/04/05 - 2001/04/06
            Orbit Numbers:           8243 - 8254
            Number of TPS Files:     12
            Occultation Sense:       Egress only
            Latitudes:               89S - 90S
            Solar Zenith Angles:     105 - 106
 
            Dates:                   2001/05/13 - 2001/05/14
            Orbit Numbers:           9747 - 9758
            Number of TPS Files:     12
            Occultation Sense:       Egress only
            Latitudes:               83S - 84S
            Solar Zenith Angles:     96 - 98
 
        Second are 843 reprocessed profiles from November 2000 through
        January 2001.  The November-December 2000 data were previously
        released on MORS_1011; the January 2001 data were released
        through a Stanford website but were not previously delivered
        to PDS.  Files 0325Q18B.TPS and 1029D33B.TPS had appeared in
        the earlier releases (MORS_1011 and web site, respectively)
        but were withdrawn from this release because of severe
        degradation by antenna motion and generally poor data quality,
        respectively.
 
            Dates:                   2000/11/01 - 2001/01/31
            Orbit Numbers:           7380 - 8504
            Number of TPS Files:     843
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress only
            Latitudes:               63N - 78N
            Solar Zenith Angles:     87 - 75
 
        The OCS directory has two files.  005105AA.OCS summarizes
        the newly released egress profiles from May 2000 through
        May 2001.  011101AB.OCS  summarizes the reprocessed profiles
        from November 2000 through January 2001; it supersedes
        011012AA.OCS on MORS_1011 though the earlier file did not
        include the January 2001 data.
 
        Also included in this volume are the first 687 Surface
        Reflection Antenna (SRA) files.  These cover  1999/127
        through 1999/178 and may be used in conjunction with SRG,
        SRI, and SRT files for the same occultations.
 
      MORS_1017
      ---------
        The TPS directory contains 433 ingress occultation profiles
        derived from data collected in April-May 2000.  These data
        were reprocessed to improve the correction for high-gain
        antenna motion during the experiment, so have file names of
        the form ydddHmmB.TPS.  The corresponding ydddHmmA.TPS files
        were generated, but were never archived.
 
            Dates:                   2000/04/01 - 2000/05/31
            Orbit Numbers:           4761 - 5504
            Number of TPS Files:     433
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress only
            Latitudes:               68N - 74N
            Solar Zenith Angles:     87 - 90
 
        The OCS directory includes a single file 004005AB.OCS,
        which contains summary data from the 433 TPS files.
 
        The SRA directory contains 693 surface reflection antenna
        files covering 1999/354-2000/038.
 
      MORS_1018
      ---------
        The TPS directory contains 993 ingress occultation profiles
        derived from data collected in February-June 2001.  These
        data have file names of the form ydddHmmA.TPS.  Scattered
        egress occultations from the same period are in MORS_1016.
 
            Dates:                   2001/02/01 - 2001/06/20
            Orbit Numbers:           8505 - 10212
            Number of TPS Files:     993
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress only
            Latitudes:               85N - 51N
            Solar Zenith Angles:     71 - 97
 
        The OCS directory includes a single file 102106AA.OCS,
        which contains summary data from the 993 TPS files.
 
        The SRA directory contains 599 surface reflection antenna
        files covering 2001/001 - 2001/090.
 
      MORS_1019
      ---------
        The TPS directory contains 360 occultation profiles derived
        from data collected in June and July 2000.  These data have
        file names of the form ydddHmmA.TPS.
 
            Dates:                   2001/06/21 - 2001/07/15
            Orbit Numbers:           10221-10517
            Number of TPS Files:     181
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress
            Latitudes:               51N - 9N
            Solar Zenith Angles:     97 - 114
 
            Dates:                   2001/06/21 - 2001/07/16
            Orbit Numbers:           10221-10534
            Number of TPS Files:     179
            Occultation Sense:       Egress
            Latitudes:               70S - 47S
            Solar Zenith Angles:     87 - 95
 
       The OCS directory includes a single file 106107AB.OCS,
       which contains summary data on the TPS files.
 
       The EDS directory includes 134 reprocessed electron density
       files from 9-21 December 2000; these have file names of the
       form  ydddHmmB.EDS and replace results originally released
       on MORS_1011.  The reprocessing included improved correction
       for high-gain antenna motion, which may have left artifacts
       in the earlier profiles.  There are also 314 new electron
       density files covering 22 December 2000 to 31 January 2001
       with names  ydddHmmA.EDS.
 
       The SHA directory includes ASCII coefficients and uncertainties
       for the JPL 85x85 MGS85H2 spherical harmonic model of the Mars
       gravity field.  The model was derived from MGS, 2001 Mars
       Odyssey, Mars Pathfinder, and Viking 1 Lander data.  No Viking
       Orbiter or Mariner 9 data are included.  The model is
       referenced to a Mars fixed frame similar to the Mars Pathfinder
       orientation model except that the prime meridian has been made
       consistent with the IAU 2000 coordinate frame.
 
      MORS_1020
      ---------
        The TPS directory contains 742 occultation profiles derived
        from data collected in February 2000 and March-May 2002.  The
        data from 2000 were delayed because of problems in the
        reconstructed spacecraft orbits.  The TPS data have file names
        of the form ydddHmmA.TPS.
 
            Dates:                   2000/02/08 - 2000/02/29
            Orbit Numbers:           4112 - 4380
            Number of TPS Files:     170
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress
            Latitudes:               63 - 64 N
            Solar Zenith Angles:     92 - 89
 
            Dates:                   2002/03/14 - 2002/05/17
            Orbit Numbers:           13470 - 14264
            Number of TPS Files:     572
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress
            Latitudes:               66 -63 N
            Solar Zenith Angles:     88 - 91
 
       The OCS directory includes two files (002002AA.OCS and
       203205AA.OCS) which contain summary data on the TPS files.
 
     MORS_1021
     ---------
       The TPS directory contains 1259 occultation profiles derived
       from data collected in March 2000 and from 13 December 2001
       through 13 March 2002.  The data from 2000 were delayed
       because of problems in the reconstructed spacecraft orbits.
       The TPS data have file names of the form ydddHmmA.TPS.  The
       summary file is in the OCS directory.
 
            Dates:                   2000/03/01 - 2000/03/31
            Orbit Numbers:           4381 - 4760
            Number of TPS Files:     214               9
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress           Egress
            Latitudes:               64 - 68 N         47 - 48 S
            Solar Zenith Angles:     89 - 88           106 - 105
            Summary File:                   003003AA.OCS
 
            Dates:                   2001/12/13 - 2002/03/13
            Orbit Numbers:           12368 - 13470
            Number of TPS Files:     563
            Occultation Sense:       Egress
            Latitudes:               11 N - 45 S
            Solar Zenith Angles:     132 - 114
            Summary File:            112203AA.OCS
 
            Dates:                   2002/01/08 - 2002/03/13
            Orbit Numbers:           12678 - 13469
            Number of TPS Files:     473
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress
            Latitudes:               62 - 66 N
            Solar Zenith Angles:     96 - 88
            Summary File:            201203AA.OCS
 
       The SHA directory contains ASCII coefficients for a 90x90
       gravity model (GGM1041C.SHA) developed by the group at
       Goddard Space Flight Center.  This model is based on MGS
       data collected through 27 May 2002.  The IMG directory
       contains maps showing gravity anomalies and the geoid
       evaluated from the first 60, 66, and 72 terms of the 90x90
       model.
 
     MORS_1022
     ---------
       The TPS directory contains 536 occultation profiles derived
       from data collected from May to July 2002, immediately prior
       to solar conjunction when signal-to-noise is lowest.  All
       occultations were ingress occultations.  The TPS data
       have file names of the form ydddHmmA.TPS.  The summary file
       is in the OCS directory.
 
            Dates:                   2002/05/18 - 2002/07/15
            Orbit Numbers:           14265 - 14978
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress           Egress
            Number of TPS Files:     536               0
            Latitudes:               55 - 63 N         N/A
            Solar Zenith Angles:     90 - 92 deg       N/A
            Summary File:                   205207AA.OCS
 
     MORS_1023
     ---------
       The TPS directory contains 523 occultation profiles derived
       from data collected in September and October 2002, immediately
       after solar conjunction when signal-to-noise is lowest.  All
       occultations were ingress occultations.  The TPS data
       have file names of the form ydddHmmA.TPS.  The summary file
       is in the OCS directory.
 
            Dates:                   2002/09/08 - 2002/10/31
            Orbit Numbers:           15648 - 16307
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress           Egress
            Number of TPS Files:     523               0
            Latitudes:               53 - 60 N         N/A
            Solar Zenith Angles:     83 - 89 deg       N/A
            Summary File:                   209210AA.OCS
 
       The EDS directory contains 284 profiles of electron density
       from data collected in November and December 2000.  All of
       these were ingress ionospheric occultations.  The EDS data
       have file names of the form ydddHmmA.EDS.
 
            Dates:                   2000/11/04 - 2000/12/08
            Orbit Numbers:           7380 - 7844
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress           Egress
            Number of Files:         284               0
            Latitudes:               63 - 68 N         N/A
            Solar Zenith Angles:     82 - 87 deg       N/A
 
     MORS_1024
     ---------
       The TPS directory contains 1225 occultation profiles derived
       from data collected between November 2002 and March 2003, as
       Earth-Mars geometry moved from post-conjunction to near-
       opposition.  All occultations were ingress occultations.  The
       TPS data have file names of the form ydddHmmA.TPS.  Two
       summary files are in the OCS directory.
 
            Dates:                   2002/11/01 - 2003/03/21
            Orbit Numbers:           16308 - 18030
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress
            Number of TPS Files:     1225
            Latitudes:               60N to 83 N
            Solar Zenith Angles:     83 to 70
            Summary Files:           211212AA.OCS (Nov-Dec 2002)
                                     301303AA.OCS (Jan-Mar 2003)
 
       The EDS directory includes 840 electron density profiles
       from 1 February to 6 June 2001; these have file names of the
       form  ydddHmmB.EDS.  All are ingress occultations with
       solar zenith angles between 71 and 87 degrees.
 
       The SHA directory includes ASCII coefficients and uncertainties
       for the JPL 85x85 MGS85F2 spherical harmonic model of the Mars
       gravity field.  The model has been adopted by several flight
       projects including Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter and Mars
       Express.  The model is referenced to a Mars fixed frame similar
       to the Mars Pathfinder orientation model except that the prime
       meridian has been made consistent with the IAU 2000 coordinate
       frame.  Also included is the JPL 95x95 model MGS95I, a more
       recent and larger model.
 
     MORS_1025
     ---------
       The TPS directory contains 697 occultation profiles derived
       from data collected between March and June 2003, as
       Earth-Mars geometry moved from post-conjunction to near-
       opposition.  All occultations were ingress occultations.  The
       TPS data have file names of the form ydddHmmA.TPS.  One
       summary file is in the OCS directory.
 
            Dates:                   2003/03/22 - 2003/06/10
            Orbit Numbers:           18039 - 19020
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress
            Number of TPS Files:     697
            Latitudes:               81 N to 69N
            Solar Zenith Angles:     70 - 81
            Summary Files:           303306AA.OCS (Mar-Jun 2003)
 
     MORS_1026
     ---------
       The TPS directory contains 640 occultation profiles derived
       from data collected between June and September 2003, as
       Earth-Mars geometry moved through opposition.  All
       occultations were ingress occultations.  The TPS data have
       file names of the form ydddHmmA.TPS.  One summary file is
       in the OCS directory.
 
            Dates:                   2003/06/18 - 2003/09/10
            Orbit Numbers:           19114 - 20149
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress
            Number of TPS Files:     640
            Latitudes:               65 N to 70N
            Solar Zenith Angles:     82 - 99
            Summary File:            306309AA.OCS (Jun-Sep 2003)
 
     MORS_1027
     ---------
       The TPS directory contains 84 egress occultation profiles
       derived from data collected between September 2002 and
       August 2003, as Earth-Mars geometry moved toward opposition.
       All occultations were collected as part of special egress
       campaigns.  The TPS data have file names of the form
       ydddHmmA.TPS.  One summary file is in the OCS directory.
 
            Dates:                   2002/09/30 - 2003/08/18
            Orbit Numbers:           15924 - 19857
            Occultation Sense:       Egress
            Number of TPS Files:     84
            Latitudes:               62 S to 90 S
            Solar Zenith Angles:     83 - 105
            Summary File:            209308AA.OCS
 
       The EDS directory contains 526 ingress electron density
       profiles collected between November and December 2002.
       File names have the form ydddHmmA.EDS.
 
            Dates:                   2002/11/01 - 2002/12/31
            Orbit Numbers:           16308 - 17051
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress
            Number of EDS Files:     526
            Latitudes:               60 - 74 N
            Solar Zenith Angles:     84 to 76
            Summary File:            none
 
     MORS_1028
     ---------
       The TPS directory contains 405 occultation profiles derived
       from data collected between September and October 2003
       as Earth-Mars geometry moved away from opposition.  The TPS
       file names have the form ydddHmmA.TPS.  One summary file is
       in the OCS directory.
 
            Dates:                   2003/09/11 -    2003/09/11 -
                                      2003/09/28      2003/10/18
            Orbit Numbers:           20150 - 20367   20151 - 20615
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress         Egress
            Number of TPS Files:     172             233
            Latitudes:               60 - 66 N       1 - 45 S
            Solar Zenith Angles:     105 - 98        92 - 124
            Summary File:            309310AA.OCS    309310AA.OCS
 
       The EDS directory contains 650 ingress electron density
       profiles collected between January and March 2003.
       File names have the form ydddHmmA.EDS.
 
            Dates:                   2003/01/01 - 2003/03/21
            Orbit Numbers:           17057 - 18030
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress
            Number of TPS Files:     650
            Latitudes:               73 - 84 N
            Solar Zenith Angles:     76 - 71
            Summary File:            none
 
     MORS_1029
     ---------
       The TPS directory contains 436 occultation profiles derived
       from data collected between November 2003 and January 2004
       as Earth-Mars geometry moved away from opposition.  The TPS
       file names have the form ydddHmmA.TPS.  One summary file is
       in the OCS directory.
 
            Dates:                   2003/11/16 - 2004/01/19
            Orbit Numbers:           20958 - 21752
            Occultation Sense:       Egress
            Number of TPS Files:     436
            Latitudes:               11 N to 11 S
            Solar Zenith Angles:     130 -132
            Summary File:            311401AA.OCS
 
       The EDS directory contains 630 ingress electron density
       profiles collected between March and June 2004. File names
       have the form ydddHmmA.EDS.
 
            Dates:                   2003/03/22 - 2003/06/04
            Orbit Numbers:           18039 - 18948
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress
            Number of EDS Files:     630
            Latitudes:               81 - 69 N
            Solar Zenith Angles:     71-80
            Summary File:            none
 
     MORS_1030
     ---------
       The TPS directory contains 1111 occultation profiles derived
       from data collected between 1 March and 24 May as Mars moved
       toward solar conjunction.  Both ingress and egress
       occultations are included, at virtually a constant 14 degree
       angle from grazing.  The TPS file names have the form
       ydddHmmA.TPS.  One summary file is in the OCS directory.
 
            Dates:                   2004/03/01 - 2004/05/24
            Orbit Numbers:           22255 - 23292
            Occultation Sense:       Egress (691); Ingress (420)
            Number of TPS Files:     1111
            Latitudes:               -26 to -61 (egr); 45 to 37 (ing)
            Solar Zenith Angles:     125 to 109 (egr); 98 to 100 (ing)
            Summary File:            403405AA.OCS
 
       The EDS directory contains 76 ingress electron density
       profiles collected between 22 June and 2 July 2003, about two
       months before opposition.  File names have the form
       ydddHmmA.EDS.
 
            Dates:                   2003/06/22 - 2003/07/02
            Orbit Numbers:           19163 - 19289
            Occultation Sense:       Ingress
            Number of EDS Files:     76
            Latitudes:               68 N
            Solar Zenith Angles:     83 - 85
            Summary File:            none
 
     MORS_1031
     ---------
       The TPS directory contains 819 occultation profiles.  Data
       collected after 21 July were contaminated by anomalous HGA
       motion and solar noise; conjunction was in mid-September.
       Both ingress and egress occultations are included.  TPS file
       names have the form ydddHmmA.TPS.  One summary file is in the
       OCS directory.
 
            Dates:                   2004/05/25 - 2004/07/21
            Orbit Numbers:           23293 - 24002
            Occultation Sense:       Egress (286); Ingress (533)
            Number of TPS Files:     819
            Latitudes:               -72 to -69 (egr); 36 to 34 (ing)
            Solar Zenith Angles:     100 to 92
            Summary File:            405407AA.OCS
 
     MORS_1032
     ---------
       The TPS directory contains 696 occultation profiles.  Early
       data were noisy because of the solar conjunction in September.
       These are mostly ingress occultations; a handful of egress
       occultations were captured in two special campaigns.  TPS file
       names have the form ydddHmmA.TPS.  One summary file is in the
       OCS directory.
 
            Dates:                   2004/10/10 - 2004/12/22
            Orbit Numbers:           24982 - 25878
            Occultation Sense:       Egress (15); Ingress (681)
            Number of TPS Files:     696
            Latitudes:               -66 and -76 (egr); 48 - 68 (ing)
            Solar Zenith Angles:     91 and 96 (egr); 87 to 76 (ing)
            Summary File:            410412AA.OCS
 
     MORS_1033
     ---------
       The TPS directory contains 898 occultation profiles.  Data
       quality improved as the ray path moved away from the Sun
       (solar superior conjunction in September 2004) and Earth-Mars
       distance decreased.  These are mostly ingress occultations; a
       handful of egress occultations were captured in a special
       campaign.  TPS file names have the form ydddHmmA.TPS.  One
       summary file is in the OCS directory.
 
            Dates:                   2004/12/26 - 2005/04/01
            Orbit Numbers:           25923 - 27096
            Occultation Sense:       Egress (9); Ingress (889)
            Number of TPS Files:     898
            Latitudes:               -78 to -79 (egr); 69 to 79 (ing)
            Solar Zenith Angles:     100 (egr); 72 to 76 (ing)
            Summary File:            412504AA.OCS
 
       The SHA directory includes ASCII coefficients and uncertainties
       for the JPL 95x95 MGS95J spherical harmonic model of the Mars
       gravity field.  The model is referenced to a Mars fixed frame
       similar to the Mars Pathfinder orientation model except that
       the prime meridian has been made consistent with the IAU 2000
       coordinate frame.  The model is based on radio tracking data
       from MGS, 2001 Mars Odyssey, Pathfinder, and Viking Lander 1;
       data from the Viking Orbiters and Mariner 9 were omitted
       because they did not seem to improve the solution.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The limitations in this data set follow from the quality of
      the execution, which is described above under Data Coverage
      and Quality.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>96-062A-00E</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

