<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mer2-m-pancam-5-solar-ops-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MER 2 MARS PANORAMIC CAMERA SOLAR RDR OPS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_exploration_rover::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mer2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:pancam.mer2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer2-m-pancam-5-solar-ops-v1.0__browserp_mer2-m-pancam-5-solar-ops-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Bell, J.F. III, The Mars Exploration Rover Athena Panoramic Camera (Pancam)
                   Investigation, Journal of Geophysical Research, June 23, 2003.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BELLETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mars Exploration Rover Mission, Camera Software Interface Specification, 2003
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CAMSIS2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MER2-M-PANCAM-5-SOLAR-OPS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MER 2 MARS PANORAMIC CAMERA SOLAR RDR OPS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2005-02-28</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-01-04T06:53:34.597Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JUSTIN MAKI</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Maki, Justin, MER 2 Mars Panoramic Camera Solar Energy Map Ops
            RDR V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            MER2-M-PANCAM-5-SOLAR-OPS-V1.0, 2005.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Mars Exploration Rover 2 Panoramic Camera Solar Energy Map,
            Operations Reduced Data Record, Version 1.0
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>not applicable</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
 
    Surface Normal for Slopes
    -------------------------
      While the Surface Normal for Slopes product is not archived, it is
      an intermediate product used as an input to the Solar Energy
      products, so it is described once here for brevity.
 
      The Surface Normal for Slopes is a unit vector indicating the
      surface normal for each pixel.  It is derived from the XYZ product
      by fitting a plane over a rover-sized patch in physical space for
      every image pixel in the input stereo images. The surface normal
      is then computed (in Site frame) as the normal to the plane fit.
 
      Note that the Surface Normal for Slopes is not the same as the UVW
      product.  While it uses fundamentally the same algorithm, the UVW
      product is based on a RAT-sized patch and is intended for use with
      IDD operations, while the surface normal used in slope
      calculations is based on a rover-sized patch and is intended for
      use with rover driving.  Also, the Slopes version is in Site
      frame, while the UVW product is expressed in Rover frame.
 
      The symbols Nx, Ny, and Nz are used below to indicate the x,y,z
      components of the unit vector for slopes.
 
 
    Solar Energy Map RDR
    --------------------
      The Solar Energy Map RDR is a single-band floating-point image
      that represents for each pixel the amount of solar energy that
      would be received by the rover if it were located at the point
      represented by that pixel.  It is expressed as a dimensionless
      number between 0 and 1, with 1 representing maximum energy.  It
      is computed as the dot product between the Surface Normal for
      Slopes vector and the Sun Angle:
 
        energy = [cos SA, 0, -cos(90 degrees - SA)] dot [Nx, Ny, Nz]
 
      The Sun Angle is an approximation, usually to the nearest degree.
      It is a single number indicating the maximum elevation of the sun
      at local noon.  This number is changed periodically (on the order
      of a few weeks)to follow the movements of the sun during
      operations, and it differs for Spirit and Opportunity.  The Sun
      Angle used in the calculation is not stored in the label.
      Therefore the Solar Energy product should be used as a guideline
      indicating relative amounts of available energy rather than as a
      calibrated insolation value.
 
      A value of 0.0 is used to indicate lack of data.  This can be
      ambiguous in the rare cases that the computed energy value is
      exactly 0.0.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    MER Camera Payload RDRs are considered Level 3 (Calibrated Data
    equivalent to NASA Level 1-A), Level 4 (Resampled Data
    equivalent to NASA Level 1-B), or Level 5 (Derived Data
    equivalent to NASA Level 1-C, 2 or 3). The RDRs are to be
    reconstructed from Level 2 edited data, and are to be assembled
    into complete images that may include radiometric and/or geometric
    correction.
 
    MER Camera Payload EDRs and RDRs will be generated by JPL&apos;s
    Multimission Image Processing Laboratory (MIPL) under the OPGS
    subsystem of the MER GDS. RDRs will also be generated by the Athena
    Pancam Science and Microscopic Imager Science Teams under the SOAS
    subsystem of the GDS.
 
    RDR data products will be generated by, but not limited to, MIPL
    using the Mars Suite of VICAR image processing software at JPL, the
    Athena Pancam Science Team using IDL software at Cornell University
    and JPL, and the Microscopic Imager Science Team using ISIS software
    at USGS (Flagstaff) and JPL. The RDRs produced will be processed
    data. The input will be one or more Camera EDR or RDR data products
    and the output will be formatted according to this SIS. Additional
    meta-data may be added by the software to the PDS label.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    RDR products generated by MIPL will have a VICAR label wrapped by a
    PDS label, and their structure can include the optional EOL label
    after the binary data. RDR products not generated by MIPL may
    contain only a PDS label. Or, RDR products conforming to a standard
    other than PDS, such as JPEG compressed or certain Terrain products,
    are acceptable without a PDS header during mission operations, but
    may not be archivable.
 
    The RDR data product is comprised of radiometrically decalibrated
    and/or camera model corrected and/or geometrically altered versions
    of the raw camera data, in both single and multi-frame (mosaic)
    form. Most RDR data products will have PDS labels, or if generated
    by MIPL (OPGS), dual PDS/VICAR labels. Non-labeled RDRs include JPEG
    compressed products and the Terrain products.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The MIPL Mars Program Suite was used to generate these RDRs.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    The data set will initially be delivered and kept online.  Upon
    Mission completion, the Panoromic Camera Operations RDRs will be
    delivered to PDS on DVD.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
NULL
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

