<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.grail-l-rss-2-edr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GRAIL MOON RSS RAW DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.gravity_recovery_and_interior_laboratory::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.grail-a::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:lgrs-a.grail-a::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.grail-l-rss-2-edr-v1.0__browserp_grail-l-rss-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.grail-l-rss-2-edr-v1.0__dvo_grail-l-rss-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Deep Space Mission System (DSMS) External Interface Specification (820-013, JPL
                   D-16765), Radio Science Receiver Standard Formatted Data Unit (SFDU), Jet
                   Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JPLD-16765</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GRAIL-L-RSS-2-EDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GRAIL MOON RSS RAW DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2014-04-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2011-09-10</start_time>
        <stop_time>2012-12-18</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DANIEL S. KAHAN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            KAHAN, D.S., GRAIL RSS Raw Data Set V1.0, GRAIL-L-RSS-2-EDR-V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 2012.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw radio science data and ancillary files from the Gravity
            Recovery and Interior Laboratory (GRAIL) mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains archival raw, partially processed, and
            ancillary/supporting radio science data acquired during the
            Gravity Recovery and Interior Laboratory (GRAIL) mission. The
            radio observations were carried out using the twin GRAIL
            spacecraft and Earth-based receiving stations of the NASA Deep
            Space Network (DSN). The observations were used in generating
            high-resolution gravity field models of the Moon. Of most
            interest are likely to be the Orbit Data Files in the ODF
            directory, the Radio Science Receiver files in the RSR directory,
            and the ionospheric and tropospheric media calibration files in
            the ION and TRO directories, respectively. The data set includes
            all raw radio science data collected in the course of the GRAIL
            mission (September 2011 - December 2012).
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Gravity Recovery and Interior Laboratory (GRAIL) Radio
      Science (RSS) Raw Data Archive is a time-ordered collection of
      raw and partially processed data collected during the GRAIL
      mission to the Moon.
 
      The DATA_SET_ID &apos;GRAIL-L-RSS-2-EDR-V1.0&apos; includes the following
      components:
          Instrument host (i.e., &apos;GRAIL&apos;)
          Target (i.e., &apos;L&apos; for Lunar)
          Instrument (i.e., &apos;RSS&apos; for Radio Science Subsystem)
          CODMAC Data processing level number (i.e., &apos;2&apos;)
          Description (i.e., &apos;EDR&apos; for Experiment Data Record)
          Version number (i.e., &apos;V1.0&apos;)
 
      This data set was collected beginning in September 2011.
 
      Two types of measurements were obtained; these are known as
      closed-loop and open-loop recordings.  The closed-loop system
      uses a phase-lock loop in the receiver to track the downlink
      signal, reporting both amplitude and frequency 1-10 times per
      second.  In the open-loop system, the signal is simply converted
      to a baseband frequency range; the entire passband is sampled
      and recorded at 1000 or more samples per second for later
      processing.
 
      Closed-loop data are efficient for characterizing slowly
      changing signals and are the input to operational navigation and
      orbit-determination processes. Open-loop data (because of their
      much higher rate and volume) are usually collected when the
      signal is expected to be very dynamic.
 
      The data set includes two primary data types. Orbit Data Files
      (ODFs) are a product of the closed-loop system, and they are
      specifically targeted to spacecraft navigators and scientists
      interested in gravity fields. Also included are Tracking and
      Navigation Service Data Files (TNFs), the most primitive (and
      most voluminous) product of the closed-loop system. Orbit Data
      Files (ODFs) are compressed versions of TNFs.  In the GRAIL
      context TNFs are not considered to be a primary data type.
      Radio Science Receiver records (RSRs) are the primary data type
      from the open-loop system.
 
      Typical users of these data might analyze range and Doppler
      measurements in ODFs to reconstruct the spacecraft trajectory.
      Relevant questions would include the measurement uncertainties
      in range and Doppler at different DSN antennas; these could set
      constraints on any model of the Moon&apos;s gravity field developed
      later, for example.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      The ODF is a compressed version of the TNF. It contains the most
      important information (range, Doppler and frequency ramps)
      needed by spacecraft navigators and investigators interested
      in determining gravity fields. Each ODF is accompanied by a full
      PDS label which describes both the content and format of the
      associated file. ODF data fields include:
           Narrowband spacecraft VLBI, Doppler mode (cycles)
           Narrowband spacecraft VLBI, phase mode (cycles)
           Narrowband quasar VLBI, Doppler mode (cycles)
           Narrowband quasar VLBI, phase mode (cycles)
           Wideband spacecraft VLBI (nanoseconds)
           Wideband quasar VLBI (nanoseconds)
           One-way Doppler (Hertz)
           Two-way Doppler (Hertz)
           Three-way Doppler (Hertz)
           One-way total count phase (cycles)
           Two-way total count phase (cycles)
           Three-way total count phase (cycles)
           PRA planetary operational discrete spectrum range (range
                units)
           SRA planetary operational discrete spectrum range (range
                units)
           RE(GSTDN) range (nanoseconds)
           Azimuth angle (degrees)
           Elevation angle (degrees)
           Hour angle (degrees)
           Declination angle (degrees)
 
      The Radio Science Receiver (RSR) files are the primary output
      from the Cassini open-loop system and they contain 16-bit
      samples of receiver output. Each RSR file is accompanied by a
      full PDS label which describes both the content and format of
      the file at the bit level [JPLD-16765].
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      ODFs are constructed by the RMDCT; they are constructed so that
      each file contains the data for approximately one day each. ODFs
      are abstracted from subsets of TNF data.
 
      A full PDS label accompanies each ODF file and gives a bit level
      description of the content and format.
 
      The open-loop Radio Science Receiver (RSR) files are screened
      for gaps.  No gaps were found in the RSR files for this archive.
      Each RSR file corresponds to one tracking pass at the DSN.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      ODFs in this archive are primarily 1-sec Doppler S-band data.
      RSRs in this archive are X-Band data.
 
      The typical ODF contains about 3 Mbytes. The typical RSR
      contains from about 30 Mbytes to about 165 Mbytes depending on
      Doppler mode and station (i.e., track duration).
 
      TNFs, from which ODFs originate, are included in this archive
      for completeness.
 
 
    Secondary Data
    ==============
      Secondary data are needed for proper analysis and interpretation
      of the radio data (ODF and RSR). Sky frequency has been computed
      from open-loop data (RSR) by the GRAIL Radio Science Systems
      Group in file type XFR. The TDM contains the same information as
      the XFR except in Tracking Data Message Standard format. The
      Open Loop File (OLF) contains the sky frequency information
      derived from RSR data, but in the format of the ODF.
 
      The &apos;biased TDM&apos; product (BTM) is in exactly the same format as
      the TDM. It is generated by subtracting off a one-way Doppler
      frequency bias at X-band from the TDM file containing the raw
      one-way Doppler measurement provided by the radio science team.
      The one-way Doppler frequency bias was estimated every orbit
      (approximately 2 hours) as part of the gravity field
      determination process and the estimates are reported in the USO1A
      data product (in the LGRS CDR data set). The one-way Doppler bias
      is computed by linearly interpolating the one-way Doppler bias
      time series in the USO1A product to the time tag of the one-way
      Doppler measurement. The computed one-way Doppler bias is then
      subtracted from the original raw TDM value and the result is
      stored in the &apos;biased TDM&apos; product. The &apos;biased TDM&apos; product is
      intended to remove non-linear drifts in the one-way Doppler bias
      induced by solar activity during the GRAIL mission.
 
      The Biased Open Loop File (BOF) is the same format as the OLF and
      is converted from the BTM.
 
 
      Sky Frequency Data (XFR Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Sky frequency (XFR) files are ASCII files with columns as
        follows: year, day of year, seconds past midnight, sky
        frequency, internal processing parameter generated in the
        course of creating the XFR but not relevant to GRAIL, internal
        processing parameter generated in the course of creating the
        XFR but not relevant to GRAIL. Times are in UTC-ERT and values
        were computed from RSR data by the Radio Science Systems Group
        at JPL.
 
      Tracking Data Message Standard (TDM Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        XFR files are converted to TDM format by the Radio Science
        Systems Group at JPL. TDMs are ASCII files, and their complete
        format requirements are described in
        TRACKINDATAMESSAGESTANDARD.TXT in the DOCUMENT directory.
 
      Open Loop File (OLF Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        For users who prefer to work with software designed for closed-
        loop data, TDMs (which originate from open-loop data) are
        converted to the OLF, which is the same (binary) format as the
        (closed-loop) ODF.
 
      Biased Tracking Data Message Standard (BTM Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        BTM files are generated from TDM files as described above.
        BTMs are ASCII files, and their complete format requirements
        are described in TRACKINDATAMESSAGESTANDARD.TXT in the
        DOCUMENT directory.
 
      Biased Open Loop File (BOF Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        For users who prefer to work with software designed for closed-
        loop data, BTMs (which originate from open-loop data) are
        converted to the BOF, which is the same (binary) format as the
        (closed-loop) ODF.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
 
      The ANCILLARY directory contains calibration files EOP (earth
      orientation parameters), ION (ionosphere), TRO (troposphere),
      and WEA (weather).
 
      Earth Orientation Parameter Files (EOP Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Earth Orientation Parameter files are ASCII files; for GRAIL
        they were produced by the Kalman Earth Orientation Filter
        (KEOF) Group at JPL. Typical file size is 24 KB.
 
      Ionosphere Calibration Files (ION Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Ionosphere Calibration files were produced by the Tracking
        System Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL. They provided
        historical and predicted Earth ionospheric conditions. Typical
        file size is 23 KB.
 
      Troposphere Calibration Files (TRO Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Troposphere Calibration files were produced by the Tracking
        System Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL. They provided
        historical and predicted Earth tropospheric conditions.
        Typical file size is 120 KB.
 
      DSN Weather Files (WEA Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        DSN Weather files were produced by the Tracking System
        Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL. Files give weather
        calibration information for DSN complexes. These are ASCII
        files of variable length records. Each record is delimited by
        an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10). WEA files were typically
        released weekly and contained all weather data for the complex
        since 1 January.
 
 
    Naming Conventions
    ==================
      Orbit Data Files (ODFs) and Tracking and Navigation Files (TNFs)
      are named, respectively, as follows:
 
      sssttaayyyy_ddd_hhmmwuudV#.odf,
      sssttaayyyy_ddd_hhmmwuudV#.tnf,
 
      where
      sss     3-character spacecraft identifier
              GRA     GRAIL-A
              GRB     GRAIL-B
              GRX     both
      tt      Target ID, e.g., LU = Moon
      aa      Activity/Experiment ID, e.g. GF = gravity field
      yyyy    year
      ddd     day of year
      hhmm    hours/minutes
      w       Ground Transmitter Band(s):
              N       none
              M       multiple
              S       S-band
              X       X-band
      uu      Uplinking Station(s) = the DSN station number, or
              NN      none
              MM      multiple
      d       way
              1       one-way
              2       two-way
              M       multiple
      V#      version number
 
      Radio Science Receiver (RSR) data, Tracking Data Messages (TDM),
      Sky Frequency Files (XFR), Open Loop Files (OLF), Biased
      Tracking Data Messages (BTM), and Biased Open Loop Files (BOF)
      are named, respectively, as follows:
 
      sssttaayyyyddd_hhmmxuudrrpD.rcs,
      sssttaayyyyddd_hhmmxuudrrpD.tdm,
      sssttaayyyyddd_hhmmxuudrrpD.xfr,
      sssttaayyyyddd_hhmmxuudrrpD.olf
      sssttaayyyyddd_hhmmxuudrrpD.btm,
      sssttaayyyyddd_hhmmxuudrrpD.bof
 
 
      where:
      sss     3-character spacecraft identifier
              GRA     GRAIL-A
              GRB     GRAIL-B
      tt      Target ID, e.g., LU = Moon
      aa      Activity/Experiment ID, e.g. GF = gravity field
      yyyy    year
      ddd     day of year
      hhmm    hours/minutes
      xuu     Uplink Transmitter Band (e.g., S, X) and 2-digit
              Uplinking Station number, or
              &apos;NNN&apos; = 1-way
      drr     Downlink Band (e.g., X) and 2-digit Receiving
              Station number
      p       Polarization
               L      left hand
               R      right hand
               M      mixed
      D       Open-loop data type
               D      RSR data
               V      VSR data
               W      WVSR data
      rcs     RSR number + channel + subchannel
      tdm     Tracking Data Message
      xfr     Sky Frequency File
      olf     Open Loop File
      btm     Biased Tracking Data Message
      bof     Biased Open Loop File
 
      Ionospheric Media Calibration (ION) files, Tropospheric Media
      Calibration (TRO) files, Earth Orientation Parameter (EOP)
      files, and weather (WEA) files are named, respectively, as
      follows:
 
      sssttaaYYYY_DDD_yyyy_ddd.ion,
      sssttaaYYYY_DDD_yyyy_ddd.tro,
      sssttaaYYYY_DDD_yyyy_ddd.eop,
      sssttaaYYYYDDDyyyyddd_##.wea,
 
      where:
      sss     3-character spacecraft identifier
              GRA     GRAIL-A
              GRB     GRAIL-B
              GRX     both
      tt      Target ID, e.g., LU = Moon (Lunar)
      aa      Activity/Experiment ID, e.g. GF = gravity field
      YYYY    start year
      DDD     start day of year
      yyyy    end year
      ddd     end day of year
       ##     DSN complex number
 
 
    Files in the CALIB Directory
    ============================
      Files in the CALIB directory are those likely to have wide
      applicability in working with the raw data.
 
      One file, GRAILCOMPONENTS.TXT is included in the CALIB
      directory. It describes the Spacecraft bus component model with
      dimensions and orientations, as well as the spacecraft
      components specular/diffuse reflectivity properties.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      Software for parsing, reducing, and analyzing data such as these
      has been developed at Stanford University, JPL, and elsewhere.
      Because such software must usually operate at the bit-level and
      is written for a narrow range of platforms, it is not suitable
      for general distribution. No software is included with this
      archival data set.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this archival data set have been collected to support
      radio science investigations, in particular derivation of the
      gravity field of the Moon.  These are similar to data collected
      using other spacecraft and are believed to be generally of good
      quality.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archive underwent PDS external review from August 31, 2012
      to November 30, 2012.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Data coverage in this dataset corresponds to individual tracking
      passes at the DSN. In some cases, supplemental RSR data were
      collected, in which GRAIL-A data were collected during GRAIL-B
      tracks or GRAIL-B data were collected during GRAIL-A tracks.
 
      XFRs, TDMs, OLFs, BTMs, and BOFs were created from RSR data with
      specific parameters and software by the Radio Science Systems
      Group at JPL. Other software or parameters could be used. Based
      on the processing at JPL, data with signal-to-noise ratio less
      than 20 dB-Hz (sometimes higher) were excluded in order to
      eliminate noise that might be interpreted as signal.
 
      Because DSN tracking occurred every day, the RSS EDR data set
      contains data from launch until end of mission, whereas the LGRS
      data sets only cover the periods when the LGRS was turned on.
      Gaps in DSN coverage are either due to normal DSN scheduling
      procedures or from occasional equipment problems. In either
      case, the data set contains all data collected at the DSN.
 
      See mission phases in CATALOG/MISSION.CAT.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The limitations in this data set follow from the coverage and
      quality of the data, as described above.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

