<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mgs-m-rss-1-ext-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MARS GLOBAL SURVEYOR RAW DATA SET - EXT V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_global_surveyor::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mgs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.mgs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-rss-1-ext-v1.0__browserp_geo_mgs-m-rss-1-ext-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-rss-1-ext-v1.0__dvo_atmos_mgs-m-rss-1-ext-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-rss-1-ext-v1.0__dvo_geo_mgs-m-rss-1-ext-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mannucci, A.J., B.D. Wilson, D.N. Yuan, C.H. Ho, U.J. Lindqwister, and T.F.
                   Runge, A Global Mapping Technique for GPS-Derived Ionospheric Total Electron
                   Content Measurements, Radio Science, 33, 565-582, 1998.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MANNUCCIETAL1998</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tyler, G.L., G. Balmino, D.P. Hinson, W.L. Sjogren, D.E. Smith, R. Woo, S.W.
                   Asmar, M.J. Connally, C.L. Hamilton, and R.A. Simpson, Radio Science
                   Investigations with Mars Observer, Journal of Geophysical Research, 97,
                   7759-7779, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TYLERETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MGS-M-RSS-1-EXT-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MARS GLOBAL SURVEYOR RAW DATA SET - EXT V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2002-09-30</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2001-02-01</start_time>
        <stop_time>2004-09-30</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>RICHARD A. SIMPSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Tyler, G.L., G. Balmino, D.P. Hinson, W.L. Sjogren, D.E. Smith,
            R. Woo, J.W. Armstrong, F.M. Flasar, and R.A. Simpson, Mars
            Global Surveyor Raw Data Set - EXT V1.0, MGS-M-RSS-1-EXT-V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This archive contains raw radio science data and ancillary files
            acquired during the Mars Global Surveyor (MGS) extended mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains archival raw, partially processed, and
            ancillary/supporting radio science data acquired during the
            Extended Mission (EXT) phase of the Mars Global Surveyor (MGS)
            mission. The radio observations were carried out using the MGS
            spacecraft and Earth-based receiving stations of the NASA Deep
            Space Network (DSN). The observations were designed to test the
            spacecraft radio system, the DSN ground system, and MGS
            operations procedures; to be used in generating high-resolution
            gravity field models of Mars; and for estimating density and
            structure of the Mars atmosphere. Of most interest are likely to
            be the Orbit Data File and Radio Science Receiver files, in the
            ODF and RSR directories, respectively, which provided the raw
            input to gravity and atmospheric investigations. The EXT phase
            began on 1 February 2001. Data were organized in approximately
            chronological order and delivered on a set of several hundred
            CD-WO volumes at the rate of 2-3 CD&apos;s per week. Typical
            volume of a one-day ODF was 300-400 kB. Typical volume of an RSR
            ranged from 5 to 10 MB, and there could be 0-30 RSR&apos;s per
            day depending on DSN schedules and observing geometry.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Mars Global Surveyor (MGS) Radio Science (RS) Raw Data
      Archive (RDA) is a time-ordered collection of raw and partially
      processed data collected during the MGS Mission to Mars.
      For more information on the investigations proposed see
      [TYLERETAL1992].
 
      This data set was collected during the Extended Mission (EXT)
      phase of MGS -- while the spacecraft was in a near-circular
      orbit and systematically collecting data from Mars.  Some of
      the data supported MGS Navigation activities, but the majority
      went directly to science analysis.
 
      Two types of measurements were conducted during EXT; these
      are known as closed-loop and open-loop recordings.  The closed-
      loop system used a phase-lock loop in the receiver to track the
      downlink signal, reporting both amplitude and frequency at
      rates typically of 1-10 times per second.  In the open-loop
      system, the signal was simply converted to a baseband frequency
      range; the entire passband was sampled and recorded for later
      processing.  Typical open-loop sampling rates for MGS were
      5000 samples per second.  Closed-loop data are efficient for
      characterizing slowly changing signals; open-loop data
      (because of their much higher volume) are collected only
      when the signal is very dynamic -- such as during an
      occultation.
 
      The data set includes three primary data types.  Archival
      Tracking Data Files (ATDFs or TDFs) are the most primitive (and
      most voluminous) product of the closed-loop system.  Orbit Data
      Files (ODFs) are edited versions of ATDFs, specifically
      targeted to spacecraft navigators and scientists interested in
      gravity fields.  Original Data Records (ODRs) are the primary
      data type from the open-loop system.
 
      Typical users of these data might analyze range and Doppler
      measurements in ATDFs or ODFs to derive the spacecraft
      trajectory during EXT.  Relevant questions would include the
      measurement uncertainties in range and Doppler at different DSN
      antennas; these could set constraints on any model of Mars&apos;
      gravity field developed later, for example.  Users of ODRs
      could identify and characterize anomalous signals within the
      recorded passband, derive the drift of the UltraStable
      Oscillator (USO), and calculate Allan Deviation for various
      radio science configurations.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      The ATDF is the primary output from the MGS closed-loop system.
      ATDFs have 150 fields, though not all had been assigned during
      the MGS era.   Each ATDF in the data set is accompanied by a
      full PDS label which defines both the content and the format
      of the file at the bit level.  ATDF data fields include:
           Range
           High- or low-rate Doppler
           High or low-rate downlink phase
           Differential Range vs Integrated Doppler (DRVID)
           Allan deviation
           Smoothed noise
           Uplink phase
      Other information included in ATDF data records is date and
      time; spacecraft ID; ground station and its configuration;
      status flags and values reported by various ground systems;
      calibration values, noise estimates, and tolerances (station
      delay, transmitter power, etc.); and signal strength.
 
      The ODF is an edited version of the ATDF; it is a smaller file,
      issued more frequently than the ATDF.  It contains the most
      important information (range and Doppler) needed by spacecraft
      navigators and investigators interested in determining
      gravitational fields of bodies such as Mars.  Each ODF is
      accompanied by a full PDS label which describes both the
      content and format of the associated file.  ODF data fields
      include:
           Narrowband spacecraft VLBI, Doppler mode (cycles)
           Narrowband spacecraft VLBI, phase mode (cycles)
           Narrowband quasar VLBI, Doppler mode (cycles)
           Narrowband quasar VLBI, phase mode (cycles)
           Wideband spacecraft VLBI (nanoseconds)
           Wideband quasar VLBI (nanoseconds)
           One-way Doppler (Hertz)
           Two-way Doppler (Hertz)
           Three-way Doppler (Hertz)
           One-way total count phase (cycles)
           Two-way total count phase (cycles)
           Three-way total count phase (cycles)
           PRA planetary operational discrete spectrum range (range
                units)
           SRA planetary operational discrete spectrum range (range
                units)
           RE(GSTDN) range (nanoseconds)
           Azimuth angle (degrees)
           Elevation angle (degrees)
           Hour angle (degrees)
           Declination angle (degrees)
 
      Open loop data records (ODRs) contain 8- or 12-bit samples of
      receiver output.  Each block of (typically) 1000 data samples
      is accompanied by a 166 byte header.  Each ODR is accompanied
      by a full PDS label which describes both the content and format
      of the file at the bit level.  Header information includes:
           Date and time of the first data sample
           Sample rate and channel assignments
           Receiver local oscillator (POCA) frequency
           Attenuator settings
           RMS voltages at several stages in the receiving chain
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      ATDFs are screened for &apos;bad&apos; data points, which are removed
      before the file is released by the JPL Radio Metric Data
      Conditioning Team (RMDCT).
 
      ODFs are abstracted from subsets of ATDF data.
 
      The open-loop data delivered to Stanford were usually in the
      ODS (Original Data Stream) format.  ODS packets were converted
      to the older ODR (Original Data Record) format for consistency
      in subsequent processing and archive.  Headers applied by the
      Ground Data System (GDS) during packet handling have not been
      retained; they contained no additional information about the
      data acquisition.  In some cases, where the GDS corrupted the
      ODS during delivery, lost it entirely, or were unable to
      deliver it electronically because of volume constraints, data
      have been recovered from tape in ODR format.  The resultant
      data (whether from ODS conversion or tape) accurately
      represent the output of the DSCC Spectrum Processing (DSP)
      Subsystem at the DSN station.  A full PDS label accompanies
      each ODR file and gives a bit level description of the content
      and format.
 
      A 32-byte label at the beginning of each ODR tape (when tape
      was used) is not included in the data file.  The 32-byte label
      gives the version of the data taking software; this information
      has been copied to the PDS label that accompanies the data
      file.   The software version recorded in the &apos;NOTE&apos; keyword is
      more likely to be accurate than the version recorded with the
      &apos;SOFTWARE_VERSION&apos; keyword.  Because the 32-byte label is no
      longer part of the data stream, users can treat the remaining
      file as an integral number of fixed-length records.  The
      32-byte label was never defined in the ODS.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      Data are stored on CD-WO volumes approximately chronologically.
      This data set contains data from the MGS EXT phase only.
      CD volumes were usually defined by the dates of included
      spacecraft engineering and DSN monitor data (data types ECH and
      MCH, respectively).  ECH and MCH files were the most regular,
      and often the largest, collected on a daily basis.  Files of
      other types were sometimes delayed in delivery to Stanford and
      may be out of strict chronological order on the CDs.  Users
      should consult listings in the INDEX/CUMINDEX.TAB file to
      ascertain full coverage of each data type.  Users working with
      dates near the beginning and end of the EXT phase should
      check INDEX/CUMINDEX.TAB in the data set covering the adjacent
      phase for files that appear to be missing; in general, files
      that bridge a phase boundary were stored with the earlier
      data set only.
 
      ATDFs were delivered approximately weekly during MGS EXT.
      ATDFs are stored in the TDF directory on archival volumes.
      File names are of the form   ydddeeeC.TDF  where  y  is the
      one-digit year of the first data,  ddd  is the three-digit
      day-of-year of the first data,  eee  is the three-digit day-
      of-year of the last data, and  C  is a single letter (beginning
      with &apos;A&apos;) denoting the sequence in which files with the same
      ydddeee  were handled.  Generally  ydddeeeB.TDF  is a revised
      version of  ydddeeeA.TDF.  The PDS label has file name
      ydddeeeC.LBL.  The typical ATDF contains about 39 Mbytes.
 
      ODFs were typically issued daily throughout MGS EXT; during
      periods of high spacecraft activity (such as around maneuvers)
      ODFs were released more often.  Most  ODFs released
      during EXT are included in the archival data set.  Of those
     that were missed, most were generated by special request, and
      Stanford did not receive a release notice.  ODFs are stored in
      the ODF directory.  File names are of the form   ydddeeeC.ODF
      where the file name components are the same as for the ATDF
      (previous paragraph).  In most cases  ydddeeeB.ODF was NOT
      simply a revised version of  ydddeeeA.ODF;  there were many
      requests for special ODF processing -- to obtain higher time
      resolution over short intervals, for example.  The PDS label
      has file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical ODF file sizes are small
      multiples of 8064 bytes (e.g., less than 100 kB).
 
      Original Data Records (ODRs) were produced whenever the DSP
      was set to &apos;run&apos; mode.  These files are stored in the ODR
      directory.  In most cases, the entire DSP run was collected
      into a single ODR file.  But in other cases, it was more
      convenient to subdivide the DSP data; queries were issued for
      shorter time spans, and separate files were produced.  File
      names are of the form  ydddhhmm.ODR  where  y  is the one-digit
      year of the first data,  ddd  is the day-of-year of the first
      data,  hh  is the hour on which the first sample was taken, and
      mm  was the minute on which the first sample was taken.  In
      cases where two files had the same  ydddhhmm  (for example, two
      DSN stations began recording at the same time, or a second query
      was submitted for data which appeared suspicious after the
      first query was processed), the less significant digit in  mm
      of the second file was converted to a letter (&apos;0&apos; became &apos;A&apos;,
      &apos;1&apos; became &apos;B&apos;, ..., &apos;9&apos; became &apos;J&apos;).  In cases were three files
      had the same  ydddhhmm, the less significant  mm  digit was
      converted to &apos;K&apos;, &apos;M&apos;, etc.  The PDS label has file name
      ydddhhmm.LBL.
 
      At 5000 12-bit samples per second, a 7-minute occultation would
      yield a 3.5 MB ODR -- one X-band (RCP) channel; 5 records per
      second, each with 1000 12-bit samples and a 166-byte header.
 
      Two one-hour surface scattering experiments were conducted on
      5 August 2001.  These data were collected in two channels (RCP
      and LCP) with 50000 8-bit samples per second in each channel
      using the DSP.  The data were also captured using one RSR on
      X-RCP and another on X-LCP.  The sampling rate for each RSR
      was 25000 I/Q pairs per second.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      An extensive set of ancillary files is needed for proper
      analysis and interpretation of the radio data (file types
      TDF, ODF, and ODR).  These are organized in parallel
      directories and stored approximately chronologically.  When
      a file type is not represented on a CD-WO volume, the
      corresponding directory has been omitted.  With the exception
      of files stored in the CALIB directory, ancillary files
      appear on only one CD-WO volume.  Users should refer to
      the INDEX/CUMINDEX.TAB listing to locate ancillary files.
 
      Files in the CALIB Directory
      ----------------------------
        Files in the CALIB directory are those likely to have wide
        applicability in working with the raw data.  They help
        unpack and allow use of the raw data, rather than being
        &apos;instrument&apos; calibration data per se.  They include
        decommutation maps, clock conversion files, files of
        planetary constants, leapsecond files, and files needed for
        display of data on the MGS Science Operations Planning
        Computer (SOPC).  Each file is accompanied by a PDS minimal
        label.
 
        Clock Conversion files were produced by the JPL/PDS
        Navigation Ancillary Information Facility (NAIF) for use
        with NAIF-developed and MGS-provided software.  These are
        ASCII files of variable length records.  Each record is
        delimited by an ASCII carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13)
        line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10), which may need to be
        converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt; before the file is used
        on the local machine.  File names have the form  TSCnnnnn.SCK
        where  nnnnn  is a sequence number beginning with  00001
        and the file with the highest number is the most recent.
        The value of  nnnnn  is set by NAIF.
 
        Planetary Constants files were produced by the JPL/PDS
        Navigation Ancillary Information Facility (NAIF) for use
        with NAIF-developed and MGS-provided software.  These are
        ASCII files of variable length records.  Each record is
        delimited by an ASCII carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13)
        line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10), which may need to be
        converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt; before the file is used
        on the local machine.  File names have the form  PCKydddC.TPC
        where  y  is the one-digit year of the file creation date,
        ddd  is the day-of-year of the file creation date, and  C
        is a character denoting sequence when more than one file
        with the same  yddd  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos;
        and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers
        of similar coverage files.
 
        Leapsecond files were produced by the JPL/PDS
        Navigation Ancillary Information Facility (NAIF) for use
        with NAIF-developed and MGS-provided software.  These are
        ASCII files of variable length records.  Each record is
        delimited by an ASCII carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13)
        line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10), which may need to be
        converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt; before the file is used
        on the local machine.  File names have the form  LSKydddC.TLS
        where  y  is the one-digit year of the file creation date,
        ddd  is the day-of-year of the file creation date, and  C
        is a character denoting sequence when more than one file
        with the same  yddd  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos;
        and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers
        of similar coverage files.
 
        Channel Conversion Language files come in three types --
        source, dependency, and binary.  File names are of the
        forms  CCLydddS.SRC,  CCLydddD.BIN,  and  CCLydddB.BIN,
        respectively, where  y  is the one-digit year of the file
        creation date and  ddd  is the day-of-year of the file
        creation date.  Source files are ASCII files of variable
        length records.  Each record is delimited by an ASCII
        carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII
        10), which may need to be converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt;
        before the file is used on the local machine.  Dependency and
        binary files are identical to those used on the SOPC.  Source
        and binary files are typically 500 kB; dependency files are
        typically 15 kB.  Channel Conversion Language files are used
        in converting raw binary data in telemetry streams to
        meaningful numbers.
 
        Channel Parameter Table files come in two types -- source and
        binary.  File names are of the forms  CPTydddS.SRC  and
        CCLydddB.BIN, respectively, where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the file creation date and  ddd  is the day-of-year of the
        file creation date.  Source files are ASCII files of variable
        length records.  Each record is delimited by an ASCII
        carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII
        10), which may need to be converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt;
        before the file is used on the local machine.  Binary files
        are identical to those used on the SOPC.  Source and binary
        files are typically less than 1 MB.  Channel Parameter Table
        files are used in converting raw binary data in telemetry
        streams to meaningful numbers.
 
        Template Description Language files come in two types --
        source and binary.  File names are of the forms  TDLydddS.SRC
        and  TDLydddB.BIN, respectively, where  y  is the one-digit
        year of the file creation date and  ddd  is the day-of-year
        of the file creation date.  Source files are ASCII files of
        variable length records.  Each record is delimited by an
        ASCII carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt;
        (ASCII 10), which may need to be converted to either &lt;CR&gt;
        or &lt;LF&gt; before the file is used on the local machine.  Binary
        files are identical to those used on the SOPC.  Source and
        binary files are typically less than 1 MB.  Template
        Description Language files are used during display of data on
        the SOPC.
 
        Decommutation Map files come in two types -- source and
        binary.  File names are of the forms  DCSxxxxx.SRC  and
        DCOxxxxx.BIN, respectively, where  xxxxx  is a mnemonic for
        the map.  Source files are ASCII files of variable length
        records.  Each record is delimited by an ASCII carriage-
        return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10), which
        may need to be converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt; before the
        file is used on the local machine.  Binary files are identical
        to those used on the SOPC.  Source and binary files are
        typically less than 200 kB.  Decommutation Map files are used
        in converting raw binary packet data to channelized formats.
        On the SOPC, they are used with the MGS-provided program
        mapx.
 
        Antenna Reconstruction Files are typically used in conjunction
        with Antenna Gimbal Kernel (AGK) files to determine the
        pointing of an antenna or the position of its phase center
        with respect to the spacecraft center of mass.  There are
        three types of Antenna Reconstruction Files: the Antenna SPK
        (ASP) File, the Hinge CK (HCK) File, and the Text Frame Kernel
        (TFK) File.  An ASP file contains the locations of low-gain
        antennas and boom lengths for the high-gain antenna (HGA).
        The HCK file contains hinge angles for the (deployed) HGA.
        The TFK file contains information on coordinate frame
        definitions for translating between the spacecraft frame and
        the frame of the high-gain antenna.  File names are of the
        forms HGAnnnnn.ASP, HINGEnnn.HCK, and HGAnnnnn.TFK, where the
        &apos;n&apos; string gives a sequence number.  ASP and HCK files are
        ASCII files in NAIF transfer format; TFK files are ASCII
        files.  In all cases, each record is delimited by the ASCII
        carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10)
        pair.  On some systems it may be necessary to convert the
        &lt;CR&gt;&lt;LF&gt; pair to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt; before using the file on
        the local machine.  Each Antenna Reconstruction File is
        accompanied by a PDS minimal label with the same file name
        except for an extension of .LBL.
 
      Antenna Gimbal Kernel Files (AGK Directory)
      -------------------------------------------
        Antenna Gimbal Kernel files were produced by NAIF.  Each AGK
        file contains information on the state of the HGA azimuth
        and elevation gimbals as a function of time.  These are ASCII
        files in NAIF transfer format.  Each record is delimited by
        an ASCII carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed (LF&gt; (ASCII
        10) pair, which may need to be converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or
        &lt;LF&gt; before the file is used on the local machine.  File
        names have the form  ydddeeeZ.AGK  where  &apos;y&apos; is the least
        significant digit of the year in which data in the file begin,
        &apos;ddd&apos; is the day-of-year when data  begin, &apos;eee&apos; is the
        day-of-year when data end, and &apos;Z&apos; is a  single upper case
        letter indicating order of files when there is more than one
        with the same &apos;ydddeee&apos; in the data set.  Z  is &apos;A&apos; for the
        first file, &apos;B&apos; for the second, etc.  Each AGK file is
        accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        ydddeeeZ.LBL.  Typical file sizes are 1 MByte.
 
      Angular Momentum Desaturation Files (AMD Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Angular Momentum Desaturation files were produced by the MGS
        Spacecraft Team (SCT).  Each AMD file documents a set of AMD
        events on the spacecraft.  These are ASCII files of variable
        length records.  Each record is delimited by an ASCII
        carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII
        10), which may need to be converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt;
        before the file is used on the local machine.  File names
        have the form  ydddeeeC.AMD  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee
        is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each AMD file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are less than 1500
        bytes.
 
      Browse Files (BRO Directory)
      ----------------------------
        Browse files are composite PostScript files summarizing
        quick-look processing of ODR or RSR data.  Each file has a
        name of the form  ydddhhmm.PSn  where  ydddhhmm  is identical
        to the character string in the source ODR or RSR file and  n
        is the receiver channel represented in the data.  Each BRO
        file is accompanied by a detached PDS label with name
        ydddhhmm.LBL.  Only one channel  n  is expected from each ODR
        or RSR.  Each PostScript file is sized to fit on a single
        8-1/2x11 inch page.  Each landscape format page includes four
        panels showing a histogram of raw data (12-bit) samples (upper
        left), one-minute average power spectra derived from the
        raw samples (upper right), one-second averages of raw sample
        power versus time (lower left), and an extract of the first
        few lines of the source ODR or RSR PDS label (lower right).
        BRO files may be helpful in quickly scanning data to determine
        which files are suitable for closer study.
 
      Channelized Engineering Data Files (ECH Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Channelized Engineering Data files were produced by the MGS
        query server, operating on telemetry packets stored in the
        MGS Central Data Base (CDB).  These are binary files, usually
        representing the collection of raw spacecraft engineering
        data received from a 24 hour period; they are not readily
        interpretable by end users.  File names have the form
        ydddeeeC.ECH  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee
        is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each ECH file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  File sizes can be as large as 200 MB.
        In general, an ECH file can be derived from the corresponding
        EPK file using MGS-provided software and a decommutation map.
 
        Also in some ECH directories are ASCII tables of extracted
        channel values--channelized state vectors, or CSV files.
        These are values for a limited number of potentially
        useful ECH channels that have been saved in tabular form.
        CSV files in the ECH directory have names of the form
        CSVydddC.ECH  where  y,  ddd,  and  C  are the same as for
        the corresponding ECH file.  Each CSV file is accompanied
        by a detached PDS label with name  CSVydddC.LBL  which
        completely describes the format and content of the CSV file.
 
      Engineering Channelized Data Summary Files (ECS Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Engineering Channelized Summary Data Files were created at
        Stanford during ingestion of spacecraft engineering data.
        Each file contains a summary line for each channel processed
        from the previous day&apos;s telemetry.  The ECS file thus gives
        a snapshot (mean and standard deviation) of each channel
        on each day.  ECS files are PDS TABLE objects; each is
        fully described as to format and content by a detached PDS
        label.  File names are of the form  ydddeeeC.ECS  where
        y  is the one-digit year of the first data,  ddd  is the
        three-digit day-of-year of the first data,  eee  is the
        three-digit day-of-year of the last data,  and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file with
        the same  ydddeee  is handled.  File sizes vary depending
        on the number of channels processed; typical growth is
        4000 bytes per day.
 
      Engineering Channel Table Files (ECT Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Engineering Channel Table Data Files are created at Stanford
        during ingestion of spacecraft engineering data.  Each ECT
        file is an ASCII table of time-ordered values from a single
        spacecraft engineering channel, and each file is fully
        described by a detached PDS label.  File names are of the
        form  XXXydddC.ECT  where  XXX  is a unique identifier for
        the engineering channel,  y  is the one-digit year of the
        first data,  ddd  is the three-digit day-of-year of the first
        data,  and  C  is a character denoting sequence when more
        than one file with the same  yddd  is handled.  File sizes
        vary depending on the rate at which a channel was sampled;
        they are typically under 100 kB.  The detached label has
        file name  XXXydddC.LBL.
 
      Experimenters Notebook Files (ENB Directory)
      --------------------------------------------
        Experimenters Notebook files are e-mail messages and other
        notes collected during and shortly after data acquisition.
        They document expectations of various measurements and
        anomalies discovered in subsequent analysis.  File names
        have the form  ENByyddd.TXT,  where  yy  is the two-digit
        year and  ddd  is the three-digit day-of-year.  In general
        the messages in file  ENByyddd.TXT  refer to activities on
        that date regardless of when the message was sent.  These
        are ASCII files with variable length records.  Each record
        is delimited by an ASCII carriage-return line-feed pair.
 
      Earth Orientation Parameter Files (EOP Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Earth Orientation Parameter files were produced by the Time
        and Earth Motion Precision Observation (TEMPO) Group at JPL.
        They documented and predicted Earth rotation (rate and axis).
        These are ASCII files of variable length records.  Each
        record is delimited by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).
        File names have the form  ydddzeee.EOP  where  y  is
        the one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is
        the day-of-year of the first data in the file,  z  is the
        one-digit year of the last data, and  eee  is the day-of-year
        of the last data in the file.  EOP files were typically
        released on Tuesdays and Fridays.  There are both &apos;long&apos;
        and &apos;short&apos; versions.  The long file covered past motion
        since about 1962 and a prediction for about three months into
        the future; these files have typical sizes of 860 kB.  The
        short file covered the most recent nine months of past motion
        and a prediction for three months into the future; these
        files are typically 30 kB.  Each EOP file is accompanied
        by a PDS minimal label with file name  ydddzeee.LBL.
 
      Engineering Packet Data Files (EPK Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Engineering Packet Data files were produced by the MGS
        query server, operating on telemetry packets stored in the
        MGS Central Data Base (CDB).  These are binary files, usually
        representing the collection of raw spacecraft engineering
        data received from a 24 hour period; they are not readily
        interpretable by end users.  File names have the form
        ydddeeeC.EPK  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee
        is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each EPK file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  File sizes can be as large as 100 MB.
        No EPK files were collected during EXT; all engineering
        data are in ECH files.
 
      Filtered Body Rate Files (FBR Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Filtered Body Rate Files were created at Stanford from
        body rate data in the spacecraft engineering telemetry
        stream.  They give spacecraft attitude as a function of
        time.  FBR files are PDS TABLE objects; each is
        fully described as to format and content by a detached PDS
        label.  File names are of the form  ydddeeeC.FBR  where
        y  is the one-digit year of the first data,  ddd  is the
        three-digit day-of-year of the first data,  eee  is the
        three-digit day-of-year of the last data,  and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file with
        the same  ydddeee  is handled.  File sizes vary depending
        on the time interval covered.  FBR files were created
        during MGS Cruise to support gravitational wave
        experiments (GWE); no FBR files were created during the
        EXT Phase.
 
      GEODYN Trajectory Files (GDN Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        GEODYN SPK files were quick look orbit reconstructions
        produced by the MOLA Precise Orbit Determination Team.  They
        were used for preliminary analysis of MOLA data and some radio
        occultations.  These files give spacecraft and planetary
        ephemerides and are identical in format to SPK files (see
        below) by the MGS NAV Team.  Files with ORIGINAL_PRODUCT_ID
        including &apos;qlnn&apos; were based on the following gravity models:
                 ql15   mgm0989a
                 ql16   mgm0989c
                 ql17   gmm2b (with no one-way Doppler daya)
                 ql18   gmm2b (with one-way Doppler data if available)
        These are ASCII files of variable length records in a special
        NAIF &apos;transfer&apos; format.  Each record is delimited by a
        carriage-return (ASCII 13) line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10) pair,
        which may need to be removed before the file is used on the
        local machine.  After delimiter conversion (if needed) the
        file would ordinarily be passed through the NAIF utility
        SPACIT  or  TOBIN  to convert it to the local binary format.
        File names have the form  ydddeeeC.GDN  where  y  is the
        one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd
        is the day-of-year of the first data in the file,  eee  is the
        day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file
        with the same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and
        progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of
        similar coverage files.  Each GDN file is accompanied by a
        PDS minimal label with file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file
        sizes are less than 5 MB.
 
      GEODYN Trajectory Files (GDF Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        GDF files are the same as GDN files (above) except that they
        are considered &apos;final&apos; versions of the orbits.  File names
        end with the .GDF suffix.  No GDF files were created during
        the EXT phase; all GEODYN reconstructions appear in the GDN
        directory.
 
      Daily Health Report Files (HEA Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Daily Health Report Files were created at Stanford; they
        summarize spacecraft engineering data of interest for Radio
        Science, list recently acquired radio data, summarize any
        analysis performed on recent radio data, summarize anomalies
        in recent radio science operations, and list files that have
        been obtained from the MGS CDB or other sources.  Daily
        Health Report Files are PDS TEXT objects; each has an
        attached PDS label.  File names are of the form  HEAydddC.TXT
        where  y  is the one-digit year of the report,  ddd  is the
        three-digit day-of-year of the report,  and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file with
        the same  ydddeee  is generated.  The first report on a day
        would be  HEAydddA.TXT;  subsequent revisions or updates
        would be  HEAydddB.TXT,  HEAydddC.TXT,  etc.
 
        Some Health Reports are accompanied by plots, saved as
        PostScript files.  File names for these plot files
        have names of the form  HEAydddC.PSn  where  y  and  ddd
        are as defined above and  n  is the figure number.
        The PostScript files are accompanied by a detached
        PDS label with name  HEAydddC.LBL.
 
        Both Health Reports themselves and accompanying PostScript
        files have variable length records delimited by carriage-
        return (ASCII 13) line-feed (ASCII 10) pairs.
 
      Ionosphere Calibration Files (ION Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Ionosphere Calibration files were produced by the Tracking
        System Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL.  They
        documented and predicted Earth ionospheric conditions.
        These are ASCII files of variable length records.  Each
        record is delimited by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).
        File names have the form  ydddeeeC.ION  where  y  is
        the one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is
        the day-of-year of the first data in the file,  eee  is the
        day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file with the
        same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses
        to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage
        files.  ION files were usually released at one week
        intervals to cover a single month;  ydddeeeA.ION  would be
        the file released during the first week,  ydddeeeB.ION  would
        be the file released during the second week, etc.  Each ION
        file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are less than 50 kB.
 
        In mid-2003 the method of producing Ionosphere Calibration
        files was improved.  Global Ionosphere Map (GIM) software
        created daily Global Ionospheric Maps from global GPS data.
        Each day, a final map was created for the UT day three days
        previously and a preliminary map was created for the UT day
        immediately before.  Also created were predict maps a couple
        times a week by averaging recent &apos;normal&apos; days. Then the
        software evaluated the maps at the spacecraft line-of-sight
        and fitted the results to a normalized polynomial versus
        time over each spacecraft pass.  This was done for all
        three modes: final, preliminary, and predict.  Then the
        software selected the best available calibration for each
        pass (in priority order final &gt; preliminary &gt; predict).
        Then the operator ran a plotting program to view all of the
        calibrations and overrode the default selections where
        desired.  The mapping technique is described by
        [MANNUCCIETAL1998].
 
 
      Light Time Files (LIT Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Light Time files were produced by the MGS Navigation Team
        (NAV).  They gave radio propagation time from the spacecraft
        to Earth vs time.  These are ASCII files of fixed
        length records.  Each record is delimited by an ASCII
        carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII
        10), which may need to be converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt;
        before the file is used on the local machine.  File names
        have the form  ydddeeeC.LIT  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee
        is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each LIT file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are less than 1 MB.
 
      Channelized DSN Monitor Data Files (MCH Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Channelized DSN Monitor Data files were produced by the MGS
        query server, operating on DSN Monitor packets stored in the
        MGS Central Data Base (CDB).  These are binary files, usually
        representing the collection of DSN Monitor data received from
        a 24 hour period; they are not readily interpretable by end
        users.  File names have the form  ydddeeeC.MCH  where  y  is
        the one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is
        the day-of-year of the first data in the file,  eee  is the
        day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file with the
        same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses
        to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage
        files.  With few exceptions C was always &apos;A&apos; until early
        2003, at which time the method for generating (and, hence,
        processing) the files changed.
 
        In early 2003, generation of the Monitor data was changed
        as part of the Network Simplification Plan (NSP). New
        channels were defined, and it became impossible to handle
        data from multiple stations in a single file because over
        the first six months of 2003 some stations were generating
        the old formats and some were generating the new. Instead,
        the data were collected individually according to antenna
        number.  The character C in the file name was interpreted
        as follows:
                     Character C      Antenna Number
                     -----------      --------------
                          A           all (pre-2003)
                          B                 14
                          C                 15
                          D                 16
                          E                 24
                          F                 25
                          G                 26
                          H                 27
                          I                 28
                          J                 34
                          K                 43
                          L                 45
                          M                 46
                          N                 54
                          O                 55
                          P                 63
                          Q                 65
                          R                 66
 
        Each MCH file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label
        with file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  File sizes can be as large as
        30 MB.  In general, an MCH file can be derived from the
        corresponding MPK file using MGS-provided software and a
        decommutation map; but this was almost never done for
        Mars Global Surveyor.  Monitor data are collected according
        to MST (Monitor Sample Time) measured in UTC.
 
        Also in some MCH directories are ASCII tables of extracted
        channel values--channelized state vectors, or CSV files.
        These are values for a limited number of potentially
        useful MCH channels that have been saved in tabular form.
        CSV files in the MCH directory have names of the form
        CSVydddC.MCH  where  y,  ddd,  and  C  are the same as for
        the corresponding MCH file.  Each CSV file is accompanied
        by a detached PDS label with name  CSVydddC.LBL  which
        completely describes the format and content of the CSV file.
        CSV files were generated only for pre-NSP data.
 
      Monitor Channel Tables (MCT Directory)
      --------------------------------------
 
        Monitor Channel Tables were derived from MCH files at
        Stanford.  Each table lists a single Monitor channel versus
        time in an ASCII PDS TABLE format.  File names have the form
        XXXydddC.MCT  where  XXX is a three-character mnemonic for
        the channel,  y  is the one-digit year,  ddd  is the three-
        digit day-of-year, and  C  is a single character (starting
        with &apos;A&apos;) denoting the version.  For NSP-derived MCT files,
        C denotes the source antenna (see assignments under MCH
        above).  Each  MCT  file is accompanied by a PDS label with
        file name  XXXyddC.LBL which completely describes both the
        content and the format of the table.  Examples of pre-2003
        MCT files include:
 
           XXX  Description
           ---  ---------------------------------------------
           AGC  AGC level from M-0349 (Ant A, Rcv A)
           DSS  DSS antenna ID from M-0300
           ELA  Elevation angle from M-0304 (Ant A)
           TSY  System temperature from M-0725 (Ant A, Rcv A)
           TSZ  System temperature from M-0725 (Ant A, Rcv B)
 
        Examples of NSP-based MCT files include:
 
           XXX  Description
           ---  ---------------------------------------------
           AZA  Antenna azimuth angle
           CON  CONSCAN drive status
           DTA  Antenna number
           ELV  Antenna elevation angle
           SNT  System noise temperature
 
      Maneuver Implementation/Reconstruction Files (MIF Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Maneuver Implementation/Reconstruction files were produced by
        the MGS Spacecraft Team (SCT); they documented spacecraft
        maneuver events.  These are ASCII files of variable length
        records.  Each record is delimited by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt;
        (ASCII 10).  File names have the form  ydddeeeC.MIF  where  y
        is the one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is
        the day-of-year of the first data in the file,  eee  is the
        day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file with the
        same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses
        to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage
        files.  Each MIF file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label
        with file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are 2327
        bytes.
 
      Maneuver Performance Data Files (MPD Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Maneuver Performance Data files were produced by the MGS
        Spacecraft Team (SCT).  They contain estimates of spacecraft
        mass and center of mass; moments of inertia; thruster
        locations, directions, and magnitudes; and propellant flow
        rate.  These are ASCII files of variable length records.
        Each record is delimited by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt;
        (ASCII 10).  File names have the form  ydddeeeC.MPD  where
        y  is the one-digit year of the first data in the file,
        ddd  is the day-of-year of the first data in the file,  eee
        is the day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C  is
        a character denoting sequence when more than one file with
        the same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and
        progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of
        similar coverage files.  Each MPD file is accompanied by a
        PDS minimal label with file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical
        file sizes are 4 kB.
 
      Maneuver Profile Files (MPF Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Maneuver Profile Files were produced by the MGS Navigation
        Team (NAV).  They are generic descriptions of orbit
        adjustments used by MGS during aerobraking.  These are ASCII
        files of variable length records.  Each record is delimited
        by a carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed &lt;LF&gt;
        (ASCII 10) pair.  File names have the form  ydddeeeC.MPF
        where  y  is the least significant digit in the year,  ddd
        is the day of year of the first data,  eee  is the day of
        year of the last data, and  C  is a character indicating the
        version of the file (&apos;A&apos; is first, &apos;B&apos; is second, ...).
        Each  MPF is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are less than 700
        bytes.
 
      DSN Monitor Packet Data Files (MPK Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        DSN Monitor Packet Data files were produced by the MGS
        query server, operating on DSN Monitor packets stored in the
        MGS Central Data Base (CDB).  Monitor data are records of
        DSN status and radio measurements.  These are binary files,
        data received from a 24 hour period; they are not readily
        interpretable by end users.  File names have the form
        ydddeeeC.MPK  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee
        is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each MPK file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  File sizes can be as large as 30 MB.
        No MPK data were collected during the EXT phase; all DSN
        Monitor data are in the MCH directories.
 
      Orbit Propagation and Time Generation Files (OPT Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Orbit Propagation and Time Generation files were produced by
        the MGS Navigation Team (NAV).  They contain estimates of
        event timing (e.g., equator crossings) that depend on
        precise knowledge of the spacecraft orbit.  These are ASCII
        files of variable length records.  Each record is delimited
        by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).  File names
        have the form  ydddeeeC.OPT  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee
        is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each OPT file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are less than 100 kB.
        Typical OPT files during EXT included one day of orbit
        reconstructions followed by several days of orbit
        predictions.
 
      Solar Array Kernel Files (SAK Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Solar Array Kernel files were produced by the MGS Spacecraft
        Team (SCT).  They give the attitude of each solar array
        panel as a function of time.  These are ASCII files of
        variable length records in a special NAIF &apos;transfer&apos; format.
        Each record is delimited by a carriage-return (ASCII 13)
        line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10) pair, which may need to be
        removed before the file is used on the local machine.
        After delimiter conversion (if needed) the file would
        ordinarily be passed through the NAIF utility SPACIT  or
        TOBIN  to convert it to the local binary format.  File names
        have the form  ydddeeeC.TCK  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file, eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee
        is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each TCK file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with
        file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are less than
        5 MB.
 
      Space Flight Operation Schedule Files (SFO Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Space Flight Operations Schedule Files were produced by the
        MGS Mission Control Team, usually in parallel with
        a corresponding Sequence of Events (SOE) file.  They
        graphically present parts of the SOE.  These are
        ASCII files of variable length records in a special format
        that allows use with the MGS-provided  sfosedt  program.
        Each record is delimited by a carriage-return (ASCII 13)
        line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10) pair, which may need to be removed
        before the file is used on the local machine.  File names
        have the form  ydddeeeC.SFO  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee  is
        handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc.
        with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.  Each SFO
        file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are less than 100 kB.
        No SFO files were produced after 1998-08-20.
 
      Sequence of Events Files (SOE Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Sequence of Events Files were produced by the MGS Mission
        Control Team.  These are ASCII files of variable length
        records.  Until 1998-08-20 SOE files were produced in a
        special format that allowed use with the MGS-provided  soeedt
        program.  After 1998-08-20, files were produced in a straight
        ASCII format that required no special software; these may be
        identified by the &apos;.tsoe&apos; suffix in the ORIGINAL_PRODUCT_ID.
        Each record is delimited by a carriage-return (ASCII 13)
        line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10) pair, which may need to be removed
        before the file is used on the local machine.  File names
        have the form  ydddeeeC.SOE  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee  is
        handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each SOE file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with
        file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are less than
        1 MB.
 
      Spacecraft/Planetary Ephemeris (SPK) Files (SPK Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Spacecraft/Planetary Ephemeris Files (also known as SP
        kernels or SPK files) were produced by the MGS Navigation Team
        (NAV).  These files give spacecraft and planetary ephemerides.
        These are ASCII files of variable length records in
        a special NAIF &apos;transfer&apos; format.  Each record is delimited
        by a carriage-return (ASCII 13) line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10)
        pair, which may need to be removed before the file is used on
        the local machine.  After delimiter conversion (if needed)
        the file would ordinarily be passed through the NAIF utility
        SPACIT  or  TOBIN  to convert it to the local binary format.
        File names have the form  ydddeeeC.SPK  where  y  is the
        one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the
        day-of-year of the first data in the file,  eee  is the
        day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file
        with the same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and
        progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of
        similar coverage files.  Each SPK file is accompanied by a
        PDS minimal label with file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file
        sizes are less than 5 MB.  Typical SPK files during EXT
        included one day of orbit reconstructions followed by several
        days of orbit predictions.
 
      Spacecraft Attitude (CK) Files (TCK Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Spacecraft Attitude Files (also known as C kernels or CK
        files) were produced by the MGS Spacecraft Team (SCT).
        These are ASCII files of variable length records in
        a special NAIF &apos;transfer&apos; format.  Each record is delimited
        by a carriage-return (ASCII 13) line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10)
        pair, which may need to be removed before the file is used on
        the local machine.  After delimiter conversion (if needed)
        the file would ordinarily be passed through the NAIF utility
        SPACIT  or  TOBIN  to convert it to the local binary format.
        File names have the form  ydddeeeC.TCK  where  y  is the
        one-digit year of the first data in the
        file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of the first data in the file,
        eee  is the day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C
        is a character denoting sequence when more than one file
        with the same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and
        progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of
        similar coverage files.  Each TCK file is accompanied by a
        PDS minimal label with file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file
        sizes are less than 5 MB.
 
      Troposphere Calibration Files (TRO Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Troposphere Calibration files were produced by the
        Tracking System Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL.
        They documented and predicted Earth tropospheric conditions.
        These are ASCII files of variable length records.  Each
        record is delimited by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).
        File names have the form  ydddeeeC.TRO  where  y  is
        the one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is
        the day-of-year of the first data in the file,  eee  is the
        day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file with the
        same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses
        to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage
        files.  TRO files were typically released at the beginning of
        a month and covered the previous month.  Each TRO file is
        accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are 100 kB.
 
        Starting in early 2001, TSAC began basing TRO files on
        surface weather and Global Positioning Satellite (GPS)
        zenith delay.  These files can be distinguished by an
        ORIGINAL_PRODUCT_ID beginning with &apos;ATC&apos; rather than the
        earlier &apos;TROPCAL&apos;.  Detailed file structure was slightly
        different, but the same Software Interface Specification
        (SIS) was used.
 
      UltraStable Oscillator Files (USO Directory)
      --------------------------------------------
        UltraStable Oscillator (USO) files are calibration data
        derived from open-loop radio measurements.  Files are PDS
        table objects with detached labels.  Examples include USO
        Allan Deviation (type A files) and the piecewise-continuous
        linear model of USO frequency (type M files).  File names
        are of the form  USOtyddd.TAB,  where  t  is the file type
        (see above),  y  is the one-digit year in which the file was
        created, and  ddd  is the three-digit day-of-year in which
        the file was created.  Each USO file is accompanied by a
        detached PDS label with name  USOtyddd.LBL  which completely
        describes the content and format of the file.
 
      DSN Weather Files (WEA Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        DSN Weather files were produced by the Tracking System
        Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL.  Files give weather
        calibration information for DSN complexes. These are ASCII
        files of variable length records.  Each record is delimited
        by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).  File names have
        the form  ydddeeeD.WEA  where  y  is the one-digit year of
        the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of the
        first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the last
        data in the file, and  D  is a single digit denoting the
        DSN complex at which the data were acquired (&apos;1&apos; for
        Goldstone, &apos;4&apos; for Canberra, or &apos;6&apos; for Madrid).  WEA files
        were typically released weekly and contain all weather data
        for the complex since 1 January.  Each WEA file is
        accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        ydddeeeC.LBL.  The files grow at the rate of approximately
        90 kB per month.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      SPK ephemeris files and TCK files were produced for the
      J2000 inertial reference frame until the second orbit after
      Mars Orbit Insertion, when the TCK files were referenced to
      the Mars Mean Equator frame.  SAK files presumably follow the
      same format as TCK files.  NAIF reader routines may be
      used to convert these to other coordinate systems.
 
      Other data types are not dependent on definition of a
      coordinate system.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      Software for parsing, reducing, and analyzing data such as
      these has been developed at Stanford University and elsewhere.
      Because such software must usually operate at the bit-level and
      is written for a narrow range of platforms, it is not suitable
      for general distribution.  No software is included with this
      archival data set.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The archival data set is written on CD-WO media using the
      Young Minds CD Studio or Yamaha/GEAR authoring system.
      The CD-WO volumes conform to ISO 9660 standards.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this archival data set have been processed as part of
      health monitoring activities of the MGS Radio Science Team.
      In general, this is a good data set.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was reviewed by the MGS Radio Science
      Team prior to submission to the Planetary Data System (PDS).
      The MGS Science Data Validation Team (SDVT) set standards and
      procedures.
 
      Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data
      set, key elements of the archive were distributed for
      preliminary review.  These included electronic versions of
      example PDS labels, CATALOG files, and Software Interface
      Specifications.  These materials were distributed to PDS
      personnel, the experiment investigator, and others,
      as appropriate.
 
      ODR files on the CD-WO volumes were checked using Stanford
      parsing and reduction software to ensure that they were both
      complete and accurate replicas of the data contained in the
      original files.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Significant events for Radio Science during MGS EXT are
      shown below.  Acronyms and abbreviations are:
 
             C-Mode   Contingency Mode
             EGR      egress
             HGA      high-gain antenna
             ING      ingress
             MSPA     Multiple Spacecraft per Aperture
             ODY      2001 Mars Odyssey
             SNR      signal to noise ratio
             TLM      telemetry
 
         YY/DDD         Comments
         ------         ----------------
         01/032         Begin Extended Mission
         01/110-01/290  Opposition; high SNR, spurs in open loop data
         01/122-01/130  Spacecraft in Contingency Mode or recovery
         01/198         Begin to see interference from HGA rewind
                         during occultations
         01/203         End occultation season
         01/217         Two bistatic radar orbits
         01/228         Begin Relay-16 spacecraft attitude control
         01/249-01/251  Spacecraft in Contingency Mode or recovery
         01/262         ODR and RSR tests
         01/284         ODR and RSR tests
         01/292-01/295  Spacecraft in Contingency Mode or recovery
         01/319         ODR and RSR tests
         01/347         Begin new occultation season; HGA rewind
                         obscures ING, TLM on during every third
                         orbit; many orbits in MSPA with ODY; using
                         RSR for open loop data collection.
         02/004         End HGA interference during ING
         02/017         End TLM on during every 3rd orbit
         02/058-02/066  Spacecraft in Contingency Mode or recovery
         02/073-03/254  Beta Supplement; no egress occultations
         02/091-02/101  Spacecraft in Contingency Mode or recovery
         02/197-02/250  Solar effects raising Allan Deviation to
                         levels high enough that occultation data
                         were not processed for atmospheric profiles
         03/128         First date on which the subreflector was
                         fixed at its existing position rather than
                         at the position it would have at EL=45 deg
                         (only applied during MSPA operations)
         03/150-03/330  Opposition; high SNR, spurs in open loop data
         03/162-03/169  Spacecraft in Contingency Mode or recovery
         03/226-03/327  Bad power supply at DSS 26; spectral artifacts
         03/273-04/101  Ingress interference from HGA rewind
         04/204         Resumption of Beta Supplement; no egress occns
 
      Quality of data was affected by anomalous conditions.  Examples
      include:
 
      Open-Loop Data Anomalies
      ------------------------------
        a) &apos;Sawtooth&apos; frequency residuals infrequently (all stations)
            Apparently caused by a buffering and merging problem in
            data acquisition system; strict synchronization lost and
            either data samples or POCA readings (or both) were lost.
            Affected only ODR (not RSR).
        b) Amplitude baseline variations more than +/-0.1 dB
            (various).  Caused by spacecraft activities, ground
            antenna pointing errors (or increasing Earth atmospheric
            opacity at low elevation angles, weather changes, and
            precipitation).
        c) Uplink Sweeps - Signals drifting through spectrum, usually
            2-3 minutes after egress and strengths as high as -35 dBc
            when using DSS 15, 45, or 65; 5-10 dB weaker when using
            lower powered ground transmitters (e.g., DSS 34).
            Caused by leakage of uplink sweep into downlink chain
            aboard the spacecraft.  Durations typically 10 s.
            Not usually apparently at Earth-Mars distances exceeding
            1 AU.
        d) HGA gimbal spurs: 5 Hz spurs on either side of the carrier
            when gimbal stepper motors were active.  Typically -35 to
            -45 dBc.  Caused usually by elevation gimbal motor, which
            ran continuously at 5 Hz during nominal mapping.  Not
            present before HGA deployment or during Fixed HGA Mapping
            after deployment.
        e) Incorrect attenuator settings (occasional)
        f) Empty data records: no signal and/or no noise (occasional;
            causes varied)
        g) No occultation: HGA rewind overlapped grazing occultation;
            data collected may be useful for characterizing radio
            system but probably contain little of interest for
            atmospheric science (July through mid-December 1999)
        h) During summer 2000 and summer 2002, when Sun-MGS-Earth
            angle was less than 10 deg, Allan Deviation increased
            significantly. These are not noted in daily logs because
            they were ubiquitous.
        i) During summer 2001 and 2003, within a few months of
            Mars opposition, carrier SNR exceeded 60 dB and spurs
            at multiples of 60 Hz appeared on both sides of the
            carrier.
 
        A one-line summary for each radio occultation attempted is
        included in OCCLOGxx.TAB files in the DOCUMENT directory of
        various reduced data archival volumes.  Included in these
        summaries are dates/times, orbit numbers, ground antennas
        used, a shorthand data quality estimation and anomaly
        indicator, a code for quick-look detection of surface echoes,
        and brief comments.  Users interested in these files should
        consult the MGS-M-RSS-5-SDP-V1.0 data set.
 
      Closed-Loop Data Anomalies (mostly observed in ODF)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Thermal sensitivity of the USO was observed during one-way
        tracking.
 
        The quality of ranging data decreased at the beginning of
        2000, but the reasons (other than generally lower signal
        strength as Mars moved farther away) were never determined.
        In early February 2000, Beta Supplement operations interrupted
        many ranging measurements and the number of good points went
        down even further.  Ranging was discontinued a couple months
        later and did not resume until the beginning of the Extended
        Mission.  The first few months of ranging operation in 2001
        produced poor quality data.
 
        During the first half of 2003, the Network Simplification Plan
        (NSP) was implemented at each DSN antenna.  The handling of
        both uplink and downlink closed loop data were changed, one
        antenna at a time.  Dates on which antennas important to MGS
        began using NSP are as follows:
 
                     DSS-24  2002-12-27
                     DSS-43  2003-02-10
                     DSS-65  2003-02-10
                     DSS-25  2003-03-09
                     DSS-26  2003-04-02
                     DSS-34  2003-04-07
                     DSS-15  2003-04-10
                     DSS-63  2003-04-24
                     DSS-45  2003-05-03
                     DSS-14  2003-05-13
                     DSS-54  2003-05-13
 
      Other Notes
      -----------
 
        a) About 15 minutes was required to &apos;unwind&apos; the HGA during
           each orbit. This was normally done while the spacecraft
           was hidden from Earth.  But in late June 1999, the
           occultation time was reduced to less than 15 minutes.
           Ingress was lost first, then egress.  Starting in early
           July only egress occultations were recorded, and those
           were limited to times after surface egress and with
           telemetry on.  In February 2000, egress operations
           could not be conducted because the Beta Supplement
           spacecraft configuration brought the HGA reflector too
           close to the HGA boom.  Approximately once per month,
           the spacecraft attitude was adjusted so that egress
           occultations could be captured over a 24-hour period.
        b) Two-way tracking time was also lost during Beta
           Supplement because the HGA had to &apos;unwind&apos; on the front
           side of the planet.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The limitations in this data set follow from the quality of
      the execution, which is described above under Data Coverage
      and Quality.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>96-062A-04A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

