<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-e-v-h-sw-epps-3-eps-cdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER E/V/H/SW EPPS CALIBRATED EPS CDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:epps.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-sw-epps-3-eps-cdr-v1.0__browserp_mess-e-v-h-sw-epps-3-eps-cdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Andrews, G.B., T.H. Zurbuchen, B.H. Mauk, H. Malcom, L.A. Fisk, G. Gloeckler,
                   G.C. Ho, J.S. Kelley, P.L. Koehn, T.W. LeFevere, S.S. Livi, R.A. Lundgren, and
                   J.M. Raines, The Energetic Particle and Plasma Spectrometer instrument on the
                   MESSENGER spacecraft, Space Science Reviews, 131, 523-556, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ANDREWSETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-E/V/H/SW-EPPS-3-EPS-CDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESSENGER E/V/H/SW EPPS CALIBRATED EPS CDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-05-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-229T19:54:21Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-120T15:08:25Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>GEORGE HO</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            George C. Ho
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The MESSENGER EPPS calibrated observations consist of energetic
            particle and plasma data collected by the EPPS instrument during
            fly-by and orbital operations of Mercury. Also included are
            cruise observations for calibration purposes.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== This data set consists of the MESSENGER
            Energetic Particle and Plasma Spectrometer (EPPS) calibrated
            observations, also known as CDRs. The system encompasses 2
            instrument subsystems - the Energetic Particle Spectrometer (EPS)
            and the Fast Imaging Plasma Spectrometer (FIPS). This data set
            contains EPS instrument data. EPS covers the energy range of 25
            to &gt; 500 keV for electrons, and 10 keV/nucleon to ~3 MeV total
            energy for ions. There are seven CDR data products for EPS
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The data set consists of calibrated observations, also known as
      CDRs.
 
      For all the CDR products there is a detached PDS label file that
      describes the contents of one data file. Each label file will have
      the same base name as the data file it is describing, with the
      extension .LBL to denote a label file. The label file defines the
      start time and end of the observation, product creation time, and
      the structure of the ASCII tables. Each data product is identified
      within the PDS label by a STANDARD_DATA_PRODUCT_ID value, shown in
      parentheses in the table below.
 
      The EPS portion of the data archive currently consists of seven CDR
      data products. The different CDR formats represent different Energy
      Resolution Spectra with different sampling rates.  There is also
      a Pulse Height/Event Record file and one representing SCAN mode data.
 
      A given CDR data file will contain all the observations obtained on
      same earth day. The following table shows the different EPS data
      products. Following is a description of each of the current EPS CDRs.
      A more complete description of each may be found in the EPPS CDR SIS
      document, located in the DOCUMENT directory of the document volume.
 
 
      Current EPS Data Products:
 
        EPS Pulse Height (EPS_PULSE_HEIGHT)
 
          Contains Pulse Height Analysis data in ASCII table format. The
          lack of priority groups after the FSW6 load on 8/18/2008 means the
          weight and group columns of the data are not meaningful after that
          time.
 
        EPS High Resolution Spectra (EPS_HIRES_SPECTRA)
 
          High resolution (energy channels) ion and electron energy
          spectra. Replaces EPS_HI_SPECTRA after FSW6 (loaded on 8/18/2008).
 
        EPS Low Resolution Spectra (EPS_LORES_SPECTRA)
 
          Low resolution (energy channel) ion and electron energy spectra
          and rate counters. Replaces EPS_MED_SPECTRA after FSW6 (loaded on
          8/18/2008).
 
        EPS Summary Spectra (EPS_SUMMARY_SPECTRA)
 
          Contains a subset of rate counters and low resolution energy
          spectra. CDR available only after FSW6 (8/18/2008).
 
        EPS Scan (EPS_SCAN_RATES)
 
          Contains the integrated hardware counters over four energy
          thresholds. Each threshold setting and integration lasts 1/4
          second. Rates are reported in both raw and &apos;delta&apos; form, see
          SIS document for details. CDR available only after FSW6
          (8/18/2008).
 
        EPS High Priority EPS Spectra (EPS_HI_SPECTRA)
          This product contains high energy resolution spectra similar to
          the EPS_HIRES_SPECTRA product, but with the configuration from
          before the new FSW6 load on 8/18/2008.
 
        EPS Medium Priority EPS Spectra (EPS_MED_SPECTRA)
          This product contains lower energy resolution spectra similar to
          the EPS_LORES_SPECTRA product, but with the configuration from
          before the new FSW6 load on 8/18/2008.
 
 
 
    Instrument Overview
    ===================
      The EPS sensor consists of a 60-mm diameter, tuna-can-like
      cylinder, in which a start foil and stop foil, wrapped around
      opposite curved sides of the cylinder, constitute the TOF chamber.
      The detectors are arranged so that each detector senses the
      events within a given range of incidence angles. Each of the 6
      detector modules is composed of 4 pixels: large and small ion and
      large and small electron.
 
      See the EPPSINST.CAT file for more information and
      [ANDREWSETAL2007] for full details.
 
 
    Calibration Overview
    ====================
      This data set is calibrated.  Spectral rates have been converted from
      raw counts to counts/sec and, where possible, to fluxes.  Pulse height
      measurements are reported in calibrated keVs.  See the calibration
      implementation document for details.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      The accumulation times for spectral rate collection are programmable
      as described in the SIS document and in the EDR Dataset Catalog. For
      the CDRs, accumulation time is reported in the table directly so
      initial raw counts can be recovered from counts/sec by a simple
      multiplication. Calibration parameters are described in the
      Calibration Implementation document.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      The EPS CDR data set products are described as follows (the STANDARD_
      DATA_PRODUCT_ID value is given in parentheses). All data is in ASCII
      table format.
 
      The High Priority EPS Spectra (EPS_HI_SPECTRA_CDR) contains
      spectral data, hardware and software count rates and flux.
      [BEFORE FSW6, 8/18/2008]
 
      The Medium Priority EPS Spectra (EPS_MED_SPECTRA_CDR) contains
      spectral data, hardware and software count rates and flux.
      [BEFORE FSW6, 8/18/2008]
 
      The EPS High Resolution Spectra (EPS_HIRES_SPECTRA_CDR) contains
      high resolution (in energy) ion and electron energy spectra as count
      rates and flux. [AFTER FSW6, 8/18/2008]
 
      The EPS Low Resolution Spectra (EPS_LORES_SPECTRA_CDR) contains
      Low resolution (in energy) ion and electron energy spectra
      as count rates and flux and rate counters as count rates.
      [AFTER FSW6, 8/18/2008]
 
      The EPS Summary Spectra  (EPS_SUMMARY_SPECTRA_CDR) contains the same
      quantities as the LORES data but sampled at the longer accumulation
      times of the HIRES data. [AFTER FSW6,8/18/2008]
 
      The EPS Scan (EPS_SCAN_SPECTRA_CDR) contains the integrated hardware
      counters over four energy thresholds. Each threshold setting and
      integration lasts 1/4 second reported as rates and differential
      inferred fluxes. [AFTER FSW6, 8/18/2008]
 
      The EPS Pulse Height CDR (EPS_PULSE_HEIGHT_CDR) contains
      Pulse Height Analysis data.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      The EPPS CDR data are the processed data set released for the
      EPPS.  Data presented here are an accurate representation of the EPPS
      data as received from the spacecraft and have been processed from
      instrument unit to physical unit.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      The EPPS CDR was reviewed internally by the EPPS team prior to
      release to the PDS. PDS also performed an external review of the
      EPPS CDR.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Data reported are the processed data received from the
      spacecraft during the following mission phases: Launch, Earth Cruise,
      Earth Flyby, Venus 1 Cruise, Venus 1 Flyby, Venus 2 Cruise,
      Venus 2 Flyby, Mercury 1 Cruise, Mercury 1 Flyby, Mercury 2 Cruise,
      Mercury 2 Flyby, Mercury 3 Cruise, Mercury 3 Flyby, Mercury 4 Cruise,
      Mercury Orbit, Mercury Orbit Year 2, Mercury Orbit Year 3, Mercury
      Orbit Year 4, and Mercury Orbit Year 5.
      These mission phases are defined as:
 
                           Start time         End time
      Phase Name           Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)
      -----------------    ----------------   ----------------
      Launch                3 Aug 2004 (216)  12 Sep 2004 (256)
      Earth Cruise         13 Sep 2004 (257)  18 Jul 2005 (199)
      Earth Flyby          19 Jul 2005 (200)  16 Aug 2005 (228)
      Venus 1 Cruise       17 Aug 2005 (229)   9 Oct 2006 (282)
      Venus 1 Flyby        10 Oct 2006 (283)   7 Nov 2006 (311)
      Venus 2 Cruise        8 Nov 2006 (312)  22 May 2007 (142)
      Venus 2 Flyby        23 May 2007 (143)  20 Jun 2007 (171)
      Mercury 1 Cruise     21 Jun 2007 (172)  30 Dec 2007 (364)
      Mercury 1 Flyby      31 Dec 2007 (365)  28 Jan 2008 (028)
      Mercury 2 Cruise     29 Jan 2008 (029)  21 Sep 2008 (265)
      Mercury 2 Flyby      22 Sep 2008 (266)  20 Oct 2008 (294)
      Mercury 3 Cruise     21 Oct 2008 (295)  15 Sep 2009 (258)
      Mercury 3 Flyby      16 Sep 2009 (259)  14 Oct 2009 (287)
      Mercury 4 Cruise     15 Oct 2009 (288)   3 Mar 2011 (062)
      Mercury Orbit         4 Mar 2011 (063)  17 Mar 2012 (077)
      Mercury Orbit Year 2 18 Mar 2012 (078)  17 Mar 2013 (076)
      Mercury Orbit Year 3 18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)
      Mercury Orbit Year 4 18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)
      Mercury Orbit Year 5 18 Mar 2015 (077)  30 Apr 2015 (120)
 
      No EPPS data were collected during Venus 1 Flyby phases.  The EPPS
      was on for brief periods during the other six mission phases prior to
      Venus 2 Cruise.
 
      During these planned operational periods, the EPS sensor on the EPPS
      did not have high voltage enable, hence no Time-of-flight data and
      only spectra data were collected.  The EPS was turned on for the
      Venus 2 Flyby and to be remained on throughout the remainder of the
      mission phases.  EPPS data were collected during all Mercury Flybys.
 
      The nominal thresholds are set at 35 keV for both ion and electron
      detectors. Energy channels that are below the energy threshold are
      not calibrated.
 
      The EPS rate data have not been corrected for priority scheme in the
      instrument processor.  During high count rate periods, the rate
      channels in different look directions are not a true representation of
      particle direction.  Users are advised to contact the instrument team
      to obtain anisotropy information from EPS.
 
      The instrument background counts have not been subtracted in the rate
      data.  Users should do proper background subtraction before using the
      data.  During orbital phase, EPS routinely switches between large and
      smallpixel on both the ion and electron detector.  Users should check
      the pixel size flag in the data to know which pixel the detectors are
      using.  The background rate correction should be done for proper pixel
      size. But the user should always consult with the instrument team at
      JHU/APL to verify the quality of specific data prior to publication.
 
      EPS High Ion Sector 1 and 5 have malfunction detectors and do not
      produce any data product.
 
      The lowest energy channel (32 to 55 keV) on the High Ion Sector 3
      and 5 have periodic high count that are due to flight software
      interaction with the instrument and should not be used.  User of
      EPS data should consult with the instrument team at JHU/APL to
      verify the quality of specific data in certain time interval prior
      to publication.
 
      During orbital phase, a certain sector in the EPS field-of-view has a
      direct view of the sunlit side of the planet. During these periods, the
      single event data (Fast, Scanned, etc) may be susceptible to photon
      contamination. The science event data (all rate and spectra data) have
      additional on-board software processing that should eliminate this
      photon contamination.  But the user should always consult with the
      instrument team at JHU/APL to verify the quality of specific data prior
      to publication.
 
      During spacecraft noon-midnight orbits, EPS instrument temperature can
      rise to levels that affect the low energy channels.  We have noticed
      during some of these orbits, the temperature induced noise renders
      those energy channels below 100 keV to be useless.  In addition, the
      higher than normal temperature also induced a data &apos;drop-out&apos; where the
      count in all rate drops by a factor during one integration period and
      remains so for a few minutes to hours.  The EPS team is currently
      investigating the cause of this &apos;drop-out&apos;.  Users should always
      consult the instrument team at JHU/APL to verify the quality of
      specific data prior to publication.
 
      During orbital phase, EPS routinely switches between large and small
      pixel on both the ion and electron detector.  User should check the
      pixel size flag in the data to know which pixel the detectors are
      using.
 
      On 18 Aug 2008 (231), a new Flight Software (FSW) was uploaded to EPPS.
      This new FSW (v6) enhances the energy resolution for EPS and adds a
      high-resolution proton distribution data packet on FIPS. Description of
      these new data products are included in the FMT file.  In addition, the
      new FSW v6 fixed the data spikes in the EPS data (as mentioned in the
      previous paragraph).
 
      On 18 Aug 2009 (230), another new FSW was uploaded to EPPS.  This new
      FSW (v7) only affects the FIPS data.
 
      In the nominal flight configuration, the FIPS sensor on the EPPS
      field-of-view will not measure the solar wind.  Periodically, the
      spacecraft was rotated such that the FIPS field-of-view can detect
      the nominal radial flowing solar wind.  These periods typically lasted
      less than 3 hours and are identified as:
 
                         Start time         End time
      Phase Name         Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)
      ----------------- ----------------   ----------------
      Earth Cruise      05 Apr 2005 (105)  05 Apr 2005 (105)
      Earth Flyby       02 Aug 2005 (214)  02 Aug 2005 (214)
                        07 Aug 2005 (219)  07 Aug 2005 (219)
      Venus 1 Cruise    27 Feb 2006 (058)  27 Feb 2006 (058)
                        06 Sep 2006 (249)  10 Sep 2006 (253)
      Venus 1 Flyby     No Data
      Venus 2 Cruise    01 Mar 2006 (060)  01 Mar 2006 (060)
 
      A dark count signature was discovered in the FIPS PHA data.
      These counts appear in a time-of-flight -- E/q histogram of PHA
      data as straight tracks in E/q, centered at about 8 different
      time-of-flights.  These dark counts significantly complicate the
      analysis of FIPS PHA data, though not significantly for low mass
      ions (H+, He+ and He2+).  All data since launch is affected.
      This situation is being heavily investigated by the FIPS team.
 
      A small bug was found in FSW v7 which causes only the high order 4 bits
      of the wedge, strip and zigzag values are transmitted in
      the data.  This has the effect of reducing the position
      resolution for heavy ions in the FSW v7 data.  A software patch
      which eliminates this bug was uploaded to the spacecraft at 19:15Z on
      16 Dec 2009 (350).
 
      There are gaps in the EPS scan spectra (EPS_SCAN_SPECTRA) products
      inclusively spanning 2014-078 through 2014-083 and 2014-246 through
      2014-254 due to lack of corresponding EDR source data.
 
      There are data gaps in the EPS scan spectra (EPS_SCAN_SPECTRA) products
      inclusively spanning 2014-334 to 2014-350 (production halted to reduce
      data volume during a low speed downlink during a solar conjunction),
      2014-352 to 2015-022 (production halted for a high voltage check), and
      2015-092 to end of mission on 2015-120 (production halted to reduce
      solid state recorder load during a solar conjunction).
 
      As always, users of the EPPS data should consult with the instrument
      team at JHU/APL to verify the quality of specific data prior to
      publication.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      This data set is minimally processed data.  The data are received
      from the spacecraft telemetry and ingested into the MESSENGER
      Science Operations Center (SOC).
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

