<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.a15l-l-lsrp-2-3-soil-mechanics-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>APOLLO 15 LSRP SOIL MECHANICS DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.apollo_15::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.a15l::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:lsrp.a15l::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.a15l-l-lsrp-2-3-soil-mechanics-v1.0__browserp_a15l-l-lsrp-2-3-soil-mechanics-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.a15l-l-lsrp-2-3-soil-mechanics-v1.0__dvo_a15l-l-lsrp-2-3-soil-mechanics-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Apollo 15 Preliminary Science Report, NASA SP-289, 546 pages, published by
                   NASA, Washington, D.C., 1972.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.APOLLO15A1972</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Costes, N.C., G.T. Cohron, and D.C. Moss, Cone penetration resistance test - An
                   approach to evaluating in-place strength and packing characteristics of lunar
                   soils, Proceedings of Second Lunar Science Conference, 3, 1973-1987, M.I.T.
                   Press, 1971.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.COSTESETAL1971</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mitchell, J.K., L.G. Bromwell, W.D. Carrier, III, N.C. Costes, and R.F. Scott,
                   Soil mechanics experiment, Apollo 15 Preliminary Science Report, NASA SP-289,
                   pages 7-1 to 7-28, published by NASA, Washington D.C., 1972.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MITCHELLETAL1972A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Scott, R.E., Apollo program soil mechanics experiment, Final Report California
                   Inst. of Tech., Pasadena, 1975.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SCOTT1975</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>A15L-L-LSRP-2/3-SOIL-MECHANICS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>APOLLO 15 LSRP SOIL MECHANICS DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2011-09-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1971-06-25T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1971-08-13T23:59:59Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID WILLIAMS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Mitchell, J., D. Carrier, N. Costes, L. Bromwell, , D. Williams,
            and J.Plescia, APOLLO 15 LSRP SOIL MECHANICS DATA V1.0,
            A15L-L-LSRP-2/3-SOIL-MECHANICS-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2012.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Tables of raw readings and reduced data from all six runs on 01
            August 1971 of the Lunar Self-Recording Penetrometer (LSRP) on
            the surface of the Moon for the Apollo 15 Soil Mechanics
            experiment.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset contains tables of raw readings and reduced data
            from all six runs on 01 August 1971 of the Lunar Self-Recording
            Penetrometer (LSRP) on the surface of the Moon for the Apollo 15
            Soil Mechanics experiment. Supporting documentation includes
            digitized scans in JPEG and PDF format of the original LSRP soil
            mechanics dataset on microfilm, videos and transcripts of the
            LSRP as it was operated on the Moon, diagrams and maps of the
            experiment areas, and photography of the Apollo 15 Station 8
            where the experiment was performed.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This dataset contains tables of raw readings and reduced data from
    all six runs on 01 August 1971 of the Lunar Self-Recording
    Penetrometer (LSRP) on the surface of the Moon for the Apollo 15
    Soil Mechanics experiment.  Supporting documentation includes
    digitized scans in JPEG and PDF format of the original LSRP soil
    mechanics dataset on microfilm, videos and transcripts of the LSRP
    as it was operated on the Moon, diagrams and maps of the experiment
    areas, and photography of the Apollo 15 Station 8 where the experiment
    was performed.
 
    All six Apollo 15 penetrometer runs were done near a 40 cm deep trench
    dug by the astronaut at Station 8 which was next to the ALSEP site
    which was centered at 26.1341 degrees North latitude, 3.6298 degrees
    East longitude, roughly 110 meters West-North-West of the lunar
    module.  The runs were performed near the end of second EVA
    (extra-vehicular activity) on 01 August 1971.  The flight unit S/N
    2003 and lunar drum S/N 2002 were used for all runs.  The drum was
    returned to Earth and the etchings made by the penetrometer were read
    and recorded on hand-written charts by the investigators.  Copies of
    the charts were sent to the National Space Science Data Center
    (NSSDC), where they were microfilmed and archived.  For more
    information about the experiment see the Chapter 7 of the Apollo 15
    Preliminary Science Report, which is provided in the DOCUMENT
    directory.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The raw readings and reduced data from each of the six runs of the
    penetrometer are provided as fixed-width ASCII text tables and are
    reproductions of the lunar penetration data reduction charts, in the
    handwritten LSRP report, which were taken from the penetrometer drum
    returned to Earth.  (The handwritten report was scanned from the
    microfilm archived at the NSSDC.)  The tables are named in the form
    A15_SMSS_71_M016935_nnn.TAB, where A15 denotes Apollo 15, SMSS is for
    soil mechanics, 71 is the year of data acquisition, M016935 is the
    microfilm reel, and nnn is the sequential frame number corresponding
    to a page that contained the data chart in the report.  Each table
    (*.TAB) is accompanied by an ASCII text file (*.TXT) that provides
    the header records for that data chart.  Each table and header
    combination is described by a detached PDS label.
 
    The header records contained in the *.TXT file for a data table
    give the mission, date, flight unit, lunar drum, index number (from 2
    to 7 and designating penetrometer runs 1 to 6), and notes on the cone
    or plate used.  The columns in the data records of a table give
    the drum load (the angle of deflection of the stylus on the drum) in
    degrees/minutes, the drum load in decimal degrees, the drum
    circumference deflection in millimeters (decimal degrees multiplied
    by .5542), the load in Newtons (calculated from a calibration curve),
    and the stress in Newtons per square centimeter (load divided by the
    cone or plate base area).  This is the value plotted for stress on
    the plots.  A second set of columns starts with a column labeled
    initial drum depth/final in cm and gives a running total of the drum
    reading.  The next column, delta Drum Depth Reading in cm gives the
    difference between the current drum depth reading and the previous
    value.  The next column, penetration depth in cm, is the drum depth
    reading multiplied by 31.5 (index 2, Apollo 15).  On some tables
    there is a final column, headed &apos;+correction add 3.75&apos;, which is the
    previous column with a 3.75 cm correction added. This is a correction
    for the additional length of the cone attached to the bottom of the
    penetrometer rod on Apollo 15.
 
    The six penetrometer runs and associated tables in the DATA directory
    are provided below.  Times in brackets are values listed in the
    Apollo Lunar Surface Journal (ALSJ at http://history.nasa.gov/alsj/)
    followed by conversion from Mission Elapsed Time (MET) to UT. The runs
    started roughly at 148:21:10 MET according to ALSJ which has all times
    approximately 6 minutes earlier than the times listed in the notes.
 
      Run 1 - Index 2 - A15A_SMSS_71_M016935_011.TAB
      Adjacent to north end of trench using 0.5 square inch cone
      18:01:15 UT  [~148:21:10 MET (ALSJ) which corresponds to 17:55:10 UT]
 
      Run 2 - Index 3 - A15A_SMSS_71_M016935_012.TAB
      Bottom of trench, 0.5 square inch cone
      18:03:30 UT  [~148:22:20 MET (ALSJ), 17:56:20 UT]
 
      Run 3 - Index 4 - A15A_SMSS_71_M016935_013.TAB
      In rover tracks directly behind the rover, 0.5 square inch cone
      18:04:25 UT  [~148:23:36 MET (ALSJ), 17:57:36 UT]
 
      Run 4 - Index 5 - A15A_SMSS_71_M016935_014.TAB
      Adjacent to rover tracks, 0.5 square inch cone
      18:05:15 UT  [~148:24:16 MET (ALSJ), 17:58:16 UT]
 
      Run 5 - Index 6 - A15A_SMSS_71_M016935_015.TAB
      Bottom of trench, flat plate
      18:06:30 UT  [~148:26:38 MET (ALSJ), 18:00:38 UT]
 
      Run 6 - Index 7 - A15A_SMSS_71_M016935_016.TAB
      Outside of trench, 4 inches from side of trench, plate, causes edge
      of trench to collapse
      18:07:33 UT  [~148:27:00 MET (ALSJ), 18:01:00 UT]
 
    Known Problems with Penetrometer Runs
    -------------------------------------
      According to the Apollo 15 Preliminary Science Report [APOLLO15A1972]
      the surface reference pad tended to ride up the shaft during the last
      four penetrometer runs, so the precise depth of penetration for runs 3
      through 6 is difficult to determine and is probably slightly less than
      the measured value.  Therefore the stress-penetration curves in these
      cases give an upper bound on the depth of penetration for an applied
      force of 111 Newtons.
 
 
  Supplementary Information
  ==========================
    The DOCUMENT directory contains supplementary information about the
    Soil Mechanics experiment, including the following items.
 
    Handwritten LSRP Report
    -----------------------
      In addition to the data tables, it is important to note that the
      handwritten LSRP report includes hand-drawn plots and notes from the
      experiment.  The Stress versus Penetration plots give the stress in
      Newtons per square centimeter versus the penetration depth in
      centimeters on a linear scale.  These are plotted from the data in
      the lunar penetration data reduction tables found in the report and
      in this dataset.
 
      Additionally sets of handwritten notes in the handwritten LSRP
      report give times and notes on the sampling locations and other
      aspects of the sampling, including diagrams.  The Post-Flight
      Calibration plots give load in Newtons versus drum circumferential
      deflection in mm.  One line shows the deadweight load and a parallel
      line shows the correction for the weight of the penetrometer. The
      latter is the line used for the calibration.  The plot is based on a
      pair of post-flight calibration tables.  The first table, &apos;load
      calibration&apos; gives the index number, the &apos;vert. scribe&apos;, which looks
      to be the starting point of the drum rotation for a given index run,
      and columns giving the load in kilograms and Newtons.  All values
      are given in degrees and minutes.  The top value in a cell is the
      actual reading and the lower value is the reading minus the vert.
      scribe value, which would represent the drum deflection. The second
      table, &apos;penetration calibration&apos;, gives the readings in cm for a
      given position and index number.  There is also a pre-flight
      calibration plot which gives the load in Newtons versus the drum
      circumferential deflection in mm with a 2 sigma error line on each
      side of the calibration line.
 
    Site Diagrams, Maps, and Images
    -------------------------------
      The DOCUMENT directory contains several diagrams and maps of the
      experiment areas including high resolution images taken by the
      Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter Camera of the entire Apollo 15 area
      and the landing site.
 
    Videos
    ------
      Index 2, 3, 4, and 6 runs were captured on video with audio and are
      included in the DOCUMENT directory.
 
    Photography
    -----------
      Still photos taken of or near the 40-cm trench of the experiment
      are included in the DOCUMENT directory.  Most of the photos apply
      to index 2, 3, 4, 6, and 7 runs; one is a context view of the
      ALSEP site of Apollo 15 Station 8.
 
    Transcript
    ----------
      A transcript of the recorded audio commentary as the astronauts
      performed the experiment at Apollo 15 Station 8 is included in
      the DOCUMENT directory.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      This data set passed an external peer review that was held on
      9 July 2012.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

