<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.vo1-vo2-m-spice-6-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>VO1/VO2 MARS SPICE KERNELS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.viking::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vo1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vo2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.vo1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.vo2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vo1-vo2-m-spice-6-v1.0__browserp_vo1-vo2-m-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vo1-vo2-m-spice-6-v1.0__browser_vo1-vo2-m-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vo1-vo2-m-spice-6-v1.0__browser_wgc_vo1-vo2-m-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.naif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>VO1/VO2-M-SPICE-6-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>VO1/VO2 MARS SPICE KERNELS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2000-05-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1976-06-01T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1980-09-01T00:00:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>BORIS V. SEMENOV</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Semenov, B.V., and C.H. Acton, VIKING ORBITER SPICE KERNELS V1.0,
            VO1/VO2-M-SPICE-6-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2000.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Navigation and ancillary data in the form of SPICE System kernel
            files for the Viking Orbiter 1 and Viking Orbiter 2 spacecraft.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set includes a substantial collection of navigation and
            other ancillary data for the Viking Orbiter spacecraft (VO1 and
            VO2) in the form of SPICE kernels, which can be accessed using
            SPICE software. The SPICE data contains geometric and other
            ancillary information needed to recover the full value of science
            instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft
            and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments,
            spacecraft orientation, spacecraft sequences of events, and data
            needed for relevant time conversions.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
 
      This data set includes a substantial collection of navigation and
      other ancillary data for the Viking Orbiter spacecraft (VO1 and
      VO2) in the form of SPICE kernels, which can be accessed using
      SPICE software. The SPICE data contains geometric and other
      ancillary information needed to recover the full value of science
      instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft
      and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments,
      spacecraft orientation, spacecraft sequences of events, and data
      needed for relevant time conversions.
 
      This data set is contained on a single virtual volume, VOSP_1000,
      including data from most mission phases and covering from
      1976-06-01 through the end of the mission, 1980-09-01.
 
 
      Data Types (SPICE kernel types)
      ===============================
 
      SPK kernels contain ephemerides for spacecraft, planets,
      satellites, comets and asteroids as well as for moving or fixed
      spacecraft and instrument structures. They provide position and
      velocity, given in a Cartesian reference frame. SPK files are
      located under the ``data/spk&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      PCK kernels contain certain physical, dynamical and cartographic
      constants for target bodies, such as size and shape
      specifications, and orientation of the spin axis and prime
      meridian. PCK files are located under the ``data/pck&apos;&apos; directory
      of this data set.
 
      IK kernels (Instrument description kernels) give descriptive and
      operational data peculiar to a particular scientific instrument,
      such as internal timing relative to the spacecraft clock and
      field-of-view model parameters. IK files are located under the
      ``data/ik&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      CK kernels describe pointing, containing a transformation
      traditionally called the C-matrix which is used to determine
      time-tagged pointing (orientation) angles for a spacecraft
      structure upon which science instruments are mounted. CK files
      are located under the ``data/ck&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      EK (Events) kernels are derived from the integrated sequence of
      events used to produce actual spacecraft commands. EK files are
      located under the ``data/ek&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      LSK (Leapseconds) kernels contain the leapseconds and the values
      of other constants required to perform a transformation between
      Universal Time Coordinated (UTC) and Ephemeris time (ET). LSK
      files are located under the ``data/lsk&apos;&apos; directory of this data
      set.
 
      SCLK (Spacecraft Clock) kernels contain on-board clock
      calibration data required to perform a mapping between Ephemeris
      time (ET) and spacecraft on-board time (SCLK.) SCLK files are
      located under the ``data/sclk&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      FK (Frame Definitions) kernels contain information required to
      define reference frames, sources of frame orientation data and
      inter-connections between these frames and other frames supported
      within the SPICE system. This includes mounting alignment
      information for each instrument. FK files are located under the
      ``data/fk&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
 
      Kernel File Details
      ===================
 
      A brief overview of the different types of Viking Orbiter kernels
      included in this data set is provided in the
      CONFIDENCE_LEVEL_NOTE section of this file while details specific
      to individual files are found in the ``*info.txt&apos;&apos; files in the
      corresponding data directory. The most detailed description of
      the data in each file is provided in metadata included inside the
      file -- in the description area of text kernels or in the comment
      area of binary kernels.
 
 
      Software
      ========
 
      The SPICE Toolkit contains software modules needed to read SPICE
      kernel files. SPICELIB software is highly documented via internal
      headers. Additional documentation is available in separate ASCII
      text files called Required Reading files. For example, the S- and
      P- Kernel (SPK) Required Reading File, named ``spk.req&apos;&apos;, describes
      use of the SPK kernel file readers and contains sample programs.
 
      The latest SPICE Toolkit for a variety of computer platforms such
      as PC, Mac, SUN, etc. is available at the NAIF Node of PDS
      electronically (via anonymous FTP and WWW servers). Refer to
      information in ``software/softinfo.txt&apos;&apos; for details regarding
      obtaining this software. Each version of the Toolkit is also
      archived at the NASA National Space Science Data Center.
 
 
      Loading Kernel Files into a SPICE-based Application
      ===================================================
 
      The easiest way to make data from a collection of SPICE kernels
      available to a SPICE-based application is to list these kernels
      in a meta-kernel and load it into the program using the high
      level SPICE data loader routine FURNSH. This data set provides
      such meta-kernel(s) under the ``extras/mk&apos;&apos; directory. For more
      information about the MGS meta-kernel(s), see the file
      ``extras/mk/mkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      Credits
      =======
 
      NAIF thanks the following people for contributing their data to
      this data set:
 
      -  K. Edwards, D. Cook, E. Eliason, R. Batson, S. Wu; USGS
         Astrogeology Brunch
 
      -  E. Guinness and S. Slavney; Washington University
 
      -  M. Caplinger; Malin Space Science Systems
 
      -  M. Davies and T. Colvin; The Rand Corporation
 
      -  T. Duxbury and A. Konopliv; JPL
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      This data set contains all Viking Orbiters (VO1 and VO2)
      navigation and ancillary data that the NAIF group could collect
      and analyze during a year long restoration that took place in
      1995-1996. Additional kernels based on the initial versions
      from 1995-1996 were created by NAIF between 2000 and 2008 and
      were added to the data set in 2008.
 
      The main goal of this restoration effort was to collect all
      available VO data of this kind in one place and to make them
      available to future users in consistent formats as SPICE kernel
      files. During this process data wasn&apos;t just copied from files
      in other formats to SPICE files; rather analysis of the data
      quality and consistency was done. When the same kinds of data
      were obtained from different sources they were compared and
      the results of these comparisons were reflected in data files
      and related documents. Also, some brand new data (spacecraft
      orbit data) were obtained.
 
      In particular the following results of this work can bring
      improvements to future VO imaging data interpretation:
 
      -  newly reconstructed VO trajectory for the primary, extended
         and continuation mission phases which provided more accurate
         VO trajectory in comparison with orbits determined during
         the Viking era,
 
      -  results of VO image time tags quality and reliability
         analysis and of an attempt to correct some of these tags based
         on this analysis;
 
      -  an extensive set of VO orientation data including both the
         original data produced by the Viking Project and the
         orientation corrections done by some science groups as the
         result of cartographic analysis.
 
      Some general information about this data set follows here,
      but the prospective user is also referred to extensive
      descriptions about each file that are stored inside each kernel
      file. These metadata provide detailed information regarding
      the information source from which the data were derived, the
      type of processing applied to the source data, applicability
      of the data, etc. Metadata are located in the ``comment area&apos;&apos;
      for binary kernel types (SPK, CK, ESQ), accessible using either
      the COMMNT or SPACIT utility program found in the NAIF Toolkit.
      Metadata are located after ``\begintext&apos;&apos; markers within the
      text kernel types (PCK, IK, LSK, SCLK), accessible by
      using any available text file display tool such as a word
      processor, text editor, or the unix ``more&apos;&apos; or ``cat&apos;&apos;
      commands.
 
 
      SPK Files
      =========
 
      Two kinds of SPK files are provided in this archive: SPK files
      for the spacecraft orbit and an SPK file for Phobos, Deimos,
      Mars, Earth and the Sun.
 
      Spacecraft Orbit SPK Files
      --------------------------
 
      Two sets of VO trajectory data are available in SPICE SPK
      format -- trajectory data from the ``original&apos;&apos; SEDR (Supplemental
      Experiment Data Record) generated by the Viking Project and
      VO spacecraft trajectories reconstructed by A. Konopliv, JPL
      in 1995.
 
      Data from the first set were actively used during the last 20
      years by different groups working on Viking Orbiter images
      registration -- USGS Astrogeology (R. Batson, S. Wu), Rand
      Corporation (M. Davies,T. Colvin), Malin Space Science Systems
      (M. Caplinger) and others. The information from this set was
      also stored in multiple derived products at USGS, Flagstaff
      and the PDS Geosciences node at Washington University, St.
      Louis.
 
      The second set, Konopliv&apos;s, became available only a short time
      ago as the result of orbit restoration using Viking Project
      era tracking data and the latest Mars gravity model. Unfortunately
      no tracking data for the VO1 survey mission were available at
      the time of restoration efforts. Therefore, Konopliv&apos;s data
      covers all mission phases (till the end of 1978) excepting the
      survey phase for both V01 and VO2.
 
      Konopliv&apos;s trajectory solutions, generated years after the end of
      the mission using a substantially better Mars gravity field
      model, are definitely more accurate for some intervals during the
      mission. Unfortunately, this is not true for the whole mission
      because for some periods data about propulsive maneuvers was not
      used and/or trajectory was extrapolated over large periods of
      time without tracking data, resulting in a great reduction in
      accuracy. For a more detailed comparison of the two solutions
      refer to the ``vo_spks.txt&apos;&apos; document provided in this data set.
 
      Solar System Body SPK File
      --------------------------
 
      The file ``mar033.bsp&apos;&apos; contains the latest (as of the publishing
      date of this data set) ephemeris data for Mars, Phobos, Deimos,
      Earth and the sun. Formal one-sigma accuracy information for
      Phobos and Deimos are reported as follows:
 
         Body         Downtrack      Crosstrack      Radial
                     Uncertainty     Uncertainty   Uncertainty
         ------      -----------     -----------   -----------
         Phobos         15 km           7 km          3 km
         Deimos         30 km          16 km          3 km
 
      Accuracies for Mars-Sun and Mars-Earth directions (positions
      obtained from SPK files) are at the level of 0.001 arc-sec (1
      sigma).
 
      NAIF did not attempt to reconstruct and/or capture the planet and
      satellite ephemeris data used during and after the VO mission
      because the latest ephemeris data provided in this data set is
      definitely more accurate and, therefore, supersedes earlier
      ephemeris solutions.
 
      Additional information about SPK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/spk/spkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      CK Files
      ========
 
      All CK files provided in this data set contain orientation of the
      VO1 or VO2 instrument scan platform with respect to the B1950
      inertial frame.
 
      This orientation was calculated from the following source data
      sets representing VO camera orientation:
 
         -- combination of the image orientation data from the
            original VO SEDR data set generated by the Viking Project
            and Viking Image Geometry (GEM) data set produced by
            K. Edwards of the USGS;
 
         -- orientation of the images registered by M. Davies of the
            Rand Corporation;
 
         -- orientation of the images registered by R.M. Batson of
            the USGS Astrogeology Branch;
 
         -- orientation of the images registered by S. Wu of the USGS
            Astrogeology Branch;
 
         -- orientation of the images registered by Malin Space Science
            Systems company (M. Malin, M. Caplinger) using automatic
            and manual registration methods;
 
      The orientation in the CK files was computed by excluding the
      transformation from the platform frame to each camera frame (this
      transformation was defined for each camera by a set of camera
      mounting alignment angles) and merging the platform orientation
      data sets calculated from camera A and camera B orientation
      together.
 
      Though the CK files generated using the first of the five source
      data sets listed above --  SEDR/GEM set -- are the most complete,
      the CKs containing the orientation that came out of the several
      image registration processes are probably more accurate.
 
      The orientation correction resulting from image registration
      was applied to orientation on each camera independently and
      it&apos;s quite possible that the constraint of constant relative
      alignment of the cameras was not taken into account during
      this process. That could cause inconsistency between orientation
      points on one orbit submitted by two cameras when the data is
      merged together.
 
      In addition to that the USGS approach for cartography and image
      registration was to assume that all the error in registering
      images to a base map was due to camera pointing and these were
      updated to match the base map in use. If however, the error was
      due to an orbit error, then it seems that using both an updated
      camera pointing (c-matrix) and an updated orbit position could
      re-introduce errors. For this reason, using inconsistent kernels
      -- CK containing pointing adjusted based on old trajectory and
      SPK containing new trajectory -- can re-introduce error. Refer to
      the meta-kernels provided in the ``extras/mk&apos;&apos; directory for the
      lists of kernels can be used together to achieve consistent
      geometry results.
 
      The CK files from the initial set produced in 1996-1997 and
      archived in 2000 were Type 1 CK files. These CK files proved to
      be unusable with the high-level APIs of the Frames Subsystem of
      SPICE. The set of Type 2 CK files containing the same orientation
      data and eliminating the usage deficiency of the Type 1 files was
      added to the data set in 2008.
 
      Caution on Using CK Files
      -------------------------
 
      While not a data accuracy issue, the CK user is nevertheless
      cautioned to understand and properly use the ``found_flag&apos;&apos; and
      tolerance arguments that are inputs to the CK reader routine
      provided in the SPICE Toolkit. Descriptions about how to read
      CK files are found in the CK reader routine headers (top of
      the source code files) and in the ``CK Required Reading&apos;&apos;
      document; these are contained in each SPICE Toolkit package.
 
      Additional information about CK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/ck/ckinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      PCK Files
      =========
 
      PCK files provide size, shape and orientation data for ``target&apos;&apos;
      bodies such as Mars, Phobos and Deimos. A description of these
      data items and reference to their source is provided inside
      the PCK file, which is a simple text file that can be viewed
      using any word processor, text editor or text display utility.
      In most cases the data for the PCK provided in this archive
      are official IAU/IAG/COSPAR values accepted in 1994.
 
      NAIF did not attempt to reconstruct and/or capture the planet and
      satellite constants used during and after the VO mission
      because the latest constant values provided in this data set are
      definitely more accurate and, therefore, supersede earlier values.
 
      Additional information about PCK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/pck/pckinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      FK Files
      ========
 
      Frames kernel files provide specifications for how one reference
      frame is defined relative to another frame. The VO FK files
      provided in this data set contains a complete set of frame
      definitions for the spacecraft, its structures such as instrument
      platform, and all of its science instruments. Meta information
      provided in the comments included in this file consists of the
      frame definitions, description of the frame relationships, source
      of and accuracy of the mounting alignment information, etc.
 
      Additional information about FK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/fk/fkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      IK Files
      ========
 
      Instrument kernel files provide specifications for field-of-view
      size, shape and orientation for the named instrument. In this
      data set the IK files also provide instrument mounting alignment
      data. Metadata describing these parameters are provided in
      each IK file included in this archive.
 
      This data set contains IK files for four VO instruments --
      the Visual Imaging Subsystem Cameras A and B (VISA and VISB)
      of VO1 and VO2. The mounting alignment and FOV data stored in
      the IK files for these instruments was extracted from the SEDR
      data.  An additional set of mounting alignment information
      provided by T. Duxbury of JPL was included in the comment
      section of the files. There were no known accuracy estimates
      for this data at the time of this archive preparation.
 
      Additional information about IK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/ik/ikinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      SCLK Files
      ==========
 
      Spacecraft Clock kernel files provide a tabulation of data
      needed for converting time measurements between ephemeris time
      (ET) and spacecraft clock time (SCLK).
 
      NAIF was not able to locate a data product containing this
      mapping of the VO on-board clocks to ET that was generated
      during or after the mission. Since supporting SCLK time was
      still necessary for tagging data in the CK files, two SCLK
      files representing fictitious on-board clocks counting
      milliseconds since the beginning of the mission were created.
      These files are included in this data set to facilitate access
      to the CK data.
 
      During the VO data restoration, NAIF analyzed and attempted
      to correct some of the VO image time tags. The results of this
      activity were captured in the EK and SCLK files. However the
      SCLK time based on this correction was not used to tag data
      in the CK files.  For more information regarding VO image time
      analysis and restoration refer to the ``vo_time.txt&apos;&apos; and
      ``vo_trec.txt&apos;&apos; documents provided in this data set.
 
      Additional information about SCLK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/sclk/sclkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      LSK Files
      =========
 
      Leapseconds kernel files provide a tabulation of ``leapseconds&apos;&apos;
      and some other terms used in converting time measurements
      between ephemeris time (ET) and Universal Time (UTC). ``Spacecraft
      Event Time&apos;&apos; (SCET) is the commonly used name for UTC events
      measured at the spacecraft.
 
      Metadata describing how the LSK data are obtained or computed
      is contained inside the LSK text file. The time conversion
      provided by SPICE LSK files is accurate to approximately
      0.000030 seconds.
 
      Additional information about LSK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/lsk/lskinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      EK Files
      ========
 
      Two kinds of Events kernel (EK) files are included in this
      archive: VO image and ancillary data catalogs and EK files
      containing results of the image time tags analysis and
      reconstruction.
 
      The VO images catalog files capture the original meta information
      for VO camera images present in the SEDR and in the VO Image
      catalog maintained by Washington University, St.  Louis. This
      information is included in this SPICE data set for reference
      purposes.
 
      The VO image time tag and time tag reconstruction EK files
      contain results of VO image time tag analysis and correction
      performed by NAIF as a part of the VO restoration. Refer to
      the ``vo_time.txt&apos;&apos; and ``vo_trec.txt&apos;&apos; documents provided
      in this data set for more information about
      these results.
 
      Additional information about EK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/ek/ekinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>PSCM-00036</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

