<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ros-e-m-a-c-spice-6-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ROSETTA SPICE KERNELS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.international_rosetta_mission::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.ro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.ro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ros-e-m-a-c-spice-6-v1.0__browserp_ros-e-m-a-c-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ros-e-m-a-c-spice-6-v1.0__browser_psa_ros-e-m-a-c-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ros-e-m-a-c-spice-6-v1.0__browser_ros-e-m-a-c-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.naif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>ROS-E/M/A/C-SPICE-6-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ROSETTA SPICE KERNELS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2006-12-22</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-03-02T09:26:21.583Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2010-10-03T12:01:06.183Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JOSE LUIS VAZQUEZ-GARCIA</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Vazquez-Garcia, J.L., Zender, J., and B. Semenov, ROSETTA SPICE
            KERNELS V1.0, ROS-E/M/A/C-SPICE-6-V1.0, European Space Agency,
            2007.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This dataset contains SPICE data for the Rosetta mission
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            SPICE deals with ancillary data needed to support the planning
            for, and analysis of, science instrument data. As well as
            software (the SPICE toolkit) and documentation, SPICE provides
            data files, called kernels, that contain ancillary information
            which has been created in such a way as to allow easy access and
            correct usage by the space science and engineering communities.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
1. SPICE System Overview
   =====================
 
   SPICE data contain geometric and other ancillary information
   needed to recover the full value of science instrument data. In
   particular, SPICE kernels provide spacecraft and planetary
   ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments and spacecraft
   orientation. Data needed for relevant time conversions is also
   included.
 
   SPICE was designed by the Navigation and Ancillary Information
   Facility (NAIF) to aid scientists and engineers with ancillary
   and engineering data. This data comes from a wide range of
   sources such as the spacecraft, the mission control center and
   the designers of the spacecraft and its instruments.
 
   The ancillary data comprises information on data acquisition;
   position and orientation of the spacecraft at the time of
   acquisition; information on the target, such as location, shape
   and orientation; reference frame specifications and time
   conversion data.
 
   The primary SPICE data sets are often called &apos;kernels&apos; or &apos;kernel
   files&apos;.  These kernels are composed of ancillary information,
   which has been created in such a way as to allow easy access and
   correct usage by the space science and engineering communities.
 
   In addition to the kernels, there is software provided, known as
   the SPICE toolkit, along with standards, documentation and
   software support. The SPICE toolkit and documentation can be
   found on:
 
      http://naif.jpl.nasa.gov/naif/
 
   The SPICE toolkit was freely offered to the worldwide space
   science and space mission engineering communities at the time
   this data set was released. The few rules governing its use are
   posted on the &apos;Rules&apos; page of the NAIF website:
 
      http://naif.jpl.nasa.gov/naif/rules.html
 
   SPICE is used on a number of space missions, such as ESA&apos;s Mars
   Express, SMART-1, Venus Express and Rosetta missions; NASA&apos;s Mars
   Global Surveyor, Stardust, Cassini, Mars Exploration Rovers, Mars
   Reconnaissance Orbiter and Deep Impact. The SPICE system has been
   produced and is maintained by Caltech&apos;s Jet Propulsion Laboratory
   under contract to the U.S. National Aeronautics and Space
   Administration.
 
   For an additional explanation of the SPICE system, please consult
   SPICE_INST.CAT
 
 
2. Data Producers and Other Key Personnel
   ======================================
 
   The Rosetta SPICE data set has been produced by
      Acton, C.        (NAIF/JPL)
      Bachman, N.      (NAIF/JPL)
      Semenov, B.      (NAIF/JPL)
      Vazquez, J.L.    (RSSD/ESA)
      Zender, J.       (RSSD/ESA)
 
   and archived by
 
      Vazquez, J.L.    (RSSD/ESA)
 
 
3. The Rosetta SPICE dataset
   =========================
 
   The Rosetta SPICE dataset consists of several SPICE kernels,
   organised as follows:
 
   *  CK kernels. This kernels contain information about
      orientation of the space vehicle or any articulating
      structure on it. More information on the CK kernels in this
      dataset is provided in CKINFO.TXT.
 
   *  FK kernels. Reference frame specifications. Definitions of,
      and specifications of, relationships between reference frames
      (coordinate systems). Among the frames kernels included,
      there are kernels that specify reference frames related to
      the earth and the spacecraft. More information on the FK
      kernels in this dataset is provided in FKINFO.TXT.
 
   *  IK kernels. Kernels that hold intrument information, such as
      field of view or internal timing. There is a IK kernel for
      every instrument, except for RSI. More information on the IK
      kernels in this dataset is provided in IKINFO.TXT.
 
   *  LSK kernel. This kernels hold a table with the leapseconds
      used to convert between ET and UTC. If there are multiple
      LSK kernels in this dataset, the latest kernel supersedes the
      previous ones. More information on the LSK kernel(s) in this
      dataset is provided in LSKINFO.TXT.
 
   *  PCK kernels. These kernels provide information about Solar
      System bodies orientation and shape, and possibly parameters
      for gravitational, atmospheric or rings models. The dataset
      contains PCK kernels for the planets, their satellites, and
      the asteroids Lutetia and Steins. More information on the PCK
      kernels in this dataset is provided in PCKINFO.TXT.
 
   *  SCLK kernel. This kernel (spacecraft clock coefficients)
      allows for conversion between ET and spacecraft clock. If
      there are multiple LSK kernels in this dataset, the latest
      kernel supersedes the previous ones. More information on the
      SCLK kernel(s) in this dataset is provided in SCLKINFO.TXT.
 
   *  SPK kernels. Kernels with information about ephemeris
      (position and velocity) of the spacecraft and solar
      system bodies. The dataset provides such information for
      the planets, the Sun, the Moon, the comet
      (CHURYUMOV-GERASIMENKO), the two fly-by asteroids
      (Lutetia and Steins), the fly-by comet (Tempel 1), the New
      Norcia tracking Station, and the spacecraft. More information
      on the SPK kernels in this dataset is provided in SPKINFO.TXT.
 
   3.1 - Origin of the kernels.
 
      a) Generic kernels provided by NAIF.
         PCK, LSK and some of the SPK (those which don&apos;t hold
         information about the spacecraft) kernels are provided
         by NAIF.
 
      b) Other kernels provided by NAIF.
         The instrument kernels (IK) have been developed by Boris
         Semenov (NAIF), in collaboration with the intrument teams
         and RSSD/ESA.
 
      c) Kernels generated with ESOC Ancillary Data.
         ESOC ancillary data are the main source of information
         required to create SPICE kernels for attitude (CK), orbit
         (SPK) and time (SCLK) information, as well as orientation
         for the High Gain Antenna and the Solar Panels. See next
         chapter (3.2) for a more detailed explanation on how these
         kernels are generated. Some PCK kernels for asteroids and
         comets have also been created using ESOC data.
 
   3.2 - Creation of SPK, CK and SCLK kernels from ESOC Ancillary
         Data.
 
      Orbit Data.
      ----------
 
         Eight different types of data products are provided by
         ESOC: ORHR, ORHO, ORHS, ORER, ORMR, ORFR, ORGR and ORWR.
         SPICE kernels corresponding to ORHR, ORWR, ORHS, ORHW
         and ORHO will be provided in this data set.
 
         The ORHR SPK file covers the cruise phase from launch to
         the rendezvous with the comet and provides the orbit data
         as heliocentric states. There will be several versions of
         the ORHR product; the user shall use the file with the
         higher version number, since it will be the most up to date
         one.
 
         The ORHW SPK file provides orbit data, centered in the
         Sun, for the comet Churyumov-Gerasimenko.
 
         The ORHS SPK file provides orbit data, centered on the
         Sun, for the asteroid 21 Lutetia.
 
         The ORHO SPK file provides orbit data, centered on the Sun,
         for the asteroid 2867 Steins.
 
         During near comet operations, one spacecraft orbit file
         (ORHR) will be provided, containing comet-centric states
         with respect to the Earth mean equator of J2000. The file
         will cover the spacecraft orbit from comet rendezvous up
         to the end of the current planning period.
 
         For each release of the dataset, only the relevant kernels
         are delivered. For example, for the first release, ORHO and
         ORHS files will not be delivered, since that release covers
         a time period previous to the two asteroid flybys.
 
      Attitude Data.
      -------------
 
         Attitude data are provided for all mission phases except
         for safe modes, for the past and the near future. The
         attitude is provided in several records, called segments,
         each covering a specific time span. These segments have
         no overlap, but there may be gaps between the segments,
         and even gaps in the segments.
 
      Time Correlation Data.
      ---------------------
 
         Time Correlation is one of the most critical pieces of
         information needed for the use of the SPICE system within
         the Rosetta mission. This information allows the conversion
         between the Rosetta S/C Clock time and UTC time.
 
      ESOC always provide predicted and reconstituted orbit data,
      but only predicted attitude data. These products are the
      source of the CK and SPK kernels.
 
      ESOC delivers time correlation data which are the source for
      the SCLK kernel.
 
      An automated system, called ADCS (Automatic Data Conversion
      System) is responsible for the generation of CK, SPK and SCLK
      kernels from the ESOC flight dynamics data. ADCS detects when
      a new product was generated or a new time correlation packet
      was available, and run a series of processes in order to
      create the proper kernels.
 
      ADCS uses the SPICE toolkit in order to fulfill its task. It
      runs in a server physically located at ESTEC until December
      2007; after that date, the server is located at ESAC.
 
   3.3 - Using the SPICE kernels.
 
      At least a basic knowledge of the SPICE system is needed in
      order to use this kernels. The SPICE toolkit provides versions
      in Fortran (SPICELIB), C (CSPICE), Matlab (Mice) and IDL (icy),
      and the user can choose any one that suits him/her.
 
      The SPICELIB routine FURNSH, CSPICE function furnsh_c, and icy
      routine cspice_furnsh load a kernel file into the kernel pool
      as shown below.
 
      CALL FURNSH ( &apos;kernel_name&apos; )
      furnsh_c    ( &apos;kernel_name&apos; );
      cspice_furnsh, &apos;kernel_name&apos;
 
      In the case when two or more files contain data overlapping in
      time for a given object, for binary kernels, the file loaded
      last takes precedence.
 
      If two (or more) text kernels assign value(s) using the &apos;=&apos;
      operator to identical keywords, the data value(s) associated
      with the last loaded occurrence of the keyword are used -all
      earlier values have been replaced with the last loaded
      value(s).
 
      Loading Kernel Files into a SPICE-based Application
      ===================================================
 
      The following list of kernels in SPICE meta-kernel format can
      be used with a SPICE-based application running on a UNIX
      workstation to load Rosetta SPICE data provided in this data
      set together (note that the logical path provided in the
      PATH_VALUES keyword and pointing to the volume root directory
      should be changed to the actual path of the volume root
      directory on the system where the volume is mounted):
 
      When there are two or more kernels that cover the same time
      interval (as is the case here for the .BSP and .BC kernels)
      the last kernel loaded is the one used by the SPICE software
      for computations in the interval or overlap.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
       The SPICE kernels in this dataset are either
       provided by NAIF (for instance, kernels containing
       parameters describing the planets, or the LSK kernel
       containing information about leapseconds) or calculated
       from the orbit and attitude data information generated
       by ESOC. In both cases the archive team are confident that
       the SPICE data is correct and accurate within the precision
       provided by the software and the instruments at the time
       the data was archived
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SUPERSEDED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

