<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.a17l-l-tg-2-traverse-gravity-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>APOLLO 17 TRAVERSE GRAVIMETER DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.apollo_17::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.a17l::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:tg.a17l::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.a17l-l-tg-2-traverse-gravity-v1.0__browserp_a17l-l-tg-2-traverse-gravity-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.a17l-l-tg-2-traverse-gravity-v1.0__dvo_a17l-l-tg-2-traverse-gravity-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Apollo 17 Preliminary Science Report, NASA SP-330, published by NASA,
                   Washington, D.C., 1973.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.APOLLO17A1973</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Apollo 17 mission - lunar roving vehicle traverse gravimeter experiment motion
                   sensitivity test, NASA Johnson Space Center, JSC-07948, Houston, Texas, Dec.
                   1973.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.APOLLO17B1973</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Apollo Scientific Experiments Data Handbook, NASA Technical Memorandum X-58131,
                   JSC-09166, published by NASA Johnson Space Center, Houston, Texas, Aug. 1974.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.APOLLOSEDH1974</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Buck, S. W., J. S. Eterno, G. Mamon, R. T. Martorana, R. G. Scott, and W. A.
                   Vachon, Traverse gravimeter experiment final report, R-739, Charles Stark
                   Draper Laboratory, Massechussetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge,
                   Massechussetts, August 1973.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BUCKETAL1973</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mamon, G., Traverse gravimeter for the lunar surface, E-2603, Charles Stark
                   Draper Laboratory, Massechussetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge,
                   Massechussetts, August 1971.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MAMON1971</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Talwani, M., G. Thompson, B. Dent, H.-G. Kahle, and S. Buck, Traverse
                   gravimeter experiment, In Apollo 17 Preliminary Science Report, NASA SP-330,
                   published by NASA, Washington, D.C., 1973.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TALWANIETAL1973</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>A17L-L-TG-2-TRAVERSE-GRAVITY-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>APOLLO 17 TRAVERSE GRAVIMETER DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2011-12-31</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1972-12-12T01:12:21Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1972-12-14T04:28:48Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID WILLIAMS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Talwani, M., S. W. Buck, G. Mamon, D. Williams, APOLLO 17
            TRAVERSE GRAVIMETER DATA V1.0, A17L-L-TG-2-TRAVERSE-GRAVITY-V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 2011.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Table of 26 readings of the Apollo 17 Traverse Gravimeter
            Experiment taken from 12 to 14 December 1972 at different
            locations near the Lunar Module landing site.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains a table of readings from the Traverse
            Gravimeter Experiment performed during the Apollo 17 mission. The
            gravimeter, which recorded relative measurements of the local
            gravitational field at the lunar surface, was manually run by the
            astronauts near the Lunar Module landing site. The data table
            includes 23 valid gravity values, with calibrations and
            corrections, that were obtained from 12 to 14 December 1972. The
            absolute value for the Lunar Module site was estimated to be
            162,694.6 milligal with an uncertainty of 5 milligal. Supporting
            documentation includes the Apollo 17 Traverse Gravimeter
            Experiment Final Report.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set contains a table of readings from the Traverse Gravimeter
    Experiment performed during the Apollo 17 mission.  The gravimeter,
    which recorded relative measurements of the local gravitational field
    at the lunar surface, was manually run by the astronauts near the
    Lunar Module landing site.  The data table includes 23 valid gravity
    values, with calibrations and corrections, that were obtained from 12
    to 14 December 1972; the results are discussed below.  Supporting
    documentation includes the Apollo 17 Traverse Gravimeter Experiment
    Final Report by Buck, et al., (1973) [BUCKETAL1973].
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The 26 readings of the Apollo 17 Traverse Gravimeter are provided as a
    fixed-width ASCII text table, A17_TRAVERSE_GRAVIMETER.TAB with a
    detached PDS label.  The table contains 16 columns for each reading
    including the location, the elapsed time at which the measurement was
    initiated (hour, minute, and second), the displayed value, the
    difference between the displayed value and the value of the LM site,
    the raw delta G (gravity) value, the delta G value after application
    of an empirical correction, the elevation in meters, and comments.
 
    The table is a reproduction of the data found in Table 11-1 of the
    principal investigator&apos;s Traverse Gravimeter Experiment Final Report
    by Buck, et al., (1973) [BUCKETAL1973].  Additional information in the
    table such as the elapsed time of the reading was taken from the
    Apollo 17 Preliminary Science Report [APOLLOA1973] and the Apollo
    Science Experiments Data Handbook [APOLLOSEDH1974].  The column
    definitions in the PDS label provide descriptions of the contents.
 
    Results
    -------
      The absolute value for the Lunar Module site was estimated to be
      162,694.6 milligal with an uncertainty of 5 milligal.  (One gal or
      galileo is defined as 0.01 meters per second-squared.)  For a summary
      of errors assumed, see table 9-1, page 57 in Buck, et al. (1973)
      [BUCKETAL1973].  Based on knowledge of the instrument and the
      measurements it was assumed the instrument drift was negligible.  The
      root-mean-square instrument noise value was given as 1.8 milligal
      based on values taken with the instrument off the Lunar Roving Vehicle
      at the Lunar Module site (readings 3, 9, 11, 17, 19, and 25).
 
      To convert the difference in the display readings to milligal, the
      higher order terms in the equation were neglected and the reading
      difference was simply multiplied by -0.03245.  For more details see
      Chapter 13, Traverse Gravimeter Experiment, of the Apollo
      17 Preliminary Science Report [APOLLOB1973].
 
 
  Supporting Documentation
  ========================
    Traverse Gravimeter Experiment Final Report by Buck, et al., (1973)
    [BUCKETAL1973] is included in the DOCUMENT directory.  It contains
    sections about the basic theory of interpretation of the results, a
    description of the equipment used, and analysis and discussion of the
    results.  Twenty-three valid gravity values were obtained and published
    along with calibrations and corrections.  The document was digitized
    from microfiche archived at the National Space Science Data Center
    with data set ID PSPG-00330 (72-096C-03A).
 
    Several figures and tables in final report are useful for understanding
    the Traverse Gravimeter data:
 
      - Gravity data table, Table 11-1, page 67 (PDF page 79)
      - Traverse map, Figure 11-2, page 69 (PDF page 81)
      - Summary of errors, Table 9-1, page 57 (PDF page 69)
      - Temperature alarms and codes, Table 7-2, page 45 (PDF page 57)
      - Thermal design cutaway, Table 7-2, page 32 (PDF page 44)
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      This data set passed an external peer review that was held on
      9 July 2012.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

