<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-mdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER MDIS MAP PROJECTED MULTISPECTRAL RDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mdis-wac.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-mdr-v1.0__browserp_mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-mdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-mdr-v1.0__browser_geo_mercury_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-mdr-v1.0__browser_mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-mdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-mdr-v1.0__dvo_imaging_mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-mdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Becker, K.J., M.S. Robinson, T.L. Becker, L.A. Weller, K.L. Edmonson, G.A.
                   Neumann, M.E. Perry, S.C. Solomon, First digital elevation model of Mercury,
                   47th Lunar and Planetary Science Conference, abstract #2949, 2016.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BECKERETAL2016</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Domingue, D.L., B.W. Denevi, S.L. Murchie, and C.D. Hash, Application of
                   multiple photometric models to disk-resolved measurements of Mercury&apos;s surface:
                   insights into Mercury&apos;s regolith characteristics, Icarus, 268, 172-203, 2016
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DOMINGUEETAL2016</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hapke, B., Theory of Reflectance Spectroscopy (Topics in Remote Sensing, 3),
                   Cambridge University Press, 272, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAPKE1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hawkins, S.E., III, J. Boldt, E.H. Darlington, R. Espiritu, R.E. Gold, B.
                   Gotwols, M. Grey, C. Hash, J. Hayes, S. Jaskulek, C. Kardian, M. Keller, E.
                   Malaret, S.L. Murchie, P. Murphy, K. Peacock, L. Prockter, A. Reiter, M.S.
                   Robinson, E. Schaefer, R. Shelton, R. Sterner, H. Taylor, T. Watters, and B.
                   Williams, The Mercury Dual Imaging System on the MESSENGER spacecraft, Space
                   Science Reviews, 131, 247-338, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAWKINSETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hawkins, S.E., III, S.L. Murchie, K.J. Becker, C.M. Selby, F.S. Turner, M.W.
                   Noble, N.L. Chabot, T.H. Choo, E.H. Darlington, B.W. Denevi, D.L. Domingue,
                   C.M. Ernst, G.M. Holsclaw, N.R. Laslo, W.E. McClintock, L.M. Prockter, M.S.
                   Robinson, S.C. Solomon, and R.E. Sterner, II, In-flight performance of
                   MESSENGER&apos;s Mercury Dual Imaging System, Proceedings of the SPIE, Volume 7441,
                   pp. 74410Z-74410Z-12, 2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAWKINSETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-H-MDIS-5-RDR-MDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESSENGER MDIS MAP PROJECTED MULTISPECTRAL RDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-05-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-08-19T18:01:23Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-04-30T11:07:43Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>CHRISTOPHER HASH</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            C. Hash, MESSENGER MDIS MAP PROJECTED MULTISPECTRAL RDR V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 2014
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Multispectral reduced data records for the wide-angle MDIS camera
            on MESSENGER.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== The Mercury Dual Imaging System (MDIS) consists
            of two cameras, a Wide Angle Camera (WAC) and a Narrow Angle
            Camera (NAC), mounted on a common pivot platform. This dataset
            includes the Multispectral Reduced Data Records for the WAC. The
            Map Projected Multispectral RDR (MDR) data set consists of a
            global color map of I/F in the 8 filters used for multispectral
            mapping during the primary mission, photometrically normalized to
            a solar incidence angle (i) = 30 degrees, emission angle (e) = 0
            degrees, and phase angle (g) = 30 degrees at a spatial sampling
            of 64 pixels per degree. The map is divided into 54 segments or
            &apos;tiles&apos;, each representing the NW, NE, SW, or SE
            quadrant of one of the 13 non-polar or one of the 2 polar
            quadrangles or &apos;Mercury charts&apos; already defined by the
            USGS. Each tile is composed of 8 bands corresponding to 8 of the
            11 WAC filters. Each tile also contains backplanes describing
            ancillary information. The subset of 8 of 11 available
            multispectral filters was selected on account of limitations in
            MESSENGER solid-state recorder space, and more or less evenly
            samples the spectral range of MDIS.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      MDIS 8-color imaging of Mercury is mosaicked into 54 non-overlapping,
      64 pixel/degree tiles (MDRs). Each tile corresponds to the NW, NE,
      SW, or SE quadrant of one of the pre-existing Mercury non-polar
      charts, or one of the two polar charts.
 
      Map tiles are named based on the quadrant of the Mercury chart they
      span:
 
      MDIS_ccc_rrrPPD_Hxxddv.IMG
 
      where:
 
        ccc = product type = MDR
        rrr = resolution in pixels/degree (PPD)
        Hxx = Mercury chart designation
        dd = quadrant within Mercury chart (NW, NE, SW, or SE), or a
           polar chart (NP, SP)
        v = version number
 
      The following is an example file name with a description of the
      individual components:
 
      MDIS_MDR_064PPD_H03NE0.IMG
 
      For this image:
        Product type = MDR (MDR)
        Resolution = 64 pixels/degree (064PPD)
        Mercury chart = Shakespeare (H03)
        Quadrant = Northeast (NE)
        Version = 0
 
      A redundant tile covering the south polar region has a modified
      nomenclature, reflecting that it includes reduced-resolution
      (to 2700 m/pixel) images in order to fill a coverage gap in the
      nominal tile.
 
      MDIS_MDR_064PPD_2700_H15SP1.IMG
 
      The MDR directory, present in the MDR archive volume, contains
      MDIS Map Projected Multispectral Reduced Data Records (MDRs).
      The MDRs are organized into subdirectories based on the Mercury
      Chart containing the MDR.  Latitude and longitude limits of
      Mercury Charts, as named at the end of mission delivery, are:
 
      Quadrangle         Subdirectory   Lat. (degrees)  Long. (deg. east)
      H-1 Borealis       H01            65 to 90        0 to 360
      H-2 Victoria       H02            22.5 to 65      270 to 360
      H-3 Shakespeare    H03            22.5 to 65      180 to 270
      H-4 Raditladi      H04            22.5 to 65      90 to 180
      H-5 Hokusai        H05            22.5 to 65      0 to 90
      H-6 Kuiper         H06            -22.5 to 22.5   288 to 360
      H-7 Beethoven      H07            -22.5 to 22.5   216 to 288
      H-8 Tolstoj        H08            -22.5 to 22.5   144 to 216
      H-9 Eminescu       H09            -22.5 to 22.5   72 to 144
      H-10 Derain        H10            -22.5 to 22.5   0 to 72
      H-11 Discovery     H11            -65 to -22.5    270 to 360
      H-12 Michelangelo  H12            -65 to -22.5    180 to 270
      H-13 Neruda        H13            -65 to -22.5    90 to 180
      H-14 Debussey      H14            -65 to -22.5    0 to 90
      H-15 Bach          H15            -90 to -65      0 to 360
 
      An MDR:
      - Consists of map-projected photometrically normalized I/F CDRs
        mosaicked into a multispectral map tile. In versions 0, 1, and 2,
        the value included for each band is from a single image set
        identified as &apos;best&apos; by the MDR metric described below. In
        version 3, the value is an average from all images meeting
        a specified set of criteria;
      - Contains image data in I/F corrected photometrically to i=30
        degrees, e=0 at a resolution of 64 pixels per degree (~665 m/pixel
        at the equator);
      - Represents one latitude-longitude bin in a global color map;
      - Is composed of up to 8 bands corresponding to the 8 of the 11
        WAC filters; and
      - For versions 0, 1, and 2, contains 5 backplanes for the reference
        750-nm band:
        (a) observation id, (b) MDR metric, (c) solar incidence angle,
        (d) emission angle, and (e) phase angle.
      - For version 3, contains 9 backplanes:
        (a) image count, the number of image sets averaged at a given
        latitude/longitude coordinate, and (b-i) standard deviations
        of the values used to determine average normalized
        I/F in each of the 8 bands.
 
 
    Versions
    ========
 
      Version numbers of MDRs increment on reprocessing or addition of
      new data.  Polar tiles are in polar stereographic projections, other
      tiles in equirectangular projection.
 
      - Version 0 was released at PDS release 9. It uses version 4 CDRs
        projected on a sphere using version 0 DDRs.
        It uses a Hapke-form photometric correction, with different
        parameters for low- and high-incidence angle products.
      - Version 1 was released just after PDS release 10. It applies an
        adjustment to each 8-image set to coregister other filters to the
        750 nm filter.
      - Version 2 was released just after PDS release 11. It includes an
        updated Hapke photometric correction whose parameters match
        those applied to version 0 MD3 data products.
      - Version 3 was released at PDS release 15 at end of mission.
        It uses version 5 CDRs projected onto a digital
        elevation model using version 1 DDRs. It also switches the
        mosaicking approach from using the single &apos;best&apos; image set
        at one location, to using the average of the several to many &apos;best&apos;
        image sets. It also switches from the Hapke photometric correction
        in to a Kasseleinen-Shkuratov correction.
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      MDIS observing variable pertaining to the MDRs are as follows.
 
      Pixel Binning: Some images are unbinned and 1024x1024 pixels.
      Some images are 2x2 pixel binned in the focal plane hardware
      (also known as &apos;on-chip&apos; binning), resulting in 512 x 512
      images. Some images are further compressed 2x2 using the
      spacecraft main processor or &apos;MP&apos;, in addition to DPU binning,
      yielding 256x256 images. Images taken at lower altitude have
      more pixel binning, to control the volume of data collected for
      the global map.
 
      12-8 bit compression: Images are read off the detector in 12-bit
      format. 12 bit images may converted to 8 bit images using one of
      eight lookup tables (LUTs). All WAC images collected as part of
      the global multispectral map have been converted to 8 bits.
 
      FAST/DPCM compression: All images are compressed losslessly using
      FAST/DCPM compression as they are read out of the DPU, to conserve
      recorder space. Once the data are written to the recorder, they can
      be uncompressed and recompressed more aggressively in the MP.
 
      Wavelet compression: Images may be integer wavelet transform-
      compressed in the MP, typically at 3:1 for color data and 8:1 for
      monochrome data, but any value from 1 to 32 can be used. The initial
      configuration in Mercury orbit was to perform 12 to 8 bit conversion
      using LUT0 for the WAC and LUT2 for the NAC, with a wavelet
      compression ratio of 4:1 for color imaging. Initial images
      exhibited unexpectedly visible compression artifacts. Beginning
      19 April 2011, LUT0 and LUT2 were replaced with LUT1 which better
      preserves image dynamic range. Beginning 31 May 2011, the wavelet
      compression ratio for color images was reduced to 3:1 for global
      mapping. Color imaging was taken losslessly compressed when
      downlink volume permitted it.
 
      Exposure Control: The exposure time of MDIS images can be set
      manually by command, or automatically by the software. In manual
      mode, exposure times from 1-989, 1001-1989, ..., to 9001-9989 ms
      are available. In autoexposure mode the exposure time of the next
      image is computed by the DPU software, and cannot exceed 989 ms
      in duration. If the time of the next image occurs before the
      calculation can be completed, and pixel binning or filter
      position change, then the algorithm compensates for predicted
      changes in scene brightness and filter transmission using an
      onboard data structure. All images in MDRs were acquired using
      automatic exposure.
 
      Pointing: The MDIS imagers are mounted on a pivot platform, which
      is itself mounted to the MESSENGER spacecraft deck. The pivot
      platform is controlled by a stepper motor, which is controlled by
      the Data Processing Unit (DPU). The pivot platform can move in
      either direction. The total range of motion is 240 degrees, limited
      by mechanical &apos;hard&apos; stops, and is further constrained by &apos;soft&apos;
      stops applied by the software. The nominal pointing position for
      MDIS is defined as 0 degrees, aligned with the spacecraft +Z axis
      and the boresight for several other instruments. The range of the
      soft stops is set to 40 degrees in the spacecraft -Y direction
      (toward the MESSENGER sunshade) and +50 degrees in the +Y direction
      (away from the sunshade). The pivot position can be commanded in
      intervals of 0.01 degrees within this range. During acquisition of
      the global multispectral map, the pivot was used to point the WAC
      to low emission angles on the surface, at times when the solar
      incidence angle was close to the lowest values possible at that
      latitude.
 
      Filter selection: The WAC imager contains a 12 position filter
      wheel to provide spectral imaging over the spectral range of the
      CCD detector. Eight of the filters were chosen for the map and
      appear in the MDR in order of increasing wavelength:
        WAC filter 6 (filter F), 430 BP 40
        WAC filter 3 (filter C), 480 BP 10
        WAC filter 4 (filter D), 560 BP 5
        WAC filter 5 (filter E), 630 BP 5
        WAC filter 7 (filter G), 750 BP 5
        WAC filter 12 (filter L), 830 BP 5
        WAC filter 10 (filter J), 900 BP 5
        WAC filter 9 (filter I), 1000 BP 15
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      A sequence of processing creates an MDR from CDRs and DDRs. A Derived
      Data Record (DDR) consists of multiband images whose line and sample
      dimensions and coordinates correspond one-for-one with those of a
      CDR. It has 5 bands of data used to help create an MDR, including for
      every image pixel: (a) latitude, (b) longitude, (c) incidence angle,
      (d) emission angle, and (e) phase angle. The DDRs are an intermediate
      product used to create MDRs and other map products, are defined as a
      distinct data product in the MDIS CDR/RDR Software Interface
      Specification, and are delivered to the PDS.
 
      The sequence of processing is as follows:
 
    (a) Experiment Data Records (EDRs) are assembled from raw data.
    (b) Radiance images are created from the EDRs and calibration files.
    (c) Radiance is converted to I/F CDRs by dividing by (pi * solar flux
        at 1 AU / heliocentricdistance_in_AU^2).
    (d) I/F is photometrically corrected to i = 30 degrees, e = 0 degrees.
    (e) Gimbal positions are extracted from the spacecraft housekeeping
        and formatted as a gimbal C kernel.
    (f) Using the pivot C kernel and other SPICE kernels, DDRs are
        created. The surface intercept on a model of Mercury&apos;s surface
        is calculated for each spatial pixel. The angles of this pixel
        relative to the equatorial plane and reference longitude constitute
        the latitude and longitude of the pixel. For that latitude and
        longitude, solar incidence, emission, and phase angles are
        determined.
    (g) I/F corrected to i = 30 degrees, e = 0 degrees is map projected
        into multiband MDRs using the latitude and longitude information
        in the DDRs.
    (h) For versions 0, 1, and 2, the same procedure is used on DDRs to
        assemble the backplanes with derived information. They are
        appended to the 8 image bands in the following order:
          OBSERVATION_ID
          MDR metric
          Solar Incidence Angle
          Emission Angle
          Phase Angle
        where OBSERVATION_ID taken from the CDR label, the
        ordinal number of the image among all MDIS images taken
        post-launch. The values for all backplanes are those for the
        filter 7 image within the color sequence. For version 3,
        backplanes are populated using statistics on the count and
        standard deviations of images that are averaged to populate
        each of the bands of normalized I/F.
 
      The MDR metric or stacking order (&apos;which image is on top&apos;) has been
      defined for MDRs and used for versions 0, 1, and 2. The objective is
      to have &apos;on top&apos; images with high spatial resolution, low emission
      angle, and low incidence angle. Any image taken as part of the 8-color
      campaign is a candidate to include in MDRs. Rather than complete images
      being map-projected and laid into the mosaics, only a portion of an
      image is used, in which the same region of Mercury is observed in all
      filters of a single sequence of color images executed as part of the
      8-color mapping campaign. The image quality metric is evaluated at the
      camera boresight of the middle image in that sequence; lowest values
      represent the &apos;best&apos; image. For each color sequence, the &apos;worst&apos; part
      of a sequence with overlapping coverage in all filters (highest value
      of the metric) is map-projected and laid into the MDR first; then
      the overlap region with the second-highest value is laid in second,
      overwriting the first overlap region, and so on until the &apos;best&apos;
      overlap region with the lowest metric is on top. At all latitude and
      solar incidence angles, the metric for MDRs is:
 
      PIXEL_SCALE / (cos i * cos e )
 
      where i is solar incidence angle, e is emission angle, and the value
      of PIXEL_SCALE is limited not to be below approximately 665 meters
      so that unfavorably illuminated images with high spatial resolutions
      do not overwrite more favorably illuminated images.
 
      For version 3 MDRs, at any location, all images that fall within the
      following criteria are averaged, to reduce residuals from the time-
      variable instrument calibration. This results in a spatially variable
      number of images having been averaged:
 
      - Controlled images are only used, with the G filter images
        part of the control set, and other filters in any given
        color set registered to the G filter images
      - Only uses images from the 8-color mapping campaign
      - Emission angle at the center of the images is &lt; 40 degrees
      - Image scale varies by type of tile:
        - For the global tile site, image scale &lt; 2000 m/pixel
        - For the redundant south polar tile, image scale &lt; 2700 m/pixel
      - Trimming of pixels with excessive emission angles varies by type
        of tile:
        - For the global tile site, pixels with emission angle &gt; 40 degrees
        - For the redundant south polar tile, pixels with emission angle
          &gt; 90 degrees
      - For the north polar tile (H01)
        - Pixels with incidence angle &gt; 88 degrees are trimmed
      - For tiles between 43.75N latitude (N/S H02 tile boundary)
        and 65N latitude:
        - Incidence angle at center of the image &lt; 82 degrees
        - Pixels with emission angle &gt; 82 degrees are trimmed
      - For tiles between 43.75N and 43.75S latitude:
        - Incidence angle at center of the image &lt; 70 degrees
        - Pixels with emission angle &gt; 70 degrees are trimmed
      - For tiles between 43.75S latitude (N/S H14 tile boundary)
        and 65S latitude:
        - Incidence angle at center of the image &lt; 82 degrees
        - Pixels with emission angle &gt; 82 degrees are trimmed
      - For the south polar tile (H15):
        - Pixels with incidence angle &gt; 88 degrees are trimmed
        - Incidence angle at center of the image &lt; 80 degrees
      - For the redundant south polar tile:
        - Incidence angle at center of the image &lt; 80 degrees
 
      In version 0 MDRs, the photometric correction applied to MDIS WAC
      images to create MDRs is based on bi-directional
      reflectance equations formulated by [HAPKE1993]. The general
      equation for I/F is given by:
 
      I/F=(w/4)[mu_not&apos;/(mu&apos; +mu_not&apos;)]{[1+B(g)]P(g)-
          1+H(mu_not&apos;)H(mu&apos;)}S(i,e,g,theta)
 
      where w is single scattering albedo, i is incidence angle, e is
      emission angle, g is phase angle, p(g) is the single particle
      scattering function, theta is a parameter representing
      macroscopic roughness, and mu_not&apos; and mu&apos; are modified versions
      of the cosines of the incidence and emission angle that take
      into account effects of theta. H(mu_not&apos;) and H(mu&apos;) describe
      approximations to the Chandrasehkar H-functions. The surface
      roughness function, S(i,e,g,theta), modifies the radiative
      transfer equation to account for surface roughness.
 
      In addition, a Henyey-Greenstein function is used to describe
      the single particle scattering function p(g). The form of the
      Henyey-Greenstein function used corresponds to the form
      utilized in the USGS ISIS software, and is given by:
 
      p(g)=c(1-b^2)(1-2b cos(g)+b^2)^(-3/2) + (1-c)(1-b^2)(1+2b
      cos(g)+b^2)^(-3/2),
 
      where g is the phase angle, b is the scattering amplitude
      parameter, and c is the partition parameter between forward and
      backward scattering.
 
      In version 0-2 MDRs, no single set of Hapke parameters was found that
      yields close matches for corrected I/F across boundaries of images
      taken at different photometric geometries, for both the 3- and 8-color
      maps taken predominantly at low solar incidence angles (average,
      about 45 degrees) included in MDRs and MD3s, and monochrome maps
      taken predominantly at high solar incidence angles (BDRs, HIEs, HIWs).
      Therefore map products emphasizing low or high incidence angles
      initially used different sets of photometric parameters optimized
      for each to minimize seams between images.
 
      The initial set parameters for the MDR Hapke photometric correction
      applied in versions 0 and 1 of the data set were
      derived by modeling data acquired from ten regions between 24
      degrees and 46 degrees south latitude and 330 degrees and 353
      degrees east longitude. These regions sample incidence angle (i),
      emission angle(e), and phase angle (alpha) coverage commensurate
      with the 8-color map imaging campaigns. The data from each of
      the ten regions was combined into a single data set and a single
      set of parameters derived for each filter.
 
      The photometric measurements were modeled using a least squares
      grid search routine over the available parameter space. The model
      parameter values were individually plotted as a function of wavelength
      over the MDIS filter central wavelength values. A polynomial trend was
      fit to each parameter as a function of wavelength. The polynomial
      trend value at each filter central wavelength was then used as the
      model parameter values for determining the photometric correction.
      Derivation of the photometric correction involved: (1) calculating the
      reflectance at the observed geometry for each pixel in each image
      (Ro), (2) calculating the reflectance at i=30 degrees, e=0 degrees,
      alpha=30 degrees (R30), (3) calculating the correction factor
      (R30/Ro), and (4) applying the correction factor to each pixel within
      each image. The Hapke model parameters used are listed for each WAC
      filter included in the 8-color map in MDRs in the table below, where
      w is the single scattering albedo, theta is the surface roughness
      parameter, and b and c are the Heyney-Greenstein single particle
      scattering function parameters defined above.
 
      The parameters applied to versions 0 and 1 were:
      filter, wavelength,      w,           b,          c ,       theta
      F,      433.2, 0.211128053, 0.334085324, 0.375167969, 26.42725116
      C,      479.9, 0.230813631, 0.324758324, 0.386526805, 26.0305832
      D,      558.9, 0.258868000, 0.314675995, 0.397505634, 25.72995496
      E,      628.8, 0.280853828, 0.309431110, 0.401712522, 25.70426606
      G,      748.7, 0.312801009, 0.305712396, 0.401020115, 25.93857518
      L,      828.4, 0.329682589, 0.305085427, 0.397910593, 26.11195641
      J,      898.8, 0.341649727, 0.304493750, 0.395361317, 26.16071183
      I,      996.2, 0.354203163, 0.301757676, 0.394795045, 25.89670121
 
      For all wavelengths, the width of the opposition surge, h, was 0.075
      and the strength of the opposition surge, B0, was 2.3.
 
      Version 1 of the MDRs introduced a feature-based adjustment to better
      align the bands of an 8 color set to a subpixel level. First, each of
      the 8 images of a color set are map projected and combined into a local
      mosaic cube, along with the backplane layers corresponding to the 750nm
      image. Using the 750-nm band as reference, the other 7 bands were
      shifted spatially to align detected features to it.  Those aligned
      image cubes are then used to build the global MDR mosaic tiles.
 
      For version 2 MDRs, additional data were acquired over the same
      geographic regions at additional photometric geometries. Fitting
      parameters to the expanded set of photometric observations yielded a
      correction with reduced seams and reduced artifacts at high incidence
      and emission angles. The updated parameters were used both to
      construct version 0 of the MD3 data set and version 2 MDRs.
 
      The parameters applied to version 2 MDRs are:
      filter, wavelength,      w,           b,          c ,       theta
      F,      433.2, 0.151360115, 0.155099698, 0.126102310, 14.60131926
      C,      479.9, 0.169685245, 0.147410229, 0.106108941, 14.74522393
      D,      558.9, 0.197384444, 0.136483073, 0.081821900, 14.78008707
      E,      628.8, 0.218696307, 0.129164430, 0.070385011, 14.65283436
      G,      748.7, 0.249052388, 0.122256228, 0.072924183, 14.27068804
      L,      828.4, 0.265449469, 0.121966502, 0.090225001, 14.02954160
      J,      898.8, 0.277789564, 0.124805212, 0.115960759, 13.90988549
      I,      996.2, 0.292068663, 0.133854741, 0.167852540, 14.00895011
 
      For all wavelengths, the width of the opposition surge, h, is 0.09
      and the strength of the opposition surge, B0, is 3.086.
 
      In version 3 MDRs delivered at the end of the mission, a different
      photometric correction is used, a Kasseleinen-Shkuratov function
      described by [DOMINGUEETAL2016]. The form of the function is
      given as:
 
      I/F = AN*exp[-(g*mu)]{c_sub_l[2cos i/(cos i + cos e)]+[1-c_sub_l]cos i}
 
      where AN is normal albedo at a given wavelength, and mu and c_sub_l
      are wavelength-dependent parameters. Their values were fit using
      multiple regions between 24 degrees and 46 degrees south latitude
      and 330 degrees and 353 degrees east longitude. These regions sample
      incidence angle (i), emission angle(e), and phase angle (g)
      coverage commensurate with global mapping campaigns. In addition
      whole-disk Mercury images taken at a large number of geometries during
      the Mercury flybys expand the phase angle range. Parameter values were
      fit in the same manner as the parameters for the Hapke model. The
      values are given in the table below:
 
      WAC
      filter, wavelength,      AN,       mu,    c_sub_l
      F,      433.2,       0.0700,   0.6363,     0.6293
      C,      479.9,       0.0797,   0.6219,     0.6277
      D,      558.9,       0.0911,   0.5976,     0.6186
      E,      628.8,       0.0986,   0.5800,     0.6228
      G,      748.7,       0.1111,   0.5628,     0.6424
      L,      828.4,       0.1194,   0.5570,     0.6369
      J,      898.8,       0.1251,   0.5494,     0.6172
      I,      996.2,       0.1250,   0.5200,     0.6303
 
 
    Data
    ====
      There is one data type associated with this volume, MDRs consisting
      of mosaicked, photometrically corrected I/F from WAC CDRs acquired
      through 8 spectral filters. Versions 0, 1, and 2 are appended with 5
      backplanes describing the component CDRs and their photometric
      geometries as recorded in DDRs. Version 3 is appended with 9
      backplanes describing the number of image sets averaged at each
      latitude / longitude location, and the standard deviations in each
      of the spectral bands.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
 
      There are two types of ancillary data provided with this
      dataset:
 
      1. The CALIB directory contains bandpasses of the spectral filters
      of MDIS used to collect the images in the dataset, to facilitate
      comparison with other data sets. See CALINFO.TXT in that directory
      for more details.
 
      2. There may be a BROWSE directory containing browse images in
      PNG and/or GeoTIFF format. See BROWINFO.TXT in that directory
      for more details.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
 
      The cartographic coordinate system used for the MDIS data products
      conforms to the J2000 celestial reference frame for star imaging,
      and the IAU planetocentric system with East longitudes being
      positive for planetary surfaces.
 
      In version 0, 1, and 2 MDRs, the IAU2000 reference system for
      cartographic coordinates and rotational elements is used for
      computing latitude and longitude coordinates of planets. However
      a Mercury radius of 2440.0 km is used.
 
      In version 3 MDRs, the value for Mercury radius is updated to
      2439.4 km.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
 
      The MDIS archive is organized and stored in the directory
      structure described in the Mercury Dual Imaging System (MDIS)
      Calibrated Data Record (CDR) and Reduced Data Record (RDR)
      Software Interface Specification (SIS). The contents of the
      archive, along with fiduciary checksums, are compressed into
      a single &apos;zip archive&apos; file for transmittal to the PDS Imaging
      node.  The zip archive preserves the directory structure
      internally so that when it is decompressed the original
      directory structure is recreated at the PDS Imaging node.
      The zip archive is transmitted to the PDS Imaging node via
      FTP to the URL specified by the node for receiving it.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      Known issues of concern are described below.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was examined by a peer review panel
      prior to its acceptance by the Planetary Data System (PDS). The
      peer review was conducted in accordance with PDS procedures.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
 
      Only a subset of raw EDR data are calibrated to CDRs and then
      incorporated into MDR products. Briefly, the following criteria
      are met:
 
      (a) The data represent a scene and not the instrument test
      pattern, as indicated by data quality index (DQI) byte 0.
 
      (b) The exposure time is greater than zero (zero exposures
      occur in some images due to software features), as indicated
      by DQI byte 1.
 
      (c) Less than 20 percent of the image is saturated (empirically
      this is a threshold dividing wholly corrupted images from
      everything else).
 
      (d) The target of the image is MERCURY.
 
      (e) In version 0, 1, 2, and 3 MDRs, the image was taken as part of
      the 8-color mapping campaign. Version 0, 1, and 2 MDRs are based on
      version 4 CDRs which correct a number of earlier calibration
      artifacts, and on version 0 DDRs. Version 3 MDRs are based on
      version 5 CDRs and version 1 DDRs. For version 3 MDRs, some
      component images may contain residuals from the following issues.
 
      (1) COMPRESSION ARTIFACTS. Wavelet compression applied to science
      images is lossy. At higher compression ratios, compression artifacts
      will degrade data precision over spatial scales comparable to or
      smaller than several pixels. The degradation can be greater
      proportionally to the image dynamic range of brightness, if the data
      are converted from 12 to 8 bits in such a way that a 1 DN error
      occupies a greater fraction of the digital dynamic range. Wavelet
      compression was used minimally prior to Mercury orbit. The initial
      configuration in Mercury orbit was to perform 12 to 8 bit conversion
      using LUT0 for the WAC and LUT2 for the NAC, with a wavelet
      compression ratio of 4:1 for color imaging. Initial images
      exhibited unexpectedly visible compression artifacts. Beginning
      19 April 2011, LUT0 and LUT2 were replaced with LUT1 which better
      preserves image dynamic range. Beginning 19 May 2011, some color
      images began to be acquired with lossless compression. Beginning
      31 May 2011, the wavelet compression ratio for color images was
      reduced to 3:1 for global mapping.
 
      (2) RADIOMETRIC ACCURACY. The radiometric calibration of the
      WAC was updated several times over the mission to iteratively
      reduce residuals from 3 sources of error: (a) time-variable
      responsivity of the detector, (b) residuals in the flat-field
      correction, and (c) residuals in the correction to
      responsivity for detector temperature. For multispectral
      products, the residuals from time-variable responsivity
      initially led to distinct seams; correction of this artifact
      is treated in more detail below.
 
      In version 4 CDRs, an additional update to responsivity
      improved temperature dependence over the full operating range.
      The correction was derived empirically by fitting as a function
      of CCD temperature the median values of images acquired from
      Mercury orbit at a wide range of temperatures but a narrow
      range of photometric geometries. The flat field was updated
      empirically using the median of hundreds of photometrically
      corrected images of relatively bland field-filling images
      of Mercury.
 
      In version 5 CDRs, a new, final temperature correction used all
      Mercury images satisfying the illumination criteria. A new, final
      flat-field correction was derived similarly to the updated
      correction used in version 4, except using more images and
      a Kasseleinen-Shkuratov photometric correction.
 
      (3) SCATTERED LIGHT. The WAC is subject to scattered light
      originating within the field-of-view or just outside it. One
      source is multiple reflections off of 13 optical surfaces (2
      sides of each of 4 lenses, the spectral filter, and the CCD cover
      glass, as well as the CCD surface itself). The scatter becomes
      worse at longer wavelengths. Just off the limb of a large
      extended source near 1 field-of-view in size, like Venus or
      Mercury, measured radiance increases with wavelength from 2% to 7%
      of the value measured on the extended source. The value decreases
      with distance off the target more quickly at shorter than at
      longer wavelengths, but remains at 1% hundreds of pixels from
      the source. Conversely, light must be scattering from bright
      parts of an image to dark parts of an image. Averaged over
      sources tens of pixels in area, and away from abrupt brightness
      contrasts, scattered light affects shapes of spectra measured
      from WAC data at least at the 1-2% level, worse near brightness
      boundaries or for small, bright crater ejecta. The expected effect
      is enhanced brightness at &gt;650 nm in dark areas, and decreased
      brightness at &gt;650 nm in small bright areas.
 
      In the end-of-mission delivery 15, a forward model of the
      expected WAC scatter from a given scene was derived using
      optical design software modeling CCD structure and hardware,
      with magnitudes of scatter calibrated against flight measurements.
      The ray trace analysis reveals an in-scene component from light
      diffracted by the CCD and reflected by the CCD cover glass, and
      an out-of-scene component from light reflected off metallic
      surfaces alongside the CCD and back off the cover glass.
      Images with the worst scattered light were excluded from
      multispectral map products.
 
      (4) TIME-VARIABLE WAC RESPONSIVITY. During Mercury orbit it was
      recognized that filter-dependent changes in WAC responsivity on
      the order of +/- 15% occurred over timescales as short as several
      days. Because those variations were not consistent from filter to
      filter, they led to spurious spectral features, which were
      particularly conspicuous near 750 nm. The cause(s) of these
      variations in responsivity are not known, but they could include
      transient radiation effects on the detector or electronics, aging
      of filters, periodic deposition and burn-off of contaminants on
      filters, or incorrect recording of exposure time. An initial
      empirical correction for images acquired in the first year of
      operations was developed and utilized in version 4 WAC CDRs used
      to create version 0, 1, and 2 MDRs.
 
      For version 5 WAC CDRs in delivery 15 at end of mission, an
      updated correction covers the full duration of the orbital
      phase. Overlaps between color image sets in color mapping campaigns
      were used to derive a multiplicative correction factor for each
      filter and for each Earth day (2-3 orbits). Version 3 MDRs use
      CDRs with this updated correction. An analysis of overlap among
      individual images shows that residual differences (which include
      errors from calibration, scattered light, and possible incomplete
      correction of photometric variation) average &lt;2% for the majority
      of the planet.
 
      (5) UNCONTROLLED MOSAIC PROJECTED ONTO A SPHERE. Version 0-2 MDRs
      are constructed by uncontrolled mosaicking, projecting the image
      data onto a sphere. At the stage where each of the 8 band images
      is locally map projected and joined into a cube, the bands are
      then spatially adjusted to match features to the 750-nm band.
      Systematic errors in spacecraft position and in knowledge of
      spacecraft and MDIS attitude, systematic errors in range to the
      surface due to ignoring topography, and systematic errors in
      latitude and longitude due projecting onto a sphere instead of a
      shape model will all contribute to mosaicking errors. In general
      these are expected to be under 1 km but locally might exceed 4 km.
 
      Version 3 MDRs are constructed from images controlled using
      c-smithed kernels and a global digital elevation model (DEM), both
      derived using a least-squares bundle adjustment of common
      features, measured as tie point coordinates in overlapping NAC and
      WAC-G filter images of Mercury at favorable solar incidence and
      emission angles. Empirically, misregistration errors between images
      decreased generally to the pixel scale of the map (0.2 km) in
      most locations. Derivation of smithed kernels and the DEM for
      end of mission data products is described by [BECKERETAL2016].
 
      (6) INACCURACY IN THE PHOTOMETRIC CORRECTION. The Hapke correction
      applied to version 0-2 MDRs required the use of illumination-dependent
      parameters implying the possibility of systematic inaccuracy. As shown
      by [DOMGINUEETAL2016] the Kasseleinen-Shkuratov correction used in
      version 3 MDRs greatly reduces residuals between images acquired at
      different photometric geometries, implying reduced systematic errors.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      None
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

