<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.near-a-mag-3-rdr-earth-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>NEAR MAG DATA FOR EARTH</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.near_earth_asteroid_rendezvous::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.near::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mag.near::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.near-a-mag-3-rdr-earth-v1.0__browserp_near-a-mag-3-rdr-earth-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.near-a-mag-3-rdr-earth-v1.0__ditdos_near-a-mag-3-rdr-earth-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Anderson, B.J., L.J. Zanetti, D.H. Lohr, J.R. Hayes, M.H. Acuna, C.T. Russell,
                   and T. Mulligan, In-flight calibration of the NEAR magnetometer, IEEE Trans.
                   Geosci. Remote Sens., Vol. 39, pp. 907-917, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ANDERSONETAL2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Cheng, A.F., R.W. Farquhar, and A.G. Santo, NEAR Overview, Johns Hopkins APL
                   Technical Digest, Vol. 19, pp. 95-106, 1998.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CHENGETAL1998</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Jenkins, J., G. Dakermanji, M. Butler, and U. Carlsson, The Near Earth Asteroid
                   Rendezvous Spacecraft Power Subsystem, Proc. 4th European Space Power Conf.,
                   T.-D. Guyenne (ed.), ESA-SP369, p. 277, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JENKINSETAL1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>NEAR-A-MAG-3-RDR-EARTH-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>NEAR MAG DATA FOR EARTH</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2001-09-27</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1998-01-23T00:00:00.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1998-01-26T23:59:59.999Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>KAZUE TAKAHASHI</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Takahashi K., NEAR MAG DATA FOR EARTH,
            NEAR-A-MAG-3-RDR-EARTH-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2001.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains vector magnetic field data acquired by the
            fluxgate magnetometer (MAG) on the NEAR spacecraft during the
            EARTH phase.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            NEAR MAG RDR volume sets contain a single data set, from one
            instrument and one mission phase (defined in the phase table in
            /AAREADME.TXT).
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
 
    NEAR MAG RDR volume sets contain a single data set, from one instrument
    and one mission phase (defined in the phase table in /AAREADME.TXT).
 
    This data set contains vector magnetic field data acquired by the
    fluxgate magnetometer (MAG) on the NEAR spacecraft during the
    EARTH phase. The data set begins on 1998-01-23T00:00:00.000
    and ends 1998-01-26T23:59:59.999.
 
    The data are processed science data provided in physical units (nT)
    in two coordinate systems Near Sun Orbital (NSO) and Eros Body Fixed
    (EBF). Instrumental and spacecraft effects have been removed from
    the data during processing.  The data are provided in ASCII tables
    located in the DATA directory.  Plots of the data are also provided
    for browsing purposes in the BROWSE directory.  Spacecraft position
    is also included in the data tables and plot files.
 
 
  Data/Parameters
  ===============
 
    The UTC time tags assigned to each sample are the spacecraft event
    time of the magnetometer output of the A/D converter.  The sample
    time has not been shifted to account for the time lag in the
    anti-aliasing filter. The UTC time tags have the format of
    year-mo-dmThr:mn:ss.ss, where year(I4) is year, mo (I2)is month, dm
    (I2)is day of month, hr(I2) is UTC hour, mn(I2) is UTC minute, and
    ss.ss(F5.2) is UTC second.  DMET is the difference between
    magnetometer and housekeeping data samples.  The difference is kept
    as small as possible for accurate evaluation of the time-dependent
    magnetic fields generated by currents flowing in the spacecraft.
 
    ASCII tables labeled NSOyyddd.TAB (yyddd indicates year and day of
    year) contain the following Level 2 MAG data.
 
    Column  Name        Description                           Unit
    ------  -----       -----------                           ----
    1.      UTC         time, UTC                             see above
    2.      MET_DAY     time, mission                         day
    3.      MET_HOUR    time, mission                         hour
    4.      MET_MINUTE  time, mission                         minute
    5.      MET_SECOND  time, mission                         second
    6.      DMET        housekeeping data time rel. to mag.   second
    7.      B_X         magnetic field NSO X component        nT
    8.      B_Y         magnetic field NSO Y component        nT
    9.      B_Z         magnetic field NSO Z component        nT
    10.     B_TOT       magnetic field magnitude              nT
    11.     NSO_X       NEAR position NSO X component         km
    12.     NSO_Y       NEAR position NSO Y component         km
    13.     NSO_Z       NEAR position NSO Z component         km
 
 
    ASCII tables labeled EBFyyddd.TAB (yyddd indicates year and
    day)contain the following Level 2 MAG data.
 
    Column  Name        Description                           Unit
    ------  -----       -----------                           ----
    1.      UTC         time, UTC                             see above
    2.      MET_DAY     time, mission                         day
    3.      MET_HOUR    time, mission                         hour
    4.      MET_MINUTE  time, mission                         minute
    5.      MET_SECOND  time, mission                         second
    6.      DMET        housekeeping data time rel. to mag.   second
    7.      B_X         magnetic field EBF X component        nT
    8.      B_Y         magnetic field EBF Y component        nT
    9.      B_Z         magnetic field EBF Z component        nT
    10.     B_TOT       magnetic field magnitude              nT
    11.     EBF_X       NEAR position EBF X component         km
    12.     EBF_Y       NEAR position EBF Y component         km
    13.     EBF_Z       NEAR position EBF Z component         km
 
 
    Files labeled nso10day_yyyy_dd0_dd1.jpg (yyyy indicate year, dd0 is
    the first day and dd1 is last day of a 10-day interval) provide
    summary plots of MAG data in NSO coordinates averaged down to 10-min
    resolution.
 
    Name    Description                             Unit
    -----   -----------                             ----
    BX      magnetic field NSO X component          nT
    BY      magnetic field NSO Y component          nT
    BZ      magnetic field NSO Z component          nT
    BTOT    magnetic field magnitude                nT
    THETA   mag. field direction from NSO Z axis    degree
    PHI     mag. field azimuth about NSO Z azis     degree
 
 
    Files labeled nso_ebf_yyddd.jpg (yyddd indicates year and day)
    provide daily plots of Level 2 MAG data in both NSO and EBF
    coordinates.
 
    Name          Description                               Unit
    -----         -----------                               ----
    X             magnetic field X component                nT
    Y             magnetic field Y component                nT
    Z             magnetic field Z component                nT
    T             magnetic field magnitude                  nT
    THETA         mag. field direction from NSO Z axis      degree
    PHI           mag. field azimuth about NSO Z axis       degree
    R             NEAR distance from the Sun                AU
    SElong        NEAR longitude in solar ecliptic coord.   degree
    SElat         NEAR latitude from solar ecliptic coord.  degree
    Sunward Exc   arcsin(NSO_X/NSO_R)                       degree
    Clock Angle   atan2(NSO_Y,NSO_Z)                        degree
    Eros lat      NEAR latitude in EBF coordinates          degree
    Eros long     NEAR longitude in EBF coordinates         degree
    Eros-NEAR     Distance between NEAR and Eros            km
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
    Raw data contained in the Level 1 MAG dataset were processed by
    applying a series of corrections known from pre-flight calibrations
    and removing spacecraft fields evaluated in-flight. A summary of the
    calibration process is provided in the MAG_CALIBRATION document and
    more detailed descriptions can be found in [LOHRETAL1997] and
    [ANDERSONETAL2001]. Formally, the correction process within the
    spacecraft (SC) coordinates can be expressed as
 
        B_final_SC = [T1](B_Obs_SC - B_SC)
 
    Where B_final_SC is the calibrated field, B_Obs_SC is the measured
    field (i.e., the raw Level 1 data converted to physical units
    incorporating parameters obtained in the pre-flight calibration),
    and B_SC is the total satellite field.  The matrix [T1] represents
    the correction in sensor orientations and gain factors resulting
    from the in-flight calibration [ANDERSONETAL2001].
 
    The pre-flight calibration evaluated the linearity, orthogonality
    and cross talk of the MAG sensor block for each axis and each
    dynamic range.  This calibration provided absolute gain calibrations
    to 0.1% (0.5%) in the least (most) sensitive range and orientation
    to 1 arc minute [LOHRETAL1997].
 
    The major challenge in producing science-quality Level 2 MAG data
    was evaluation of spacecraft fields [ANDERSONETAL2001]. There are
    several known sources of spacecraft fields and each source was
    evaluated using the extensive in-flight data.  The following table
    summarizes the sources of spacecraft fields together with their
    approximate magnitude, characteristic time scale and type of signal,
    and mitigation approach.
 
    Source                 Propulsion valve motion.
    Magnitude              ~100nT.
    Time Scale             Propulsion events.
    Type of Signal         Discrete pairwise jumps - zero net change.
    Mitigation Approach    Flag Propulsion events.  Correcting data.
                           during propulsion events not necessary.
 
    Source                 Terminal board:  all spacecraft loads.
    Magnitude              25 nT.
    Time Scale             ~10 min (heaters),  &lt; 1 s (NLR).
    Type of Signal         Variable baseline with discrete jumps.
    Mitigation Approach    Field is directly proportional to load currents
                           monitored in spacecraft engineering data.
                           Loops measured during assembly.
 
    Source                 Digital power system shunts.
    Magnitude              5 to 10 nT.
    Time Scale             Hours to months.
    Type of Signal         Discrete jumps.
    Mitigation Approach    Ratio between digital shunt and total solar
                           array current identifies shunt step.  Field
                           fixed in each level.
 
    Source                 Analog power system shunts.
    Magnitude              5 nT.
    Time Scale             minutes.
    Type of Signal         Gradual variations with intermittent discrete
                           jumps
    Mitigation Approach    Field is proportional to analog current within
                           each of segments in analog shunt current
                           corresponding to the six analog shunt resistors
                           on the spacecraft.
 
    Source                 Solar Arrays.
    Magnitude              30 nT.
    Time Scale             hours to months.
    Type of Signal         Gradual shift with discrete jumps.
    Mitigation Approach    Field is proportional to total solar array
                           current.  Independent of digital shunt level.
 
    Source                 Momentum wheels.
    Magnitude              1 to 2 nT.
    Time Scale             0.2 to 10s Hz.  usually &gt; 0.5 Hz.
    Type of Signal         Superposition of four sinusoids corresponding
                           to rotation rate of four wheels.
    Mitigation Approach    Benign - wheel speeds kept above 0.5 Hz &amp;
                           monitored in engineering data.  Speeds &lt; 0.5 Hz
                           occur during maneuvers.  MAG 0.5 Hz filter
                           elimiates contamination.  1/s sampling allows
                           additional filtering if needed.
 
 
    Predictive correction algorithms (see Software below) were developed
    to evaluate these fields using the available spacecraft housekeeping
    data.  The corrections applied in the production of Level 2 MAG data
    include:
 
    1. Subtraction of constant offset fields.
    2. Subtraction of magnetic field generated by the system terminal
       board.
    3. Subtraction of magnetic field generated by the analog and
       digital power system shunts.
    4. Subtraction of magnetic field generated by solar array.
    5. Correction of stepwise fields due to on/off of sensor heaters.
 
    The final Level 2 MAG data were generated by rotating the field
    vector from spacecraft (SC) to NSO and EBF coordinates using the
    appropriate rotation matrix [T2] derived from information available
    in the SPICE volume:
 
        B_final = [T2]B_final_SC
 
 
    Sampling Rate
    =============
 
    MAG data were sampled at a rate that varied by command between 0.01
    and 20 samples/s.  During Eros observations the nominal rate was 1
    sample/s.  Brief, 10 minute, periods of 20 sample/s data were taken
    as part of weekly calibration checkout sequences.  During cruise
    operations the MAG sample rate was commanded to coarse values of
    0.01 samples/s or 0.02 samples/s.  During full MAG instrument
    checkout the instrument was commanded through the complete range of
    sample rates.  Full checkouts were performed after launch
    activation, after turn-on following the deep space maneuver and
    Mathilde fly-by, and prior to Eros orbit insertion.
 
    The full-time resolution data can be found in the Level 1 MAG
    volume.  The sampling rate presented in the Level 2 science data
    files differs from the original rate since it was necessary to
    remove spacecraft fields using housekeeping data that were sampled
    differently.  The spacecraft housekeeping data were 44 times more
    voluminous than the magnetometer data and were recorded at a maximum
    rate of one sample/s.  In practice, the spacecraft telemetry and
    data allocations allowed sampling of housekeeping no more often than
    one sample every 10s and typically 50s to 600 s between samples.
    The data rate for valid science data therefore actually ranged from
    two to four orders of magnitude less than the capabilities of the
    magnetometer instrument [ANDERSONETAL2001].
 
    It is important to note that the MAG science data sample rate
    varied, often irregularly.  This is due to the sequence of the
    command and telemetry processor (CTP) - spacecraft housekeeping
    data.   For the Level 2  science data, MAG samples that were nearest
    to CTP samples were selected in order to accurately remove
    time-dependent spacecraft fields.  There are a variety of reasons
    for occasional irregular sampling of CTP data: operations commands,
    commands from other instruments, and spacecraft autonomy.  All of
    the available CTP data were used to maximize the MAG science
    records.
 
 
    Range Setting
    =============
 
    The magnetometer had 8 ranges covering full-scale ranges from
    plus/minus 4 nT (range 0) to 65536 nT (range 7).  A 20-bit A/D
    conversion for these ranges resulted in resolutions of 1 pT (range
    0, limited by intrinsic instrument noise) to 2.0 nT (range 7).
    Range control was done either manually or automatically.  Automatic
    range control provided transition to less sensitive ranges when any
    one axis exceeded 87.5% of full scale for 0.25 s and shifted to a
    higher sensitivity when the field on all three axes fell below 17%
    of full-scale continuously for 1 min.  This ensured that the
    instrument follow rapid increases in field strength without rapidly
    toggling between ranges.  During cruise, the instrument was operated
    in range 3 (plus/minus 256 nT full scale, 0.008 nT resolution)
    [ANDERSONETAL2001].  The range setting is not provided in the Level
    2 data files.  All necessary range scale factors have been applied
    in Level 1 and Level 2 data files.  The range information is
    contained in Level 1 MAG files submitted to PDS. The range indicator
    ACTUAL_RANGE can be found in the Level 1 MAG data files
    MAGyyddd.FIT, where yyddd indicates year and day of year.
 
    The magnetometer operated in range 3 (256 nT full scale) for almost
    the entire mission.  Exceptions occurred during Earth flyby when the
    instrument cycled through all ranges, during instrument calibration
    and checkout, and during periods when the spacecraft field was
    larger than the maximum for range 3.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
 
    NEAR attitude and location and EROS location, which are necessary
    for MAG coordinate transformation, are included in separate SPICE
    volumes.  In each of the SPICE volumes that are organized by mission
    phase, there are the /DATA/SPK directory for EROS and NEAR position
    information and the /DATA/CK directory for the NEAR attitude
    information.
 
 
    Coordinate Systems
    ==================
 
    Two coordinate systems are adopted for Level 2 MAG data presentation.
 
    NEAR Sun Orbital (NSO) coordinates are Cartesian coordinates defined
    with respect to the NEAR-Sun line and the orbit plane of Eros.  The
    X-axis points from NEAR to the Sun, the Z direction is given by the
    Eros velocity vector crossed into X, northward normal to the Eros
    orbital plane, and Y completes the right-handed set.
 
    Eros Body Fixed (EBF) coordinate system has its Z-axis along the
    Eros spin axis, the X-axis is in the Eros equatorial plane, and lies
    in the direction of the prime meridian. The Y-axis completes the
    right-handed set.
 
 
    Software
    ========
 
    Software for production of science-quality Level 2 data from the raw
    magnetometer data contained in the Level 1 data is provided in
    MAG_SW document in this volume.  The software consists of two
    packages, SDC_PROC and SCI_PROC.  The packages perform all data
    processing needed as the result of sensor calibration and evaluation
    of spacecraft fields as described above under the subheading of
    Processing.
 
    The SDC_PROC codes were used for reading Hierarchical Data Format
    (HDF) data files produced by the Science Data Center (SDC),
    extracting the pertinent magnetometer, command telemetry processors
    (CTP), and housekeeping data, and producing plots and data files for
    the NEAR MAG experiment.  The files generated by these codes are
    used as input to the second software package SCI_PROC.
 
    The main functions of SCI_PROC are: open and read the input files,
    apply corrections to the data, and produce plots and ASCII data
    files.
 
    The codes are found in the in the MAG_SW directory of the present
    volume.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
 
    This data set is released as a CDROM set.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This data set is currently undergoing external peer review within
      PDS in August, 2001.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
 
    Gaps in data coverage exist for many reasons including telemetry
    outage.  Gaps are not filled with flagged data.
 
    The magnetometer was calibrated using in-flight data acquired during
    the Earth swing-by of January 1997 and during simultaneous solar
    wind measurements by the WIND from January 22-24, 1997
    [ANDERSONETAL2001].  The calibration during the Earth swing-by
    resulted in less than 50 nT residuals in the Earth&apos;s main field of &gt;
    20000 nT, corresponding to an accuracy better than 0.3 percent.  As
    for the absolute accuracy, the final magnetometer data are accurate
    to ~1 nT.  This corresponds to ~0.4 percent of the full scale of
    range 3, which is used during most of the NEAR mission.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
 
    Samples with unusually large values, producing spikes when plotted,
    occur in the Level 2 MAG data.  These are caused either by internal
    MAG calibration signals or by firing of the spacecraft thruster
    (propulsion events).  The calibration signals have a shape of a
    box-car with a magnitude of ~470 nT and a duration of ~300 seconds.
    During Eros operations these calibrations were performed weekly.
    The thruster-induced spikes have varying amplitudes and durations
    and can be easily distinguished from the calibration signals.  They
    occur at times of spacecraft maneuvers or momentum management
    activities.
 
    The following table lists the dates and approximate times of
    propulsion events on the NEAR spacecraft during the Eros orbital
    phase of the mission.  Propulsion events are indicated by the
    mnemonic adopted by NEAR Mission Operations.
 
    Event   Year    Day of year Time UTC    Orbital change/description
                                (hhmm)
 
    OIM     2000       045       1530        Orbit insertion
    OCM1    2000       055       1700        to 365 X 204 km
    OCM2    2000       063       1800        to 204 x 200 km
    MCM1    2000       075       2000        Momentum management
    OCM3    2000       093       0205        to 210 x 100 km
    OCM4    2000       102       2110        to 100 x 100 km
    OCM5    2000       113       1730        to 101 x 50 km
    OCM6    2000       121       1615        to 51 x 49 km
    MCM3    2000       131       1400        Momentum management
    MCM4    2000       138       1300        Momentum management
    MCM5    2000       145       1300        Momentum management
    MCM6    2000       152       1600        Momentum management
    MCM7    2000       159       1600        Momentum management
    MCM8    2000       166       1600        Momentum management
    MCM9    2000       173       1600        Momentum management
    MCM10   2000       180       1600        Momentum management
    OCM7    2000       189       1800        to 50 x 35 km
    OCM8    2000       196       0300        to 37 x 35 km
    OCM9    2000       206       1700        to 50 x 37 km
    OCM10   2000       213       1930        to 51 x 49 km
    OCM11   2000       221       2325        retrograde inclination adjust
    OCM12   2000       239       2325        to 100 x 50 km
    OCM13   2000       249       2300        to 100 x 100 km
    MCM12   2000       264       1700        Momentum management
    OCM14   2000       287       0545        to 98 x 50 km
    OCM15   2000       294       2140        to 50 x 50 km
    OCM16   2000       299       2210        to 50 x 19 km
    OCM17   2000       300       1740        to 198 x 67 km
    OCM18   2000       308       0700        to 198 x 195 km
    MCM13   2000       320       2000        Momentum management
    MCM14   2000       334       1730        Momentum management
    OCM19   2000       342       1535        to 196 x 35 km
    OCM20   2000       348       2015        to 36 x 34
    MCM15   2000       362       1925        Momentum management
    MCM16   2001       009       1840        Momentum management
    OCM21   2001       024       1605        to 35 x 21 km
    OCM22   2001       028       0120        to 35 x 19 km
    OCM23   2001       028       1810        to 36 x 34
    OCM24   2001       033       0851        Preparation for end of mission
    OCM25   2001       037       1743        Preparation for end of mission
    EMM1    2001       043       1514        End of mission - descent
    EMM2    2001       043       1858        End of mission - descent
    EMM3    2001       043       1914        End of mission - descent
    EMM4    2001       043       1930        End of mission - descent
    EMM5    2001       043       1941        End of mission - descent
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>DVD-R</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>96-008A-03B</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

