<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mgn-v-rss-1-tracking-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MAGELLAN RAW RADIO TRACKING DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.magellan::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mgn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.mgn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgn-v-rss-1-tracking-v1.0__browserp_mgn-v-rss-1-tracking-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Konopliv, A.S., and W.L. Sjogren, Venus Gravity Handbook, Jet Propulsion
                   Laboratory Publication 96-2, January 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KONOPLIV-SJOGREN1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Konopliv, A.S., W.B. Banerdt, W.L. Sjogren, Venus Gravity: 180th degree and
                   order model, Icarus, 139, 3-18, 1999.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KONOPLIVETAL1999</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MGN-V-RSS-1-TRACKING-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MAGELLAN RAW RADIO TRACKING DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2010-10-28</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1989-05-04</start_time>
        <stop_time>1994-10-12</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>RICHARD A. SIMPSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Simpson, R.A., Magellan Raw Radio Tracking Data V1.0,
            MGN-V-RSS-1-TRACKING-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2010.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw radio tracking data from the MAGELLAN mission to Venus
            (1989-1994)
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Archival Tracking Data Files (ATDFs, also sometimes known as
            TRK-2-25 data) from the MAGELLAN mission to Venus (1989-1994) and
            Orbit Data Files (ODFs, also known as TRK-2-18 data) from the
            final 2-3 years of the MAGELLAN mission (1992-1994). These data
            include range and Doppler measurements from the radio tracking
            system of the NASA Deep Space Network (DSN). The measurements can
            be used to derive a spherical harmonic model of the Venus gravity
            field.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      This data set contains 243 Archival Tracking Data Files (ATDFs) and
      6 Orbit Data Files (ODFs) from the MAGELLAN mission to Venus.
      The ATDFs were collected at Earth stations of the NASA Deep Space
      Network (DSN) from May 1989 (as MAGELLAN began its cruise to Venus)
      until October 1994 (after the MAGELLAN &apos;termination experiment&apos;).
      ODF coverage is only from April 1992 to end of mission; ODFs were
      reconstructed from NAVIO files (an in-house format at the NASA Jet
      Propulsion Laboratory, JPL).  The data have been used to derive
      spherical harmonic models of the Venus gravity field
      [KONOPLIVETAL1999][KONOPLIV&amp;SJOGREN1996].  The models can be
      obtained from the NASA Planetary Data System (PDS), where they are
      part of data set MGN-V-RSS-5-GRAVITY-L2-V1.0.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      ATDFs and ODFs contain measurements of range between the Earth
      station and MAGELLAN spacecraft, Doppler shift of the carrier
      frequency, carrier signal strength, and ground station azimuth
      and elevation angles.  They also contain many ground station
      configuration parameters.  The ODF is an edited and compressed
      (time integration) version of the ATDF.  The ODFs in this archive
      are aggregations covering about one year each (1992, 1993, and
      1994).
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      ATDF data were collected using one or more DSN closed-loop receivers,
      which reported frequency and amplitude of the MAGELLAN carrier signal
      at a rate (typically) of 10 times per second.  When a coded (ranging)
      subcarrier was used, a correlator estimated round-trip time between
      Earth and spacecraft, which can be interpreted as two-way distance.
      The file of measured values was screened manually, and &apos;bad&apos;
      measurements were removed.  There has been no other ATDF processing.
 
      ODF files are usually derived from one or more ATDFs.  The MAGELLAN
      ODFs were reconstructed from NAVIO files (an internal JPL format).
      In addition to being edited versions of ATDFs, these ODFs contain
      averaged values of observation parameters -- both 2- and 10-second
      averages are available (in separate files).
 
 
    Data
    ====
      The archive comprises 243 ATDFs, 6 ODFs, and supporting
      documentation on the structure and content of the ATDF and ODF.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      Also included in the data set are four data types that may be used
      to calibrate the radio tracking measurements.  Angular Momentum
      Desaturation (AMD) files -- also known as Small Forces Files -- are
      included in the AMD directory.  Media calibration files for
      ionospheric and tropospheric effects are in the ION and TRO
      directories, respectively.  Local weather conditions at the
      NASA DSN complexes are stored in the WEA directory.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      The radio data are not strongly dependent on coordinate systems.
      Ground antenna azimuth and elevation are in an unknown local frame;
      but it is the range and Doppler measurements which are most important
      and those are independent of the coordinate system chosen.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      No software is included with this archive.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      This archival data set were delivered to the PDS Geosciences (GEO)
      Node on three DVD+R discs.  They will be distributed electronically.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      These data have not been reviewed for quality.  Five original files
      were not included in the archive for the reasons noted below:
 
          Coverage (YYYY/DDD)   Reason for Omission from Archive
          -------------------  ----------------------------------
           1990/166-1990/193   Lost before GEO collection in 1997
           1991/084-1991/112   Corrupted
           1992/034-1992/050   Duplicate
           1993/313-1993/313   Duplicate
           1994/162-1994/164   Corrupted
 
      The NAVIO files (parents of the ODFs) have been used to compute a
      180x180 spherical harmonic model of the Venus gravity field
      [KONOPLIVETAL1999].   Additional information on data quality may
      be found in the Venus Gravity Handbook [KONOPLIV&amp;SJOGREN1996].
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was reviewed by a peer review panel prior
      to its acceptance by the Planetary Data System (PDS).  The peer
      review was conducted by the PDS Geosciences Node in accordance with
      PDS procedures.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      The ATDF tracking data began on 1989-05-04, as MAGELLAN started its
      cruise to Venus.  The last ATDF ends on 1994-10-12, the day after
      the MAGELLAN &apos;termination&apos; experiment.  ODF coverage began on
      1992-04-22 and ended on 1994-10-12.
 
      The coverage and quality are variable, but were sufficiently good
      that [KONOPLIVETAL1999] derived a 180x180 spherical harmonic model
      of the gravity field from the tracking data.  Corrupted and lost data
      are listed above under Overview.
 
      There are five angular momentum desaturation (AMD) files covering
      the years 1990 (days 215-365), 1991, 1992, 1993, and 1994 (to end of
      mission).  Fifty-six (56) ION files cover 1990 to end of mission except
      that June and July 1993 are missing.  Forty-four (44) TRO files cover
      1990 (days 091-365), 1991 (except that February - April are missing),
      1992 (January - August are missing), 1993, and 1994 (through end of
      mission).  Fifteen (15) WEA files are included, covering 1989 through
      1994 except that 1991 files are missing for all DSN complexes.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      No limitations are known other than those which would apply
      when working with data of this quality.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

