<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ody-m-mar-3-rdr-calibrated-data-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ODYSSEY MARS MARIE CALIBRATED DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.2001_mars_odyssey::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.ody::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mar.ody::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-mar-3-rdr-calibrated-data-v1.0__browserp_ody-m-mar-3-rdr-calibrated-data-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CUCINOTTA2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Zeitlin, C., F. Riman, S. Joy and M. Sharlow, MARIE Standard Products
                   Archive Volume Software Interface Specification (MARIE Archive Volume
                   SIS), Version 1.03 (draft document), Planetary Data System, September 11,
                   2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ZEITLINETAL2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>ODY-M-MAR-3-RDR-CALIBRATED-DATA-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ODYSSEY MARS MARIE CALIBRATED DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2002-07-18</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2001-04-23</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. CARY ZEITLIN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Data set contains calibrated data from the MARIE instrument
            onboard the Mars Odyssey spacecraft. All data (cruise, prime
            mission, etc.) are contained in this data set. Data have been
            calibrated and processed into physical units.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The MARIE (Martian Radiation Environment Experiment), aboard the
            2001 Mars Odyssey spacecraft, was launched on April 7, 2001, and
            arrived at Mars on October 24, 2001. Data were collected
            intermittently during the cruise phase, starting in late April
            and ending in late July. A problem with MARIE&apos;s onboard
            computer occurred in early August, and the instrument was turned
            off until early March, 2002, after Odyssey&apos;s mapping orbit
            had been established. Data have been collected from that time to
            the present without major interruption. Routine minor
            interruptions of up to 36 hours have occurred during the orbital
            phase the instrument&apos;s data is erased from local storage
            (after having been downloaded). MARIE is oriented to point in the
            direction opposite Odyssey&apos;s velocity vector. Space
            radiation is for the most part isotropic, so the orientation of
            Odyssey is usually not critical and references to external
            coordinate systems are not a part of the data returned by MARIE.
            There is one exception to the statement that space radiation is
            isotropic: During the early stages of solar particle events,
            there can be directionality in the particle flux.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The MARIE (Martian Radiation Environment Experiment), aboard the
    2001 Mars Odyssey spacecraft, was launched on April 7, 2001, and
    arrived at Mars on October 24, 2001. Data were collected
    intermittently during the cruise phase, starting in late April and
    ending in late July. A problem with MARIE&apos;s onboard computer
    occurred in early August, and the instrument was turned off until
    early March, 2002, after Odyssey&apos;s mapping orbit had been
    established. Data have been collected from that time to the present
    without major interruption. Routine minor interruptions of up to 36
    hours have occurred during the orbital phase; the outages occur when
    the instrument&apos;s data is erased from local storage (after having
    been downloaded). MARIE is oriented to point in the direction
    opposite Odyssey&apos;s velocity vector. Space radiation is for the most
    part isotropic, so the orientation of Odyssey is usually not
    critical and references to external coordinate systems are not a
    part of the data returned by MARIE. There is one exception to the
    statement that space radiation is isotropic: During the early stages
    of solar particle events, there can be directionality in the
    particle flux.
 
    A manuscript containing a detailed description of MARIE is in
    preparation at the time of this writing (September 2002).
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The MARIE consists primarily of silicon detectors, of three
    different types: the A detectors, which are square in cross-section
    (25.4 mm on a side) and 1 mm in depth; the B detectors, circular,
    63.5 mm diameter and 5 mm thick; and the PSDs, or
    position-sensitive detectors. The PSDs are square double-sided
    strip detectors with 24 1-mm strips on each side (the strips on one
    side are orthogonal to those on the other side), and have a
    thickness of 0.3 mm. There are two A detectors, A1 and A2;
    sandwiched in between them are PSD1 and PSD2; behind A2, there are
    the B detectors, B1 through B4. Downstream of B4 is a circular
    piece of quartz, 10 mm thick, that radiates photons (Cerenkov
    radiation) generated by the passage of high-velocity particles
    through it. The Cerenkov photons are reflected by a 45-degree
    mirror into a photomultiplier tube that sits out of the path of
    particles that hit the detectors.
 
    The MARIE is triggered by a coincidence of hits in detectors A1 and
    A2. Once triggered, the data acquisition system records 12-bit
    digitized outputs that are proportional to the energies deposited
    in the A and B detectors. A two-byte data word is stored for each
    of these channels. The pulse height from the Cerenkov phototube is
    similarly digitized in 12 bits and stored.
 
    Readout of the PSDs is more complex. Each PSD has two orthogonal
    sides, referred to as columns and rows. The following description
    applies to each side of each detector. Onboard hardware analyzes
    the signals from each of the 24 strips and finds the two largest
    pulse heights. For each, the pulse height is digitized in 8 bits
    (256 channels) and stored, along with the strip number. The largest
    pulse height and position are referred to as &apos;event1&apos;, the
    second-largest as &apos;event2.&apos; The event2 data are often detector
    noise not resulting from the passage of a charged particle. Four
    quantities are stored for each side of each detector, so that a
    total of sixteen words (thirty-two bytes) of PSD data are stored on
    each event. The eight-bit digitized pulse heights are referred to
    as &apos;magnitudes&apos; (abbreviated to &apos;_Mag&apos; in the list below). The
    positions (listed as &apos;_Pos&apos; below) are valid only when in the range
    1 to 24.
 
    The full 72-byte data structure for each event is listed below.
    Please note well that this structure is not directly reflected in
    the RDR data files, which are obtained by processing of the REDR
    files that do have a structure like the one described here:
 
    The first nine bytes are instrument and record identifiers,
    checksums, etc. Bytes 10-15 are the timestamp. Detector data begin
    at byte 16 and consist of 23 2-byte words. Bytes 62-72 are flags,
    the first seven of which are unused; the last four are the PSD
    status registers (one for each side of each PSD).
 
       TypeId  : Byte;        { identifies what kind of record this is }
       InstID  : Byte;        { identifies which instrument this is }
       RunId   : Byte;        { identifies the current run }
       RecordId: Byte;        { running count of records }
       len     : Word;        { 2 bytes - size of actual record on
                                flash }
       CheckSum: word;        { 2 bytes }
       NumberEvents: byte;    { 1 byte total of events per 100 ms. FF
                                max }
       Time    : real;        { 6 bytes }
       Event   : EventsArray; { 46 bytes of digitized detector pulse
                                heights }
       Flags   : FlagsArray;  { 11 bytes }
 
    The following bytes are always the same in every valid record:
    TypeId (value = 3B hexadecimal), InstID (value = 1), and len (48
    hexadecimal, 72 decimal). The first nine bytes are considered
    housekeeping data and are not kept in the RDR data files.
 
    The 46 bytes of detector data are 23 2-byte words, ordered as
    follows:
 
           A1, A2, B1, B2, B3, B4, C1; { for all, valid data in the
                                         lowest 12 bits }
           PSD1_Row_Event1_Mag;   { valid data in the lowest 8 bits }
           PSD1_Row_Event1_Pos;   { valid data in the range 1 to 24 }
           PSD1_Row_Event2_Mag;   { valid data in the lowest 8 bits }
           PSD1_Row_Event2_Pos;   { valid data in the range 1 to 24 }
           PSD1_Col_Event1_Mag;   { valid data in the lowest 8 bits }
           PSD1_Col_Event1_Pos;   { valid data in the range 1 to 24 }
           PSD1_Col_Event2_Mag;   { valid data in the lowest 8 bits }
           PSD1_Col_Event2_Pos;   { valid data in the range 1 to 24 }
           PSD2_Row_Event1_Mag;   { valid data in the lowest 8 bits }
           PSD2_Row_Event1_Pos;   { valid data in the range 1 to 24 }
           PSD2_Row_Event2_Mag;   { valid data in the lowest 8 bits }
           PSD2_Row_Event2_Pos;   { valid data in the range 1 to 24 }
           PSD2_Col_Event1_Mag;   { valid data in the lowest 8 bits }
           PSD2_Col_Event1_Pos;   { valid data in the range 1 to 24 }
           PSD2_Col_Event2_Mag;   { valid data in the lowest 8 bits }
           PSD2_Col_Event2_Pos;   { valid data in the range 1 to 24 }
 
    The 11 bytes of the flag array are, in order:
 
           FlagA1,   FlagA2,   FlagA3,
           FlagB1,   FlagB2,   FlagB3,   FlagC1,
           FlagPSD1_Row, FlagPSD2_Row, FlagPSD1_Col, FlagPSD2_Col
 
    Only the last four contain valid data.
 
    The RDR data files do not directly reflect the above described
    record structure, but they are obtained from processing of raw
    data files which do have this structure.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    These data have been calibrated for the A and B detectors, and
    converted into physical units rather than digitizer output. In the
    calibration procedure, cruise data was used to select a sample of
    events triggered by noise (i.e., with no real particle in the
    detectors). From these data, the digitizer offsets, also known as
    &apos;pedestals,&apos; were determined. A second sample containing high-
    energy protons was also culled from the cruise data. Because the
    energy deposited by a proton in a given depth of silicon is easily
    calculated, one can obtain the scaling factor needed for each
    detector channel to convert (after subtracting the pedestal for
    that channel) digitizer values into deposited energies. The
    processing involves extraction and calculation of the data values
    found in the processed data files, including the calculation of the
    particle incident angles based on the PSD hits.  In addition,
    records or values judged to contain errors are removed or flagged.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    These data consist of tabular files (extension .TAB) in ASCII
    format. Each record consists of 20 fields and is terminated by a
    carriage return/ line feed (ASCII 13/ASCII 10) line ending.  The
    first two fields of each record comprise a two-part time tag for
    the record. The total length of each record, including line
    terminator, is 149 bytes.
 
    The column structure of each record is summarized below.
 
      Column   Data       Description
               Type
      ------   ----       ------------------------------
        1      Character  Time (2 fields, year and decimal day,
                          with beginning of Jan. 1 = 1.0)
        2      Real       Event number (with events numbered
                          sequentially)
        3      Real       Energy deposited in A1
        4      Real       Energy deposited in A2
        5      Real       Energy deposited in B1
        6      Real       Energy deposited in B2
        7      Real       Energy deposited in B3
        8      Real       Energy deposited in B4
        9      Real       Cerenkov detector pulse height (uncalibrated)
       10      Real       Row magnitude from PSD1
       11      Real       Row position from PSD1
       12      Real       Column magnitude from PSD1
       13      Real       Column position from PSD1
       14      Real       Row magnitude from PSD2
       15      Real       Row position from PSD2
       16      Real       Column magnitude from PSD2
       17      Real       Column position from PSD2
       18      Real       Sum of energies deposited in A1, A2, and
                          B1-B4
       19      Real       Incident angle of particle (calculated)
 
    Deposited energy values in the A and B detectors are given in
    units of MeV (millions of electron volts).  The scale factors and
    offsets needed to convert digitizer outputs to physically
    meaningful deposited energy values were determined by the
    calibration procedure outlined above.  Saturation of the A detector
    electronics is observed to occur at about 70 MeV, and at about 350
    MeV for the B detectors, in both cases corresponding to about
    charge 11 for highly relativistic heavy ions.  In principle similar
    calibration constants could be applied to the PSD magnitudes, but
    this has not been implemented owing to the generally poor
    resolution of those data. The signal from the Cerenkov detector is
    uncalibrated and reported only in units of digitizer channels (0 to
    4095 valid).
 
    The PSD positions and magnitudes are derived from the full set of
    reported hits in the raw data, referred to as &apos;event1&apos; (which is
    determined by the strip number that reports the largest-magnitude
    hit) and &apos;event2&apos; (corresponding to the second-largest hit
    magnitude). Each detector plane (row or column) reports event1 and
    event2. In the majority of cases, &apos;event2&apos; position and magnitude
    are both reported as 0, which is reasonable because on most
    triggers only one particle passes through the MARIE detectors.  In
    some cases, event1 may be reported with an unphysical value (0 or &gt;
    24), while event2 reports a physically-reasonable value.  When this
    occurs, the processing software outputs the position and magnitude
    of event2 as the values for that detector plane.
 
    The PSD hits are used to calculate the incident angle of the
    particle. When one or more PSD planes report a value of 0, or
    greater than 24, the angle cannot be calculated and the output
    value is set to -5 in order to flag the problem. Valid angles are
    calculable on a minority of events. When a valid calculation is
    possible, the formula given below is used, and the value is
    converted to degrees in the output. Due to the constraints imposed
    by the A1 * A2 coincidence requirement, only angles less than about
    34 degrees are possible.
 
    On every trigger, the MARIE clock is polled and the time is stored
    in a 6-byte data word in the event record. The time is measured in
    minutes on the Julian calendar, which takes as its starting time 12
    hours Universal Time (Greenwich mean noon) on noon of November 24,
    -4713. In processing, the 6-byte data words are converted to a year
    and day of year, which includes a fractional day. The day of year
    is stored, in the processing software, as a 4-byte real number,
    hence some precision is lost. In the .TAB files, the time is
    represented by the year, in column 1, along with a real number in
    column 2 that corresponds to the day of year. The day of year
    contains 8 digits to the right of the decimal place; the least
    significant digit equals (approximately) 1 millisecond. Due to
    rounding errors, and MARIE&apos;s ability to acquire data at a fairly
    high rate, it is possible for consecutive events to appear to occur
    at the same time, to the precision given here.
 
    Invalid values of the year and position columns have been flagged
    with the value &apos;-1.&apos;.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    The ancillary data provided with this dataset include files of the
    following four kinds.  These ancillary files are classified as part
    of the raw reformatted (REDR) dataset.
 
    (1)  Detector files (file type DET):  These are ASCII table files
    which describe the temperatures of the detectors in the instrument.
    At the beginning of each file is a table header which names the
    columns.
 
    (2)  High Voltage files (file type EXT):  These are ASCII table
    files which describe the maximum voltages in the electronic boards
    in the instrument.  At the beginning of each file is a table header
    which names the columns.
 
    (3)  Board files (file type BRD):  These are ASCII table files
    which describe the temperatures of the electronic boards in the
    instrument.  At the beginning of each file is a table header which
    names the columns.  (The BRD files differ from the DET files
    because each board is only part of a detector and has its own
    thermistor for temperature monitoring, distinct from the thermistor
    for the board.)
 
    (4)  Power files (file type PWR):  These are ASCII table files
    which describe the power consumption of the detectors.  At the
    beginning of each file is a table header which names the columns.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    MARIE&apos;s internal coordinate system is defined by the geometry of
    the detector. The PSDs have their own coordinate system in the sense
    that each strip (corresponding to a row or a column) is assigned a
    sequential number from 1 to 24. These values are not referenced to
    any other coordinate system, as the primary purpose of the PSDs is
    to calculate the angle at which incident particles traverse the
    silicon detectors. With valid hits in all rows and columns, the
    angle THETA with respect to the vertical (normal incidence) can be
    calculated as follows. We define
 
 
    DELTAr = PSD1_Row_Pos - PSD2_Row_Pos,
    DELTAc = PSD1_Col_Pos - PSD2_Col_Pos, and
    d = the distance between PSD1 and PSD2. Then
 
           tan(THETA) = [ (DELTAr**2 + DELTAc**2) / d**2 ]**1/2
 
    where ** indicates exponentiation.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    A version of the software used for production of calibrated
    data from raw data files is included in the EXTRAS directory
    on the archive volume.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    Data are archived on recordable DVD (DVD-R) in UDF/ISO 9660 Bridge
    format with ISO 9660 level 2 compliance in the ISO partition. The
    data are provided as ASCII tables of time tagged data (see file
    description above).
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
 
    Review
    ------
      The raw (REDR) data on which these data are based have been
      reviewed by the instrument team and are of the highest quality
      that can be generated at this time. The process for production of
      RDR data has been evaluated by the instrument team and by the PDS.
      These data will be reviewed collaboratively by the team and by the
      PDS, and will undergo PDS peer review.
 
 
    Data Coverage/Quality
    ---------------------
      MARIE was on for parts of the 2001 Mars Odyssey cruise phase,
      starting in late April 2001 and ending in late July 2001. A
      problem with the onboard computer occurred in early August, and
      the instrument was turned off until mid-March, 2002, after
      Odyssey&apos;s mapping orbit had been established. Data have been
      collected from that time to the present without major
      interruption. Routine minor interruptions of up to 48 hours have
      been encountered during the orbital phase; the outages occur when
      the instrument&apos;s data is erased (after having been downloaded).
      Additional shorter outages of approximately 2 hours duration occur
      on a daily basis while data are downloaded.
 
      A small fraction (typically &lt; 1% of events in a given file) of the
      time tags in the processed data are out of chronological order.
      This occurs in the raw (REDR) data and is propagated to the
      processed data set; it reflects a problem with the MARIE clock
      that is not understood at this time.  As there is no obvious way
      to correct these errors, they have not been removed or adjusted in
      the processed data set.  In addition, some time tags are corrupted
      and contained an invalid year.  In the processed data, these
      records have been flagged with a &apos;-1.&apos; in the year field.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
 
    Geometric Acceptance
    --------------------
      MARIE&apos;s geometry is optimized for detecting particles coming into
      the detector (hitting A1 first) in a forward cone of half-angle
      approximately 30 degrees. The angle is defined with respect to the
      centerline of the silicon detectors. Particles incident at larger
      angles may hit one or more detectors, but will not satisfy the
      requirement of coincident hits in A1 and A2. Forward-going
      particles encounter minimal (but finite) mass before entering
      MARIE, and must have residual range sufficient to penetrate as far
      as A2. As of this writing (May 2002), best estimates of the
      material in front of MARIE lead to the prediction that the minimum
      free-space (i.e., before encountering any material) kinetic energy
      required for a proton to reach A2 is about 30 MeV. For helium-4
      ions, the minimum kinetic energy is 30 MeV/nucleon, and for
      heavier ions, the energy per nucleon increases as a function of
      the ion&apos;s charge and mass. MARIE can also be triggered by
      particles entering from the rear, provided they are sufficiently
      energetic to hit both A2 and A1. For a proton, this corresponds to
      a minimum energy of 72 MeV incident on B4. However, any such
      particle must pass through a considerable (currently unknown) mass
      in order to reach B4. (The mass in question is primarily due to
      Odyssey&apos;s oxidizer tank.)  Backward-going particles must therefore
      be far more energetic than their forward-going counterparts in
      order to trigger MARIE&apos;s readout.
 
      In the data, backward-going particles can, in some cases, be
      distinguished by the patterns of energy deposition they leave in
      the silicon detectors; for particular particle/energy
      combinations, these patterns may be quite distinct from those of
      forward-going particles of the same type and energy. In addition,
      the Cerenkov detector is directional, and no Cerenkov photons will
      be recorded for backwards-going particles.
 
 
    Saturation of Electronics
    -------------------------
      As of May 2002, all MARIE data have been taken with all silicon
      detectors operating at full depletion. The gains of the
      electronics combined with the limitations on input voltage into
      the analog-to-digital converters (ADCs) - are such that the A
      channels saturate at approximately 70 MeV energy deposited, while
      the B channels saturate at about 350 MeV energy deposited. Because
      deposited energy is a function of the charge (Z) squared of an
      incident heavy ion, this limits the detectable range of particle
      charges. In the present configuration, the largest usable signal
      corresponds to highly-energetic ions of charge 11. For more
      highly-charged particles, the signals are so large that the
      digitizer outputs go to full scale, and all resolution is lost.
      The Galactic Cosmic Radiation contains all elements up to uranium,
      though ions heavier than iron (charge 26) are rare. At present,
      and for the foreseeable future, ions with charge 12 and greater
      are detected by MARIE, but with no resolution.
 
 
    PSD Performance
    ---------------
      The PSD performance for sparsely-ionizing particles such as
      protons is known to be marginal. The detectors are thin
      (300 microm), so that signals are small and noise (which falls
      with increasing detector depth) is relatively large. The onboard
      algorithm for finding hits returns many 0 values (no hit found),
      many more values of 1 than is physically reasonable, and in the
      case of PSD1 columns, many more values of 24 than is physically
      reasonable. It is likely the case that the edge channels of the
      PSDs are nosier than those in the middle, and hence are often
      mistakenly identified by the onboard processing algorithm as
      having been hit. If the detectors were working optimally, all
      histograms of row and column positions would show broad
      distributions peaked in the middle. Only the distribution of hits
      in the PSD1 rows approximates the expected shape. One possible
      improvement would be to raise the software thresholds the
      hit-finding algorithm in the onboard firmware uses.  This would
      result in more &apos;0&apos; values (no hit found) but would reduce or
      eliminate erroneous positions from noise hits. At the time of this
      writing (Septmber 2002), the instrument team is also investigating
      the possibility that some non-physical readings are caused by bit
      flips in the processing firmware. Some of these may be correctable
      in future processing.
 
 
    Cerenkov Detector Performance
    -----------------------------
      The Cerenkov detector performance is currently marginal. Signals
      are far smaller than expected, which suggests that the voltage on
      the photomultiplier tube is too low or possibly that the alignment
      of the 45 degree mirror is bad. Attemps to raise the phototube
      voltage failed due to a bug in the onboard control software. This
      may be corrected in the future when new control software is
      uploaded.
 
 
    Clock Issues and Time Tag Significance
    --------------------------------------
      Occasionally, MARIE&apos;s clock appears to jump backward by a fairly
      large interval (often on the order of minutes) from one event to
      the next. The source of this error is unknown. Usually, within the
      next few events, the clock jumps ahead to where one would expect
      it to be. Such jumps have been noted to occur up to 25 times in a
      file of 50,000 event records. As of this writing (September 2002),
      the instrument team is unable to diagnose or cure the problem. As
      few events are affected, and most users will likely be binning
      data in time bins on the order of many minutes or even hours,
      these do not present a serious problem.
 
      A second category of clock problems occurs when MARIE data is
      being downloaded to the spacecraft&apos;s data buffer at midnight.
      When this happens, the MARIE clock does not increment the day
      counter, and when data acquisition resumes, the clock is one day
      behind.  It remains in this state until the next data erase
      sequence (which typically occurs about once every 7 to 10 days,
      depending on solar activity), at which time MARIE&apos;s clock is
      synchronized to the Odyssey master clock and the problem is fixed
      (until the next time it occurs). For this reason, deliberate
      efforts have been made to avoid downloading MARIE data over
      midnight boundaries. While the problem has not been entirely
      eliminated, the frequency with which it occurs has decreased.
 
 
    Calibration Issues
    ------------------
      There are considerable uncertainties in the calibration constants
      that are used to convert raw pulse height readings to deposited
      energies. For the A1 and A2 detectors, we estimate the
      uncertainties to be +- 20%. For the B detectors, we estimate the
      uncertainties to be +- 15%. These are uncertainties in the
      absolute scale of deposited energy; they are not expected to vary
      significantly within a particular data set, but they may show
      long-term variations. As of this writing (Dec. 2002), further
      work to determine these constants with greater precision is in
      progress, using stopping protons from Solar Particle Events.
      Periodic monitoring of the constants will be needed to look for,
      and correct, any drifts in amplifier gains.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

