<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dif-c-e-x-spice-6-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>EPOXI SPICE KERNELS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.epoxi::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.103p-hartley_2_1986_e2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:star.gj_436::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:star.hat-p-4::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:star.hat-p-7::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:star.tres-2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:star.tres-3::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:star.wasp-3::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:star.xo-2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:star.xo-3::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dif-c-e-x-spice-6-v1.0__browserp_dif-c-e-x-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dif-c-e-x-spice-6-v1.0__browser_dif-c-e-x-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dif-c-e-x-spice-6-v1.0__browser_wgc_dif-c-e-x-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.naif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DIF-C/E/X-SPICE-6-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>EPOXI SPICE KERNELS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2009-03-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2005-08-23T17:19:48Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2011-03-01T00:59:44Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>BORIS V. SEMENOV</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Semenov, B.V., and C.H. Acton, EPOXI SPICE KERNELS V1.0,
            DIF-C/E/X-SPICE-6-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2009.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Navigation and ancillary data in the form of SPICE System kernel
            files for the EPOXI mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set includes the complete set of EPOXI SPICE data files
            (``kernel files&apos;&apos;), which can be accessed using SPICE
            software. The SPICE data contains geometric and other ancillary
            information needed to recover the full value of the science
            instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft
            and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments,
            spacecraft orientation, spacecraft sequences of events, and data
            needed for relevant time conversions.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
 
      This data set includes the complete set of EPOXI SPICE data files
      (``kernel files&apos;&apos;), which can be accessed using SPICE software.
      The SPICE data contains geometric and other ancillary information
      needed to recover the full value of the science instrument data.
      In particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft and planetary
      ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments, spacecraft
      orientation, spacecraft sequences of events, and data needed for
      relevant time conversions.
 
 
      Data Types (SPICE kernel types)
      ===============================
 
      SPK kernels contain ephemerides for spacecraft, planets,
      satellites, comets and asteroids as well as for moving or fixed
      spacecraft and instrument structures. They provide position and
      velocity, given in a Cartesian reference frame. SPK files are
      located under the ``data/spk&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      PCK kernels contain certain physical, dynamical and
      cartographic constants for target bodies, such as size and shape
      specifications, and the orientation of the spin axis and prime
      meridian. PCK files are located under the ``data/pck&apos;&apos; directory
      of this data set.
 
      IK kernels (Instrument description kernels) give descriptive and
      operational data peculiar to a particular scientific instrument,
      such as internal timing relative to the spacecraft clock and
      field-of-view model parameters. IK files are located under the
      ``data/ik&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      CK kernels describe pointing, containing a transformation
      traditionally called the C-matrix which is used to determine
      time-tagged pointing (orientation) angles for a spacecraft
      structure upon which science instruments are mounted. CK files
      are located under the ``data/ck&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      EK (Events) kernels are derived from the integrated sequence of
      events used to produce actual spacecraft commands. EK files are
      located under the ``data/ek&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      LSK (Leapseconds) kernels contain the leapseconds and the values
      of other constants required to perform a transformation between
      Universal Time Coordinated (UTC) and Ephemeris time (ET). LSK
      files are located under the ``data/lsk&apos;&apos; directory of this data
      set.
 
      SCLK (Spacecraft Clock) kernels contain on-board clock calibration
      data required to perform a mapping between Ephemeris time (ET)
      and spacecraft on-board time (SCLK.) SCLK files are located under
      the ``data/sclk&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      FK (Frame Definitions) kernels contain information required to
      define reference frames, sources of frame orientation data and
      inter-connections between these frames and other frames supported
      within the SPICE system. This includes mounting alignment
      information for each instrument. FK files are located under
      the ``data/fk&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
 
      Kernel File Details
      ===================
 
      A brief overview of the different types of EPOXI kernels included
      in this data set is provided in the CONFIDENCE_LEVEL_NOTE section
      of this file while details specific to individual files are found
      in the ``*info.txt&apos;&apos; files in the corresponding data directory.
      The most detailed description of the data in each file is
      provided in metadata included inside the file -- in the
      description area of text kernels or in the comment area of binary
      kernels.
 
 
      Software
      ========
 
      The SPICE Toolkit contains software modules needed to read
      SPICE kernel files. SPICELIB software is highly documented
      via internal headers. Additional documentation is available
      in separate ASCII text files called Required Reading files.
      For example, the S- and P- Kernel (SPK) Required Reading File,
      named SPK.REQ, describes use of the SPK kernel file readers
      and contains sample programs.
 
      The latest SPICE Toolkit for a variety of computer platforms such
      as PC, Mac, SUN, etc. is available at the NAIF Node of PDS
      electronically (via anonymous FTP and WWW servers). Refer to
      information in ``software/softinfo.txt&apos;&apos; for details regarding
      obtaining this software. Each version of the Toolkit is also
      archived at the NASA National Space Science Data Center.
 
 
      Loading Kernel Files into a SPICE-based Application
      ===================================================
 
      The easiest way to make data from a collection of SPICE kernels
      available to a SPICE-based application is to list these kernels
      in a meta-kernel and load it into the program using the high
      level SPICE data loader routine FURNSH. This data set provides
      such meta-kernel(s) under the ``extras/mk&apos;&apos; directory. For more
      information about the EPOXI meta-kernel(s), see the file
      ``extras/mk/mkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      This data set contains SPICE kernel files created during mission
      operations and after mission data reconstruction and analysis.
      Some general information about this collection follows here,
      but the prospective user is also referred to extensive
      descriptions about each file that are stored inside each kernel
      file. These metadata provide detailed information regarding
      the information source from which the data were derived, the
      type of processing applied to the source data, applicability
      of the data, etc. Metadata are located in the ``comment area&apos;&apos;
      for binary kernel types (SPK, CK, ESQ), accessible using either
      the COMMNT or SPACIT utility program found in the NAIF Toolkit.
      Metadata are located after ``\begintext&apos;&apos; markers within the
      text kernel types (PCK, IK, FK, LSK, SCLK), accessible by
      using any available text file display tool such as a word
      processor, text editor, or the UNIX ``more&apos;&apos; or ``cat&apos;&apos;
      commands.
 
      In some cases data accuracy information does not exist because
      it could not be estimated even after mission completion.
 
      Where there are questions about data accuracy or ``confidence&apos;&apos;
      not addressed herein the reader is invited to examine subsequent
      SPICE archive releases associated with this data set (if such
      exist), or to contact the NAIF node of the Planetary Data System
      for possible further information.
 
 
      SPK Files
      =========
 
      The SP-Kernel files included in this data set provide reconstructed
      trajectory of the Deep Impact Flyby (DIF) spacecraft and ephemeris
      data for the mission target comet Hartley 2, Solar System planets,
      and the Sun.
 
      Additional information about SPK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/spk/spkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      CK Files
      ========
 
      C-kernel files included in this data set provide the orientation
      of the DIF spacecraft bus and the DIF high gain antenna (HGA).
      Some of these CK files were produced from engineering telemetry
      downlinked from the spacecraft; others, containing predicted
      data, were produced by attitude simulation tools based on the
      planned attitude profiles. As is often the case with spacecraft
      engineering telemetry-based measurements, considerable
      uncertainty exists as to the accuracy of such measurements, and,
      data quality (accuracy and completeness) can vary significantly.
 
      DIF Spacecraft Bus CK files
      ---------------------------
 
      Three kinds of the DIF spacecraft bus orientation CK files are
      included in this data set.
 
      The first kind are reconstructed attitude kernels based on the
      low rate telemetry (1/8 Hz). The coverage provided by these files
      is full of gaps, which due to the attitude data downlink strategy
      frequently happen at the times of transitions between different
      attitude modes, making interpolation over these gaps produce
      grossly incorrect attitude. For this reason the interpolation
      intervals in these reconstructed files should not be altered
      using CKSPANIT or a similar tool.
 
      The second kind is the reconstructed attitude kernel based on the
      high rate telemetry (up to 5 Hz) providing coverage only for
      about 8 hour period around closest approach to Hartley 2. The
      version 1 of this CK had internal time tags truncated by up to 2
      milliseconds, introducing attitude errors of almost 30
      microradians during the fastest spacecraft turn rates in the
      ~200 second interval around the closest approach to Hartley 2
      (at other times attitude errors due to this truncation were
      negligible). This problem was fixed in the version 2 of this CK.
 
      The accuracy of the DIF spacecraft bus orientation determined
      on-board and stored in the low- and high- CK files varied
      significantly, from 50 micro-radians (~5 MRI pixels) at the times
      when the attitude was determined based on the star tracker
      measurements to a few hundreds of micro-radians (tens of MRI
      pixels) for the periods when the attitude was determined by
      propagating ACS gyro data without any star tracker updates for
      extended periods of time.
 
      The third kind are predicted kernels providing nominal attitude
      for the whole or a part of the mission or just for the periods of
      target star observations during the EPOCh part of the mission.
      The predicted files were generated using prediCkt tool and are
      included in the data set with the sole purpose of providing some
      attitude for the periods when the reconstructed files have gaps.
 
      Although a comparison of reconstructed and predicted CK files for
      the periods when both provided coverage showed that in many cases
      the predicted CK data matched the actual attitude to a fraction
      of degree, the accuracy of the predicted CK files in general is
      suspect because of the idealistic attitude modeling rules,
      incorrect timing of attitude mode transitions, and lack of
      modeling of some spacecraft activities altogether. Any users of
      the predicted CKs are encouraged to compare them against the
      reconstructed CKs during the period(s) of interest using the
      FRMDIFF tool provided in the SPICE toolkit to assess the
      differences.
 
      All three types of files need to be loaded at the same time to
      provide the most complete coverage with the predicted CKs loaded
      first so that data from them is accessed last (lowest priority),
      the low rate CKs with corrected times tags (v2) loaded second
      (medium priority), and the high rate CK for the encounter loaded
      last (highest priority).
 
      DIF HGA CK Files
      ----------------
 
      Two kinds of the DIF HGA orientation CK files are included in
      this data set. The first kind is based on the measured HGA gimbal
      angles provided in telemetry (``V-channels&apos;&apos;) while the second
      kind is based on the commanded HGA gimbal angles provided in
      telemetry (``B-channels&apos;&apos;). These files should be loaded together
      to provide the most complete coverage with the file based on
      measured angles loaded last (to be accessed first.) Even when
      loaded together, the combined coverage provided by the files is
      full of gaps, which can be alleviated by modifying the
      interpolation interval information by using the CKSPANIT program.
 
      Additional information about CK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/ck/ckinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      PCK Files
      =========
 
      PCK files provide size, shape and orientation data for ``target&apos;&apos;
      bodies such as planets, satellites, comets and asteroids. A
      description of these data items and reference to their source is
      provided inside the PCK file, which is a simple text file that
      can be viewed using any word processor, text editor or text
      display utility.
 
      This data set contains generic PCK file based on the official
      IAU/IAG/COSPAR values accepted in 2000 and PCK file for EPOXI
      mission target -- Hartley 2 -- providing constants determined
      after the encounter. The PCK file for Hartley 2 contains both
      rotation and shape/size data derived by the EPOXI science team
      during post encounter data analysis.
 
      Additional information about PCK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/pck/pckinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      FK Files
      ========
 
      Frames kernel files provide specifications for how one reference
      frame is defined relative to another frame. The DI FK provided in
      this data set contains a complete set of frame definitions for
      the both spacecraft, their structures such as antennas, and all
      of their science instruments. Comments in the FK file provide
      the frame definitions, a description of the frame relationships,
      the source of and accuracy of the mounting alignment information,
      etc. The instrument frame definitions provided in the file
      incorporate the latest mounting alignment data available at the
      end of the mission.
 
      Additional information about FK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/fk/fkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      IK Files
      ========
 
      Instrument kernel files provide specifications for the optical
      and physical instrument parameters and -- where applicable --
      field-of-view size, shape and orientation for the named
      instrument. Metadata describing these estimates are provided in
      each IK file included in this archive. While a majority of the of
      parameters included in the IK files archived in this data set
      are based on the nominal instrument data, the files incorporate
      the latest version of optical distortion model derived by the DI
      optical navigation team.
 
      Additional information about IK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/ik/ikinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      SCLK Files
      ==========
 
      Spacecraft Clock kernel files provide a tabulation of data needed
      to convert time measurements between ephemeris time (ET) and
      spacecraft clock time (SCLK). A SPICE SCLK file is made from a
      similar file -- SCLK/SCET or SCLKvSCET file -- produced by
      another mission entity. Each newly made SCLK file fully replaces
      the previous SCLK file.
 
      This data set includes SCLK kernels providing the correlations
      for the DIF spacecraft primary (SCU-A) and secondary (SCU-B)
      on-board clocks. Two SCLK kernels -- the ``official&apos;&apos; version and
      ``science&apos;&apos; version -- are available for the DIF primary clock
      while only one SCLK kernel -- ``official&apos;&apos; version -- is
      available for the DIF secondary clock.
 
      The main difference between the ``official&apos;&apos; version of the
      primary clock SCLK kernel and the ``science&apos;&apos; version is that the
      ``official&apos;&apos; version is based on the latest time correlation that
      were used by the project during mission operations while the
      ``science&apos;&apos; version contain updated correlation that were used to
      process science data for archiving in PDS.
 
      The correlation update for the DIF primary clock SCLK kernel
      was done to eliminate ``artificial&apos;&apos; data points introduced by
      the tool-set that created source SCLKvSCET file and to adjust
      clock rates in order to connect actual data points in a
      continuous fashion. Such ``artificial&apos;&apos; data points were
      eliminated only during two periods -- 2009-01-06 to 2010-10-27
      and 2010-11-17 to 2011-03-01 -- because the ``official&apos;&apos;
      correlation prior to 2009-01-06 and around Hartley 2 encounter
      did not need such adjustments.
 
      Unfortunately, the absolute accuracy of both ``official&apos;&apos; and
      ``science&apos;&apos; correlations for all periods EXCEPT for the period
      around Hartley 2 encounter (2010-10-27 to 2010-11-17) is no
      better than 0.5 seconds due to poor quality of the source clock
      correlations data. For the encounter period the correlation has
      much better accuracy, down to .01 seconds for evaluating SCLK -&gt;
      UTC around closest approach, thanks to efforts by Steve Wissler
      and Amy Walsh of EPOXI Spacecraft Team in correcting and
      re-fitting the source correlation data
 
      Note that the clock format defined by both ``official&apos;&apos; and
      ``science&apos;&apos; SCLK kernels (seconds with fractional seconds given
      as a count of 1/256 second ticks) does not match the format of
      on-board time tags in mission telemetry (seconds with fractional
      seconds given as top 8 or 16 or full 20 bits of a count of
      micro-seconds). For details on this discrepancy and the algorithm
      to fix it see ``sclk140.txt&apos;&apos; provided in Deep Impact and EPOXI
      documentation set (DI-C-HRII/HRIV/MRI/ITS-6-DOC-SET-V3.0).
 
      While all science images sent to the ground contained SCLK time
      in the headers (spacecraft primary, SCU-A, SCLK for DIF),
      optical- and auto-navigation image headers contain a different
      time. This time was a so called on-board Ephemeris Time (ET) that
      optical/auto navigation on-board software used internally to
      perform autonomous trajectory and attitude solutions. This
      on-board ET was computed from on-board clock by adding a constant
      delta to it to make it synchronous with the actual ET to the
      extent possible. Since the on-board clock was drifting throughout
      the mission, the delta had to be changed many times. The table
      below shows the delta, in seconds, that must be subtracted from
      the on-board ET to get corresponding SCLK (spacecraft primary,
      SCU-A, SCLK for DIF) and the time when a particular delta had
      been uplinked and took effect in the on-board software (shown as
      UTC):
 
        Applicability Start UTC     Delta
        -----------------------    --------
        2007-351T17:35:02.1287      512.325
        2007-363T17:25:04.4477      525.293
        2008-078T16:12:19.5120      665.717
        2008-105T23:24:20.9104      732.653
        2008-137T03:57:41.1835      821.037
        2008-142T10:13:15.6053      857.544
        2008-151T19:54:10.8499      875.314
        2008-165T17:57:03.9399      897.396
        2008-184T11:28:57.2223      806.231
        2008-212T17:28:54.5972      839.715
        2008-240T04:28:57.5992      864.011
        2008-268T02:58:58.9329      890.432
        2008-319T23:59:00.3904      943.327
        2008-349T23:59:08.6112      969.590
        2009-005T21:59:15.8754      989.965
        2009-046T00:14:05.8648     1056.877
        2009-074T00:14:07.1411     1095.119
        2009-083T22:13:28.6435     1121.229
        2009-105T00:13:59.7459     1146.244
        2009-135T00:13:59.6404     1187.763
        2009-147T08:03:22.1973     1213.564
        2009-153T06:34:59.1203     1223.314
        2009-166T00:13:58.7132     1230.997
        2009-182T11:59:00.0174     1252.004
        2009-196T00:13:59.7825     1270.692
        2009-227T00:14:00.0946     1311.956
        2009-258T00:14:00.1187     1354.722
        2009-268T15:30:09.3380     1371.659
        2009-275T18:51:55.1384     1382.729
        2009-288T00:14:01.1509     1396.132
        2009-316T17:19:33.1640     1449.351
        2009-319T00:14:05.5821     1435.769
        2009-337T11:32:02.5265     1471.203
        2009-344T19:02:28.8364     1481.542
        2009-349T00:14:02.2259     1483.738
        2009-351T15:28:11.1679     1490.387
        2009-358T21:14:01.2625     1499.945
        2010-001T02:14:01.7135     1510.532
        2010-015T00:14:02.6994     1530.969
        2010-046T00:13:58.9541     1581.193
        2010-071T17:35:08.3947     1623.057
        2010-074T00:13:58.9368     1622.033
        2010-105T00:13:58.3922     1666.541
        2010-135T00:13:59.2603     1708.935
        2010-166T00:13:59.4915     1750.700
        2010-183T20:58:59.3697     1775.852
        2010-190T20:39:27.8465     1789.371
        2010-196T00:13:59.4687     1792.938
        2010-227T00:14:02.0552     1835.460
        2010-246T18:50:23.1339     1866.382
        2010-258T00:13:53.1890     1878.792
        2010-272T20:47:43.1103     1906.565
        2010-288T10:54:55.5247     1927.342
        2010-289T08:49:17.9432     1924.467
        2010-300T19:05:35.6008     1939.803
        2010-307T19:16:24.8070     1949.819
        2010-319T00:13:56.3420     1973.249
        2010-349T00:14:00.1550     1999.840
        2011-015T00:13:52.2455     2037.864
        2011-046T00:13:44.2797     2076.248
        2011-074T00:13:54.5237     2087.404
        2011-105T00:14:01.1949     2105.201
        2011-135T00:14:10.3797     2127.709
        2011-166T00:13:42.7977     2176.681
 
      Additional information about SCLK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/sclk/sclkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      LSK Files
      =========
 
      Leapseconds kernel files provide a tabulation of ``leapseconds&apos;&apos;
      and some other terms used in converting time measurements between
      ephemeris time (ET) and Universal Time (UTC). ``Spacecraft Event
      Time&apos;&apos; (SCET) is the commonly used name for UTC events measured
      at the spacecraft.
 
      Metadata describing how the LSK data are obtained or computed is
      contained inside the LSK text file. The time conversion provided
      by SPICE LSK files is accurate to approximately 0.000030 seconds.
 
      Additional information about LSK files provided in this data set
      is available in the file ``data/lsk/lskinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
      EK Files
      ========
 
      No Events kernel (EK) files are included in this archive.
 
 
      Kernel Files Not Included In This Data Set
      ===========================================
 
      A number of kernel files used to process image data archived in
      PDS and mentioned in the image labels were not included in this
      data set because they either were superseded by the files
      provided in this archive, or were known to contain incorrect or
      out-of-date information, or could be easily re-created from the
      data provided in this archive using utility program(s) available
      from NAIF. Among such files are:
 
        - regular OPS SPK files:
 
            spk_od218_full.bsp
            spk_od219_full.bsp
            spk_od221_full.bsp
            spk_od222_full.bsp
            spk_mars_drm232.bsp
 
          were superseded by the SPK files ``dif_epoch_nav_v1.bsp&apos;&apos; and
          ``dif_dixi_nav_v1.bsp&apos;&apos; included in this data set.
 
        - Jovian system SPK file
 
            jup164_20year.bsp
 
          is not included because no observations of Jupiter or its
          satellites were made during the mission.
 
        - SPK file containing an earlier version of Hartley 2 ephemeris
 
            hartley_2_2005_2020.bsp
 
          was superseded by the SPK file ``dif_dixi_nav_v1.bsp&apos;&apos;
          included in this data set.
 
        - predicted CK files:
 
            dif_epoxi_predict_v20081206.bc
            dif_pred_earthobs4_1.bc
 
          were superseded by the predicted CK files
          ``dif_sc_071103_090127_p.bc&apos;&apos; and
          ``dif_sc_071103_090127_p_to.bc&apos;&apos; included in this data set.
 
        - star position SPK and PCK files:
 
            starnames_2008253_074135.tpc
            starnames_2009338_165219.tpc
            stars_2008253_074135.bsp
            stars_2010078_071625.bsp
 
          were used in the Science Data Center image processing
          pipeline to provide access via SPICE interfaces to positions
          of the mission target stars. While these kernels successfully
          served their purpose, they were not fully compliant with
          official NAIF practices. For this reason they were not included
          into this data set. On the other hand, recognizing the
          importance of this data, it was decided to include the star
          positions stored in these files and the NAIF names and ID codes
          assigned to these stars into this data set&apos;s documentation
          for the reference. The table below provides these positions.
          Each line contains J2000 RA (hours, minutes, seconds), J2000
          DEC (degrees, arcminutes, arcseconds) and name.
 
            10,24,23.71,-74,1,53.8,PRETEND I CAR HD 90589
            0,25,45.07,-77,15,15.3,BET HYI HD 2151
            10,2,42,-60,7,0,NGC3114
            6,23,57.11,-52,41,44.4,CANOPUS HD 45348
            1,37,42.85,-57,14,12.3,ACHERNAR HD 10144
            21,7,6,42,14,0,NGC7027
            19,41,48.95,50,31,30.2,16 CYG A HD 186408
            7,33,27.32,-50,35,3.3,HD 60753
            18,36,56.34,38,47,1.3,VEGA HD 172167
            0,24,5.22,-72,4,57.9,47 TUC NGC104
            6,45,08.92,-16,42,58.0,SIRIUS HD 48915
            9,11,16.72,-62,19,1.1,I CAR HD 79447
            11,5,33,-58,43,48,NGC3532
            18,51,6,-6,16,0,M11
            10,36,16.079,-58,16,38.20,HD 92044
            8,40,36,-53,2,0,OMI VEL CLUSTER IC2391
            11,42,11.5968,26,42,16.812,GJ436
            22,57,46.8,38,40,27.84,HAT-P-1
            16,20,36,41,2,52.8,HAT-P-2
            13,44,22.56,48,1,44.4,HAT-P-3
            15,19,57.92712,36,13,46.7904,HAT-P-4
            19,4,9.84,36,37,58.8,TRES-1
            19,7,14.0304,49,18,59.2992,TRES-2
            17,52,7.032,37,32,46.1004,TRES-3
            17,53,12.96,37,12,43.2,TRES-4
            0,20,40.08,31,59,24,WASP-1
            20,30,54.24,6,25,48,WASP-2
            16,2,11.76,28,10,12,XO-1
            7,48,6.4704,50,13,32.988,XO-2
            4,21,53.5104,57,49,0.5988,XO-3
            9,22,39.7267,50,36,13.927,HD 80607
            21,50,54.7530,25,19,07.495,TYC 2206-1748-1
            18,34,31.6249,35,39,41.546,WASP-3
            19,28,59.3616,47,58,10.264,HAT-P-7
            17,48,1.95,-35,00,19.48,MOA-2009-BLG-266
 
          The following NAIF name/ID mappings were assigned to these
          stars:
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;PRETEND I CAR HD 90589&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999000 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;BET HYI HD 2151&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999001 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;NGC3114&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999002 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;CANOPUS HD 45348&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999003 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;ACHERNAR HD 10144&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999004 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;NGC7027&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999005 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;16 CYG A HD 186408&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999006 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;HD 60753&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999007 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;VEGA HD 172167&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999008 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;47 TUC NGC104&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999009 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;SIRIUS HD 48915&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999010 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;I CAR HD 79447&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999011 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;NGC3532&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999012 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;M11&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999013 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;HD 92044&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999014 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;OMI VEL CLUSTER IC2391&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999015 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;GJ436&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999016 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;HAT-P-1&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999017 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;HAT-P-2&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999018 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;HAT-P-3&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999019 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;HAT-P-4&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999020 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;TRES-1&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999021 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;TRES-2&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999022 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;TRES-3&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999023 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;TRES-4&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999024 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;WASP-1&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999025 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;WASP-2&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999026 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;XO-1&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999027 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;XO-2&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999028 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;XO-3&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999029 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;HD 80607&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999030 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;TYC 2206-1748-1&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999031 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;WASP-3&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999032 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;HAT-P-7&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999033 )
 
            NAIF_BODY_NAME += ( &apos;MOA-2009-BLG-266&apos; )
            NAIF_BODY_CODE += ( 9999034 )
 
        - text kernel providing times of encounter for the SDC pipeline
 
            impacttoi_0007h2.tpc
 
          This text kernel had the following contents:
 
            Deep Impact/EPOXI at Hartley 2
 
            Local times of DI TCA Hartley 2 as a leapsecond-corrected UTC
 
            EOB_TOI:  local time that photons from Hartley 2 reach the
                      Earth
 
            DIF_TOI:  local time that photons from Hartley 2 reach the
                      Deep Impact Flyby S/C
 
            DII_TOI:  local time that the Deep Impact Impactor S/C hits
                      Tempel 1
 
            \begindata
 
            EOB_TOI = ( &apos;2010-308T14:01:05.242&apos; )
            DIF_TOI = ( &apos;2010-308T13:59:47.310&apos; )
            DII_TOI = ( &apos;2005-185T05:44:34.200&apos; )
 
            \begintext
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

