<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.stardust-cal-nc-2-preflight-v2.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>STARDUST NAVCAM RAW PREFLIGHT CALIBRATION IMAGES V2.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.stardust::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.sdu::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:navcam.sdu::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.81p-wild_2_1978_a2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.stardust-cal-nc-2-preflight-v2.0__browserp_stardust-cal-nc-2-preflight-v2.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., D. Brown, B. Carcich, T. Farnham, W. Owen, and P. Thomas,
                   Stardust-NExT NAVCAM Calibration and Performance, Icarus, 222(2), 436-452,
                   2013, doi:10.1016/j.icarus.2012.01.025.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2011B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Newburn, R.L., Jr., S. Bhaskaran, T.C. Duxbury, G. Fraschetti, T. Radey, and M.
                   Schwochert, Stardust Imaging Camera, J. Geophys. Res., v. 108, no. E10, p.
                   8116, 2003, doi:10.1029/2003JE002081.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NEWBURNETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>STARDUST-CAL-NC-2-PREFLIGHT-V2.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>STARDUST NAVCAM RAW PREFLIGHT CALIBRATION IMAGES V2.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2011-11-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1998-04-08</start_time>
        <stop_time>1998-04-10</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>TONY FARNHAM</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Newburn, R.L, T.L. Farnham, K.P. Klaasen, and S.A. McLaughlin,
            STARDUST-CAL-NC-2-PREFLIGHT-V2.0, STARDUST NAVCAM RAW PREFLIGHT
            CALIBRATION IMAGES V2.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2011.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw, preflight, thermal-vacuum calibration images collected by
            the Stardust Navigation Camera on 8-10 April 1998.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset contains the raw, preflight, thermal-vacuum
            calibration images collected by the Navigation Camera (NAVCAM) on
            8-10 April 1998 for the Stardust mission. This is version 2.0 of
            the dataset, in which the original image data were converted from
            the standard PDS IMG format to the FITS format; no corrections
            were applied. The NExT mission to comet 9P/Tempel 1 used some of
            these preflight data to check the exposure time offsets due to
            shutter reversal and to determine dark current rates. This
            dataset supersedes version 1.0 which was safed by PDS because the
            data were not considered to be scientifically useful for the
            Stardust mission, due to problems encountered during the flight
            (stuck filter wheel, contamination on the instrument window,
            etc.) that changed the instrument characteristics.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Dataset Overview
  ================
 
    This dataset contains the raw, preflight, thermal-vacuum calibration
    images collected by the Navigation Camera (NAVCAM) on 8-10 April 1998 for
    the Stardust mission.  This is version 2.0 of the dataset, in which the
    original image data were converted from the standard PDS IMG format to
    the FITS format; no corrections were applied. This dataset supersedes
    version 1.0 which was safed by PDS because the data were not considered
    to be scientifically useful for the Stardust mission, due to the problems
    encountered during the flight (stuck filter wheel, contamination on the
    instrument window, etc.) that changed the instrument characteristics.
    During the Stardust-NExT mission (New Exploration of Tempel) to comet
    9P/Tempel 1, additional data were obtained to improve the calibrations.
    During these recalibrations, some of these preflight data were used to
    check the exposure time offsets due to shutter reversal and to determine
    dark current rates.
 
    Images in this dataset were taken during calibration sequences that were
    executed with the Focal plane array at temperatures of -30, -40, and -50
    degrees celsius (to cover the range of potential operating temperatures),
    using an integrating sphere as the observation target.  (The preflight
    calibration temperature of -30 deg C was closest to the operating
    temperature of the CCD during flight.)  The DOCUMENT/NCLOG subdirectory
    contains the calibration log sheets and additional files about the
    individual images.  Documents in the DOCUMENT/CALRPT directory describe
    the data and how they were originally used to perform the tasks needed to
    characterize the instrument.  Information about how the data were used in
    the updated calibration performed during the Stardust-NExT mission, see
    Klassen et al. (2011) [KLASSENETAL2011].  For complete list of the images
    in this dataset and their parameters, refer the PDS index table,
    INDEX/INDEX.TAB.
 
    The preflight images have been divided into four groups in the DATA
    directory.  The &apos;MINUS30C&apos;, &apos;MINUS40C&apos;, and &apos;MINUS50C&apos; directories
    contain calibration images taken at -30, -40, and -50 degrees celsius,
    respectively.  The &apos;UNUSABLE&apos; directory contains calibration images that
    were determined to be unusable.  See UNUSABLE.ASC in the DOCUMENT
    directory for a list of the problematic images and a description of why
    they are considered to be unusable.
 
  Data
  ====
    The images in this dataset have been converted by the PDS Small Bodies
    Node from the standard PDS IMG format to the FITS format with detached
    PDS labels.  Relevant information in the PDS label has been placed into
    the FITS header, though due to differing conventions, the keywords may
    have changed.  The description field in the FITS header should make it
    clear what the keyword represents.
 
    Camera Description
    ------------------
      The STARDUST camera has an angular resolution of 59 microrad/pixel
      (12 arcsec/pixel) and a focal length of 202 mm at an f-ratio of
      about f/3.5.  Early in the flight the filter wheel failed, possibly
      due to a failed power supply. Fortunately it failed on the filter
      with the largest throughput, but the broad bandpass of that filter
      caused images taken through it to have significant chromatic
      aberration, which resulted in an image resolution of about 2.5
      pixels at FWHM (full width at half maximum) when observing a point
      source such as a star.  (The high resolution filter, intended to be
      used for near encounter imaging, would have resulted in resolution
      exceeding a half pixel.)  Without any image processing, the 2.5 pixel
      resolution resulted in a best linear resolution at closest approach
      of about 20 m/pixel.
 
      The camera has a 1024x1024 array as the active portion of the CCD.
      The images that are stored on this volume, however, contain more
      than just the active portion of the CCD.  Each line contains a sync
      pattern, a line counter, 12 baseline stabilization pixels, the 1024
      pixels from the active portion of the CCD, and finally 8 over-clock
      pixels used to measure the quantum efficiency.  The number of rows
      for each image is always 1024, no matter what compression mode is
      used, but the number of columns for each image depends on the
      compression mode used.
 
    Compression Modes
    -----------------
      The NAVCAM images can be either 8-bit or 12-bit data.  The 12-bit
      data is commonly referred to as &apos;uncompressed data&apos;, while the 8-bit
      is referred to as &apos;compressed data&apos;.  This compression is
      accomplished by a 12-bit to 8-bit square-root look-up-table
      compression method, which is implemented in the hardware of the
      camera electronics.  This compression is lossy and the estimate of
      the 12-bit image can be recovered using the look-up table mentioned
      in Appendix 3 of the Stardust NAVCAM Calibration Document located in
      the DOCUMENT directory.
 
      In uncompressed mode with 12-bit data, the pixels are expressed in
      two bytes, as 16 bits per pixel.
 
    Image Orientation
    -----------------
 
      During the conversion to FITS format, the camera&apos;s mirror image
      has been removed by flipping the images from top to bottom.
      This is the same convention used in other Stardust and
      Stardust-NExT datasets. Images of the calibration lamp filament
      can be used to confirm the orientation relative to other data
      sets.
 
    Exposure Durations
    ------------------
      The double-bladed shutter utilized by the camera has a delay in its
      slide mechanism that introduces an offset in the actual exposure
      time, compared to the commanded exposure time.  During the
      recalibration of the NAVCAM as part of the Stardust NExT mission, it
      was determined that the original information about the exposure time
      offsets and the forward/reverse shutter parity were incorrect.
      However the images in this dataset have not been corrected to
      account for the updated information.  See the file
      SHUTTER_CORRECTION.ASC in the DOCUMENT directory for more
      information.
 
    Author
    ------
      The descriptions in this file were copied from version 1.0 of this
      dataset and modified by the PDS Small Bodies Node to include relevant
      information about conversion process and the NExT mission.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
 
    The Stardust NExT mission used select pieces of these preflight
    data to help recalibrate the NAVCAM instrument for the comet
    9P/Tempel1 encounter in February 2011.  In particular some of the
    images were used to determine exposure time offsets and dark
    current rates.  For more information see the NExT NAVCAM
    Calibration Overview report and the Shutter Polarity report
    located in the DOCUMENT directory.  Also see Newburn, et al.,
    2003a [NEWBURNETAL2003] and Klaasen, et al., 2011
    [KLAASENETAL2011B].
 
 
  Data Quality
  ============
    As noted above in the Dataset Overview section, the DATA/UNUSABLE
    directory contains preflight calibration images that were determined
    to be unusable.  See UNUSABLE.ASC in the DOCUMENT directory for a
    description and list of the problematic images.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    The data were peer review in December 2011.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

