<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dif-c-mri-5-tempel1-photometry-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DEEP IMPACT MRI PHOTOMETRY OF COMET 9P/TEMPEL 1 V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_impact::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mri.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.9p-tempel_1_1867_g1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dif-c-mri-5-tempel1-photometry-v1.0__browserp_dif-c-mri-5-tempel1-photometry-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hampton, D.L., J.W. Baer, M.A. Huisjen, C.C. Varner, A. Delamere, D.D.
                   Wellnitz, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, and K.P. Klaasen, An Overview of the Instrument Suite
                   for the Deep Impact Mission, Space Science Reviews, 117, 43-93, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3390-8.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAMPTONETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., M.F. A&apos;Hearn, M. Baca, A. Delamere, M. Desnoyer, T. Farnham, O.
                   Groussin, D. Hampton, S. Ipatov, J. Li, C. Lisse, N. Mastrodemos, S.
                   McLaughlin, J. Sunshine, P. Thomas, and D. Wellnitz, Deep Impact Instrument
                   Calibration, Rev. Sci. Instrum., 79, 091301, 2008, doi:10.1063/1.2972112.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DIF-C-MRI-5-TEMPEL1-PHOTOMETRY-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DEEP IMPACT MRI PHOTOMETRY OF COMET 9P/TEMPEL 1 V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2008-06-12</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2005-05-01T20:05:07.337Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2005-07-04T01:27:21.636Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>FABIENNE A. BASTIEN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Bastien, F.A., M.F. A&apos;Hearn, T.L. Farnham, and D.D.
            Wellnitz, DEEP IMPACT MRI PHOTOMETRY OF COMET 9P/TEMPEL 1 V1.0,
            DIF-C-MRI-5-TEMPEL1-PHOTOMETRY-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2008.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Approach photometry of comet 9P/Tempel 1 derived from images
            acquired by the Deep Impact Medium Resolution CCD Instrument from
            1 May 2005 to 4 July 2005.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset contains photometric measurements of comet 9P/Tempel
            1 from images taken with the Medium Resolution CCD Instrument
            during the approach phase of the Deep Impact mission (from 1 May
            2005 to 4 July 2005). These data, based on circular apertures
            ranging from 5 to 30 pixels in diameter, were derived from both
            science and navigation images taken through clear filters.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set contains photometric measurements of comet 9P/Tempel 1
    from images taken with the Medium Resolution CCD Instrument during the
    approach phase of the Deep Impact mission (from 1 May 2005 to 4 July
    2005).  These data, based on circular apertures ranging from 5 to 30
    pixels in diameter, were derived from both science and navigation
    images taken through clear filters.
 
 
    Observations
    ------------
      These tables consist of measurements performed on images taken
      from 1 May 2005 to about six hours before impact, defined here as
      05:44:34.265 UT 4 July 2005 at the flyby spacecraft.  All dates
      provided in the tables refer to the mid-point of the observation.
      The heliocentric distance of 9P/Tempel 1 goes from 1.64 AU to 1.51
      AU during approach.  A total of 3014 images were analyzed: 595
      science images and 2419 optical navigation images.
 
 
    Related Data Sets
    -----------------
      The following PDS data sets were used to derive these data:
 
        DIF-C-MRI-3/4-9P-ENCOUNTER-V2.0/DATA/RADREV : Calibrated, radiance
                                                      MRI encounter data,
                                                      version 2.0
        DIF-C-MRI-2-NAV-9P-ENCOUNTER-V1.0           : Raw MRI navigation
                                                      data
 
      Please note that MRI reversibly calibrated, radiance (RADREV) science
      images were used in this analysis.  These data were not processed to
      remove artifacts, such as cosmic rays, which sometimes affect the
      tabulated results.  Also, measurements derived from navigation images
      were acquired from the raw data.
 
 
  Data
  ====
 
    Tables of Photometric Data
    --------------------------
      The nav_phot.tab and sci_phot.tab files are fixed-width, ASCII
      tables that contain photometric measurements of comet 9P/Tempel 1
      taken with 5, 7, 9, 15, 20, 25, and 30 pixel diameter apertures.
      Observation dates are included in the tables, as is the centroid
      position of the comet in the image.  These files additionally
      contain a column specifying the filter used to take the image and
      another column listing the centroid&apos;s distance from the horizontal
      boundary between the CCD quadrants.  For more information about
      the MRI CCD instrument and its filters, Deep Impact instruments
      publication by Hampton, et al. (2005) [HAMPTONETAL2005] provided
      in the Deep Impact documentation data set,
      DI-C-HRII/HRIV/MRI/ITS-6-DOC-SET-V1.0, which is archived by the PDS.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The following assumes that the images are displayed with lines
    increasing up and samples to the right.
 
 
    Science Data
    ------------
      Photometric measurements were derived from the reversibly calibrated
      RADREV images taken through the MRI clear filters.  An additional
      background subtraction algorithm was applied to these data in order
      to remove the horizontal &apos;&apos;striping&apos;&apos; caused by electrical
      interference.  This noise, whose amplitude is on the order of a few
      DN, most adversely affects the data taken early on in the approach
      sequence.
 
      In many of these images, the comet was located on or close to the
      boundary between the upper and lower halves of the CCD.  The pixels
      in the rows surrounding this boundary are 1/6 of a pixel smaller
      than the other pixels of the CCD.  This increases the point spread
      function of objects that overlap this boundary by 1/3 of a pixel.
      Flux measurements similarly tend to be greater at the boundary.
      In about 80 percent of the images, the comet centroid lies less than
      20 pixels away from this boundary.  For a more detailed discussion
      of how this affects the data and what corrections were applied,
      please see the Deep Impact MRI photometry report included in the
      document directory of this data set.
 
      For more information about how the RADREV science data were
      calibrated, see the Deep Impact (Science) Calibration Pipeline
      Summary included in the document directory of the data set or
      the Deep Impact instrument calibration report by Klaasen, et al.
      (2006) [KLAASENETAL2006] included in the Deep Impact documentation
      data set, DI-C-HRII/HRIV/MRI/ITS-6-DOC-SET-V1.0, which is archived
      by the PDS.
 
 
    Optical Navigation Data
    -----------------------
      An optical navigation image consists of a number of &apos;&apos;snippets&apos;&apos;,
      each containing an object of interest to the navigation team (for
      example, a guide star).  Comet 9P/Tempel 1 is always contained in one
      of these &apos;&apos;snippets&apos;&apos;, which varied in size from 350x350 pixels for
      most of the approach sequence to 150x150 pixels for the last week
      before impact.  These images do not have serial and parallel
      overclock pixels and therefore needed to be treated differently from
      the science images.  Only the raw navigation images are used in this
      analysis.
 
      A background subtraction procedure was applied only to the snippet
      containing the comet.  This procedure also removed the horizontal
      striping previously discussed for all images taken more than one week
      before impact.  In data taken between UTC 2005-06-27T05:44:09.225 and
      impact, the comet&apos;s coma fills the snippet, which could therefore not
      be used to remove the background.  For this time frame, the
      background was measured in the relevant image quadrant from a raw
      science image taken close in time to the navigation image of
      interest.
 
      For a detailed description of the navigation data, please see the
      Deep Impact navigation images report included in the document
      directory of this data set.  For additional information on the
      reduction processes applied to these data, please see the Deep Impact
      MRI photometry report included in the document directory of this data
      set.
 
 
    This data set overview was provided by F. Bastien.  For a detailed
    discussion of this data set, please refer to the Deep Impact MRI
    photometry report included in the document directory of this data set.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    The following assumes that the images are displayed with lines
    increasing up and samples to the right.
 
 
    Navigation Images
    -----------------
      These data excluded the serial and parallel overclock pixels.
      Therefore, quadrant bias and background was determined from the
      edge of the snippet of interest for most of approach.  For more
      information about how the raw navigation images were processed,
      please see the Deep Impact navigation images report included
      in the document directory of this data set.
 
 
    &apos;&apos;Striping&apos;&apos;
    ------------
      All the data were affected by a horizontal striping of a few DN
      in amplitude caused by electrical interference.  This primarily
      affected the early approach images.
 
 
    CCD Horizontal Gap
    ------------------
      The pixels in the two rows surrounding the horizontal boundary
      between the upper and lower halves of the CCD are each 1/6 of a
      pixel smaller than the other pixels of the CCD.  This increases
      the point spread function of objects that overlap this boundary
      by 1/3 of a pixel.  Flux measurements similarly tend to be
      greater at the boundary.
 
 
    For more on how these limitations were dealt with, see the Deep Impact
    MRI photometry report included in the document directory of this data
    set.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    This data set was peer-reviewed in June 2008 and was approved
    for archiving pending resolution of liens.  Liens were resolved
    in January 2009.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

