<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.vg2-n-pls-5-rdr-ionmagsphere-48sec-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>VG2 NEP PLS DERIVED RDR ION MAGNETOSPHERE 48SEC V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.comet_sl9-jupiter_collision::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.voyager::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vg2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:pls.vg2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.neptune::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vg2-n-pls-5-rdr-ionmagsphere-48sec-v1.0__browserp_vg2-n-pls-5-rdr-ionmagsphere-48sec-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Belcher, J.W., et al, Plasma Observations at Neptune:
                   Initial results from Voyager 2, Science, 246, 1478-1483,
                   1989.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BELCHERETAL1991</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Richardson, J.D., J.W. Belcher, R.L. McNutt, Jr., and
                   M. Zhang, Low Energy Ions near Neptune, J. Geophys.
                   Res., in press, 1991.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.RICHARDSONETAL1991A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Richardson, J.D., and R.L. McNutt, Jr., Low-Energy Plasma
                   in Neptune&apos;s Magnetosphere, Geophys. Res. Lett., 17,
                   1689-1692, 1991.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.RICHARDSONETAL1991B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Zhang, M., V.M. Vasylinunas, G.L. Siscoe, R.L. Lepping,
                   and  N.F. Ness, Evidence for a diurnally rocking plasma
                   mantle at Neptune, Geophys Res. Lett, 17, 2285-2288, 1991.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ZHANGETAL1991B</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>VG2-N-PLS-5-RDR-IONMAGSPHERE-48SEC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>VG2 NEP PLS DERIVED RDR ION MAGNETOSPHERE 48SEC V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1991-07-22</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1989-08-24T23:30:00.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1989-08-25T08:00:00.000Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JOHN D. RICHARDSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            VG2 NEP PLS DERIVED RDR ION MAGNETOSPHERE 48SEC V1.0
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set gives the best available values for ion densities,
            temperatures, and velocities near Neptune derived from data
            obtained by the Voyager 2 plasma experiment. All parameters are
            obtained by fitting the observed spectra (current as a function
            of energy) with Maxwellian plasma distributions, using a
            non-linear least squares fitting routine to find the plasma
            parameters which, when coupled with the full instrument response,
            best simulate the data. The PLS instrument measures
            energy/charge, so composition is not uniquely determined but can
            be deduced in some cases by the separation of the observed
            current peaks in energy (assuming the plasma is co-moving). In
            the upstream solar wind protons are fit to the M-long data since
            high energy resolution is needed to obtain accurate plasma
            parameters. In the magnetosheath the ion flux so low that several
            L-long spectra (3-5) had to be averaged to increase the
            signal-to-noise ratio to a level at which the data could be
            reliably fit. These averaged spectra were fit using 2 proton
            maxwellians with the same velocity. The values given in the
            upstream magnetosheath are the total density and the
            density-weighted temperature. In both the upstream solar wind and
            magnetosheath full vector velocities, densities and temperatures
            are derived for each fit component. In the magnetosphere spectra
            do not contain enough information to obtain full velocity
            vectors, so flow is assumed to be purely azimuthal. In some cases
            the azimuthal velocity is a fit parameter, in some cases rigid
            corotation is assumed. In the &apos;outer&apos; magnetosphere
            (L&gt;5) two distinct current peaks appear in the spectra H+ and
            N+. In the inner magnetosphere the plasma is hot and the
            composition is ambiguous, although two superimposed Maxwellians
            are still required to fit the data. These spectra are fit using
            two compositions, one with H+ and N+ and the second with two H+
            components. The N+ composition is preferred by the data provider.
            All fit values in the magnetosphere come with one sigma errors.
            It should be noted that no attempt has been made to account for
            the spacecraft potential, which is probably about -10 V in this
            region and will effect the density and velocity values. In the
            outbound magnetosheath and solar wind both moment and fit values
            are given for velocity, density, and thermal speed. The
            signal-to-noise ratio in the M-longs is very low, especially near
            the magnetopause, which can result in the analysis giving
            incorrect values. The L-long spectra have too low an energy
            resolution to permit accurate determinations parameters in many
            regions temperature and non-radial velocity components may be
            inaccurate.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      This data set gives the best available values for ion
      densities, temperatures, and velocities near Neptune derived
      from data obtained by the Voyager 2 plasma experiment.  All
      parameters are obtained by fitting the observed spectra
      (current as a function of energy) with Maxwellian plasma
      distributions, using a non-linear least squares fitting routine
      to find the plasma parameters which, when coupled with the full
      instrument response, best simulate the data.  The PLS
      instrument measures energy/charge, so composition is not
      uniquely determined but can be deduced in some cases by the
      separation of the observed current peaks in energy (assuming
      the plasma is co-moving).  In the upstream solar wind protons
      are fit to the M-long data since high energy resolution is
      needed to obtain accurate plasma parameters.  In the
      magnetosheath the ion flux so low that several L-long spectra
      (3-5) had to be averaged to increase the signal-to-noise ratio
      to a level at which the data could be reliably fit.  These
      averaged spectra were fit using 2 proton maxwellians with the
      same velocity.  The values given in the upstream magnetosheath
      are the total density and the density-weighted temperature.  In
      both the upstream solar wind and magnetosheath full vector
      velocities, densities and temperatures are derived for each fit
      component.  In the magnetosphere spectra do not contain enough
      information to obtain full velocity vectors, so flow is assumed
      to be purely azimuthal.  In some cases the azimuthal velocity
      is a fit parameter, in some cases rigid corotation is assumed.
      In the &apos;outer&apos; magnetosphere (L&gt;5) two distinct current peaks
      appear in the spectra; these are fit assuming a composition of
      H+ and N+.  In the inner magnetosphere the plasma is hot and
      the composition is ambiguous, although two superimposed
      Maxwellians are still required to fit the data.  These spectra
      are fit using two compositions, one with H+ and N+ and the
      second with two H+ components.  The N+ composition is preferred
      by the data provider.  All fit values in the magnetosphere come
      with one sigma errors.  It should be noted that no attempt has
      been made to account for the spacecraft potential, which is
      probably about -10 V in this region and will effect the density
      and velocity values.  In the outbound magnetosheath and solar
      wind both moment and fit values are given for velocity,
      density, and thermal speed.  The signal-to-noise ratio in the
      M-longs is very low, especially near the magnetopause, which
      can result in the analysis giving incorrect values.  The L-long
      spectra have too low an energy resolution to permit accurate
      determinations parameters in many regions; in particular the
      temperature and non-radial velocity components may be
      inaccurate.
 
      References:
 
      Richardson, J.  D., M.  Zhang, J. W.  Belcher, and R. L.
      McNutt, Jr., Low-energy ions near Neptune, J. Geophys.  Res.,
      in press, 1991.
 
      J. W.  Belcher, H. S.  Bridge, et al., Plasma Observations Near
      Neptune: Initial Results from Voyager 2, Science, 246,
      1478-1483, 1989.
 
      Zhang, M., V. M.  Vasyliunas, G. L.  Siscoe, R. P.  Lepping,
      and N. F.  Ness, Evidence for a diurnally rocking plasma mantle
      at Neptune, Geophys. Res.  Lett., 17, 2285-2288, 1990.
 
      Richardson, J. D.  and R. L.  McNutt, Jr., Low-energy plasma in
      Neptune&apos;s magnetosphere, Geophys. Res.  Lett., 17, 1689-1692,
      1990.
 
      Processing Level Id            : 5
      Software Flag                  : Y
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;ION DENSITY&apos;
      --------------------------------
        A derived parameter equaling the number of ions per unit
        volume over a specified range of ion energy, energy/charge,
        or energy/nucleon.  Discrimination with regard to mass and or
        charge state is necessary to obtain this quantity, however,
        mass and charge state are often assumed due to instrument
        limitations.
 
        Many different forms of ion density are derived.  Some are
        distinguished by their composition (N+, proton, ion, etc.) or
        their method of derivation (Maxwellian fit, method of
        moments).  In some cases, more than one type of density will
        be provided in a single dataset.  In general, if more than
        one ion species is analyzed, either by moment or fit, a total
        density will be provided which is the sum of the ion
        densities.  If a plasma component does not have a Maxwellian
        distribution the actual distribution can be represented as
        the sum of several Maxwellians, in which case the density of
        each Maxwellian is given.
 
        Data Set Parameter Name        : ION DENSITY
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : CM**-3
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : UNK
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : UNK
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : UNK
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : UNK
        Noise Level                    : UNK
 
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;ION TEMPERATURE&apos;
      ------------------------------------
        A derived parameter giving an indication of the mean
        energy/ion, assuming the shape of the ion energy spectrum to
        be Maxwellian (i.e.highest entropy shape).  Given that the
        ion energy spectrum is not exactly Maxwellian, the ion
        temperature can be defined integrally (whereby the mean
        energy obtained by integrating under the actual ion energy
        spectrum is set equal to the integral under a Maxwellian,
        where the temperature is a free parameter for which to
        solve), or differentially (whereby the slopes of the actually
        ion energy spectrum at various energies are matched to the
        slopes of a corresponding Maxwellian).  The temperature
        parameter is often qualified with a range of applicable
        energies.  temperatures can be angularly anisotropic.  If the
        ions do not have a Maxwellian distribution the actual
        distribution can be represented as the sum of several
        Maxwellians, each with a separate temperature.
 
        Data Set Parameter Name        : ION TEMPERATURE
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : EV
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : UNK
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : UNK
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : UNK
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : UNK
        Noise Level                    : UNK
 
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;ION THERMAL SPEED&apos;
      --------------------------------------
        A measure of the velocity associated with the temperature of
        the ions.  It is formally defined as the Ion Thermal Speed
        squared equals two times K (Boltzmann&apos;s constant) times T
        (temperature of ion) divided by M (ion mass).  Each component
        of a plasma has a thermal speed associated with it.
 
        Data Set Parameter Name        : ION THERMAL SPEED
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : KM/S
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : UNK
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : UNK
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : UNK
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : UNK
        Noise Level                    : UNK
 
 
    Source Instrument Parameters
    ============================
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : ION DENSITY
      Instrument Parameter Name       : ION RATE
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : ION DENSITY
      Instrument Parameter Name       : ION CURRENT
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : ION TEMPERATURE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : ION RATE
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : ION THERMAL SPEED
      Instrument Parameter Name       : ION RATE
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : ION TEMPERATURE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : ION CURRENT
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : ION THERMAL SPEED
      Instrument Parameter Name       : ION CURRENT
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : ION DENSITY
      Instrument Parameter Name       : PARTICLE MULTIPLE PARAMETERS
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : ION TEMPERATURE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : PARTICLE MULTIPLE PARAMETERS
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      Processing History
      ------------------
        Source Data Set ID          : N/A
        Software                    : UNK
        Product Data Set ID         :
        VG2-N-PLS-5-RDR-IONMAGSPHERE-48SEC-V1.0
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      Magnetospheric data can be distorted by spacecraft charge; in
      particular values in the region 4-6 Neptune radii from the
      planet outbound where only the H+ plasma component was observed
      may be tainted by this effect.  The deviation of the azimuthal
      velocity from corotation is probably an artifact of the
      charging.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XM-11A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

