<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mgn-v-rdrs-5-scvdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MAGELLAN SURFACE CHARACTERISTICS VECTOR DATA RECORD</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.magellan::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mgn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rdrs.mgn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgn-v-rdrs-5-scvdr-v1.0__browserp_geo_mgn-v-rdrs-5-scvdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgn-v-rdrs-5-scvdr-v1.0__dvo_geo_mgn-v-rdrs-5-scvdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Barry, S., Magellan Mission Operations System: Radar System Interface
                   Requirements, Hughes Aircraft Co. Report HS513-823-3, May 1987
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BARRY1987</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Brill, R., and C. Meisl, Magellan Altimeter Processing: Algorithms and
                   Constants, Jet Propulsion Laboratory Document D-6143, 15 February 1990
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BRILL-MEISL1990</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Cuevas, C., Magellan Radar Sensor Compensation Report, Hughes Aircraft
                   Co. Report HS513-5029, 18 August 1989
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CUEVAS1989</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lyons, D.T., Magellan Planetary Constants and Models, JPL D-2300, Jet
                   Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, Calif., 1988.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LYONS1988</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Planetary Data System Standards Reference, Jet Propulsion Laboratory Document
                   D-7669, Part 2, 20 November 1992
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PDSSR1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Project Magellan Software Interface Specification: Magellan Science EDR
                   (TPS-101), 30 January 1991
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SCIEDR</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Project Magellan Software Interface Specification: Full-Resolution Basic
                   Image Data Record, Revision E, 31 August 1992
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SDPS101</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Magellan Project Radar System: Analysis Methods and Performance Estimates,
                   Hughes Aircraft Co. Report HS513-062-49, July 1989
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SE011</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tyler, G.L., R.A. Simpson, M.J. Maurer, and E. Holmann, Scattering
                   Properties of the Venusian Surface: Preliminary Results from Magellan,
                   Journal of Geophysical Research, 97, 13115-13139, 1992
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TYLER1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MGN-V-RDRS-5-SCVDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MAGELLAN SURFACE CHARACTERISTICS VECTOR DATA RECORD</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1995-01-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1990-09-15T16:22:14Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1992-09-14T02:28:41Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. G. LEONARD TYLER</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Tyler, G. L., MAGELLAN SURFACE CHARACTERISTICS VECTOR DATA
            RECORD, MGN-V-RDRS-5-SCVDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 1995
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Magellan Surface Characteristics Vector Data Record (SCVDR)
            archive contains orbit-by-orbit reductions of Magellan scattering
            and emission measurements acquired during its mission to Venus.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains the Magellan Surface Characteristics
            Vector Data Record (SCVDR) which is an orbit-by-orbit reduction
            of Magellan scattering and emission measurements carried out at
            Stanford University. The SCVDR includes near-nadir scattering
            functions obtained by numerical inversion from altimetry (ALT)
            echoes, results (e.g., rms surface slopes and Fresnel
            reflectivity) from fitting analytic functions to those
            inversions, scattering function segments at oblique incidence
            angles derived from synthetic aperture radar (SAR) echoes, and
            estimates of surface emissivity derived from thermal microwave
            radiometry (RAD) measurements. The SCVDR is one of several inputs
            to the Global Vector Data Record (GVDR), a gridded summary of
            scattering results, also produced at Stanford.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Surface Characteristics Vector Data Record (SCVDR) is an
      orbit-by-orbit reduction of Magellan scattering and emission
      measurements carried out at Stanford University.  The SCVDR
      includes near-nadir scattering functions obtained by numerical
      inversion from altimetry (ALT) echoes, results (e.g., rms
      surface slopes and Fresnel reflectivity) from fitting analytic
      functions to those inversions, scattering function segments
      at oblique incidence angles derived from synthetic aperture
      radar (SAR) echoes, and estimates of surface emissivity
      derived from thermal microwave radiometry (RAD) measurements.
      The SCVDR is one of several inputs to the Global Vector Data
      Record (GVDR), a gridded summary of scattering results, also
      produced at Stanford.
 
      The SCVDR parallels the Altimetry and Radiometry Composite
      Data Record (ARCDR) produced at the Massachusetts Institute
      of Technology in its orbit-by-orbit organization.  But the
      SCVDR differs from the ARCDR in that no a priori assumptions
      are made regarding the form of the scattering function.
 
      The SCVDR was originally recorded on a set of 8 mm Unix &apos;tar&apos;
      tapes.  Data were blocked typically in groups of 100 orbits,
      but the coverage in a few cases was as large as several
      hundred orbits or as few as a dozen depending on mapping
      activity or mission scheduling.  For transfer to CD-WO (the
      SCVDRCD) blocking was adjusted to match the capacity of the
      CD media.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      The Magellan raw data set comprises three basic data types:
      echoes from the nadir-viewing altimeter (ALT), echoes from
      the oblique backscatter synthetic aperture radar (SAR)
      imaging system, and passive radiothermal emission
      measurements (RAD) made using the SAR high-gain antenna
      (HGA).  The objective in compiling the SCVDR is to obtain
      an accurate estimate of the surface backscattering function
      (sometimes called the specific backscatter function or
      &apos;sigma-zero&apos;) for Venus from these three data types and to
      show its variation with incidence (polar) angle, azimuthal
      angle, and surface location.
 
      The Magellan data have been &apos;inverted&apos; using techniques
      described by [TYLER1992].  If a surface is statistically
      homogeneous and scatters isotropically, the distribution
      of echo signal can be predicted using the radar equation on
      small surface elements, then sorting and accumulating the
      incremental power contributions by time-delay and Doppler
      frequency.  Given a measured radar echo versus range and
      Doppler, the process may be inverted to yield the specific
      radar cross section as a function of incidence angle.  In
      the SCVDR the Magellan empirical backscattering function
      has been obtained from ALT data at nadir to as much as 10
      degrees from normal incidence in steps of 0.5 degrees.
      The empirical backscattering function at oblique angles
      (15 to 50 degrees from normal incidence) has been obtained
      over narrow ranges (1-4 degrees) from the SAR data.  The
      emissivity, which in some models is the complement of the
      Fresnel reflectivity, has been obtained from the RAD
      measurements.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      ALT and SAR data have been processed at Stanford University
      using &apos;inversion&apos; methods, whereby the radar equation is
      converted to a matrix-vector relationship and that is solved
      (using least-squares techniques) to obtain an &apos;empirical&apos;
      scattering function for each radar echo [TYLER1992].  In
      the case of ALT data, stability of the solution requires
      considerable attention; in the case of SAR data, it is the
      variability of the surface scattering itself that leads to
      the most uncertainty.  Stanford has also independently
      confirmed the results of the MIT processing of emissivity
      data but without developing separate algorithms.
 
      At Stanford ALT-EDR tapes were the input for calculation of
      near-nadir empirical backscattering functions.  For oblique
      backscatter, C-BIDR tapes from the Magellan Project and
      F-BIDR files obtained via Internet from Washington
      University were the input products.  Emissivity results were
      calculated from radar burst headers, which are included among
      both the ALT-EDR and C/F-BIDR files.  Output was collected
      on an orbit-by-orbit basis into the SCVDR.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      Each SCVDR includes data from several orbits.  For each orbit,
      there are six files:
        (1) Orbit Header File
        (2) Altimetry Inversion File (ANF)
        (3) Inversion Fit File (NNF)
        (4) Sinusoidal Image File (SIF)
        (5) Oblique Image File (OIF)
        (6) Emissivity Data File (EDF)
 
      The Orbit Header File contains basic information about the
      Magellan orbit and summary data from the other five files.
      OHF information includes average Keplerian orbit elements,
      the number of entries in each of the other files, and
      starting and ending times for data in the other files.
 
      The Altimetry Inversion file contains the results of the
      altimetry echo inversion (sigma-zero versus incidence
      angle at spacings typically of 0.5 degree to a maximum of
      about 10 degrees from nadir).  The ANF also includes
      uncertainties in sigma-zero, geometry for the ALT
      observations, parameters of the radar system used in
      computing the absolute backscatter, and echo timing
      estimates which could be converted to Venus radius values.
 
      The Inversion Fit File contains results from fitting up to
      five scattering laws to the experimentally derived near-nadir
      sigma-zero function (the ANF).  The five laws include:
      Hagfors, exponential, gaussian, Rayleigh, and Muhleman.
      Free parameters (for example, the roughness parameter C and
      the Fresnel reflectivity R for the Hagfors law) are also
      reported, as is an estimate of the rms surface roughness
      corresponding to each fit.  Residuals between the analytic
      function and the data indicate which function best matches
      the experimental results.
 
      The Sinusoidal Image File contains the results of fitting
      a quadratic function to the average SAR pixel values across
      a sinusoidal equal area image strip.  The image strips are
      from either C-BIDR or F-BIDR files; the best fit quadratic
      represents the sigma-zero function over a few degrees of
      incidence angle for a surface area about 20 km across track
      and about 2 km along track.  Geometrical data, uncertainties,
      and other information is also included in the SIF.
 
      The Oblique Image File contains the results of fitting a
      quadratic approximation to pixel values stored in the
      Magellan oblique sinusoidal equal area projection.  The OIF
      and SIF are identical except for the projection of the input
      pixel data.  The OIF contains data for north and south polar
      regions.
 
      The Emissivity Data File contains results of analysis of
      Magellan RAD data.  Surface emissivities, uncertainties,
      geometrical data, and system parameter values are included.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      Inversion of the altimetry data requires use of matrices
      incorporating information about the geometry of the
      observations and the relationships of geometry to radar
      range, Doppler frequency offset, and incidence angle on
      the planet&apos;s surface.  Matrices were computed at
      approximately one degree increments in spacecraft latitude
      for orbits on which viewing conditions were distinctly
      different.  These matrices are included with the SCVDR
      data in the GEOMETRY directory on the CD-WO.
 
      Ancillary data for most processing at Stanford was obtained
      from the data tapes and files received from the Magellan
      Project.  These included trajectory and pointing information
      for the spacecraft, clock conversion tables, spacecraft
      engineering data, and SAR processing parameters.  For
      calibration of the radar instrument itself, Magellan Project
      reports (including some received from Hughes Aircraft Co.
      [BARRY1987; CUEVAS1989; SE011]) were used.  Documentation on
      handling of data at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory was also
      used [BRILL&amp;MEISL1990; SCIEDR; SDPS101].
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      Most information about spacecraft positions and velocities
      is stored using J2000 inertial coordinates.  Most
      information about surface locations is stored using
      Venus Body Fixed 1985 coordinates [LYONS1988].
 
 
    Software
    ========
      A special library and several example programs are provided
      in source code form for reading the SCVDR data files.  One
      main program is provided for each file type (including the
      geometry files).  These are provided to illustrate access to
      the data using the reader subroutine(s); the main programs
      themselves do nothing beyond returning diagnostic messages.
      Source code and include files are in the C language; a Unix
      makefile (for creating executables) and a Perl script (to
      list contents of SCVDR files) are also provided.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The SCVDR will be delivered using compact disc write once
      (CD-WO) media.  Formats will be based on standards for such
      products established by the Planetary Data System (PDS)
      [PDSSR1992].
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      The SCVDR is intended to be a systematic and comprehensive
      reduction of radar and radio data acquired by the Magellan
      Mission.  It emphasizes extraction of electromagnetic
      properties of the Venus surface with minimal assumptions
      regarding the form of the backscatter function.  Limitations
      implicit in the analysis approach and in the resulting data
      are summarized below.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      The SCVDR has been reviewed internally by the Magellan Project
      prior to release to the planetary community.  The review
      included compilation of the Global Vector Data Record (GVDR)
      at Stanford and independent confirmation of formats and
      values at M.I.T.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Because the orbit of Magellan was elliptical during most of
      its mapping operations, the character of the signal varied
      considerably over an orbit as well as from place to place
      on the surface.  Although the SCVDR quantifies much of the
      spatial variation, systematic limitations of both the
      instrument and the mission mean that some variability was
      missed or only partially captured.
 
 
      General Limitations
      -------------------
        It is important to remember that, since the SAR and ALT
        antennas were aimed at different parts of the planet
        during each orbit, building up a collection of composite
        scattering data for any single surface region requires
        that results from several orbits be integrated.  In the
        case of data from polar regions, where only the SAR was
        able to probe, there will be no ALT data.  When scheduling
        or other factors interrupted the systematic collection of
        data, there may be ALT data for some regions but no
        comparable SAR or radiometry data (or vice versa).
 
        Outages played an important role in determining coverage
        for all Cycles.  For example, although a goal of Cycle 3
        radar mapping was radar stereo, early orbits were used to
        collect data at nominal incidence angles that had been
        missed during Cycle 1 because of thermal problems with the
        spacecraft.  A transmitter failure during Cycle 3 caused a
        further loss of data.  It is not within the scope of this
        description to provide detailed information on data
        coverage.
 
        Leading Edge: Identification of the echo leading edge is
        critical for both topographic analysis and extraction of
        the near-nadir scattering function from ALT data.  For
        topography, a timing error translates directly into an
        error in planetary radius.  For calculation of the
        scattering function, both the inferred echo dispersion and
        the inferred echo amplitude will be in error if the
        initial rise of the echo is improperly identified.  This
        limitation applies most commonly when the spacecraft ALT
        antenna was aimed away from nadir and the surface was
        rough (e.g., during Cycle 1 over Aphrodite Terra).
 
        Inversion Stability: Although the ALT inversions require
        no assumptions about the form of the backscatter function,
        inversion processes are unstable in the presence of noise.
        Second differences were constrained during ALT inversions
        to improve stability.  The quantitative constraint was
        varied from periapsis to the poles based on whether the
        &apos;noise&apos; was radar echo speckle or speckle plus thermal
        system noise in the receiver.  Instabilities affect
        primarily the inversion results at the largest incidence
        angles.
 
        Noise Baseline: During ALT inversion, an estimate of
        &apos;thermal&apos; noise was derived from the data.  At low
        spacecraft altitudes noise was primarily radar clutter
        (for example, aliased signal from frequencies outside the
        nominal Doppler window).  At high spacecraft altitudes,
        both range aliasing and real system thermal noise
        contributed.  The erroneous inclusion of high-angle
        scattered signal in the &apos;noise&apos; estimate leads to the
        following consequences:
          (1) the derived scattering function amplitude will be
              underestimated (inferred reflectivity will be too
              small);
          (2) the echo decay rate with incidence angle will be
              overestimated (inferred rms surface slope will be
              too small);
          (3) uncertainty in the derived scattering function
              will be too small (especially at the largest angles).
 
        Orbit Eccentricity: Periapsis throughout the radar mapping
        mission was near 10 degrees N latitude at altitudes of
        approximately 300 km.  The altitude near the poles, on the
        other hand, was on the order of 3000 km.  For all data
        types this means lower confidence in results obtained at
        the poles than near the equator.
 
        Dynamic Antenna Pointing: The spacecraft attitude varied
        during each orbit to compensate partially for the changing
        SAR range to the surface and to provide scattering at
        higher incidence angles when the echo signal was expected
        to be strongest.  The SAR antenna was pointed at about 45
        degrees from nadir near periapsis; this was reduced to
        about 15 degrees at the poles.  The ALT antenna, at a
        constant 25 degree offset from the SAR antenna, followed
        in tandem but at angles which were not optimized for
        obtaining the best altimetry echo.
 
        Footprints: A nominal nadir footprint can be assigned to
        altimetry results, but this footprint is biased near
        periapsis because the ALT antenna is rotated about 20
        degrees from nadir (during Cycle 1).  Over polar regions
        in Cycle 1, the ALT antenna is rotated about 10 degrees
        to the opposite side of nadir.  A more important
        consideration in polar regions is that the area
        illuminated by the ALT antenna is approximately 100 times
        as large as near periapsis because of the higher spacecraft
        altitude.  The region contributing to echoes in polar
        regions -- and therefore the region over which estimates
        of Fresnel reflectivity and rms surface tilts apply -- is
        much larger than at periapsis.
 
 
      Cycle 1 Mapping
      ---------------
        During Mapping Cycle 1 almost half the orbits provided SAR
        images of the north pole; because of the orbit inclination,
        ALT data never extended beyond about 85N latitude in the north
        and 85S in the south.  No SAR images of the south pole were
        acquired during Mapping Cycle 1 because the SAR antenna was
        always pointed to the left of the ground track; Cycle 1 SAR
        image strips near the south pole were at latitudes
        equatorward of 85S.
 
        Beginning at approximately orbit 600 and extending until
        nearly orbit 1100, onboard recording of radar data slowly
        degraded.  Most of these data were subsequently reprocessed,
        with some improvement in data quality.  Where available, the
        reprocessed data have been included in the SCVDR.
 
 
      Cycle 2 Mapping
      ---------------
        During much of Mapping Cycle 2, the spacecraft was flown
        &apos;backwards&apos; so as to provide SAR images of the same terrain
        but with &apos;opposite side&apos; illumination.  This adjustment also
        meant that the SAR could image near the Venus south pole (but
        not near the north pole).  The ALT data continued to be
        limited to latitudes equatorward of 85N and 85S.
 
        SCVDR processing of image data within about two degrees of
        the south pole suffers from errors.  This apparently
        resulted from reprojection of the oblique sinusoidal pixels
        but the precise cause of the problem was never isolated and
        corrected.  This problem potentially affects all south pole
        OIF data, including any obtained in Cycle 3 as well as the
        larger volume from Cycle 2.
 
 
      Cycle 3 Mapping
      ---------------
        During Mapping Cycle 3 the emphasis was on obtaining SAR
        data at the same viewing azimuth as in Cycle 1 but at
        different incidence angles (for radar stereo).  In fact,
        most data were acquired at an incidence angle of about 25
        degrees, which meant that the ALT antenna was usually aimed
        directly at nadir instead of drifting from side to side,
        as had been the case in Cycles 1 and 2.  These Cycle 3 data,
        therefore, may be among the best from the altimeter.
        Dynamic range in SAR data was larger than in Cycles 1 and 2
        because the incidence angle was fixed rather than varying to
        compensate for the changing spacecraft altitude.
 
 
    Other Comments
    ==============
      Although information on radar echo timing is included in the
      ANF, a thorough analysis for topography was not attempted in
      the SCVDR.  Comparison of the preliminary SCVDR results with
      results in the ARCDR showed consistency in the altitude
      estimates.  Systematic errors were more carefully addressed
      in the ARCDR.  ARCDR topography was carried forward to the
      GVDR.
 
      Likewise, the EDF results in the SCVDR are consistent with
      emissivity data in the ARCDR.  The ARCDR emissivity results
      were carried forward to the GVDR.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>89-033B-011</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

