<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mgs-m-rss-5-tps-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MGS RS: ATMOSPHERIC TEMPERATURE-PRESSURE PROFILES V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_global_surveyor::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mgs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.mgs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-rss-5-tps-v1.0__browserp_mgs-m-rss-5-tps-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-rss-5-tps-v1.0__dvo_atm_mgs-m-rss-5-tps-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Clancy, R.T., B.J. Sandor, M.J. Wolff, P.R. Christensen, M.D. Smith, J.C.
                   Pearl, B.J. Conrath, and R.J. Wilson, An Intercomparison of Ground-Based
                   Millimeter, MGS TES, and Viking Atmospheric Temperature Measurements: Seasonal
                   and Interannual Variability of Temperatures and Dust Loading in the Global Mars
                   Atmosphere, Journal of Geophysical Research, 105, 9553-9571, 2000.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CLANCYETAL2000</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Davies, M.E., V.K. Abalakin, A. Brahic, M. Bursa, B.H. Chovitz, J.H. Lieske,
                   P.K. Seidelmann, A.T. Sinclair, and Y.S. Tjuflin, Report of the IAU/IAG/COSPAR
                   Working Group on Cartographic Coordinates and Rotational Elements of the
                   Planets and Satellites: 1991, Celestial Mechanics and Dynamical Astronomy, 53,
                   377-397, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DAVIESETAL1992B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Fjeldbo, G., A.J. Kliore, and V.R. Eshleman, The Neutral Atmosphere of Venus as
                   Studied with the Mariner V Radio Occultation Data, Astron. J., 76, 123-140,
                   1971.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FJELDBOETAL1971</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hinson, D.P., R.A. Simpson, J.D. Twicken, G.L. Tyler, and F.M. Flasar, Initial
                   Results from Radio Occultation Measurements with Mars Global Surveyor, Journal
                   of Geophysical Research, 104, 26997-27012, 1999.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HINSONETAL1999</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hinson, D.P., G.L. Tyler, J.L. Hollingsworth, and R.J. Wilson, Radio
                   Occultation Measurements of Forced Atmospheric Waves on Mars, Journal of
                   Geophysical Research, 106, 1463-1480, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HINSONETAL2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hinson, D.P., M.D. Smith, and B.J. Conrath, Comparison of Atmospheric
                   Temperatures Obtained through Infrared Sounding and Radio Occultation by Mars
                   Global Surveyor, Journal of Geophysical Research, 109, E12002,
                   doi:10.1029/2004JE002344, 2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HINSONETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tyler, G.L., G. Balmino, D.P. Hinson, W.L. Sjogren, D.E. Smith, R. Woo, S.W.
                   Asmar, M.J. Connally, C.L. Hamilton, and R.A. Simpson, Radio Science
                   Investigations with Mars Observer, Journal of Geophysical Research, 97,
                   7759-7779, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TYLERETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tyler, G.L., G. Balmino, D.P. Hinson, W.L. Sjogren, D.E. Smith, R.A. Simpson,
                   S.W. Asmar, P. Priest, and J.D. Twicken, Radio science observations with Mars
                   Global Surveyor: Orbit insertion through one Mars year in mapping orbit,
                   Journal of Geophysical Research, 106, 23327-23348, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TYLERETAL2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MGS-M-RSS-5-TPS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MGS RS: ATMOSPHERIC TEMPERATURE-PRESSURE PROFILES V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2008-05-31</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1998-01-28T03:38:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2006-09-19T23:56:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID P. HINSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Hinson, D.P., Mars Global Surveyor Radio Occultation Profiles of
            the Neutral Atmosphere - Reorganized, MGS-M-RSS-5-TPS-V1.0, NASA
            Planetary Data System, 2008.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Mars Global Surveyor radio occultation neutral atmosphere
            profiles - reorganized onto one volume.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains over 21000 temperature-pressure profiles
            (TPS files) of the neutral atmosphere derived from Mars Global
            Surveyor (MGS) radio occultation data. The profiles were
            previously archived in the MGS-M-RSS-5-SDP-V1.0 data set along
            with other reduced data products from the MGS Radio Science Team
            (RST). Here they have been pulled from the original 38 volumes
            and reorganized in chronological order on a single volume. The
            profiles themselves have not been modified, and the labels have
            been edited only to conform with the requirements of the new data
            set. This set of profiles is accompanied by a single occultation
            summary file which lists key characteristics of each experiment.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      MGS radio occultation experiments were conducted using a 3.6-cm
      wavelength radio signal transmitted by the spacecraft and received
      on Earth.  In principle this &apos;downlink&apos; configuration allows
      atmospheric structure to be sampled twice per orbit. Occultation
      entry and exit generally occurred in the northern and southern
      hemispheres, respectively, and the latitude of the measurements
      drifted gradually in response to changes in the observing geometry.
      The experiments eventually visited essentially all latitudes on
      Mars.  However, far more experiments were performed at occultation
      entry than exit, owing to a problem with one of the gimbals used
      to point the spacecraft high-gain antenna (HGA).  This resulted
      in particularly dense coverage at latitudes of 60-80 deg in the
      northern hemisphere. The coverage in longitude of the data set
      is fairly dense and uniform with few exceptions.
 
      Radio occultation temperature-pressure (T-p) profiles were
      computed with standard vertical resolution (approximately 500 m);
      an option to compute them at high resolution (approximately 20 m,
      after correction for diffraction effects) was never exercised.
      T-p files are stored as ASCII tables, preceded by a header record
      which contains supplementary information as described below.
 
      The headers from each individual file have been collected in a
      single occultation summary file, which may be useful for scanning
      the data set, identifying profiles of particular interest, and
      reviewing the coverage in latitude, season, and local time.
 
      David Hinson at Stanford University created all T-p profiles and
      the occultation summary file.
 
      For more information about these data, see [TYLERETAL1992],
      [HINSONETAL1999], [HINSONETAL2001], [TYLERETAL2001], and
      [HINSONETAL2004].
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      Temperature-pressure profiles are tables of geopotential,
      temperature, pressure, and molecular number density versus
      radius from Mars&apos; center of mass.  Each profile extends from
      the surface to the 10-Pa pressure level with a sample spacing
      of about 1 km.  A header record prepended to each table
      provides information about observing times and geometry,
      surface conditions, and files used in the data processing.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      T-p profiles are derived from raw receiver output in several
      steps.
 
      First, deterministic sources of frequency change are identified
      and removed coherently. These included motion of the spacecraft,
      motion of the Earth receiving station, drift of the UltraStable
      Oscillator (USO), and relativistic effects associated with
      gravity fields of solar system bodies.  This leaves the carrier
      signal at a known frequency except for phase drift associated
      with passage of the radio ray through Mars&apos; atmosphere and/or
      ionosphere.  Drift associated with passage through solar plasma
      or the Earth&apos;s atmosphere or ionosphere is assumed to be
      negligible over the time of a Mars occultation (approximately
      two minutes).
 
      Second, using an accurate reconstruction of the spacecraft
      trajectory, the phase of the signal versus time is converted
      into a measure of refraction angle versus impact parameter --
      the perpendicular distance between the incoming raypath and the
      center of curvature of the atmosphere.
 
      Third, the index of refraction versus radius is obtained using
      an Abel inversion [FJELDBOETAL1971].  From knowledge of the
      composition of the atmosphere and laboratory measurements of
      refractive index for major constituents, index of refraction
      versus radius for the neutral atmosphere is converted to
      vertical distribution of mass density.
 
      Fourth, assuming hydrostatic equilibrium and an ideal gas law,
      the mass density profile is converted to a profile of both
      temperature and pressure for the neutral atmosphere.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      Data are stored on a single volume in the TPS directory
      in subdirectories in the order they were collected.  Thirty-four
      subdirectories have been defined with names of the form
      yyyy_ddd  where  yyyy  is the year and  ddd  is the day-of-year
      of the first profile in each directory.  Directory boundaries
      have been chosen so that collections have common characteristics,
      such as similar Ls values, or are easily separated by periods
      when there was little MGS RST activity, such as solar conjunction
      or spacecraft anomalies when no data were collected.  When these
      criteria allowed more than 1000 profiles in a directory,
      arbitrary boundaries were added so that the largest directory
      contains only 971 profiles.  The directories and their
      boundaries are summarized below.
 
      Temperature-pressure profiles are stored with file names of
      the form  ydddhmmC.TPS  where  y  is the least significant
      digit of the year,  ddd  is the three-digit day number,
      h  is a one-character string denoting the hour, and  mm  is
      a two-character string denoting the minute in which data
      acquisition began.  h  is  &apos;A&apos; if the hour was  00,  &apos;B&apos;
      if the hour was  01, ... and &apos;X&apos; if the hour was 23.  In
      most cases  mm  is the two-digit minute; but when data were
      collected from two sources and the start time was in the
      same minute, the second digit in  mm  was changed to a
      letter in the second file name (minute  00  becomes  0A,  01
      becomes  0B,  etc.).  C  is a single character
      indicating the version of the file, starting with &apos;A&apos;.
      T-p profiles from 2006 have file names in which  y  is set
      to &apos;G&apos; to avoid conflict with files which might have
      originated in 1996.  In fact, there were no occultation
      profiles in 1996, but other data types do have files from
      those years.
 
      An occultation summary file is stored in the OCS directory.
      Its file name is 801609AA.OCS where 801 indicates that the
      first occultation was from January 1998 and 609 indicates that
      the last occultation was from September 2006. &apos;AA&apos; is a two
      character string which indicates that this is the first version
      of the file.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      OCCLOG.TAB in the DOCUMENT directory provides single-line
      summaries for each observation opportunity.  Parameters listed
      mostly relate to settings of and quick-look results from data
      acquisition.  See detached PDS label OCCLOG.LBL for details.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      MGS RST SDP files use a Mars centered body-fixed coordinate
      system with positive east longitude.
 
      Gravity models generally use the IAU 1991 [DAVIESETAL1992B]
      coordinate frame.  Variations are noted in the labels of
      specific gravity products.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      None.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The archival data set was written on CD-WO media using the
      Sun Ultra-60/PlexWriter/cdrtoaster system.  The CD-WO
      volumes conform to ISO 9660 standards.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this archive have been reduced as part of mission data
      analysis activities of the MGS Radio Science Team.  Products
      of questionable validity have been flagged or omitted.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was reviewed by the MGS Radio Science
      Team prior to submission to the Planetary Data System (PDS).
 
      All of the profiles had been in the public domain as elements
      of the MGS-M-RSS-5-SDP-V1.0 data set for as much as seven years
      before this reorganized data set was compiled.
 
    Data Coverage
    ==============
 
      The following table describes the directories that contain
      the profiles.  Each directory is represented by one row.  The
      first two columns list the year and day-of-year of the first
      and last profiles in each directory, respectively.  The first
      column is also the directory name.  The third and fourth
      columns provide the same information in standard calendar
      format.  The fifth and sixth columns give the number of the
      Martian year (MY, as defined by [CLANCYETAL2000]) and the
      approximate areocentric longitude of the Sun (Ls, in degrees)
      of the first and last profiles in each directory, respectively.
      The last column specifies the number of profiles in each
      directory.  Blank rows denote gaps caused by solar
      conjunction (see below).
 
       Start     End       Start       End      Start   End
      yyyy_ddd yyyy_ddd  yyyy-mm-dd yyyy-mm-dd  MY/Ls  MY/Ls   Number
      -------- --------  ---------- ----------  ------ ------  ------
      1998_028 1998_100  1998-01-28 1998-04-10  23/264 23/308    88
      1998_358 1998_365  1998-12-24 1998-12-31  24/074 24/077    36
      1999_068 1999_086  1999-03-09 1999-03-27  24/108 24/116    97
      1999_126 1999_178  1999-05-06 1999-06-27  24/135 24/161   882
      1999_350 2000_038  1999-12-16 2000-02-07  24/264 24/297   800
      2000_039 2000_152  2000-02-08 2000-05-31  24/297 25/000   838
 
      2000_214 2000_305  2000-08-01 2000-10-31  25/029 25/070   854
      2000_306 2001_031  2000-11-01 2001-01-31  25/070 25/111   904
      2001_032 2001_122  2001-02-01 2001-05-02  25/111 25/155   687
      2001_130 2001_197  2001-05-10 2001-07-16  25/159 25/197   690
      2001_347 2002_058  2001-12-13 2002-02-27  25/290 25/334   906
      2002_066 2002_137  2002-03-07 2002-05-17  25/338 26/014   702
      2002_138 2002_196  2002-05-18 2002-07-15  26/014 26/041   536
 
      2002_251 2002_304  2002-09-08 2002-10-31  26/065 26/089   544
      2002_305 2002_365  2002-11-01 2002-12-31  26/089 26/116   557
      2003_001 2003_080  2003-01-01 2003-03-21  26/116 26/156   694
      2003_081 2003_161  2003-03-22 2003-06-10  26/156 26/201   720
      2003_169 2003_253  2003-06-18 2003-09-10  26/205 26/258   654
      2003_254 2003_291  2003-09-11 2003-10-18  26/258 26/282   405
      2003_320 2004_019  2003-11-16 2004-01-19  26/299 26/336   436
      2004_061 2004_100  2004-03-01 2004-04-09  26/358 27/017   388
      2004_101 2004_145  2004-04-10 2004-05-24  27/017 27/038   723
      2004_146 2004_203  2004-05-25 2004-07-21  27/038 27/064   819
 
      2004_284 2004_357  2004-10-10 2004-12-22  27/099 27/133   696
      2004_361 2005_090  2004-12-26 2005-03-31  27/135 27/185   898
      2005_091 2005_181  2005-04-01 2005-06-30  27/185 27/241   971
      2005_182 2005_238  2005-07-01 2005-08-26  27/241 27/276   597
      2005_252 2005_296  2005-09-09 2005-10-23  27/285 27/312   794
      2005_297 2005_334  2005-10-24 2005-11-30  27/312 27/333   604
      2005_335 2005_365  2005-12-01 2005-12-31  27/333 27/350   610
      2006_001 2006_050  2006-01-01 2006-02-19  27/350 28/014   309
      2006_130 2006_181  2006-05-10 2006-06-30  28/051 28/073   381
      2006_182 2006_218  2006-07-01 2006-08-06  28/073 28/089   699
      2006_219 2006_262  2006-08-07 2006-09-19  28/089 28/109   724
 
 
      Data coverage was limited by many factors.  This is
      particularly true during the pre-mapping phases of the
      mission, which extended into early 1999.  Prior to the
      start of the mapping phase, the spacecraft frequently
      conducted special maneuvers for aerobraking and temperature
      control, and scientific observations were constrained by
      numerous other operational issues.  The following discussion
      focuses on the mapping phase of the mission, when data
      collection was much more systematic.  The most significant
      gaps in coverage fall into five categories.
 
      Coverage in Local Time
      ----------------------
        These occultation measurements are geometrically constrained
        to occur near the terminator within a restricted range of
        local true solar time.  With few exceptions, observations at
        latitudes between 60 deg N and 60 deg S are available only at
        local times of about 3-6 hours.  Observations at local times
        of 9-16 hours are available only at latitudes poleward of
        60 deg, and this daytime coverage is generally restricted to
        autumn and winter of the respective hemispheres.
 
      Solar Conjunction
      ------------------
        The noise level of the radio occultation measurements
        increased dramatically near solar conjunction.  This
        prevented retrieval of profiles in the following intervals,
        denoted by blank rows in the preceding table:
        2000_153 - 2000_213
        2002_197 - 2002_250
        2004_204 - 2004_283
        2006_263 - 2006_277
 
      Beta Supplement
      ----------------
        The range of motion of one of the gimbals that controls
        pointing of the spacecraft HGA was severely restricted
        until late in the mission, when the obstruction vanished
        for reasons unknown. During the extended intervals when
        the failed gimbal prevented normal operations, the
        spacecraft was configured in a &apos;beta supplement&apos; mode
        that restored most of its functionality. This had no
        effect on measurements at occultation entry (northern
        hemisphere) but experiments could not be conducted
        routinely at occultation exit (southern hemisphere) when
        the spacecraft was in the beta supplement mode.  The
        resulting loss of exit data was reduced slightly through
        use of special spacecraft maneuvers that allowed
        collection of radio occultation data over sequences of
        typically 12 consecutive orbits at intervals of about
        one month.  The spacecraft operated in the beta supplement
        mode during the following periods, during which exit
        measurements are extremely sparse:
        2000_039 - 2001_171
        2002_073 - 2003_253
        2004_204 - 2005_251
 
      Spacecraft Anomalies and Emergencies
      --------------------------------------
        The spacecraft occasionally stopped collecting scientific
        data for periods of several days in response to problems
        with flight software or hardware.  This prevented
        occultation experiments from being conducted in the
        following intervals:
        2001_123 - 2001_129
        2002_059 - 2002_065
        2002_092 - 2002_100
        2003_162 - 2003_168
        2004_358 - 2004_360
        2005_239 - 2005_251
        2005_256 - 2005_261
 
      Broadside Orbit / Highly Grazing Geometry
      --------------------------------------------
        In periods when the MGS orbit plane was nearly broadside
        as viewed from Earth, the atmospheric occultation either
        occurred in a highly grazing geometry or was entirely
        absent.  For this reason no profiles are available in
        the following intervals:
        1999_179 - 1999_349
        2001_198 - 2001_346
        2006_051 - 2006_129
 
      Anomalous HGA Motion
      ---------------------
        Throughout most of its mission, MGS orbited Mars with
        its nadir panel facing the surface.  The HGA was
        positioned at the end of a rotating boom that maintained
        pointing toward Earth.  Radio occultation data were
        calibrated to remove effects caused by the mean motion
        of the HGA, but it was not possible to correct for
        abrupt changes in HGA pointing.  The occultation data
        are especially vulnerable to HGA motion associated with
        two types of spacecraft activity: (1) repositioning of
        the solar arrays, performed in discrete steps several
        times per orbit, and (2) rewinding of the HGA, which
        usually occurred when the spacecraft was behind Mars.
        These types of HGA motion interfered with the
        occultation experiments and prevented retrieval of
        atmospheric profiles in the following periods:
        2001_347 - 2002_006 (entry)
        2001_352 - 2002_001 (exit)
        2003_272 - 2004_100 (entry)
        2003_265 - 2003_275 (exit)
        2003_292 - 2003_319 (exit)
        2004_020 - 2004_060 (exit)
        2004_134 - 2004_171 (exit)
        2005_297 - 2005_309 (entry)
        2006_001 - 2006_006 (exit)
        2006_012 - 2006_034 (exit)
        2006_012 - 2006_050 (entry)
        2006_130 - 2006_169 (entry)
        2006_134 - 2006_160 (exit)
 
 
    Data Quality
    =============
 
      Each profile includes uncertainties on the estimates of
      pressure, temperature, and number density.  This is the
      best source of information about data quality.  Some
      obvious trends are apparent in the error bars, such as a
      general increase in the noise level when the spacecraft
      was close to solar conjunction.  Data quality can vary
      significantly between successive experiments, and
      sometimes from one DSN complex to another, and these
      variations are reflected in the error bars.
 
      Some error sources are difficult to quantify, and their
      effects are therefore not included in the formal
      uncertainties. As a general rule, diametric occultations
      yield more reliable results than grazing occultations.
      (The header of each profile includes several parameters,
      such as the &apos;angle from diametric&apos;, that characterize
      the experiment geometry.)
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The limitations in this data set follow from the quality of
      the execution, which is described above under Data Coverage
      and Quality.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

