<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mpfl-m-asimet-2-edr-surf-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MPFL MARS ATM STRUCT INST AND MET PKG RAW SURFACE V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_pathfinder::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mpfl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:asimet.mpfl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:windsock.mpfl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mpfl-m-asimet-2-edr-surf-v1.0__browserp_mpfl-m-asimet-2-edr-surf-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mpfl-m-asimet-2-edr-surf-v1.0__dvo_atmos2_mpfl-m-asimet-2-edr-surf-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mpfl-m-asimet-2-edr-surf-v1.0__dvo_atmos_mpfl-m-asimet-2-edr-surf-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Schofield, J.T., J.R. Barnes, D. Crisp, R.M. Haberle, J.A. Magalhaes, J.R.
                   Murphy, A. Seiff, S. Larsen, and G. Wilson, The Mars Pathfinder Atmospheric
                   Structure Investigation/Meteorology (ASI/MET) Experiment, Science, 278,
                   1752-1758, 1997.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SCHOFIELDETAL1997</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Seiff, A., J.E. Tillman, J.R. Murphy, J.T. Schofield, D. Crisp, J.R.
                   Barnes, C.KaBaw, C. Mahoney, J.D. Mihalov, G.R. Wilson, and R. Haberle, The
                   Atmosphere Structure and Meteorology Instrument on the Mars Pathfinder
                   Lander, J. Geophys. Res., 102, 4045-4056, 1997.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SEIFFETAL1997</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Vaughan, R., Mars Pathfinder Project Planetary Constants and Models, JPL
                   Document 12947, PF-100-PMC-01, 136 pp., December, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.VAUGHAN1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MPFL-M-ASIMET-2-EDR-SURF-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MPFL MARS ATM STRUCT INST AND MET PKG RAW SURFACE V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1998-01-04</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1997-07-04T21:11:55.216Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1997-09-27T04:54:42.300Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JOHN T. SCHOFIELD</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Mars Pathfinder Atmospheric Structure Instrument/Meteorology
            package (ASI/MET) and Windsock Experiment Data Record
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Mars Pathfinder bounced down and rolled to a stop on the surface
            of Mars on July 4, 1997. It landed in an ancient floodplain in
            the Ares Vallis region of Chryse Planitia at 19.17 degrees North
            latitude, and 33.21 degrees West longitude.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    Mars Pathfinder bounced down and rolled to a stop on the surface
    of Mars on July 4, 1997.  It landed in an ancient floodplain in
    the Ares Vallis region of Chryse Planitia at 19.17 degrees North
    latitude, and 33.21 degrees West longitude.
 
    The total duration of the mission was 83 sols.  Surface
    meteorology data were collected by the MET instrument on 76 of
    these sols (sols 17, 31, 43, 45, 46, 48, and 51 contain no
    meteorology data).
 
    MET data are organized into science and housekeeping data
    records.  Each record is composed of 12 parameters, which for all
    intents and purposes are measured simultaneously.  The science
    data record consists of surface pressure (two instrument
    sensitivity ranges), atmospheric temperature at three vertical
    locations on the MET mast (referred to as TOP, MIDDLE, and
    BOTTOM), atmospheric temperature as measured by the Descent
    Thermocouple located near the top of the MET mast, and wind speed
    and direction at the top of the MET mast.  See [SEIFFETAL1997]
    for a complete description of the instruments.  The housekeeping
    data record consists of various instrument voltages, currents,
    and reference temperatures.
 
    At the time of writing (Sept.  1998), we had not yet derived
    reliable wind speeds and directions from the data received from
    the Martian surface.  We continue to re-calibrate the wind
    sensor, and hope to have the wind results released soon.
 
    The parameters contained in the science data record are the
    measured atmospheric pressure obtained with the two instrument
    sensitivity ranges (6-10 and 0-12 millibars).  Also included are
    the three temperatures measured along the MET mast, as well as
    the temperature measured by the Descent Thermocouple.  We have
    also included in this data set the measured temperatures of each
    of the six wire segments which comprise the wind sensor.  These
    temperatures, and their spatial variation around the sensor&apos;s
    central cylinder, are the data from which wind speed and
    direction will be derived.  The housekeeping data consist of
    several reference voltage measurements from which the stability
    of instrument power supplies and sensor constant current sources
    can be determined.  Additionally, the thermocouple reference
    junction temperature, the internal temperature of the wind-sensor
    cylinder, the temperature of the pressure sensor, and the
    temperature of the MET circuit board are measured.  All science
    and housekeeping parameters are derived from sampled digitized
    voltages.
 
    The time intervals during which data were collected are referred
    to as sessions.  Each session is characterized by a session
    number, a duration, and science and housekeeping data record
    sampling rates.  Session numbers during the mission ranged from
    39 (~ 7 AM LST on Sol 1) to 1430 (Sol 83).  Session durations
    varied in duration from 184 seconds to 89052 seconds.  This
    latter duration, used on 5 occasions, produced what we have
    referred to as &apos;Presidential MET Sessions&apos;, during which data
    were continually collected at a 0.25 Hz rate for an entire sol.
    The science data record sampling rate used during the mission
    varied per the specifications of the ASI/MET science team.  It
    ranged from 0.25 Hz (a single point measurement of each variable
    once every four seconds) to 2 Hz (2 point measurements per
    second).
 
    For more info, see [SEIFFETAL1997, SCHOFIELDETAL1997].
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The data downlinked from the spacecraft are digital numbers
    derived from measured voltages.  Digitization is to 14 bits,
    compared with the 10 bit resolution available to the Viking
    meteorology instruments.  These numbers are stored in the
    Experiment Data Record (EDR) files, whereas the Reduced Data
    Records (RDR), contain results in scientific units (millibars,
    Kelvin, etc.).  EDR values are converted to volts and
    subsequently scientific units using calibration information.
 
    During the nominal mission (sols 1-30), the nominal MET
    observation strategy was 51 equally spaced 3 minute measurement
    sessions per Sol.  For each session science data records were
    sampled at a rate of 0.25 Hz.  Interspersed with these sessions
    were longer (15 minute, one hour, entire sol) sessions often
    sampled at a higher rate (1 Hz).  The purpose of this strategy
    was to characterize the full diurnal cycle throughout the sol, as
    well as higher frequency fluctuations at a variety of times
    during the sol.  These times were spread over a number of sols to
    remain within data downlink constraints.  Thus, we planned to
    characterize the diurnal cycle at &apos;low-frequency&apos; (51 times each
    sol), and then over the period of ~10 sols to accumulate
    information at higher sampling frequencies so that every hour of
    the day would have such sampling.  Continuous sampling for a
    complete sol at 0.25 Hz (a &apos;Presidential MET Session&apos;) was first
    conducted on Sol 25 and subsequently on sols 32,38,55, and 68.
    These are the only sols during the extended mission (sols 31-83)
    when MET data were collected outside the hours of 0900 - 1500
    LST.
 
    Data are stored on a session-by-session basis.  Thus, data for a
    particular sol are included in multiple files, for sols 1-49.  On
    later sols, single sessions were specified to cover the duration
    of spacecraft activity on that sol (nominally 9 AM to 2:30 PM).
    Thus, from sol 50 (Session 1398) through sol 83 (Session 1430),
    data for each sol are contained in a single data file (session).
 
    Session numbers ranged from 39-1430, but no data for sessions
    1330, 1338, 1340, 1341, 1362, 1370, 1376, 1379, 1384, 1385, 1386,
    1387, 1389, 1390 were returned.  Thus, there are no files for
    these sessions.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The following process was used to create the MET Surface
    Experiment Data Records:
 
        1)  The individual packets of binary data were constructed into
            single-session data files.
 
        2)  The 14-bit binary numbers were converted to ASCII numbers.
 
        3)  Time-related values which were measured in RTIs (Real Time
            Interrupts, where 125 milliseconds = 1 RTI) were converted
            to seconds.
 
        4)  SCLK values were calculated for cases where the first packet
            was missing from a session.
 
    The above files are those that were distributed by the
    Multimission Image Processing Laboratory (MIPL) during the
    mission.  After the mission, a timing error was discovered in the
    telemetry data and all of the SCLK values were recalculated.
    Further details of the timing error are described below in the
    section on Ancillary Data.
 
    Finally, the data were converted to PDS format, by separating the
    science and housekeeping records into distinct files, converting
    the tab-delimited fields to fixed-width fields, and exchanging
    the multiple packet headers for a single session header.  (The
    original packet headers have been retained in a separate file
    called &apos;PKT_HDRS.TAB&apos;; see Ancillary Data, below.)
 
    The real time processing of the MET Surface EDRs was performed at
    the Jet Propulsion Laboratory&apos;s Multimission Image Processing
    Laboratory using the VICAR suite of data processing programs.
    For questions concerning the creation of the data products,
    please contact:
 
    Address:     Allan Runkle
                 M/S 168-414
                 Jet Propulsion Laboratory
                 4800 Oak Grove Drive
                 Pasadena, CA 91109
 
    Phone:       (818) 354-6006
    Email:       Allan.Runkle@jpl.nasa.gov
 
    For science related questions about the data, please contact the
    ASI/MET Facility Instrument Science Team Lead:
 
    Address:     Tim Schofield
                 M/S 169-237
                 Jet Propulsion Laboratory
                 4800 Oak Grove Drive
                 Pasadena, CA 91109
 
    Phone:       (818) 354-2517
    Email:       John.T.Schofield@jpl.nasa.gov
 
 
  Data
  ====
    All of the data in this data set are contained in ASCII tabular
    files with detached PDS labels.  Science and housekeeping data
    have been split into separate files, stored in the directories
    SURF_EDR/SCIDATA and SURF_EDR/HKPDATA, respectively.  Beneath
    that, the data files are separated by session number into
    fourteen directories labeled SE00XXS through SE14XXS (for the
    science data) and SE00XXH through SE14XXH (for the housekeeping
    data).
 
    Individual filenames are constructed as follows:
 
                             SE0559S.TAB
 
                             1234567.890
 
        1: The first character will always be an &apos;S&apos;, representing
           Surface data.
        2: The second character will always be an &apos;E&apos;, signifying the
           raw data (Experiment Data Record).  The corresponding
           calibrated data (ie., Reduced Data Record) can be found in
           the SURF_RDR directory, in a file with the same name, except
           that the &apos;E&apos; will be an &apos;R&apos;.
      3-6: The next four characters provide the session number of the
           data file.
        7: The seventh character will be either an &apos;S&apos; or an &apos;H&apos;.
           &apos;S&apos; signifies science data; &apos;H&apos; signifies housekeeping data.
      8-0: The file extension indicates which type of file it is.  The
           only two options are &apos;LBL&apos; (the PDS label file), or &apos;TAB&apos; the
           ASCII table containing the data.
 
    As an example, the data from session 559 is stored in the following
    locations on the ASI/MET CD:
 
    SURF_EDR/SCIDATA/SE05XXS/SE0559S.TAB - raw data file
    SURF_EDR/SCIDATA/SE05XXS/SE0559S.LBL - PDS label for SE0559S.TAB
 
    SURF_EDR/HKPDATA/SE05XXH/SE0559H.TAB - raw housekeeping file
    SURF_EDR/HKPDATA/SE05XXH/SE0559H.LBL - PDS label for SE0559H.TAB
 
    SURF_RDR/SCIDATA/SR05XXS/SR0559S.TAB - calibrated data file
    SURF_RDR/SCIDATA/SR05XXS/SR0559S.LBL - PDS label for SR0559S.TAB
 
    SURF_RDR/HKPDATA/SR05XXH/SR0559H.TAB - calibrated housekeeping file
    SURF_RDR/HKPDATA/SR05XXH/SR0559H.LBL - PDS label for SR0559H.TAB
 
    The tabular files are formatted so that they may be read directly
    into many database management systems (DBMS) or spreadsheet
    programs on various computers.  Each of the files contains two
    tables.  The first is the header table, and is only a single
    record in length.  The second table contains all of the data
    records for a session and varies in length.
 
    All fields in the tables are stored in columns of fixed width and
    are right justified.  The records are of fixed length; since the
    header records are shorter than the data records, they have been
    padded with blank spaces at the end of the record.  The last two
    bytes of each record contain the ASCII carriage return and line
    feed characters.  This allows the tables to be treated as fixed
    length record files on computers that support this file type and
    as normal text files on other computers.
 
    The ancillary data file, PKT_HDRS.TAB, (described below,) is
    similar to the regular data files, except that it only contains a
    single table with 8,173 records, and the fields in the table are
    comma separated.
 
    The PDS labels are object-oriented.  The object to which the
    labels refer (the tables) is denoted by a statement of the form:
 
        ^object = location
 
    in which the carat character (&apos;^&apos;, also called a pointer in this
    context) indicates that the object starts at the given location.
    For an object located outside the label file (as in this case),
    the location denotes the name of the file containing the object,
    along with the starting record.  For example:
 
        ^DATA_TABLE = (&apos;SE0559S.TAB&apos;, 2)
 
    indicates that the DATA_TABLE object begins at record 2 of the
    file SE0559S.TAB, in the same directory as the detached label
    file.  (Records are counted starting at 1, not 0.) When there is
    only a single object in the data file (as with PKT_HDRS.TAB), the
    record number may be dropped:
 
        ^TABLE = &apos;PKT_HDRS.TAB&apos;
 
    The detached label files are stream format files, with a carriage
    return (ASCII 13) and a line feed character (ASCII 10) at the end
    of each record.  This allows the files to be read by the MacOS,
    DOS, UNIX, and VMS operating systems.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    As mentioned above, a timing problem was discovered in the MET
    telemetry data after the mission.  The root cause of the problem
    is not completely understood, but likely involved a software
    error in the counting of the housekeeping vs.  science records
    with their varying sampling rates.  However, the problem is
    sufficiently understood to correct the data.
 
    Most of the time, the housekeeping sensors were sampled every
    thirty-six seconds, while the science sensors were sampled every
    four seconds.  (Each sample corresponds to a record within a
    packet.) However, at packet boundaries, the interval alternates
    between zero seconds at one boundary, and eight seconds at the
    next.
 
    In those cases where the science sampling rate was every two
    seconds, the packet boundary problem is only seen every seventeen
    packets; an interval of zero seconds is followed by an interval
    of four seconds.  When the science sampling rate is every second,
    the problem recurs roughly every thirty packets, with an interval
    of zero seconds followed by an interval of two seconds.
 
    In general, the problem can be corrected by shifting the SCLK
    values of all the science data records in a packet following a
    zero second packet boundary.  In all cases, the values should be
    shifted forward by an amount equal to the science sampling
    interval.
 
    None of the housekeeping data records were affected by this
    problem.
 
    Due to the necessity of correcting this problem and of
    calculating SCLKs in cases where the first packet in a session
    was missing, all of the SCLK values provided in the EDR files are
    calculated values, rather than the original values received in
    the telemetry.  Given the possibility of an error in the
    correction of the timing problem, it was decided that the
    original SCLK values should be retained somewhere.  Therefore,
    all of the original UNCORRECTED packet headers were stripped out
    of the original data files and concatenated into a single
    ancillary data file called &apos;PKT_HDRS.TAB&apos;.
 
    This is a single ASCII tabular data file stored in the INDEX
    directory of the ASI/MET CD.  The structure of the individual
    records in the file is almost identical to that of the header
    records in each of the data files, and is fully described by the
    PDS label included in the same directory.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The ASI/MET Surface EDR tables can be displayed on UNIX,
    Macintosh, and PC platforms as simple ASCII files, or using the
    PDS developed program, NASAView.  This software is freely
    available from the PDS Central Node and may be obtained from
    their web site at http://pds.nasa.gov/.  For more information
    or help in obtaining the software, contact the PDS operator at
    the following address:
 
    Address:     Planetary Data System, PDS Operator
                 Jet Propulsion Laboratory
                 4800 Oak Grove Drive
                 Pasadena, CA 91109
 
    Phone:       (818) 354-4321
    Email:       pds_operator@jpl.nasa.gov
    WWW URL:     http://pds.nasa.gov/
 
 
  Media / Format
  ==============
    The ASI/MET Surface EDR data will be stored and distributed on
    compact disc-read only memory (CD-ROM) media.  The CDs are
    formatted according to ISO-9660 and PDS standards.  The data
    files do not include extended attribute records (XARs), and will
    therefore not be readable on some older VMS operating systems.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
 
    Review
    ------
      The contents of this CD have been peer reviewed by the
      following people:
 
      Lyle Huber        - PDS Atmospheres Node, New Mexico State
                          University
      Julio Magalhaes   - MPF ASI/MET Team, NASA Ames Research Center
      Jim Murphy        - MPF ASI/MET Team &amp; PDS Atmospheres Node,
                          New Mexico State University
      Tim Schofield     - MPF ASI/MET Team Lead, Jet Propulsion
                          Laboratory
      Rob Sullivan      - MPF Participating Scientist,
                          Cornell University
      Betty Sword       - PDS Central Node Data Engineer, Jet Propulsion
                          Laboratory
      John Wilson       - Non-MPF scientist, Geophysical Fluid Dynamics
                          Laboratory/NOAA, Princeton University
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    During pre-flight testing, the pressure sensor was tested at
    temperatures (190 K) that were significantly lower than its
    design limits (220 K), and much colder than it experienced within
    the spacecraft on the Martian surface.  This extreme stressing of
    the sensor cast doubt upon the calibration which had been
    obtained prior to that point, and the schedule thereafter did not
    permit recalibration of the sensor in a controlled environment.
    During cruise to Mars, the ASI/MET system was periodically
    powered up and the pressure sensor signal, as well as its
    temperature, were measured.  These measurements, together with
    measurements obtained during free fall and entry, provided a data
    set from which the variation of sensor zero-offset as a function
    of the temperatures experienced during cruise (270-280K) could be
    determined.  It became clear that thermal stressing had changed
    the offset and increased its variation with temperature by a
    factor of 3.  It was not possible to verify gains in flight, but
    laboratory testing on the flight spare sensor suggested that
    sensor stressing would not produce significant gain changes.  The
    flight data, in addition to the pre-flight calibration data, have
    been used to determine pressure from the down-linked pressure
    sensor signals.
 
    The thermocouples appeared to work very well, and there is no
    reason to question the results from them.
 
    As stated above, the determination of wind speed and direction is
    ongoing, and a new wind data set will be issued following
    analyses of recent sensor recalibration work, and application of
    its results to wind-sensor data returned from the Martian
    surface.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

