<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ody-m-grs-5-ahd-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 5 AHD V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.2001_mars_odyssey::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.ody::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:grs.ody::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-grs-5-ahd-v1.0__browserp_geo_ody-m-grs-5-ahd-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-grs-5-ahd-v1.0__dvo_geo_ody-m-grs-5-ahd-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-grs-5-ahd-v1.0__pds.ua.grs_web_site::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Boynton, W. V., W. C. Feldman, I. Mitrofanov, L. G. Evans, R. C. Reedy, S.
                   W. Squyres, R. Starr, I. Trombka, C. d&apos;Uston, J. R. Arnold, P. A. J.
                   Englert, A. E. Metzger, H. Wanke, J. Bruckner, D. M. Drake, C. Shinohara,
                   C. Fellows, D. K. Hamara, K. Harshman, The Mars Odyssey gamma-ray
                   spectrometer instrument suite, Space Sci. Rev., 110 (1-2): 37-83, 2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BOYNTONETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Planetary Data System Standards Reference, JPL Document D-7669, Part 2, Jet
                   Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PDSSR2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Seidelmann, P.K., V.K. Abalakin, M. Bursa, M.E. Davies, C. de Bergh, J.H.
                   Lieske, J. Oberst, J.L. Simon, E.M. Standish, P. Stooke, and P.C. Thomas,
                   Report of the IAU/IAG working group on cartographic coordinates and rotational
                   elements of the planets and satellites: 2000, Celestial Mechanics and Dynamical
                   Astronomy, 82, 83-111, 2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SEIDELMANNETAL2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>ODY-M-GRS-5-AHD-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 5 AHD V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2004-07-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2002-02-19T00:00:00.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>WILLIAM BOYNTON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Boynton, W.V., Mars 2001 Odyssey Gamma Ray Spectrometer Averaged
            High Energy Neutron Detector Data V1.0, ODY-M-GRS-5-AHD-V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Mars Odyssey Gamma Ray Spectrometer (GRS) Averaged High
            Energy Neutron Detector Data (AHD) archive contains temporally
            and spatially binned neutron counting rates and fluxes generated
            from Derived HEND Data (DHD).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Odyssey Gamma Ray Spectrometer (GRS) Averaged HEND Data (AHD)
            products are temporally and spatially binned neutron counting
            rates and fluxes that can be used to create global maps. These
            products are generated from the Derived HEND Data (DHD) product,
            which in turn are derived from HEND EDRs.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The Mars Odyssey Gamma-Ray Spectrometer (GRS) is a suite of
    three instruments working together to collect data that will
    permit the mapping of elemental concentrations on the surface of
    Mars. The suite of three instruments, the gamma-ray sensor head
    (GS), the Los Alamos National Laboratory (LANL) neutron
    spectrometer (NS) and the Russian Academy of Science Institute
    for Space Research (IKI) high-energy neutron detector (HEND),
    are a complementary set of instruments in that the neutron
    instruments have better counting statistics and sample to a
    greater depth than the GS, but the GS determines the abundance
    of many more elements. A full description of the Mars
    Odyssey Gamma-Ray Spectrometer instrument can be found in
    [BOYNTONETAL2004].
 
    The ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 5 AHD (AHD) data set is a
    collection of data tables that contain an average counting rate
    and the associated engineering data for each of the five
    neutron signals obtained by HEND&apos;s four detectors that have
    been summed by signal over 5-degree by 5-degree latitude
    longitude cells on the surface of Mars over a time period of
    15-degrees of solar longitude (Ls). The five neutron signals of
    interest are the:
 
       Small Detector,  SD,  energy range 0.4 eV to 1 keV;
       Medium Detector, MD,  energy range 10 eV to 100 keV;
       Large Detector,  LD,  energy range 10 eV to 1 MeV;
       Inner Scintillator, IN_SC_LOW,
                             neutron pulse height 1 MeV to 2.5 MeV;
       Inner Scintillator, IN_SC_HIGH,
                             neutron pulse height &gt; 2.5 MeV;
 
    Each of the GRS HEND detectors collects a new spectrum (pixel
    or frame) approximately every 20 seconds, 360 times per orbit.
    Approximately 4200 spectra are expected to be received every
    day. The data (both science and engineering) are downloaded
    from the spacecraft by the Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) into
    the Telemetry Data System (TDS). The TDS sends data to a process
    that translates data packets and examines instrument health via
    messages. Data are output to a spooler that passes it to both
    the University of Arizona (UA) database ingest process and to
    IKI. The UA ingest process inputs raw data into the UA database.
    IKI maintains a separate database that is used to process the
    derived neutron data set that is the basis for the averaged
    neutron data set. HEND data are processed by IKI through a
    number of processes to yield  background subtracted counts for
    the five neutron signals obtained by HEND&apos;s four detectors. The
    background subtracted counts are used in the computation of
    average normalized count rates and subsequently orbital
    epithermal and fast neutron fluxes for 5x5 degree latitude
    longitude grids over a time interval of 15 degrees of Ls.
 
    The AHD is intended to be the second intermediate data product
    available for the HEND portion of the GRS. These data should
    be useful to those scientists who are experienced in neutron
    spectroscopy.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The AHD data set is composed of a single data type (AHD). The
    objective of compiling the AHD is to create a table of HEND
    data table with average normalized counting rates and neutron
    fluxes for the five HEND neutron signals in an easily mappable
    form. Each AHD product data file will contain a 2592-row table.
    The table will contain 1 data record (row) for each of the
    5x5 degree latitude longitude cells. The data files will be
    grouped by time, so that for each 15 degrees of Ls there will
    be one data directory.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    A full description of the HEND data processing can be found in
    the Mars Odyssey Gamma-ray Spectrometer HEND Data Processing
    document located in the document folder that accompanies this
    release. The following paragraphs are a summary of how the data
    are processed from data receipt through averaging, items in all
    capitols are references to data column names.
 
    GRS HEND data are downloaded from the Mars Odyssey spacecraft
    by JPL into the Telemetry Data System (TDS). The TDS sends the
    data to a process called GRS_tl that translates GRS packets
    from any source to any destination and examines instrument
    health via messages. The data are checked for packet types,
    header information, messages, errors, engineering and
    channelized data values and are output to a spooler and to a
    data display IDL program called GRS Displays. Data sent to the
    spooler are passed to the UA database ingestion process, which
    inputs raw data into the UA database. Data sent to the GRS
    Displays program are recorded at IKI and held in a data
    repository.  All additional steps of HEND data processing are
    done at IKI.
 
    All data packets received by the GRS Displays program are
    processed for timing and spatial information. Once time data
    are extracted from the data packet, UTC time is calculated from
    the spacecraft event time (sc_ev_time, time at the middle of
    the collection interval in 256th seconds) by a SPICE function.
    The UTC time is then inserted into the database. The spatial
    portion of the data packet is calculated using other SPICE
    routines. The returned values are all the spatial elements of
    an observation, including latitude and longitude at the
    mid-point of the observation. Once raw HEND data, with
    associated timing, spatial and engineering data is entered into
    the database, a series of processing steps are started to
    correct, normalize and average data.
 
    The HEND instrument collects five neutron signals from four
    independent detectors whose response functions are sensitive to
    different energy regions. Raw neutron counts are reported in
    the HEND portion of the EDR data set as a 16-channel spectra
    for each of the four detectors (SD_SPECTRUM, MD_SPECTRUM,
    LD_SPECTRUM,NEUTRON_SPECTRUM). In the DHD data set, raw neutron
    counts are reported as the sums of channels 1-16 in the SD
    (Small Detector), MD (Medium Detector), and LD (Large Detector).
    The inner scintillator records two neutron signals, LOW (sum of
    channels 1 -4 in the inner scintillator) and HIGH (sum of
    channels 5-15 in the inner scintillator). The raw neutron
    counts for the LOW and HIGH signals are reported in the DHD as
    the sum of channels 1-4 and 5-15 respectively, of the
    NEUTRON_SPECTRA field of the HEND portion of the EDR data set.
 
    A background term that is  a combination of the galactic
    cosmic-ray flux induced spacecraft background and a spacecraft
    orbital geometry term, which accounts for shadowing by the
    planet of the galactic cosmic-ray flux, is accounted for in the
    derived HEND data (see the DHD data set description) yielding
    background subtracted counts for each HEND neutron signal.
 
    Background subtracted count values for each of the five neutron
    signals (SD, MD, LD, LOW, HIGH) are temporally and spatially
    binned to compare seasonal changes in the neutron flux. The
    temporal binning is 15-degrees of LS and the spatial binning is
    a grid of 5-degrees latitude by 5-degrees longitude. Membership
    in a temporal bin is determined by calculating the fraction of
    the collection interval time spent in each temporal cell.
    Membership in a spatial bin is determined by calculating the
    fraction of the collection interval length in a given spatial
    cell along the orbital trajectory projection on the Martian
    surface. The temporally and spatially binned counts for
    each of the five signals (SD, MD, LD, LOW, HIGH) are calculated
    by: 1) multiplying the background subtracted counts by the
    collection interval faction and summing the result for each
    collection interval within the 15-degree LS interval
    2) multiplying the duration (in seconds) of each collection
    interval by the collection interval faction and summing the
    result for each collection interval within the 15-degree LS
    interval 3) dividing the summed counts by the summed time to
    yield a counting rate in units of counts per second. The summed
    time is the EXPOSURE.
 
    The averaged counting rates are then normalized by the average
    counting rate from the Solis Planum region of Mars defined as
    245E to 295E and 15S to 55S. The normalization values for each
    signal are the SD_NORMALIZATION, MD_NORMALIZATION,
    LD_NORMALIZATION, IN_SC_HIGH_NORMALIZATION, and
    IN_SC_LOW_NORMALIZATION fields given in the AHD data set. The
    normalization calculation yields the SD_RATE,
    MD_RATE, LD_RATE, IN_SC_HIGH_RATE, and IN_SC_LOW_RATE fields,
    which can be used to create signal specific neutron maps.
    Because the rates are ratios of counting rates, they are
    unitless. Error fields, SD_ERR, MD_ERR, LD_ERR, IN_SC_HIGH_ERR,
    IN_SC_LOW_ERR are also present for each of the signals.  The
    errors are simply based on the counting statistics for the raw
    HEND counts.
 
    The conversion of normalized counting rates to neutron fluxes
    requires knowledge of the efficiency of each of the neutron
    detectors. Efficiency functions, derived from model
    calculations and direct calibrations, describe the directional
    and energy dependent response of each of the four HEND
    detectors, SD, MD, LD, and the inner scintillator, to
    bombardment by neutrons. A series of Monte-Carlo simulations
    were run to calculate the efficiency of each HEND detector. The
    simulations accounted for the composition and geometry of the
    HEND instrument. In parallel, a series of experimental
    calibration measurements were carried out to understand the
    quality of the Monte-Carlo simulations. Two types of
    experiments were performed. The first experiment measured the
    HEND response to monoenergetic neutron sources with known
    spectra and the second measured the HEND response to energetic
    neutron fluxes. The combined results of the numerical
    simulations and the experiments yield detector specific
    efficiency functions.
 
    As a further analysis of the data, calculations have been made
    with MCNPX for various models of Mars. The neutron flux at the
    spacecraft predicted by these calculations was fitted with a
    power law, AE^-alpha. The power law spectrum is then multiplied
    by the five efficiency functions to obtain computed counting
    rates in the HEND detectors.  These computed counting rates are
    compared to the real counting rates in via a Pearson minimizing
    procedure. The values, A and alpha, for the model that best
    satisfy the minimization criterion, are inserted into AHD as
    NEUTRON_NORMALIZATION and ALPHA fields.
 
    The NEUTRON_NORMALIZATION and ALPHA values are used to estimate
    the neutron flux (n/(cm^2-s)) at the Odyssey orbit in different
    ranges of epithermal and fast neutrons (EPITHERMAL_FLUX1
    100 eV - 10 KeV, EPITHERMAL_FLUX2 10 KeV - 1 MeV, FAST_FLUX1
    1 MeV - 2.5MeV, and FAST_FLUX_2 2.5 MeV - 10 MeV) for each
    5-degree by 5-degree map grid by taking the integral of the
    neutron spectrum as described by A and alpha over the energy
    interval. See Equation 9 in the HEND Processing document located
    in the Documents directory that accompanies this release for
    further details.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The AHD data set is composed of a series of data tables labeled
    with Mars year, starting Ls and ending Ls. Each file contains one
    data table with 2592 rows of data, corresponding to the 2592
    5-degree latitude longitude bins on the planet.
 
 
    Averaged HEND Data
    -------------
      Averaged HEND Data products are composed of averaged
      normalized counting rates, orbital neutron fluxes and the
      associated timing, spatial and engineering information. The
      AHDs consists of the cumulative background subtracted and
      normalized counts of neutrons at the four HEND detectors
      averaged over the 5x5 degree latitude longitude, 15-degree Ls.
      Please refer to the HEND processing document located in the
      documents directory that accompanies this release for a full
      description of how HEND spectra are processed to yield
      averaged normalized counting rates and orbital neutron fluxes.
      The timing and spatial data provided with each AHD record
      include the time and spatial range over which the average was
      generated.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    Ancillary data needed to understand the HEND data processing
    can be found in the Mars Odyssey Gamma-ray Spectrometer HEND
    Data Processing document located in the document folder that
    accompanies this release.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    The coordinate system used for all GRS data is a Mars
    areocentric system following the IAU convention
    [SEIDELMANNETAL2002], with east longitudes from 0 to 360.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    A library of source code to parse the AHD data product files
    is included in the software directory. This library allows a
    programmer to build applications that display or manipulate
    AHD data. This source is written in the Java language, and
    requires version 1.3 of the Java Runtime Environment (JRE) or
    Java Software Development Kit (SDK).
 
    Documentation for the code is located in the software directory
    in the file GRS_CODE_DOC.ZIP. The contents of this file are
    described in the label GRS_CODE_DOC.LBL.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    The AHD will be delivered electronically. Formats will be
    based on standards established by the Planetary Data
    System (PDS) [PDSSR2001].
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The data presented in the AHD are intended to be the second
    intermediate data set released for the HEND portion of the GRS.
    Data presented here are a highly processed and re-binned
    representation of the GRS HEND data. It is possible that
    changes will be made in the processing procedures that the AHD
    products are based on if errors are found. If errors are found,
    the data will have to be regenerated from the corrected data
    set.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    The AHD was reviewed internally by the GRS team prior to
    release to the PDS. PDS will also perform an external review of
    the AHD.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    Except for background estimates, data reported are the
    processed and re binned HEND data received from the spacecraft
    during the mapping mission stage. Data coverage and quality are
    addressed in the following sections.
 
 
    Primary Mapping
    ---------------
    The mapping portion of the mission began February 19, 2002, and
    is expected to last until August, 2004. Primary mapping is
    broken into two phases: stowed mapping and deployed mapping.
 
 
    Stowed Mapping
    --------------
      The stowed mapping configuration began on February 19, 2002
      and lasted until June 1, 2002. The stowed mapping
      configuration is with the Odyssey spacecraft in a mapping
      orbit, with the GRS in data collection configuration without
      the 6-meter boom deployed. The reason for data collection in
      the stowed configuration is to measure the gamma background
      signal from the spacecraft. HEND data collection was not
      affected. On June 1, 2002 the GRS was shutdown to prepare
      for boom deployment, which occurred on June 4, 2002. No data
      were collected during this time period.
 
      There are short periods of missing data due to missing
      telemetry that cannot be recovered.
 
 
    Deployed Mapping
    ----------------
      Deployed Mapping began on June 5, 2002 and is expected to
      continue until at least August, 2004.
 
      A number of solar particle events, and solar flare events
      have been recorded. HEND data collected during these times,
      as indicated by the SUN_ACTIVITY field in the DHD data
      product being greater than 1, are suspect. These data have
      not been included in the AHD data product.
 
      There are short data gaps due to missing telemetry that
      cannot be recovered.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    The major limitation of this data set is that it is derived from
    the raw minimally processed HEND data. The data are received
    from spacecraft telemetry, and ingested into a database. If gaps
    exist in the telemetry, data are lost. Timing and spatial
    components of the data set rely on the accuracy of the NAIF SPICE
    kernels. The validity of the derived HEND counts is based
    on the &apos;correctness&apos; of each step in the processing. It is
    possible that changes will be made in the processing procedures
    if errors are found. If errors are found, the data will
    have to be regenerated from the raw unprocessed data set.
 
 
  Data Compression
  ===============
    No compression is used on the AHD data set.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

