<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dawn-a-fc2-5-mosaic-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DAWN FC2 DERIVED VESTA GLOBAL MOSAICS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.dawn_mission_to_vesta_and_ceres::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:fc2.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.4_vesta::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dawn-a-fc2-5-mosaic-v1.0__browserp_dawn-a-fc2-5-mosaic-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   IAU-WGCCRE-Coordinate-System-for-Vesta,
                   http://astrogeology.usgs.gov/search/details/Docs/WGCCRE/
                   IAU-WGCCRE-Coordinate-System-for-Vesta/pdf
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ARCHINAL2013</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Jaumann, R., D.A. Williams, D.L. Buczkowski, R.A. Yingst, F. Presuker, H.
                   Hiesinger, N. Schmedemann, T. Kneissl, and 35 others, Vesta&apos;s shape and
                   morphology. Science, 336, p687-690, 2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JAUMANNETAL2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Preusker, F., F. Scholten, K.-D. Matz, T. Roatsch, R. Jaumann, S.P. Joy, M.D.
                   Raymon, C.A. Raymond, and C.T. Russell, Stereo-photogrammetrically derived
                   topography of asteroid (4) Vesta.,AGU Fall meeting,abstract 2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PREUSKERETAL2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Roatsch, T., E. Kersten, K.-D. Matz, F. Preusker, F. Scholten, R. Jaumann, C.A.
                   Raymond, and C.T. Russell, High Resolution Vesta High Altitude Mapping Orbit
                   Atlas derived from Dawn Framing Camera images, Planetary and Space Sciences 73,
                   p283-286, 2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ROATSCHETAL2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Roatsch, T., E. Kersten, K.-D. Matz, F. Preusker, F. Scholten, S. Elgner, R.
                   Jaumann, C.A. Raymond, and C.T. Russell, High-resolution Vesta Low Altitude
                   Mapping Orbit Atlas derived from Dawn Framing Camera images, Planetary and
                   Space Science 85, p293-298, 2013.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ROATSCHETAL2013</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Schroeder, S.E., T. Maue, P. Gutierrez-Marques, S. Mottola, K.M. Aye, H.
                   Sierks, H.U. Keller, and A. Nathues, In-fight Calibration of the Dawn Framing
                   Camera. Icarus 226, p1304-1317, 2013.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SCHROEDERETAL2013A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Schroeder, S.E., S. Mottola, H.U. Keller, C.A. Raymond, and C.T. Russell,
                   Resolved photometry of Vesta reveals physical properties of crater regolith,
                   Planetary and Space Sciences, 85, 198-213, 2013.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SCHROEDERETAL2013B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Schroeder, S.E., S. Mottola, K.-D. Matz, and T. Roatsch, In-flight calibration
                   of the Dawn Framing Camera II: Flat fields and stray light correction, Icarus,
                   234, 99-108, 2014.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SCHROEDERETAL2014</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Sierks, H., P. Lamy, C. Barbieri, D. Koschny, H. Rickman, R. Rodrigo, M.F.
                   A&apos;Hearn, F. Angrilli, M.A. Barucci, J.-L. Bertaux, I. Bertini, S. Besse, B.
                   Carry, G. Cremonese, V. Da Deppo, B. Davidsson, S. Debei, M. De Cecco, J. De
                   Leon, F. Ferri, S. Fornasier, M. Fulle, S.F. Hviid, R.W. Gaskell, O. Groussin,
                   P. Gutierrez, W. Ip, L. Jorda, M. Kaasalainen, H.U. Keller, J. Knollenberg, R.
                   Kramm, E. Kuhrt, M. Kuppers, L. Lara, M. Lazzarin, C. Leyrat, J.J. Lopez
                   Moreno, S. Magrin, S. Marchi, F. Marzari, M. Massironi, H. Michalik, R. Moissl,
                   G. Naletto, F. Preusker, L. Sabau, W. Sabolo, F. Scholten, C. Snodgrass, N.
                   Thomas, C. Tubiana, P. Vernazza, J.-B. Vincent, K.-P. Wenzel, T. Andert, M.
                   Patzold, and B.P. Weiss, Images of Asteroid 21 Lutetia: A Remnant Planetesimal
                   from the Early Solar System, Science 334, pp. 487-490, 2011,
                   doi:10.1126/science.1207325.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SIERKSETAL2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Xu, S., R.P. Binzel, T.H. Burbine, and S.J. Bus, Small Main-belt Asteroid
                   Spectroscopic Survey: Initial results, Icarus, 115, 1-35, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.XUETAL1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DAWN-A-FC2-5-MOSAIC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DAWN FC2 DERIVED VESTA GLOBAL MOSAICS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2015-02-13</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2011-09-29T23:11Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2012-07-24T15:02Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>THOMAS ROATSCH</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Roatsch,T., E. Kersten,K.-D. Matz,F. Preusker, F. Scholten,
            S.Elgner, S.E. Schroeder, R. Jaumann, C.A. Raymond, C.T.Russell,
            DAWN FC2 DERIVED VESTA GLOBAL MOSAICS V1.0,
            DAWN-A-FC2-5-MOSAIC-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2015.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Dawn Framing Camera 2 Vesta global mosaics derived from HAMO and
            LAMO altitude encounter phases.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== This data set includes various Vesta global
            mosaics derived from images acquired by the Framing Camera 2
            (FC2) on the NASA Dawn spacecraft at the high and low altitude
            mapping orbits (HAMO and LAMO). Data are provided in cylindrical
            and polar stereographic projections. In addition to the mosaics,
            the flatfield and stray light used during the processing of the
            raw images are provided.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Dataset overview
    ================
      This data set includes various Vesta global mosaics derived from images
      acquired by the Framing Camera 2 (FC2) on the NASA Dawn spacecraft at
      the high and low altitude mapping orbits (HAMO and LAMO). Data are
      provided in cylindrical and polar stereographic projections. In addition
      to the mosaics, the flatfield and stray light correction images used
      during the processing of the raw images are provided.
 
      Dawn mission is equipped with two identical framing cameras (FC1 &amp; FC2)
      [SIERKSETAL2011] which have one clear filter and seven band pass
      filters. At Vesta, only the FC2 was used to acquire science images while
      the FC1 was held in reserve. Clear filter images which were taken during
      HAMO were used to produce a global mosaic of the illuminated part of
      Vesta with a resolution of ~60m/pixel [ROATSCHETAL2012]. Dawn orbited
      Vesta during in 6 cycles between the end of September and early
      November 2011 (HAMO-1) and another 6 cycles between late June and the
      end of July in 2012 (HAMO-2). A cycle is a single complete mapping of
      surface at a fixed off-nadir attitude. The framing camera took about
      2500 clear filter images with a resolution of about 60 m/pixel during
      each of these mapping phases. The images were taken with different
      viewing angles and illumination conditions in order to provide input to
      the stereo-photogrametric [PREUSKERETAL2012] and stereo-photoclinometric
      analyses of the Vesta topography. Images from one cycle (HAMO-1,
      cycle #3; HAMO-2, cycle 6) were selected for the  mosaicking
      process to have similar viewing and illumination conditions.
      HAMO-1, cycle #3 with 518 images and HAMO-2, cycle 3 with 440 images
      were selected since each was the first cycle with nearly complete global
      coverage. Very minor gaps in the coverage were filled with three images
      from HAMO-1, cycle #4.  HAMO-1 occurred during the northern winter and
      HAMO-2 occurred during the northern spring so the southern hemisphere
      was mosaicked using HAMO-1 images and the northern hemisphere used
      images acquired during HAMO-2.
 
      Full color imaging (clear plus seven band pass filters) was performed
      twice during HAMO-1 (cycles 1 and 6) with body-center pointing. These
      images were used to produce the southern hemisphere portions of the
      various color and color ratio mosaics included with this data set.
      Since most of the surface of Vesta south of 30 degrees north was already
      imaged in full color during HAMO-1, color images were only acquired
      during the final cycle of HAMO-2 (cycle 6) when the northern hemisphere
      had its maximum illumination. Even still, the illumination was poor at
      the highest latitudes. Color images from HAMO-2, cycle 6 were used to
      create the northern hemisphere color image mosaics.
 
      Imaging in LAMO was challenging for several reasons: large gravity
      gradient influences on the spacecraft trajectory, and low downlink
      bandwidth for image return. The FC2 acquired about 10,000 clear filter
      images in LAMO allowing the creation of a global mosaic
      of Vesta with a resolution of 20m/pixel. This LAMO atlas is a
      higher-resolution supplementary atlas to the HAMO atlas
      [ROATSCHETAL2012]. The LAMO mission phase occurred during Northern
      winter which kept the north pole region in darkness; only 84% of the
      surface was illuminated and good illumination(incidence angle less
      than 70 deg) was only available for 66.8% of the surface
      [ROATSCHETAL2013].
 
      For more information on the contents and organization of the volume
      set refer to the aareadme.txt file located in the root directory of
      the data volumes.  A description of the map projections used in this
      data sets is provided in the dsmap.cat file in the catalog directory
      of this archive volume.
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The image data returned from the spacecraft are distributed
      inside the Dawn team in PDS (Planetary Data System) format
      [http://pds.nasa.gov]. The first step of the image processing
      pipeline is the conversion to VICAR (Video Image Communication
      and Retrieval) format [http://rushmore.jpl.nasa.gov/vicar.html]
      followed by the radiometric calibration of the images.
 
      The next step of the processing chain deals with the orthorectification
      of the images into a cartographic map projection at a
      specified scale. This process requires detailed information with
      regard to Vesta&apos;s global shape. Vesta is best described by a global
      digital terrain model as derived from FC images by [PREUSKERETAL2012]
      and [JAUMANNETAL2012]. However, to facilitate comparison and
      interpretation of the maps, the DTM was used only for
      the calculation of the surface intersection points of the line of
      sight vectors, while the map projection itself was done onto a
      sphere with the mean radius (255 km). The Dawn orbit and
      attitude data used for the calculation of the surface intersection
      points are provided as SPICE kernels [http://naif.jpl.nasa.gov] and
      were improved using a bundle-adjustment technique [PREUSKERETAL2012].
      A cylindrical equidistant map projection was chosen for the global
      mosaic. The coordinate system adopted by the Dawn mission for satellite
      mapping is the IAU &apos;planetographic&apos; system, consisting of
      planetographic latitude and positive east longitude [ARCHINAL2013]. But
      because a spherical reference surface is used for map projections of the
      satellites, planetographic and planetocentric latitudes are numerically
      equal. In addition, stereographic projections of the HAMO and LAMO data
      are provided for both hemispheres (0-90 deg). The stereographic
      projections reduce the distortion that is clear in the higher latitude
      regions of the cylindrical projection. The longitude system of Vesta is
      defined by the tiny crater Claudia which is located at 206 degrees east
      (Claudia double-prime coordinates). Mosaicking of the single images was
      the final step of the image processing.
 
      For more detailed information on the image calibration process,
      please refer to [SCHROEDERETAL2013A],[SCHROEDERETAL2013B] and
      [SCHROEDERETAL2014].
 
      All of the various products described below use the same projections.
      The cylindrical projection covers +/- 90 degrees of latitude and
      is centered at 30 degrees Claudia double-prime longitude. The minimum
      and maximum longitudes are -150 and +210 degrees. The northern
      hemisphere stereographic projection has 90 degrees north latitude at the
      center and the equator at the edge. The top of projection is 30 degrees
      Claudia double-prime longitude and the bottom is 210 degrees with
      longitude increasing to the east. The southern hemisphere projection
      has 90 degrees south latitude at the center and the equator at the edge,
      -150 degrees longitude at the top and 30 degrees longitude at the
      bottom. For a description of the coordinate system, please refer to
      vesta_coordinates_131018 document contained on this archive volume at
      the PDS and [ARCHINAL2013].
 
    Data Products
    =============
      HAMO Clementine Color Ratio Mosaics (located at DATA/LAMO_CLEM)
      -----------------------------------
      Spectral differences of surface materials are often mapped by using the
      ratios of various spectral bands to bring out diagnostic spectral
      features. In this data set we include a global cylindrical projection
      plus northern and southern hemisphere stereographic projections of
      of the three color ratios as three bands in the image. The bands are
      created from the quotients of photometrically corrected color images
      where:
 
      red   = filter # 3 / filter # 8
      green = filter # 3 / filter # 4
      blue  = filter # 8 / filter # 3
 
      filter # 3: 749 nm
      filter # 4: 917 nm
      filter # 8: 438 nm
 
      conversion from real to byte:
 
      red   : input range 1.106 - 1.337 -&gt; output range 1 - 255
      green : input range 1.018 - 2.036 -&gt; output range 1 - 255
      blue  : input range 0.769 - 0.905 -&gt; output range 1 - 255
 
      map_scale = 60 m/pixel
 
      Calibration, stray light correction, and photometric correction
      as described by [SCHROEDERETAL2013A] and [SCHROEDERETAL2014].
 
      HAMO Color Mosaics (located at DATA/LAMO_COLOR)
      ------------------
      Photometrically and stray light corrected color images from each of the
      seven band pass filters are mosaicked. The first number in file name is
      filter number. The map_scale = 60 m/pixel.
 
      Calibration, stray light correction, and photometric correction
      as described by [SCHROEDERETAL2013A] and [SCHROEDERETAL2014].
 
      HAMO Mosaic (located at DATA/HAMO_CLEAR)
      -----------
      Clear filter mosaic with a map scale of 60 m/pixel.
      Calibration, stray light correction, and photometric correction
      as described by [SCHROEDERETAL2013A] and [SCHROEDERETAL2014].
 
      LAMO Mosaic (located at DATA/LAMO_CLEAR)
      -----------
      Clear filter mosaic with a map scale of 20 m/pixel.
      Calibration and photometric correction as described by
      [SCHROEDERETAL2013A]and [SCHROEDERETAL2014].
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Stray light correction
    ======================
    The stray light correction applied to these data [SCHROEDERETAL2014] is a
    linear interpolation of the observed pattern which is a simplification
    of the true effect. However, the existing data do not support more complex
    interpolation schemes at this time.
 
    Data Coverage
    =============
    None of the mosaics provide complete surface coverage of Vesta. During
    HAMO, some images were lost creating the small gaps in the mid and low
    latitude regions. The extreme south pole was missed as a result of
    under-sampling and extreme topographic effect and the high northern
    latitudes were never fully illuminated. All in all, better than 90%
    of the Vesta was imaged at 60m/pixel in the HAMO mission phases.
 
    Clear filter coverage in LAMO is limited to latitudes south of
    60 degrees north. In addition, there are a few bands where
    images were never acquired. The LAMO orbit was optimized for
    gravitational stability rather than imaging coverage. Since there
    are only nadir images acquired during LAMO, it was not possible
    to create a LAMO resolution DTM. LAMO data were projected on to a
    HAMO resolution DTM for photometric correction which reduces the
    quality of the correction applied.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

