<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.nh-x-lorri-3-launch-v1.1</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>NEW HORIZONS LORRI POST-LAUNCH CHECKOUT V1.1</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.new_horizons::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.nh::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:lorri.nh::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.nh-x-lorri-3-launch-v1.1__browserp_nh-x-lorri-3-launch-v1.1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>NH-X-LORRI-3-LAUNCH-V1.1</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>NEW HORIZONS LORRI POST-LAUNCH CHECKOUT V1.1</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2009-03-04</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2006-01-19T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2007-01-01T00:00:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JOSEPH PETERSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Cheng, A., NEW HORIZONS LORRI POST-LAUNCH CHECKOUT V1.1,
            NH-X-LORRI-3-LAUNCH-V1.1, NASA Planetary Data System, 2007.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Calibrated data taken by New Horizons Long Range Reconnaissance
            Imager instrument during the LAUNCH mission phase.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains Calibrated data taken by the New Horizons
            Long Range Reconnaissance Imager instrument during the
            post-launch checkout mission phase.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
 
      This data set contains Calibrated data taken by New Horizons
        Long Range Reconnaissance Imager
      instrument during the LAUNCH mission phase.
 
      During the Launch Phase, LORRI conducted a variety of instrument
      commissioning activities in preparation for science operations.
      An extensive series of bias images was collected during the
      spring and summer of 2006, before the LORRI aperture door was
      opened. Images were also collected of LORRI&apos;s internal lamps.
      The LLORRI aperture door was opened on 2006 August 29, and an
      extensive series of calibration observations of stars in the
      open cluster M7 was performed during the next several days.
      Commissioning test observations were also performed on the
      planetary targets Jupiter, Uranus, Neptune, and Pluto. The
      Jovian observations were conducted specifically to test LORRI&apos;s
      ability to perform imaging using exposure times that were short
      compared to the frame transfer time (i.e., shorter than 13 ms).
      Some solar scattered light observations were performed during a
      Ralph commissioning test, but only histograms (APID=0x611) were
      collected, not the images themselves.
 
 
      Every observation provided in this data set was taken as a part of a
      particular sequence.  A list of these sequences follows:
 
      Sequence IDs &amp; start times (end times are the start times
      of the following Sequence IDs) for the LORRI instrument
      during the LAUNCH phase of the New Horizons Mission
      =========================================================
 
      Sequence ID:  COLO_LORRI-005
      Start UTC:    2006-02-24T00:00:00
      Start SCLK:   1/0003045117:33729
      Description:  24 Feb 2006: all currents, voltages, power, and
                    temperatures nominal
 
      Sequence ID:  COLO_LORRI-025
      Start UTC:    2006-04-23T00:00:00
      Start SCLK:   1/0008056317:32411
      Description:  23-24 April and 2-3 May 2006: in-flight noise test
 
      Sequence ID:  COLO_LORRI-006
      Start UTC:    2006-07-30T00:00:00
      Start SCLK:   1/0016523517:31575
      Description:  30 Jul 2006: Dark series bias images, cover door closed
 
      Sequence ID:  COLO_LORRI-007
      Start UTC:    2006-08-29T00:00:00
      Start SCLK:   1/0019115517:31416
      Description:  29 Aug 2006: Door opening verification images (Messier
                    7)
 
      Sequence ID:  COLO_LORRI-010/COLO_LORRI-018
      Start UTC:    2006-08-31T00:00:00
      Start SCLK:   1/0019288317:31406
      Description:  31 Aug 2006: Radiometric/PSF images (Messier 7) MVIC
                    co-alignment images
 
      Sequence ID:  COLO_LORRI-027
      Start UTC:    2006-09-04T00:00:00
      Start SCLK:   1/0019633917:31388
      Description:  04 Sep 2006: Jupiter exposure/auto exposure/scattered
                    light tests
 
      Sequence ID:  COLO_LORRI-029/COLO_LORRI-030
      Start UTC:    2006-09-10T00:00:00
      Start SCLK:   1/0020152317:31360
      Description:  10,19 Sep 2006: Uranus/Neptune
 
      Sequence ID:  COLO_LORRI-023a
      Start UTC:    2006-09-21T00:00:00
      Start SCLK:   1/0021102717:31311
      Description:  21, 24 Sep 2006: Pluto
 
      For the list of observations and their parameters, refer to
      the data set index table (typically INDEX.TAB &amp; CUMINDEX.TAB,
      initially in the /INDEX/ area of the data set).
 
 
    Time
    ====
 
      There are several time systems, or units, in use in this dataset:
      New Horizons spacecraft MET (Mission Event Time or Mission Elapsed
      Time), UTC (Coordinated Universal Time), and TDB Barycentric
      Dynamical Time.
 
      This section will give a summary description of the relationship
      between these time systems.  For a complete explanation of these
      time systems the reader is referred to the documentation
      distributed with the NAIF/SPICE toolkit from the NAIF PDS node.
 
      The most common time unit associated with the data is is the
      spacecraft MET.  MET is a 32-bit counter on the New Horizons
      spacecraft that runs at a rate of about one increment per second
      starting from a value of zero at
 
        19.January, 2006 18:08:02 UTC
 
      or
 
        JD2453755.256337 TDB.
 
      The leapsecond adjustment (DELTA_ET = ET - UTC) over this dataset
      is 65.184s.
 
      The data labels for any given product in this dataset usually
      contain at least one pair of common UTC and MET representations
      of the time at the middle of the observation.  Other portions
      of the products, for example tables of data taken over periods
      of up to a day or more, will only have the MET time associated
      with a given row of the table.
 
      For the data user&apos;s use in interpreting these times, a reasonable
      approximation (+/- 1s) of the conversion between Julian Day (TDB)
      and MET is as follows:
 
        JD TDB = 2453755.256337 + ( MET / 86399.9998693 )
 
      For more accurate calculations the reader is referred to the
      NAIF/SPICE documentation as mentioned above.
 
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      The data in this data set were created by a software data
      processing pipeline on the Science Operation Center (SOC) at
      the Southwest Research Institute (SWRI), Department of Space Studies.
      This SOC pipeline assembled data as FITS files from raw telemetry
      packets sent down by the spacecraft and populated the data labels
      with housekeeping and engineering values, and computed geometry
      parameters using SPICE kernels. The pipeline did not resample
      the data.
 
 
    Calibration
    ===========
 
 
      Detailed information about calibration of LORRI images is available
      in the SOC Instrument Interface Control Document (ICD) in the
      DOCUMENT section of this data set.  The LORRI calibration will only
      be briefly summarized here.
 
      The calibration of LORRI images involves all of the following steps
      in order:
 
      1)  Bias subtraction
      2)  Signal linearization
      3)  Charge transfer inefficiency (CTI) correction
      4)  Dark subtraction
      5)  Smear removal
      6)  Flat-fielding
      7)  Absolute calibration (conversion to radiance units)
 
      Ground testing has demonstrated that the linearization, CTI and
      dark subtraction steps are not necessary i.e. the output from the
      Bias subtraction step may be passed directly to Smear removal step.
 
      Ongoing in-flight calibration observations will be analyzed to
      assess the long term stability of the calibration, including whether
      the currently unused steps may need to be implemented in the future.
 
 
    Data
    ====
 
      The observations in this data set are stored in data files using
      standard Flexible Image Transport Sytem (FITS) format.  Each FITS
      file has a corresponding detached PDS label file, named according
      to a common convention.  The FITS files have image and/or table
      extensions; see the PDS label plus the DOCUMENT files for a
      description of these extensions and their contents.
 
 
      This Data section comprises the following sub-topics:
 
      - Filename/Product IDs
      - Other sources of information useful in interpreting these Data
      - CODMAC Level 3 LORRI data details
      - Instrument description
      - Visit Description, Visit Number, and Target in the Data Labels
      - Unresolved Liens on the Data
 
 
      Filename/Product IDs
      --------------------
 
        The filenames and product IDs of observations adhere to a
        common convention e.g.
 
         ALI_0123456789_0X0AB_ENG_1.FIT
         ^^^ ^^^^^^^^^^ ^^^^^ ^^^ ^\__/
         |        |       |    |  | ^^
         |        |       |    |  |  |
         |        |       |    |  |  +--File type (includes dot)
         |        |       |    |  |     - .FIT for FITS file
         |        |       |    |  |     - .LBL for PDS label
         |        |       |    |  |     - not part of product ID
         |        |       |    |  |
         |        |       |    |  +-- Version number from the SOC
         |        |       |    |      (Science Operations Center)
         |        |       |    |
         |        |       |    +--ENG for CODMAC Level 2 data *
         |        |       |       SCI for CODMAC Level 3 data *
         |        |       |
         |        |       +--Application ID (ApID) of the telemetry data
         |        |          packet from which the data come
         |        |
         |        +--MET (Mission Event Time) i.e. Spacecraft Clock
         |
         +--Instrument designator
 
          * For those datasets where the NH project is delivering
            CODMAC Level 1 &amp; 2 data (REX &amp; PEPSSI), ENG and SCI apply
            to CODMAC Level 1 &amp; 2 data, respectively.
 
 
        Instrument   Instrument designators              ApIDs
        ===========  ==================================  =============
         LORRI        LOR                                0X630 - 0X634
 
         * Not all values in this range are used
 
         There are other ApIDs that contain housekeeping values and
         other values.  See the documentation for more details.
 
 
        Here is a summary of the types of files generated by each ApID
        along with the instrument designator that go with each ApID:
 
 
      ApIDs   Data product description/Prefix(es)
      =====   ===================================
      0x630 - LORRI High-res Lossless (CDH 1)/LOR
      0x636 - LORRI High-res Lossless (CDH 2)/LOR
      0x632 - LORRI High-res Lossy (CDH 1)/LOR
      0x638 - LORRI High-res Lossy (CDH 2)/LOR
      0x631 - LORRI High-res Packetized (CDH 1)/LOR
      0x637 - LORRI High-res Packetized (CDH 2)/LOR
      0x633 - LORRI 4x4 Binned Lossless (CDH 1)/LOR
      0x639 - LORRI 4x4 Binned Lossless (CDH 2)/LOR
      0x635 - LORRI 4x4 Binned Lossy (CDH 1)/LOR
      0x63B - LORRI 4x4 Binned Lossy (CDH 2)/LOR
      0x634 - LORRI 4x4 Binned Packetized (CDH 1)/LOR
      0x63A - LORRI 4x4 Binned Packetized (CDH 2)/LOR
 
 
      Other sources of information useful in interpreting these Data
      --------------------------------------------------------------
 
        Refer to the following files for more information about these data
 
          NH Trajectory table:
 
            /DOCUMENT/NH_TRAJECTORY.*
 
          LORRI Field Of View definitions:
 
             /DOCUMENT/NH_FOV.*
             /DOCUMENT/NH_LORRI_V###_TI.TXT
 
 
 
 
      Instrument description
      ----------------------
 
        Refer to the following files for a description of this instrument.
 
        CATALOG
 
          LORRI.CAT
 
        DOCUMENTS
 
          LORRI_SSR.*
          NH_LORRI_V###_TI.TXT  (### is a version number)
          SOC_INST_ICD.*
 
 
      Visit Description, Visit Number, and Target in the Data Labels
      ---------------------------------------------------------------
 
        The observation sequences were defined in Science Activity
        Planning (SAP) documents, and grouped by Visit Description and
        Visit Number.  The SAPs are spreadsheets with one Visit Description
        &amp; Number per row.  A nominal target is also included on each row
        and included in the data labels, but does not always match with the
        TARGET_NAME field&apos;s value in the data labels.  In some cases, the
        target was designated as RA,DEC pointing values in the form
        ``RADEC=123.45,-12.34&apos;&apos; indicating Right Ascension and Declination,
        in degrees, of the target from the spacecraft in the Earth
        Equatorial J2000 inertial reference frame.  This indicates either
        that the target was either a star, or that the target&apos;s ephemeris
        was not loaded into the spacecraft&apos;s attitude and control system
        which in turn meant the spacecraft could not be pointed at the
        target by a body identifier and an inertial pointing value had to
        be specified as Right Ascension and Declination values.  The PDS
        standards do not allow putting a value like RADEC=... in the PDS
        TARGET_NAME keyword&apos;s value; in those cases the PDS TARGET_NAME
        value is set to CALIBRATION.
 
 
      Unresolved Liens on the Data
      ----------------------------
 
        None exist at the present time.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
 
      The geometry items included in the data labels were computed
      using the SPICE kernels archived in the New Horizons SPICE
      data set, NH-X-SPICE-6-LAUNCH-V1.0.
 
 
    Reference Frame
    ===============
 
 
      Geometric Parameter Reference Frame
      -----------------------------------
        Earth Mean Equator and Vernal Equinox of J2000 (EMEJ2000) is the
        inertial reference frame used to specify observational geometry
        items provided in the data labels.  Geometric parameters are based
        on best available SPICE data at time of data creation.
 
 
      Epoch of Geometric Parameters
      -----------------------------
        All geometric parameters provided in the data labels were
        computed at the epoch midway between the START_TIME and
        STOP_TIME label fields.
 
 
 
    Software
    ========
 
      The observations in this data set are in standard FITS format
      with PDS labels, and can be viewed by a number of PDS-provided
      and commercial programs. For this reason no special software is
      provided with this data set.
 
 
    Contact Information
    ===================
 
      For any questions regarding the data format of the archive,
      contact the person whose PDS_USER_ID is ACHENG
      as described in PERSONNEL.CAT.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      During the processing of the data in preparation for
      delivery with this volume, the packet data associated with each
      observation were used only if they passed a rigorous verification
      process including standard checksums.
 
      In addition, raw (Level 2) observation data for which adequate
      contemporary housekeeping and other ancillary data are not available
      are not reduced to calibrated (Level 3) data.  This issue is raised
      here to explain why some data products in the raw data set,
 
        NH-X-LORRI-2-LAUNCH-V1.1,
 
      do not have corresponding data products in the calibrated data set,
 
        NH-X-LORRI-3-LAUNCH-V1.1.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      The data have been reviewed and validated by the instrument team
      members, as well as by SOC personnel.
 
 
 
 
     LORRI updates for Data Sets V1.1
     ================================
 
 
       Improvements to geometry &amp; timing in data header sections
       ---------------------------------------------------------
 
         The data pipeline re-ran the data with updated SPICE files; SPICE
         files contain information relating to geometry and timing of
         observations.  This may have changed values in the data PDS
         labels and the data files&apos; FITS header section (referred to as
         OBJECT *_HEADER in the PDS labels), but not the data in those files.
 
 
       Improvements to ancillary files
       -------------------------------
 
         Some of the supporting files, mainly in the /DOCUMENT/
         subdirectory hierarchy, have been updated for content
         and for readability.  The primary file for which this
         was done was the SOC Instrument Interface Control
         Document (often referred to as the SOC Instrument ICD).
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

