<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-h-rss-mla-5-sdp-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER MERCURY RSS/MLA LEVEL 5 DERIVED DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-rss-mla-5-sdp-v1.0__browserp_mess-h-rss-mla-5-sdp-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-rss-mla-5-sdp-v1.0__browser_mess-h-rss-mla-5-sdp-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-rss-mla-5-sdp-v1.0__dvo_geo_mess-h-rss-mla-5-sdp-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Smith, D.E., M.T. Zuber, R.J. Phillips, S.C. Solomon, S.A. Hauck, II, F.G.
                   Lemoine, E. Mazarico, G.A. Neumann, S.J. Peale, J.L. Margot, C.L. Johnson, M.H.
                   Torrence, M.E. Perry, D.D. Rowlands, S. Goossens, J.W. Head, and A.H. Taylor,
                   Gravity field and internal structure of Mercury from MESSENGER, Science, 336,
                   214-217, 2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SMITHETAL2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-H-RSS/MLA-5-SDP-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESSENGER MERCURY RSS/MLA LEVEL 5 DERIVED DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-05-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2008-007T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-120T11:13:55Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>MARK E. PERRY</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Perry, M.E., Lemoine, F.G., Smith, D.E., Zuber, M.T., Neumann, G.
            A., Solomon, S.C., MESSENGER Radio Science Reduced Data Record
            (MESS-H-RSS-5-SDP-V1.0), NASA Planetary Data System, 2016.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Derived radio science data products from the MESSENGER mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains archival results from radio science
            investigations conducted during the MESSENGER mission. Radio
            measurements were made using the MESSENGER spacecraft and
            Earth-based stations of the NASA Deep Space Network (DSN). The
            data set includes three products: 1) high-resolution spherical
            harmonic models of Mercury&apos;s gravity field. These results
            were derived from raw radio tracking data; 2) measurements of
            Mercury&apos;s radius at several locations around the planet.
            These radii are derived from radio occultations; and 3) spherical
            harmonic models of Mercury&apos;s surface shape. Both Mercury
            Laser Altimeter (MLA) data and occultation data were used to
            generate the shape models. The investigations were conducted by
            personnel at JHU/APL, GSFC, and JPL.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The MESSENGER Radio Science (RS) Reduced Data Archive (RDA) is
      a collection of derived data products created from raw data collected
      during the MESSENGER mission to Mercury. These products are generated
      from radio occultation, MLA, and gravity investigations conducted by
      members of the MESSENGER Radio Science Team.
 
      Gravity data and planet-shape products consist of spherical harmonic
      models. Personnel at the Goddard Space Flight Center (GSFC) produced
      spherical harmonic models. Occultation products include measurements of
      Mercury&apos;s radius produced at the Johns Hopkins University Applied
      Physics Laboratory (JHU/APL).
 
      The models are derived from both flyby data and orbit-phase data.
      MESSENGER&apos;s orbit is highly eccentric, with a periapsis altitude
      between 5 km and 450 km, and an apoapsis altitude initially near
      13,000 km. The apoapsis was reduced to 10,000 km in April 2012. The
      orbit inclination is 84-85 degrees with a periapsis northward of 60N,
      so the resolution of the gravity models varies with latitude, with the
      coarsest resolution near the south pole. MESSENGER&apos;s eccentric orbit
      also restricts MLA data to the northern hemisphere, and the shape
      models rely on occultation measurements of radius for the southern
      hemisphere. Since MLA measurements are more accurate and much more
      plentiful than occultations, the shape model is better constrained in
      the north. The uncertainty of the occultation measurements of radius
      depends primarily on the quality of the RF signal, which depends on the
      whether the low-gain or high-gain antenna was used. With the low-gain
      antennas, the spacecraft attitude, the Earth-spacecraft distance, and
      the quantity of solar plasma along the RF path are important. In some
      cases, alternate processing parameters or algorithms can reduce
      uncertainty. Currently, the measurements with the lowest uncertainty are
      the measurements from occultations that occur between January and April
      of each year that MESSENGER was in orbit about Mercury.
      See PERRYETAL2015 [doi:10.1002/2015GL065101] for additional information
      on processing of occultation data.
 
      The products were generated using radio data collected during flybys
      and during the orbital phase of the MESSENGER mission. For the first
      twelve months of the orbital phase, when the orbit period was twelve
      hours, tracking data were usually obtained for eight hours
      per Earth day, centered near the apoapsis of every other orbit. After
      the orbit period was reduced to eight hours in April 2012, tracking
      was usually six hours per Earth day. MESSENGER used a High-Gain
      Antenna (HGA) during these periods.  There are also data collected
      during some periapsis passes, usually every other orbit. These data
      were obtained using the low-gain antennas. During the last six months of
      the mission, MESSENGER&apos;s periapsis was maintained between 5 and 200 km;
      data from this period contain the highest-resolution signals for
      analyzing Mercury&apos;s gravity.
 
      This data set includes three primary data product types: occultation
      summary files (OCCSUM), Spherical Harmonics ASCII Data Records (SHADR),
      and Spherical Harmonics Binary Data Records (SHBDR). The MLA data
      acquisition and processing are described in the MLA archive.
 
      Please see documentation in the DOCUMENT directory for
      additional information on the data files and their format. A
      description of the mission phases is provided in the MISSION.CAT file
      included with the archive volume.
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      For the gravity and shape products, the data set consists of the
      spherical harmonic coefficients and their uncertainties. For
      occultations, the data set contains information on each archived
      occultation, including the name of the raw data file, the surface
      location and radius, and quality information such as the effective
      signal margin and the time uncertainty. See individual Software
      Interface Specification (SIS) documents, which are located in the
      DOCUMENT directory, for detailed descriptions of each file contained in
      this data archive.
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      Spherical harmonic models and occultation radii are derived from
      raw radio tracking data, Radio Science Receiver (RDR) data, and MLA
      data in several steps.
 
      The tracking data are processed in large orbit determination programs
      that integrate the equations of motion (GEODYN at NASA GSFC
      [PAVLISETAL2007]) and model mathematically the radio science
      observables (ramped Doppler and range data). The observations are
      related to the geophysical parameters through the numerical integration
      and the detailed mathematical modeling of the radio science
      observables and of all forces acting on the spacecraft trajectory,
      including Mercury and third body gravity, solar radiation pressure,
      planetary radiation pressure, solid body tides, and relativity.
 
      The gravity field coefficients are obtained by accumulating normal
      equations from hundreds of data arcs and solving these systems
      of linear equations for thousands of unknowns. The unknowns include
      arc parameters, particular to one data arc (such as the spacecraft
      state and radiation pressure scale factors) and common parameters (such
      as the gravity coefficients and the Mercury gravitational constant or
      GM). Radio tracking data are processed in arcs, usually 24 hours long.
 
      The occultation radius measurements use RF data obtained at the DSN
      when Mercury occults the RF transmissions from MESSENGER. The RF power
      history for each occultation is extracted from Radio Science Receiver
      measurements. Fits to a diffraction curve then provide the occultation
      time and its uncertainty. Combined with an ephemeris, this time provides
      Mercury&apos;s radius at the point where the RF path grazes the surface with
      the assumption that Mercury&apos;s surface is smooth. The radius derived and
      described in DOCUMENT/OCCSUM.TXT in this archive volume is not corrected
      for local topographic effects, which may have moved the occulting edge
      from the smooth-sphere location. The OCCSUM.TXT software interface
      specification document contains more information on the processing. See
      PERRYETAL2015 for further details.
 
      The shape model coefficients are based on weighted, constrained, least-
      squares fit of spherical harmonics to the MLA and occultation data. The
      MLA data comprise more than 25 million individual measurements of
      radius. In order to fit spherical harmonic coefficients of high degree
      and order without undue computational effort, the MLA observations are
      conservatively assigned an uncertainty of 1 km, averaged into 0.5 by 0.5
      degree bins, and weighted according to the number of observations in
      each bin. While the topography in each of the 335,571 bins measured by
      MLA is known on 20 to 80-m-diameter footprints with uncertainties of a
      few meters radially, the average height in a region is not as well known
      owing to undersampling of topography. Occultation data are weighted
      based on an uncertainty of 0.33 km, which reflects the uncertainty in
      the accuracy of the Digital Terrain Model (DTM) used to adjust the raw
      occultation radius for the effects of local topography as well as
      the areal averaging employed.
 
      The distribution of data on the surface of Mercury is extremely sparse
      in the southern hemisphere, with only 1% of the observations south of
      the equator, and only 313 observations south of 20 degrees south
      latitude. The spherical harmonic expansion to degree and order 155
      results in a least-squares fit of &gt;20,000 coefficients to a total of
      110,752 observations. While formally overconstrained, the solution is
      numerically ill-conditioned, and the solution is truncated at degree and
      order 150 to avoid aliasing. A planetary power law is applied in a
      similar manner as that employed for gravity [e.g., MAZARICOETAL2014]
      to damp the least-squares equations, resulting in a better-conditioned
      solution, at the expense of a negligibly worse fit to the observations.
      A damping term of (2n+1)n^2 is added to terms of degree n on the normal
      matrix diagonal, to constrain the solution variance at degrees n&gt;0. The
      formal uncertainties, given as 1 standard deviation (s.d.), are obtained
      from the diagonal terms of the solution covariance matrix, and reflect
      the lack of knowledge of the true coefficient power as well as the power
      law assumptions. Thus, the formal uncertainties must increasingly be
      regarded as underestimates at higher degrees. The (0,0) term
      corresponding to the mean radius is unconstrained, as are the lowest
      degree-and-order shape coefficients, however the sparseness of southern
      occultations reduces confidence in the coefficients of degrees higher
      than 2.
 
    Data
    ====
      Users should consult listings in the INDEX.TAB file to ascertain full
      coverage of each data type. The DATA directory contains the SHADR,
      SHBDR, and OCCSUM products.
 
      OCCSUM files are named MESS_RS_OCC_V&lt;nn&gt;.CSV. The ASCII text spherical
      harmonic files are named GGMES_&lt;dd&gt;V&lt;nn&gt;_SHA.TAB and
      GTMES_&lt;ddd&gt;V&lt;nn&gt;_SHA.TAB for the gravity and shape models respectively
      and the binary version of the gravity model is named
      GGMES_&lt;dd&gt;V&lt;nn&gt;_SHB.DAT. &lt;ddd&gt; or &lt;dd&gt; indicates the degree and order of
      the model used. &lt;nn&gt; is a version number, range 01..99. The file naming
      conventions for these products are described in detail in their
      associated SIS documents.
 
      Every file in the directory has a PDS label. Except for files in the
      root and in the CATALOG directories and the *INFO.TXT files in the
      other directories, the label is a separate file in the same directory
      with the same name but a LBL extension.
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      The MESSENGER RDR products use the Mercury planetocentric fixed body
      coordinate system. The MESSENGER mission has adopted the Planetocentric
      model for Mercury. At 2439.4 km, the geodetic reference radius is
      slightly smaller than the 2439.7 km IAU value [ARCHINALETAL2011].
 
    Software
    ========
      Software is not included with this archival data set.
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      This is an electronically stored and transferred data set and may be
      downloaded from http://pds.nasa.gov.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this archive have been reduced as part of mission data
      analysis activities of the MESSENGER mission.  Products of
      questionable validity have been flagged or omitted.
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was reviewed by the MESSENGER RS Team prior to
      submission to the Planetary Data System (PDS). Data set design,
      documentation, and sample products have passed a PDS peer review.
 
      Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data set, key
      elements of the archive were distributed for preliminary review.  These
      included electronic versions of example PDS labels, CATALOG files, and
      Software Interface Specifications.  These materials were distributed to
      PDS personnel, the experiment investigator, and others, as appropriate.
      The archived data set incorporates changes based on the reviews.
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      This volume contains gravity and shape models generated from MESSENGER
      data collected through April 2015 for the gravity model and shape model.
      The tracking data include flyby data and orbit-phase data. Due to
      MESSENGER&apos;s eccentric orbit with a periapsis that is northward of 60N,
      the spatial resolution of the gravity field is higher in the northern
      hemisphere than in the southern hemisphere.
 
      There are 170 occultation measurements of radius that overlap with
      the MLA data. The occultation measurements are an average of 5
      meters higher than the MLA data with a standard deviation of 130 meters,
      in agreement with the average time-based uncertainty. The time-based
      uncertainty is the uncertainty in the time of occultation multiplied by
      the perpendicular speed and the data set only includes occultations
      where this uncertainty is 500 meters or less. The data are also filtered
      for excessive difference from the image-based DTM and for low noise.
      Future, improved processing may add more occultations, reduce
      uncertainty, or both. Since most of the egress events had large time
      uncertainties, the archived occultations consist almost exclusively of
      ingresses.
 
      For some of the carrier power calculations (Pc/No) in the occultation
      summary product with Pc/No greater than 25 dB-Hz, the reported power is
      low by up to 5 dB-Hz because a portion of the carrier power was
      inadvertently included in the noise, reducing the power-to-noise ratio.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The limitations in this data set follow from the quality of
      the execution, which is described above under Data Coverage
      and Quality.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

