<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.go-j-nims-4-adr-sl9impact-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GO NIMS TABULAR DATA FROM THE SL9 IMPACT WITH JUPITER V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.comet_sl9-jupiter_collision::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.galileo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:nims.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-j-nims-4-adr-sl9impact-v1.0__browserp_go-j-nims-4-adr-sl9impact-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-j-nims-4-adr-sl9impact-v1.0__dvo_imaging_go-j-nims-4-adr-sl9impact-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-j-nims-4-adr-sl9impact-v1.0__dvo_usgs_go-j-nims-4-adr-sl9impact-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Carlson, R.W., P.R. Weissman, W.D. Smythe, J.C. Mahoney, and the NIMS Science
                   and Engineering Teams, Near-Infrared Mapping Spectrometer Experiment on
                   Galileo, Space Science Reviews 60: 457-502, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CARLSONETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Carlson, R.W., P.R. Weissman, J. Hui, M. Segura, W.D. Smythe, K.H. Baines,
                   T.V. Johnson, P. Drossart, Th. Encrenaz, F. Leader, R. Mehlman, Some Timing
                   and Spectral Aspects of the R and G Collision Events as Observed by the
                   Galileo Near-Infrared Mapping Spectrometer, ESO Conference and Workshop
                   Proceedings 52: 69-74, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CARLSONETAL1995A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Carlson, R.W., P.R. Weissman, M. Segura, J. Hui, W.D. Smythe, T.V. Johnson,
                   K.H. Baines, P. Drossart, T. Enerenaz, and F.E. Leader, Galileo infrared
                   observations of the Shoemaker-Levy 9 G impact fireball: A preliminary
                   report, Geophysical Research Letters 22: 1557-1560, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CARLSONETAL1995B</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GO-J-NIMS-4-ADR-SL9IMPACT-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GO NIMS TABULAR DATA FROM THE SL9 IMPACT WITH JUPITER V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1996-01-19</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1994-07-14T08:09:03Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1994-07-21T05:04:36Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. ROBERT W. CARLSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Carlson, R.W., W. D. Smythe, and R. Mehlman, GO NIMS TABULAR DATA
            FROM THE SL9 IMPACT WITH JUPITER V1.0,
            GO-J-NIMS-4-ADR-SL9IMPACT-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 1996.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Galileo NIMS tabular data from the P/Shoemaker-Levy 9 impact with
            Jupiter
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Near Infrared Mapping Spectrometer (NIMS) on the Galileo
            spacecraft took unique data of Comet Shoemaker-Levy/9&apos;s
            impact with Jupiter. A preliminary analysis of this data is
            presented in this submission to the Planetary Data System (PDS).
            It consists of nine small tables with detached labels and
            documentation.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Near Infrared Mapping Spectrometer (NIMS) on the Galileo
      spacecraft took unique data of Comet Shoemaker-Levy/9&apos;s impact with
      Jupiter.  A preliminary analysis of this data is presented in this
      submission to the Planetary Data System (PDS).  It consists of nine
      small tables with detached labels and documentation.
 
 
    Background
    ==========
      The Galileo spacecraft, enroute to Jupiter, was situated 240 million
      kilometers from Jupiter with a spacecraft-Jupiter-Sun phase angle of
      51 degrees during the collision of Comet Shoemaker-Levy/9 with the
      planet.  This geometry allowed a direct view of the impacts, which
      occurred on the nightside of Jupiter, not viewable from the Earth,
      and provided an opportunity to investigate the early temporal
      evolution of the impact events.  Much of the radiation occurs in the
      infrared region, and time-resolved infrared spectral observations,
      obtained over a broad wavelength range, are ideal for studying these
      phenomena.
 
      The Galileo Near Infrared Mapping Spectrometer (NIMS) instrument
      (CARLSONETAL1992, see REF.CAT) observed the C, F, G, and R events,
      simultaneously with the Photopolarimeter (PPR) and Ultraviolet
      Spectrometer (UVS) instruments.  Only data for the G and R events
      were telemetered to Earth.
 
      In order to ensure successful observations of the impacts, given
      uncertainties in the absolute spacecraft pointing, a &apos;checkerboard&apos;
      scan pattern was used, covering Jupiter and the immediate vicinity.
      One dimension of scanning was provided by the NIMS mapping
      capability, giving a 10 mrad column of 20 pixels. Each pixel is
      acquired in 1/63 sec and is 0.5 mrad by 0.5 mrad in size (Jupiter&apos;s
      diameter as seen from Galileo was 0.6 mrad).  The spacecraft scan
      platform provided the second dimension, scanning back and forth by 3
      mrad at 0.92 mrad/sec and a period of 10 2/3 sec.  Jupiter was in
      the field-of-view for only a fraction of each scan, giving a net
      time resolution of 5 1/3 seconds.
 
      The instrument was operated in the &apos;Fixed Map&apos; mode in which, for
      each spatial pixel, 17 spectral bands are simultaneously monitored.
      The wavelength setting was chosen to include continuum bands, where
      the atmospheric gases are transparent, and bands with differing
      absorption strengths so as to perform vertical sounding of the
      fireball in the atmosphere.  It also included a band for possible
      H3+ emissions.  For short wavelengths, the intense reflected
      sunlight signal precludes ready identification of fireball emission
      while Jovian thermal emission obscures the fireball signature in the
      5 micron region.  Between these limits, in the 1.8 to 4.4 micron
      region, the reflected sunlight signal is weak and little atmospheric
      thermal emission occurs.  Consequently, we employ this region for
      our preliminary analysis.  The corresponding wavelengths and
      atmospheric absorption properties are listed in the table below.
      The spectral resolution for each wavelength channel is 0.025
      microns.
 
         Wavelengths and Jovian Atmospheric Absorption Properties
 
        Det. No.     Wavelength    Wavenumber      Absorber, Emitter
                      (microns)      (cm-1)
        ========     ==========    ==========    ==========================
            6           1.84         5430        Continuum
            7           2.12         4710        Molecular hydrogen,
                                                  pressure induced
            8           2.40         4160        Methane (stratosphere)
            9           2.69         3720        Continuum
           10           2.97         3370        Ammonia (troposphere)
           11           3.25         3075        Methane (stratosphere)
           12           3.53         2830        Methane (stratosphere),
                                                  H3+
           13           3.82         2620        Methane (stratosphere)
           14           4.10         2440        Continuum
           15           4.38         2280        Phosphine (troposphere)
 
 
      Some of the above has been abstracted from CARLSONETAL1995A.
      Another useful reference is CARLSONETAL1995B.  In addition, a
      comprehensive paper on the G fireball is being submitted to Icarus,
      and an analysis of the G and R splash spectra is currently
      underway.
 
      Tables in the Dataset
      ---------------------
      The data provided here for the G and R events are of three types:
      calibration data, raw and averaged data numbers, and processed data,
      giving source intensities in physical units.
 
 
      CAL_DATA.TAB: A file of calibration data and related information
                    useful for interpretation.
 
      JREF_DNS.TAB: Reference spectra for the undisturbed full disc
                    Jupiter, in data numbers (DNs).
 
      JREF_GAM.TAB: Reference spectra for Jupiter&apos;s morning hemisphere,
                    just prior to the G fireball event, in DNs.
 
      JREF_RAM.TAB: Reference spectra for Jupiter&apos;s morning hemisphere,
                    just prior to the R fireball event, in DNs.
 
      G_DATA.TAB:   Raw DNs versus time for pixels containing the G impact
                    site.
 
      R_DATA.TAB:   Raw DNs versus time for pixels containing the R impact
                    site.
 
      SI_G_1.TAB:   Source intensities versus time for the G event using
                    chi squared minimization for the fireball period,
                    which finds the fraction (eta) of reflected light to
                    subtract to obtain the best fit of a blackbody
                    spectrum.  A regression fit of eta to detector 1 was
                    developed from the fireball period and applied to the
                    pre- and post-fireball periods.
 
      SI_G_2.TAB:   Same as above, but the regression algorithm found in
                    the chi squared minimization was used for all data,
                    including the fireball period.  This is to test the
                    sensitivity of the results to the analysis procedure.
 
      SI_R_2.TAB:   Same as above, but for the R event.
 
 
      Details of the structure and contents of these tables may be found
      in the detached label accompanying each table and in the
      AAREADME.TXT file.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The raw NIMS data received from the spacecraft were collected on
      EDRs by the Image Processing System (MIPS) at the Jet Propulsion
      Laboratory (JPL) and are archived on PDS CD-ROM volume GO_1004.  The
      tables in the submitted dataset were generated by Dr. Robert W.
      Carlson of JPL, Principal Investigator of the NIMS experiment on the
      Galileo Orbiter.  The detached PDS labels were prepared by Bob
      Mehlman of the NIMS team and UCLA, who also edited the documentation
      supplied by Dr. Carlson into PDS format.
 
 
    Data structure
    ==============
      The table files follow PDS structure and labelling conventions.  A
      detached PDS label accompanies each file, and describes its
      structure and contents using ASCII keyword=value statements.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      Calibration files derived from ground and flight calibration of the
      NIMS instrument were used in generating the CAL_DATA.TAB file in
      this dataset, but are not included with it.  These calibration files
      are continually being improved.  The most recent calibration files
      are available with the Integrated Software for Imaging Spectrometers
      (ISIS) system.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      The nine tables in this dataset are small and in ASCII character
      format.  They are therefore printable and accessible with ordinary
      editing software.  They are also easily ingested by most database
      systems.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      This dataset is an electronic submission to PDS but may be included
      on a future CD-ROM volume of NIMS data from the Jupiter Tour.
      Formats are based on standards for table objects established by
      PDS.
 
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
UNK
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XD-B3B</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

