<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.grail-l-lgrs-3-cdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GRAIL MOON LGRS CALIBRATED AND RESAMPLED SCIENCE V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.gravity_recovery_and_interior_laboratory::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.grail-a::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:lgrs-a.grail-a::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.grail-l-lgrs-3-cdr-v1.0__browserp_grail-l-lgrs-3-cdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.grail-l-lgrs-3-cdr-v1.0__dvo_grail-l-lgrs-3-cdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kahan, D.S., GRAIL Data Product Software Interface Specification, Jet
                   Propulsion Laboratory, 2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KAHAN2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GRAIL-L-LGRS-3-CDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GRAIL MOON LGRS CALIBRATED AND RESAMPLED SCIENCE V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2014-04-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2012-03-01</start_time>
        <stop_time>2012-12-18</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DANIEL S. KAHAN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            KAHAN, D.S., GRAIL LGRS Calibrated and Resampled Science Data Set
            V1.0, GRAIL-L-LGRS-3-CDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2012.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Calibrated and resampled data from the Lunar Gravity and Ranging
            System (LGRS) on each of the two spacecraft comprising the
            Gravity Recovery and Interior Laboratory (GRAIL) mission
            [KAHAN2012].
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains calibrated and resampled engineering
            (e.g., star tracker data and timing) and science data acquired
            from the Lunar Gravity and Ranging System (LGRS) on the two
            spacecraft comprising the Gravity Recovery and Interior
            Laboratory (GRAIL) mission. The data in the set are at NASA Level
            1 and have been archived for general use. Products in this set
            have been derived from NASA Level 0 (the LGRS EDR data set) by
            the GRAIL Science Data System (SDS). The observations were used
            to generate high-resolution gravity field models of the Moon. The
            data set includes all of the Level 1 LGRS data from the GRAIL
            mission (March-December 2012).
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Gravity Recovery and Interior Laboratory (GRAIL) Lunar
      Gravity Ranging System (LGRS) Calibrated Data Record Archive is
      a time-ordered collection of processed data collected during the
      GRAIL mission to the Moon.
 
      The DATA_SET_ID &apos;GRAIL-L-LGRS-3-CDR-V1.0&apos; includes the following
      components:
          Instrument host (i.e., &apos;GRAIL&apos;)
          Target (i.e., &apos;L&apos; for Lunar)
          Instrument (i.e., &apos;LGRS&apos; for Lunar Gravity Ranging System)
          CODMAC Data processing level number (i.e., &apos;3&apos;)
          Description (i.e., &apos;CDR&apos; for Calibrated Data Record)
          Version number (i.e., &apos;V1.0&apos;)
 
      This data set was derived from data collected during
      March-December 2012.
 
      Data in this set have been created from the Level 0 files in the
      LGRS EDR data set. They are distinguished by two processing
      levels, 1A and 1B.
 
      Level 1A comprises edited data that are still in units produced
      by the instrument but that have been corrected so that values
      are expressed in or are proportional to some physical unit such
      as meters per second.
 
      Level 1B data have been resampled in the time or space domains
      in such a way that the original edited data cannot be
      reconstructed. Some of these data may also have been calibrated
      in addition to being resampled.
 
      Typical users of GRAIL products interested in original
      measurements will use this data set. The data of primary
      interest will be the KBR1C and SBR1B files.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      All forty-three LGRS CDR file types are in ASCII format. Most of
      the file types are spacecraft-specific. Types DEL1A, PLT1A,
      TC61A, KBR1C, and SBR1B apply to both spacecraft together, as
      they convey a relationship between the two.
 
      Some of the parameters conveyed by the data include conversions
      between different time frames, locations of data sources within
      the spacecraft frame, information about spacecraft health, and
      ranging measurements made by the LGRS. See Data section below
      for more specific information about data parameters.
 
      Each Level 1A or 1B product is accompanied by a minimal PDS
      label that points to the relevant table in the data product
      SIS (DPSIS.PDF, DOCUMENT directory).
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      The GRAIL Science Data System (SDS) is defined as the
      infrastructure at NASA&apos;s Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) for the
      collection of all science and ancillary data relevant to the
      GRAIL mission. It includes hardware, software tools, procedures,
      and trained personnel. The SDS receives data and carries out
      calibration, editing, and processing to produce NASA Level 1A
      and 1B GRAIL science data
 
      The SDS creates edited data that are still in units produced by
      the instrument, but that have been corrected so that values are
      expressed in or are proportional to some physical unit such as
      radiance. No resampling is done, so original values can be
      recovered.
 
      Level 1B data have been resampled in the time or space domains
      in such a way that the original edited data cannot be
      reconstructed. They could be calibrated in addition to being
      resampled.
 
      Level 1A and 1B files have been processed from the Level 0 files
      in the LGRS EDR data set by the GRAIL SDS at JPL; they are
      constructed so that each file contains the data for one day.
 
      The Algorithm Theoretical Basis Document (ATDB.PDF) in the
      DOCUMENT directory describes the data processing flow from EDR
      to CDR as implemented by the GRAIL Team.
 
      GRAIL timing requires coordination of three clocks on each
      satellite, and two time standards:
      1. LGRS: Lunar Gravity Ranging System clock. Very stable clock
         for on-board Ka-band ranging (KBR), X-band (RSB), and S-band
         Time Transfer System (TTS) instruments. Driven by an
         Ultra-Stable Oscillator (USO). Set to 0 when booted. Produces
         a pulse per second (pps) signal. LGRS time starts at 0
         seconds when powered on. The SDS adds a bias to LGRS time to
         create an approximate UTC time tag. This time will be
         referred to as LGRS + bias.
      2. BTC: Base Clock Time. On-board satellite clock, comparable in
         stability to a wristwatch. Roughly synced to UTC at launch
         time.
      3. RTC: Real Clock Time. Flight software clock. Set to 0 when
         booted. Relatively unstable clock.
      4. UTC: Coordinated Universal Time.
      5. TDB: Barycentric Dynamical Time.
 
 
    Data
    ====
 
      All forty-three LGRS CDR file types are in ASCII format.  Types
      DEL1A, PLT1A, TC61A, KBR1C, and SBR1B apply to both spacecraft
      together, as they convey a relationship between the two; all of
      the other file types have separate files for each spacecraft.
 
      LGRS to TDB time correlation (CLK1A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        Time correlation between LGRS time + bias and TDB time.
        Clock: LGRS time + Bias
 
 
      Inter-satellite LGRS clock offset between spacecraft (DEL1A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        Inter-satellite LGRS clock offset between spacecraft by TDB
        time. One file combined for BOTH spacecraft.
        Clock: LGRS time + Bias
 
 
      Spacecraft temperature sensor data from Engineering
      Housekeeping data (EHK1A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        EHK1A contains temperature sensor data for locations near LGRS
        instruments.
        Clock: UTC
 
      LGRS Housekeeping Data (IHK1A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        Housekeeping data for the LGRS in IHK1A includes voltage,
        temperature, and current measurements.
        Clock: LGRS time + Bias
 
      LGRS Health Status data (IHS1A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        IHS1A includes other LGRS status data.
        Clock: LGRS time + Bias
 
      LGRS log messages (ILG1A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        ILG1A contains log messages from the LGRS.
        Clock: LGRS time + Bias
 
      Ka-Band Ranging Data (KBR1A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        KBR1A records raw carrier-phase measurements, flagged for
        phase breaks. Gaps of up to 2 seconds are filled in by
        quadratic interpolation; longer gaps are classified as
        missing data.
        Clock: LGRS time + Bias
 
      Position vector and light time between one spacecraft and DSN
      station (LTM1A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        From the best ephemeris solution, spacecraft to DSN relative
        position and light time are computed in the EME 2000
        Lunar-Centered Solar System Barycentric Frame
        Clock: TDB
 
      Satellite Mass Data (MAS1A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        MAS1A lists spacecraft mass as a function of UTC time
        Clock: UTC
 
      Phase Center to Center of Mass Correction
      ------------------------------------------------------
        PCI1A lists Ka-band antenna range corrections, range rate
        corrections, and range acceleration corrections.
        Clock: TDB
 
      Position vector and light time between two spacecraft (PLT1A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        From the best ephemeris solution, spacecraft to DSN relative
        position and light time are computed in the EME 2000
        Lunar-Centered Solar System Barycentric Frame, and spacecraft
        to spacecraft relative position and light time are computed
        in the DE 421 Lunar Body-Fixed Frame. One file combined for
        BOTH spacecraft.
        Clock: TDB
 
      LGRS Pulse Per Second (PPS) Time Record (PPS1A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        A PPS1A product lists the LGRS time of PPS signals.
        Clock: LGRS time + Bias
 
      Relativistic time correction (REL1A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        An approximation of the relativistic time correction from TDB
        to on-board satellite proper time is calculated in the REL1A
        product, treating the Moon as a point mass.
        Clock: TDB
 
      Solar Array Eclipse Data (SAE1A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        SAE1A lists solar array short circuit currents and voltages,
        to identify eclipse events for spacecraft ephemeris models.
        Clock: UTC
 
      S-Band Ranging Data (SBR1A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        SBR1A tracks S-Band carrier phase and a modulating range code.
        Clock: LGRS time + Bias
 
      Star Tracker Data (SCA1A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        Because GRAIL-A and GRAIL-B antennas are offset from the
        spacecraft center of mass, distance between GRAIL-A and
        GRAIL-B Ka-band antennas depends on spacecraft attitude. An
        on-board Kalman filter processes Star Tracker attitude data
        and Inertial Measurement Unit (IMU) angular rotation data.
        Filtered attitudes are saved in SCA1A.
        Clock: BTC
 
      S-Band navigation product (SNV1A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        The SNV1A S-band navigation product contains ancillary
        information for the Time Transfer System (TTS), which
        primarily serves to tell the ground whether GRAIL-A and
        GRAIL-B are communicating correctly with each other.
        Clock: LGRS time + Bias
 
      LGRS to BTC time correlation (TC11A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        LGRS to BTC time correlation, approximated by flight software.
        Clock: LGRS time + Bias
 
      LGRS to BTC time correlation from BTC clock cycle counts (TC21A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        LGRS to BTC time correlation from BTC clock cycle counts. More
        accurate mapping than TC11A.
        Clock: LGRS time + Bias
 
      BTC to RTC time correlation (TC31A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        BTC to RTC time correlation.
        Clock: BTC
 
      LGRS to RTC time correlation (TC41A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        LGRS to RTC time correlation.
        Clock: LGRS time + Bias
 
      RTC to UTC time correlation (TC51A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        RTC to UTC time correlation.
        Clock: RTC
 
      UTC to TDB time correlation (TC61A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        UTC to TDB time correlation. One product applies to both
        spacecraft.
        Clock: UTC
 
      Thruster Activation Data (THR1A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        THR1A contains thruster activation data, including time tags,
        cumulative work cycles by thruster, current thruster on time,
        and cumulative thruster on time.
        Clock: UTC SCET
 
      Oscillator frequency data (USO1A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        Radio Science Receivers (RSR, in RSS_EDR data set), located at
        DSN sites, record X-band Radio Science Beacon (RSB) signals.
        Since the LGRS clock drives the RSB, LGRS frequency at TDB
        can be estimated for USO1A.
        Clock: TDB
 
      Center of mass displacement from spacecraft mechanical frame
      origin (VCM1A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        VCM1A describes center of mass displacement from the
        spacecraft mechanical frame origin.
        Clock: UTC SCET
 
      Wheel Rotational Speed Data (WRS1A)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        WRS1A describes rotational wheel speed of each of four
        Reaction wheels as determined by a digital tachometer.
        Clock: UTC
 
      LGRS to TDB time correleation (CLK1B)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        Best estimate of LGRS to TDB time correlation.
        Clock: LGRS time + Bias
 
      Spacecraft temperature sensor data from Engineering Housekeeping
      data (EHK1B)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        EHK1B contains temperature sensor data for locations near LGRS
        instruments. Same as EHK1A, except in TDB time.
        Clock: TDB
 
      GRAIL satellite orbit solution in Moon centered Inertial frame
      (GNI1B)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        Best estimate of spacecraft ephemeris in EME 2000
        Lunar-Centered Solar System Barycentric Frame.
        Clock: TDB
 
      Satellite orbit Solution in lunar body fixed frame (GNV1B)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        Best estimate of spacecraft ephemeris in DE 421 Lunar
        Body-Fixed Frame.
        Clock: TDB
 
      Dual-One-Way Ka-Band Ranging Data (KBR1C)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        KBR1C contains biased dual one-way range between GRAIL-A and
        GRAIL-B, digitally filtered, but not corrected for time of
        flight or antenna offset. After the dual one-way range
        combination has been formed, gaps of up to 20 seconds are
        filled in by quadratic interpolation. KBR1C also contains
        corrections for time of flight and antenna offset from center
        of mass.
 
        In addition, KBR1C also contains the first and second
        derivatives of the biased dual one-way range between GRAIL-A
        and -B and associated time of flight and antenna offset
        corrections.
 
        In general, the instantaneous range, range rate, and range
        acceleration is used for scientific analysis. The
        instantaneous range, range rate, and range acceleration are
        computed by adding the time of flight correction and antenna
        offset correction to the dual one-way range, range rate, or
        range acceleration measurement.
 
        This (level 1B) product is designated as &apos;1C&apos; to distinguish it
        from earlier versions of KBR1B which did not contain an
        additional four columns of information on the temperature range
        corrections. The raw temperature range correction, filtered
        temperature range correction, filtered temperature range rate
        correction, and filtered temperature range acceleration
        correction are the final four columns of the KBR1C product.
 
        One file combined for BOTH spacecraft.
        Clock: TDB
 
      Spacecraft Mass Data (MAS1B)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        MAS1B lists spacecraft mass as a function of time. Same as
        MAS1A except in TDB time rather than UTC SCET.
        Clock: TDB
 
      Solar Array Eclipse Data (SAE1B)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        SAE1B lists solar array short circuit currents and voltages,
        to identify eclipse events for spacecraft ephemeris models.
        Same as SAE1A except time-tagged by TDB rather than UTC SCET.
        Clock: TDB
 
      Dual one-way S-Band Ranging data (SBR1B)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        S-Band Carrier phase and a modulating range code are tracked
        in SBR1B. In SBR1B, a more accurate range is produced by
        carrier smoothing over each arc. One file combined for BOTH
        spacecraft.
        Clock: TDB
 
      Star Tracker Data (SCA1B)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        Because GRAIL-A and GRAIL-B antennas are offset from the
        spacecraft center of mass, distance between GRAIL-A and
        GRAIL-B Ka-band antennas depends on spacecraft attitude. An
        on-board Kalman filter processes Star Tracker attitude data
        and Inertial Measurement Unit (IMU) angular rotation data.
        Filtered attitudes are saved in SCA1B. Same as SCA1A except
        time tagged by TDB rather than BTC time.
        Clock: TDB
 
      Thruster Activation Data (THR1B)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        THR1A contains thruster activation data, including time tags,
        cumulative work cycles by thruster, current thruster on time,
        and cumulative thruster on time. Same as THR1A except
        time-tagged by TDB rather than UTC SCET.
        Clock: TDB
 
      USO Frequency Estimate (USO1B)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        Best estimate of LGRS frequency at TDB.
        Clock: TDB
 
      Center of mass displacement from spacecraft mechanical frame
      origin (VCM1B)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        VCM1B describes center of mass displacement from the
        spacecraft mechanical frame origin (See section 4.3.2 of
        [Kahan2012]). Same as VCM1A except
        lists results relative to TDB rather than UTC SCET.
        Clock: TDB
 
      S-Band antenna switch time (VGS1B)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        GRAIL transmits information to the Deep Space Network using
        S-band. S-band communication from each GRAIL spacecraft to
        the DSN depends on a pair of low-gain antennas (LGAs),
        located on opposite sides of the spacecraft. At a given TDB,
        only one antenna can communicate with the DSN. The VGS1B
        product contains a list of the TDB times at which the antennas
        are switched, with the Mechanical Frame (MF) vector of the
        new transmitting antenna phase center.
        Clock: TDB
 
      X-Band antenna switch time (VGX1B)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        Each GRAIL spacecraft transmits an unmodulated X-band carrier
        to the DSN through one of a pair of Radio Science Beacons
        (RSB). The VGX1B product contains a list of the TDB times at
        which beacons are switched, with the Mechanical Frame vector
        of the new transmitting beacon phase center.
        Clock: TDB
 
      Ka-Band Boresight Vector (VKB1B)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        The VKB1B file is the Ka boresight vector, as a result of
        Ka-Band boresight calibration analysis.
        Clock: TDB
 
      Wheel Rotational Speed Data (WRS1B)
      ------------------------------------------------------
        WRS1B describes rotational wheel speed of each of four
        Reaction wheels as determined by a digital tachometer.
        Clock: TDB
 
    Naming Conventions
    ==============================================
      For all LGRS data, the product identifier, in conjunction with
      either a date or a range of dates in a specified format,
      determines the filename containing the data product.
 
      The file naming convention for all Level 1A/1B LGRS products is:
 
        PRDID_YYYY_MM_DD_S_VV.EXT
 
        where
 
        PRDID   product identification label, e.g. CLK1B
        YYYY    year
        MM      month
        DD      day of month
        S       GRAIL satellite identifier:
                        A     GRAIL-A
                        B     GRAIL-B
                        X     combined product of GRAIL-A and GRAIL-B
        VV      data product version number (starting from 00)
        EXT     file extension indicating binary (DAT) or ASCII (ASC)
                files
 
      The Product ID (PRDID) is of the form XXXLL, where:
        XXX     is a three-character mnemonic, and
        LL      specifies the data product Level (00, 1A, 1B).
 
 
    Files in the CALIB Directory
    =============================
      Files in the CALIB directory are those likely to have wide
      applicability in working with the raw data.
 
      One file, GRAILCOMPONENTS.TXT is included in the CALIB
      directory. It describes the Spacecraft bus component model with
      dimensions and orientations, as well as the spacecraft
      components specular/diffuse reflectivity properties.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      Software for parsing, reducing, and analyzing data such as
      these has been developed at JPL and elsewhere. Because such
      software must usually operate at the bit-level and is written
      for a narrow range of platforms, it is not suitable for general
      distribution. No software is included with this archival data
      set.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this archival data set have been collected to support
      derivation of the gravity field of the Moon. These are similar
      to data collected with the GRACE spacecraft and are believed to
      be generally of good quality.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      Data validation occurs in three steps: validation of the data
      themselves, validation of the correctness and completeness of
      the data set documentation, and validation of the compliance of
      the archive with PDS standards. The primary method by which
      Science Team members validated the various archive products was
      by using them for science. Calibrated data files (CDRs) were
      derived from the raw data files (EDRs) in the archive; then
      reduced data records (RDRs) were created from the archival CDRs.
      Errors in the raw and calibrated data products were caught by
      the Science Team in this process.
 
      In addition, this archive underwent PDS external review from
      August 31, 2012 to November 30, 2012.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Files in this data set were constructed to cover one day each.
 
      Data coverage includes the science phase (March 1, 2012, to May
      29, 2012), the extended mission phase (August 29, 2012, to
      December 12, 2012), and the decommissioning phase (December 12,
      2012, to December 18, 2012) as described in the mission catalog.
 
      The GRAIL science orbits for the primary mission are based on
      Deep Space Network one-way Doppler and two-way Doppler tracking
      data. In addition, the inter-satellite range rate measurements
      were included in the orbit determination process. The gravity
      field used for the GRAIL science orbits is a GRAIL internal
      gravity field of degree and order 420 (420b8a), which had all
      primary mission inter-satellite range data included. The
      resulting orbit accuracy of the orbit in absolute sense is at
      the meter level and in relative range rate error between the
      spacecraft is better than 20 micrometers/sec.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      Certain spacecraft events have an impact on the science
      processing. These events include propulsive maneuvers, Ka
      boresight calibration attitude maneuvers, telecommunication
      configuration changes, and Lunar Gravity Ranging System (LGRS)
      events.
 
      Both spacecraft performed propulsive maneuvers. The mass change
      history for both spacecraft can be found in the MAS1A/B Level-1
      products, and the thruster on-times are available in the THR1A/B
      level-1 products. LGRS measurements are taken during the
      propulsive maneuvers, but it is recommended to break science
      data arcs at the propulsive maneuver event times, since the
      velocity changes imparted on the spacecraft are not known with
      sufficient accuracy for science processing.
 
      LGRS measurements are taken during the angular momentum
      desaturation maneuvers but it is recommended to break science
      data arcs at the desaturation maneuver event times, since the
      velocity changes imparted on the spacecraft are not known with
      sufficient accuracy for science processing. For detailed
      thruster on time histories see level-1 product THR1A/B.
 
      The LGRS Gravity Processor Assemby (GPA) rebooted several times
      resulting in the loss of Ka range and the Time Transfer System
      (TTS) observables for about 1.5 minutes. After a GPA reboot the
      LGRS clock is synched with the LGRS clock on the non-rebooting
      spacecraft using the TTS system. GPA reboots will cause a gap in
      the inter-satellite range data products (KBR1B, SBR1B) of about
      2 minutes.
 
      On GRAIL-B the TTS phase measurement is reset to zero due to a
      software bug in the LGRS software. The TTS ranging measurement
      is not affected, but the relative LGRS clock reconstruction
      analysis needs to be restarted at a phase reset.
 
      Due to orbital viewing geometry the GRAIL spacecraft are
      changing between the +X and -X S-band and X-band (Radio Science
      Beacon) antennas approximately every 14 days. The complete
      history for the antenna change are listed in the VGS1B product
      (S-band) and VGX1B (X-band).
 
      During the primary and extended missions, the GRAIL spacecraft
      were in nominal science attitude called orbiter point attitude
      mode. For this mode the solar arrays of the spacecraft are
      parallel to the orbital plane and the Ka boresight vectors (2.1
      degrees off the -Z axis in the YZ spacecraft frame) are pointed
      in the direction of line of sight toward the other spacecraft.
      The GRAIL spacecraft remained in orbit point attitude mode
      except during Ka boresight vector calibration maneuvers when the
      spacecraft performed two orthogonal slews of 3 degrees about the
      line of sight vector between the two spacecraft. LGRS
      measurements are taken during the maneuvers but should not be
      used in the science processing because the measured range change
      is the sum of orbit geometry, lunar gravity and range change
      induced by spacecraft attitude variation. Ka boresight vector
      data contain range corrections for the phase center to center of
      mass offset during the maneuvers but these corrections are not
      reliable and should not be used.
 
      For specific dates of the above events, see the operational
      considerations section in LGRS_A_INST.CAT and LGRS_B_INST.CAT.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

