<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.vg2-n-mag-4-summ-nlscoords-12sec-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>VG2 NEP MAG RESAMPLED SUMMARY NLS COORDINATES 12SEC V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.comet_sl9-jupiter_collision::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.voyager::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vg2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mag.vg2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.neptune::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vg2-n-mag-4-summ-nlscoords-12sec-v1.0__browserp_vg2-n-mag-4-summ-nlscoords-12sec-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Connerney, J.E.P., M.H. Acuna, and N.F. Ness, The Magnetic
                   Field at Neptune, J. Geophys, Res., 96 (supplement),
                   pp. 19023-19042, 1991.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CONNERNEYETAL1991</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Ness, N.F., M.H. Acuna, L.F. Burlaga, J.E.P. Connerney,
                   R.P. Lepping, and F.M. Neubauer, Magnetic Fields at
                   Neptune, Science, 246, 1473-1478, 1989.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NESSETAL1989</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>VG2-N-MAG-4-SUMM-NLSCOORDS-12SEC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>VG2 NEP MAG RESAMPLED SUMMARY NLS COORDINATES 12SEC V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1989-03-07</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1989-08-24T18:00:00.557Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1989-08-26T08:19:48.379Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. NORMAN F. NESS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            VG2 NEP MAG RESAMPLED SUMMARY NLS COORDINATES 12SEC V1.0
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            INTRODUCTION:
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      INTRODUCTION:
 
      The Voyager magnetometer investigation (P.I.- Norman F.  Ness)
      makes available archival data through the National Space
      Science Data Center (NSSDC) located at NASA/GSFC as well as
      through the Planetary Data System (PDS) and other channels.
      The primary archive format, referred to as a &apos;summary tape&apos; or
      &apos;conjoint summary tape&apos; has been used consistently since the
      beginning of the Voyager mission to the outer planets (1977).
      This format makes available magnetometer observations,
      supplementary engineering and ephemeris data in one data file,
      and it is one product of Voyager magnetometer routine data
      processing.  Users are referred to the summary format data for
      all data requirements with one exception: Neptune encounter
      high field observations.  Neptune close approach observations
      are archived separately and in a different format from that
      with which many are familiar.  This high-field archive is
      described here.
 
      The special demands of the Neptune encounter flyby exceeded
      (finally) the capabilities of the routine data processing
      system conceived and implemented in the mid 1970&apos;s.  As a
      result, it was necessary to implement an additional data
      processing system with which the near-encounter, high field
      magnetometer observations were processed.  The data products
      available with this new data processing system are not
      available in the same format as the standard Voyager
      magnetometer observations; thus the need for a separate archive
      and a new format description.  We appreciate the desirability
      of a consistent archive format, but find no reasonable
      alternative to the present solution.  We expect, however, that
      users interested in near encounter observations will find this
      new format both useful and easy to assimilate.
 
      The magnetic fields investigation on Voyager carries a total of
      four tri-axial ring core fluxgate magnetometers: two identical
      high field magnetometers mounted on the spacecraft body (HFM&apos;s)
      and two identical low field magnetometers (LFM&apos;s) arranged on a
      13 m boom (Behannon et al., 1977).  The two LFM&apos;s automatically
      step through a total of eight dynamic ranges (ranges 0 through
      7) in response to changes in the measured field, starting with
      a nominal dynamic range of 8 nT, and increasing to a nominal
      dynamic range of 50,000 nT.  The two HFM&apos;s each operate in two
      dynamic ranges (ranges 0 and 1) with nominal values of 50,000
      nT and 200,000 nT.  In the Neptune encounter mode, each
      magnetometer was sampled periodically with a temporal
      resolution of between 0.600 s and 0.060 s, and
      analog-to-digital converted with 12 bit resolution for
      subsequent telemetry.  The magnitude of the maximum observed
      field at Neptune (approximately 10,000 nT) was sufficiently
      large that data from all four of the magnetometers proved
      useful.
 
      1) MAGNETOMETER DATA PRODUCT
 
      ctime - Decimal seconds past 1966-01-02T00:00:00.000 (an
      internal time format)
      SCET - Spacecraft event time PDS/ISO standard time format.
      B_R - Magnetic field vector radial component in units of
      nanotesla; planetocentric right-handed spherical
      coordinate system.
      B_THETA - Magnetic field vector theta component, units
      nanotesla.
      B_PHI - Magnetic field vector phi component, units
      nanotesla.
 
      The vector magnetic field is rendered in a right handed
      spherical coordinate system in which the angles THETA and PHI
      are the usual polar angles, with THETA (colatitude) measured
      from the axis of rotation and PHI increasing in the direction
      of rotation.  The orientation of Neptune&apos;s pole is specified by
      a right ascension of 298.90 and declination of 42.84 at the
      time of the encounter, as given in the Jet Propulsion
      Laboratory&apos;s distribution of physical constants dated 11/06/89.
      Planetary longitudes are based on a 16.11 hour rotation period
      (Warwick et al., 1989) adopted by the Voyager Project shortly
      after the encounter.  The zero longitude is defined by the
      requirement that the West Longitude of the spacecraft at 0356
      SCET day 237 (near closest approach) be 167.7 NLS; West
      Longitudes of the Neptune Longitude System (NLS) are simply
      related to the angle PHI:
 
      WLONG = 360. - PHI   (degrees)
 
      This definition of the zero longitude was adopted by the
      Voyager Project Steering Group in order to minimize differences
      in longitudes resulting from changes in the assumed rotation
      period.
 
      The field values are instantaneous, not averaged, samples of
      &apos;full word&apos; magnetic field observations.  These &apos;full word&apos;
      observations are obtained from each of the Voyager low-field
      (inboard and outboard) magnetometers and high-field (inboard
      and outboard) magnetometers every 0.6 seconds.  (Note that
      &apos;delta&apos; word samples are available at much higher sample rates
      of 16.666 samples/second).  These &apos;full word&apos; samples are
      resampled at a time resolution of 12 seconds for present
      purposes (in the high-field region of the magnetosphere, these
      data are highly redundant at 0.6 seconds resolution).  All four
      triaxial fluxgate magnetometers operated throughout the
      encounter.  The comprehensive data set is constructed of
      inboard low-field magnetometer samples and outboard high-field
      magnetometer samples as follows:
 
         SCET 89 236 18 0 0 557
           to 89 237 3 44 0 512: inboard low-field magnetometer
         SCET 89 237 3 44 12 512
           to 89 237 4 2 24 511: outboard high-field
                                 magnetometer
         SCET 89 237 4 2 36 511
           to 89 238 8 19 48 379: inboard low-field magnetometer
 
      This procedure was adopted as a result of an increased level of
      spacecraft interference and telemetry anomalies experienced
      during the Neptune encounter by MAG.  The composite set of
      observations has good time continuity.  Spacecraft zeros are
      assumed constant throughout the interval represented by this
      data set, and for that reason users of low-field data are
      referred to the summary tape format (standard archive format)
      in which greater care is exercised with the estimation of
      time-variable spacecraft zeros (differences of 0.05 nT or
      less).  This data set extends from inbound MP to outbound MP
      for the convenience of users who do not require better
      weak-field accuracy than that quoted above.
 
      2.) INTERNAL - A BINARY file of observations and supplementary
      ephemeris data organized specifically for analyses of the
      planetary magnetic field (Connerney, Acuna, and Ness, Journal
      of Geophysical Research, 1991).  These data are resampled &apos;full
      word&apos; observations of inboard low-field magnetometer and
      outboard high-field magnetometer observations according to the
      schedule given above.  These data are a subset of the Voyager 2
      vector magnetic field observations obtained within 12 Rn radial
      distance of Neptune (SCET day 236 hr 2340 to SCET day 237
      0811).  During this time the field magnitude ranged from
      approximately 10 nT to nearly 10,000 nT.  These data were
      resampled (decimated in time without averaging) to produce
      samples every 48, 24, and 12 seconds, with the highest temporal
      resolution reserved for the closest approach interval (where
      Voyager 2&apos;s motion relative to the planet was greatest).  Note
      that the format of this ASCII file is different from that
      described above; a segment of the file is reproduced here,
      again beneath column headings inserted here only:
 
      RADIUS     THETA      PHI    B_COMPONENT   SIGMA   TYPE
      --------------------------------------------------------
      1.349     0.685     4.614    6902.570     3.500     0
      1.349     0.685     4.614    3598.230     3.500     1
      1.349     0.685     4.614   -2457.560     3.500     2
      1.339     0.669     4.602    7153.850     3.500     0
      1.339     0.669     4.602    3555.870     3.500     1
      1.339     0.669     4.602   -2591.020     3.500     2
      1.334     0.661     4.595    7275.760     26.00     0
      1.334     0.661     4.595    3540.800     26.00     1
      1.334     0.661     4.595   -2623.690     26.00     2
      1.328     0.652     4.589    7401.400     26.00     0
      1.328     0.652     4.589    3506.690     26.00     1
      1.328     0.652     4.589   -2720.230     26.00     2
 
          RADIUS - Spacecraft radial distance in units of Rn
                   (1 Rn = 24,765 km)
           THETA - Theta coordinate of spacecraft in units of
                   radians
             PHI - Phi coordinate of spacecraft in units of
                   radians
     B_COMPONENT - Magnetic vector field component in units of
                   nanotesla
                   according to the value of identifier TYPE
            TYPE - Magnetic field value designation
                     TYPE = 0: Radial component
                     TYPE = 1: Theta component
                     TYPE = 2: Phi component
                     TYPE = 3: Magnitude of magnetic field
           SIGMA - Estimated standard deviation of the
                   observation in units of nanotesla.
 
 
      Each vector observation was weighted with the expected standard
      deviation of the observation in the analysis of the internal
      field.  This practice insures that each residual (the
      difference between an observation and a model field) is
      compared with its expected error.  For the standard deviation
      of each measurement, we adopted 1 nT or the nominal
      quantization stepsize of the measurement, whichever was
      greater.  The former value approximates the variable
      magnetospheric magnetic field &apos;noise&apos;, the unmodelled temporal
      and spatial variations in the ambient field.  The latter
      approximates the estimated measurement error ( 0.05 nT + 0.1%
      of full scale).  The quantization step size of the measurement
      is a function of the ambient field strength (or time), since
      the Voyager magnetometers automatically change range in
      response to changes in the ambient field.  In ranges 0 through
      5, the quantization stepsize of the lfm measurement increased
      from a nominal value of 0.005 nT to 1.1 nT.  In ranges 6 and 7
      (the highest two ranges) each lfm was sampled with a
      quantization stepsize of approximately 3.5 and 26 nT,
      respectively.  Each hfm, operating in range 0 throughout the
      encounter, was sampled with a quantization of approximately 26
      nT.  Therefore, weights of 1 nT were used for observations
      obtained in the lower instrument ranges, from SCET day 236/2340
      to day 237/0330 and from day 237/0431 to 237/0811.  Weights of
      3.5 nT were used for observations obtained in lfm range 6, from
      SCET day 237/0330 to 237/0344 and from day 237/0402 to
      237/0431.  Weights of 26 nT were used for the hfm observations,
      from SCET day 237/0344 to 237/0402.  The segment of data
      illustrated above includes the transition to hfm observations
      with an associated estimated standard deviation of 26
      nanoteslas.  The sampling interval was also adjusted according
      to instrument range, with a 48 second sampling interval for lfm
      range 5 observations, a 24 second sampling interval for lfm
      range 6 observations, and a 12 second sampling interval for hfm
      observations.
 
      3.) INTERNAL FIELD MODEL COEFFICIENTS - electronic form A
      Neptune spherical harmonic magnetic field model (Connerney et
      al., 1991) is listed here in electronic format for use in
      magnetic field calculations.  The model is based upon a partial
      solution (44ev) to an 8th order expansion of the internal
      field, as is necessary to adequately represent the field
      measured by Voyager close to the surface of Neptune.  However,
      few of the model coefficients are resolved, or uniquely
      determined; these few are marked with an asterisk (*).  Some
      additional coefficients are marginally resolved; these are
      marked with a # sign.  The remaining coefficients are not
      resolved, which means that they are not constrained by the
      data, and may assume practically any value.  They are, however,
      necessary to represent the field along the Voyager trajectory
      close to the planet.  USERS ARE ENCOURAGED TO READ CAREFULLY
      THE DISCUSSION IN THE NEPTUNE SPECIAL ISSUE OF JGR REGARDING
      MODEL PARAMETER RESOLUTION AND USE OF THE MODEL COEFFICIENTS.
 
      Beyond about 2.5 or 3 Rn, where higher order terms are
      sufficiently attenuated, the quadrupole approximation is a good
      approximation to the field globally.  These terms are (more or
      less) uniquely determined.  At close-in radial distances, our
      description of the field is necessarily incomplete.  The entire
      expansion to eighth degree and order provided will well
      describe the field in the vicinity of the Voyager trajectory.
      Those parts of the field that the data are insensitive to are
      effectively zero along the Voyager trajectory.  As one strays
      further from the Voyager trajectory in close to the planet, the
      real field may be expected to (increasingly) deviate from that
      calculated with the entire expansion.  Given Voyager&apos;s close
      approach (1.18 Rn) to the planet, any low-order approximation
      to the field is expected to be inaccurate, even on the
      spacecraft trajectory (Figure 9 in the paper by Connerney et
      al.  illustrates this problem).  For use in modeling the field
      near the planet, (at radial distances of less than
      approximately 2 or 3 Rn), an octupole approximation to the
      field is required to even grossly approximate the field.
      Unfortunately, many of these coefficients are not well
      resolved.
 
      For global field modeling near the planet, we advocate use of a
      model field consisting of orders 1, 2 and 3 (dipole,
      quadrupole, and octupole) from Table 1.  This model, a subset
      of the coefficients listed below, is referred to as the &apos;O8&apos;
      model (the octupole (O) part of an eighth degree and order
      spherical harmonic expansion).  This decision reflects a
      compromise between the limited model parameter resolution
      afforded by the Voyager trajectory and the anticipated demands
      on the model.  However, some of the quadrupole and octupole
      parameters are not well resolved and we expect these to be
      inaccurate.  This is an inescapable consequence of the limited
      information content of the observations.
 
 
      ====================== TABLE 1 ======================
 
 
      Neptune I8E1 44ev Magnetic Field Model
      Schmidt-Normalized Spherical Harmonic Coefficients
      Neptune Radius = 24,765 km
 
      n         m        g(n,m)        h(n,m)
      ___       ___     ________      ________
      1         0       0.09732 *
      1         1       0.03220 *    -0.09889 *
      2         0       0.07448 #
      2         1       0.00664 #     0.11230 *
      2         2       0.04499 *    -0.00070 *
      3         0      -0.06592 *
      3         1       0.04098      -0.03669 #
      3         2      -0.03581       0.01791 #
      3         3       0.00484 #    -0.00770 #
      4         0       0.02243
      4         1       0.00557      -0.01889 #
      4         2       0.03099       0.02607
      4         3      -0.01287       0.01204
      4         4      -0.05073      -0.00456
      5         0      -0.00202
      5         1      -0.00229      -0.00739
      5         2       0.00526      -0.01134
      5         3      -0.02846       0.01067
      5         4      -0.01425      -0.01551
      5         5      -0.02835      -0.01090
      6         0      -0.02175
      6         1      -0.00466       0.04432
      6         2      -0.01269      -0.01598
      6         3      -0.02233       0.01721
      6         4      -0.00887       0.00370
      6         5      -0.00496      -0.01932
      6         6       0.00755       0.01439
      7         0       0.01671
      7         1       0.01678      -0.03159
      7         2       0.01625       0.01862
      7         3       0.02157      -0.01120
      7         4      -0.00483       0.00515
      7         5       0.01873       0.01923
      7         6       0.00584      -0.02749
      7         7       0.00664       0.03344
      8         0      -0.00689
      8         1       0.00238       0.01446
      8         2      -0.00090      -0.00079
      8         3      -0.01304       0.01043
      8         4       0.00311      -0.00022
      8         5      -0.00367      -0.00465
      8         6      -0.00249       0.01043
      8         7       0.01333      -0.02138
      8         8      -0.01239       0.02519
 
 
      * = Coefficient WELL RESOLVED (Rxx &gt; 0.95)
      # = Coefficient MARGINALLY RESOLVED (0.75 &lt; Rxx &lt; 0.95)
      ALL OTHER COEFFICIENTS are POORLY RESOLVED or UNRESOLVED
      Refer to text of Connerney et al., 1991, for explanation.
 
      REFERENCES:
 
      Behannon, K.  W., M. H.  Acuna, L. F.  Burlaga, R. P.  Lepping,
      N. F.  Ness, and F. M.  Neubauer, &apos;Magnetic field experiment
      for Voyagers 1 and 2&apos;, Space Sci.  Rev., 21, 235-257, 1977.
 
      Connerney, J. E.  P., M. H.  Acuna, and N. F.  Ness, &apos;The
      magnetic field of Neptune&apos;, J. Geophys.  Res., vol.  96,
      Supplement, 19023-19042, 1991.
 
      Ness, N.  F., M. H.  Acuna, L. F.  Burlaga, J. E. P.
      Connerney, R. P.  Lepping, and F. M.  Neubauer, &apos;Magnetic
      fields at Neptune&apos;, Science, 246, 1473-1478, 1989.
 
      Warwick, J. W.  et al., &apos;Voyager planetary radio astronomy at
      Neptune&apos;, Science, 246, 1498-1501, 1989.
 
 
      Processing Level Id            : 4
      Software Flag                  : Y
      Processing Start Time          : UNK
      Processing Stop Time           : UNK
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;MAGNETIC FIELD VECTOR&apos;
      ------------------------------------------
        A derived parameter which combines the 3 orthogonal magnetic
        field component measurements.
 
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Data Set Parameter Name        : MAGNETIC FIELD VECTOR
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 12.000000
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : 19770820120000.000000
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : UNK
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : 12.000000
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : 0.060000
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : NANOTESLA
        Noise Level                    : 0.006000
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND
 
 
    Source Instrument Parameters
    ============================
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : MAGNETIC FIELD VECTOR
      Instrument Parameter Name       : MAGNETIC FIELD COMPONENT
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : MAGNETIC FIELD VECTOR
      Instrument Parameter Name       : WAVE MAGNETIC FIELD INTENSITY
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      Processing History
      ------------------
        Source Data Set ID    : N/A
        Software              : UNK
        Product Data Set ID   : VG2-N-MAG-4-SUMM-NLSCOORDS-12SEC-V1.0
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      The data provider (Dr. J.E.P.  Connerney) has removed data from
      this dataset which was of questionable quality.  All data in
      this dataset can be used with the highest level of confidence.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XM-11A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

