<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dif-cal-hrii-2-epoxi-calibrations-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>EPOXI INFLIGHT CALIBRATIONS - HRII RAW SPECTRA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.epoxi::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:hrii.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dif-cal-hrii-2-epoxi-calibrations-v1.0__browserp_dif-cal-hrii-2-epoxi-calibrations-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hampton, D.L., J.W. Baer, M.A. Huisjen, C.C. Varner, A. Delamere, D.D.
                   Wellnitz, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, and K.P. Klaasen, An Overview of the Instrument Suite
                   for the Deep Impact Mission, Space Science Reviews, 117, 43-93, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3390-8.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAMPTONETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., B. Carcich, G. Carcich, E.J. Grayzeck, and S. McLaughlin, Deep
                   Impact: The Anticipated Flight Data, Space Science Reviews, 117, 335-372, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3385-5.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., M.F. A&apos;Hearn, M. Baca, A. Delamere, M. Desnoyer, T. Farnham, O.
                   Groussin, D. Hampton, S. Ipatov, J. Li, C. Lisse, N. Mastrodemos, S.
                   McLaughlin, J. Sunshine, P. Thomas, and D. Wellnitz, Deep Impact Instrument
                   Calibration, Rev. Sci. Instrum., 79, 091301, 2008, doi:10.1063/1.2972112.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DIF-CAL-HRII-2-EPOXI-CALIBRATIONS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>EPOXI INFLIGHT CALIBRATIONS - HRII RAW SPECTRA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2009-09-30</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2007-10-04T22:23:49.183Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2008-10-08T15:09:15.244Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STEPHANIE MCLAUGHLIN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            McLaughlin, S.A., B. Carcich, K.P. Klaasen, and D.D. Wellnitz,
            EPOXI INFLIGHT CALIBRATIONS - HRII RAW SPECTRA V1.0,
            DIF-CAL-HRII-2-EPOXI-CALIBRATIONS-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2009.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw calibration spectra acquired by the Deep Impact High
            Resolution Infrared Spectrometer from 04 October 2007 through 08
            October 2008 for the EPOXI mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains raw calibration spectra acquired by the
            Deep Impact High Resolution Infrared Spectrometer from 04 October
            2007 through 08 October 2008 for the EPOXI mission.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set contains version 1.0 of raw calibration data
    acquired by the High Resolution Infrared Spectrometer (HRII)
    during the EPOXI mission.  The data for this version were
    collected from 04 October 2007 through 08 October 2008, during the
    first cruise and EPOCh phases of the mission as well as the early
    part of the second cruise phase.  Future versions of this data set
    will include calibrations acquired during the remaining part of
    the second cruise phase and the 103P/Hartley 2 encounter phase of
    the EPOXI mission.
 
    The purpose of these data are to monitor the HRII spectrometer and
    improve its calibration as needed.  Therefore EPOXI calibration
    activities for the instrument generally followed those designed for
    Deep Impact.  For example standard calibration targets continue to
    include the Moon, 16 Cyg A, 47 Tuc, Beta Hyi, HD 79447, NGC 7027, Vega,
    sky frames, and dark frames.  For a detailed discussion of how these
    data are used to calibrate the instrument, see the Deep Impact
    instrument calibration publication by Klaasen, et al. (2008)
    [KLAASENETAL2006].  The calibration observations for EPOXI are based
    on those designed for Deep Impact which are discussed by Klaasen,
    et al. (2005) [KLAASENETAL2005].
 
      Phase and                                                Exposure ID
      Calibration Activity          Obs Date/DOY    Target    Start    Stop
      ----------------------------  --------------  --------  -------  -------
      Cruise 1
        Instrument Checkout         2007-10-04/277  Sky       1010100  1010107
        Instrument Checkout Retest  2007-12-04/338  Sky       1010200  1010208
        Lunar Calibration           2007-12-29/363  Moon      1000005  1070000
        Standard Cruise Cal         2008-01-09/009  Beta Hyi  2000000  2000001
                                                    HD 79447  2000002  2000002
                                                    47 Tuc    2000003  2000004
                                                    Vega      2010000  2010001
                                                    16 Cyg A  2010002  2010003
                                                    Dark      2011000  2012010
                                                    NGC 7207  2012011  2012012
        Dark Retake for Lunar Cal   2008-01-16/016  Dark      1000000  1000054
                                    2008-01-17/017  Dark      1000005  1000154
      EPOCh
        Darks for Earth Obs #1      2008-03-18/078  Dark      1000000  1000001
                                    2008-03-19/079  Dark      1002024  1002025
        Darks for Earth Obs #4      2008-05-28/149  Dark      1000000  1000001
                                    2008-05-29/150  Dark      1002024  1002025
        Darks for Earth Obs #5      2008-06-04/156  Dark      1000000  1000001
                                    2008-06-05/157  Dark      1002024  1002025
        Standard Cruise Cal         2008-06-23/175  Vega      2010000  2010001
                                                    16 Cyg A  2010002  2010003
                                                    NGC 7207  2010004  2010005
                                                    Dark      2011000  2012020
                                    2008-06-24/176  Beta Hyi  2000000  2000001
                                                    HD 79447  2000002  2000002
                                                    47 Tuc    2000003  2000004
      Cruise 2
        HRII Reciprocity Test       2008-09-18/262  Dark      3200000  3200019
        HRII Dark Flush Test        2008-09-26/270  Dark      3000001  3000011
        HRII Encounter Darks Rerun  2008-10-02/276  Dark      9000030  9020002
        HRII Dark Gap Test          2008-10-08/282  Dark      3100000  3100024
 
      Instrument Checkout:  On 4 October the three science instruments
      were turned on for the first time in more than two years.  Sky
      frames acquired by the HRII spectrometer confirmed the mechanical
      components were functioning.  The instrument exhibited nominal
      behavior of background levels although several detector pixels had
      an odd response when compared to Deep Impact.
 
      Instrument Checkout Retest:  On 4 December 2007 a retest of the
      October instrument checkout sequence was performed for the three
      science instruments.  The focus of this retest was to determine if
      HRII pixels that had an odd response during checkout had changed
      or improved.
 
      Lunar Calibration:  On 29 December 2007 as the spacecraft approached
      Earth, the three science instruments used the Moon as a target to
      acquire data for recalibration purposes.  Due to a minor error in
      the lunar calibration sequence, a series of HRII dark frames were
      not recorded.  A retest to acquire the missing HRII darks was
      scheduled for 16-17 January 2008.
 
      Standard Cruise Calibration:  On 9 January 2008, the first of the
      standard cruise calibrations for the three science instruments was
      performed.  The calibration sequence included observations of
      several standard stars, both solar analogs and hot stars with few
      absorption lines in their spectra for absolute calibration of all
      instruments, a stellar cluster for checking geometric distortion in
      the cameras, and a planetary nebula for checking the wavelength
      calibration of the spectrometer.  This sequence was designed such
      that it could be rerun, with few if any changes, after completion
      of the EPOCh observations and then again just before and just after
      the observing program for comet 103P/Hartley 2.
 
      HRII Dark Retake for Lunar Cal:  Due to a minor error in the lunar
      calibration sequence that was executed in December, a series of HRII
      dark frames was not recorded.  However that sequence was successfully
      rerun for the HRII spectrometer on 16-17 January 2008.
 
      EPOCh Earth Obs Darks:  At the beginning and end of each EPOCh Earth
      observation period, HRII dark frames were acquired for calibration
      purposes and included in this data set.
 
      Standard Cruise Calibration:  A second standard cruise calibration
      was performed on 23-25 June 2008 for the HRII and HRIV instruments.
      The sequence was very similar to that used for the calibration
      performed on 9 January 2008, except the MRI instrument was turned
      off because of thermal and telecommunication concerns.
 
      HRII Reciprocity Test:  On 18 September 2008, an HRII reciprocity
      test was performed to determine the background signal level of the
      READ and RESET frames of the IR spectrometer as a function of the
      past history of integration delay times and the timing gap between
      sets of frames using the diagnostic imaging mode (number 6).  The
      ultimate objective of this test along with the HRII Dark Flush, HRII
      Dark Gap, and HRII Subframe Gain tests performed over the next four
      months is to develop a more accurate model of the variation in the
      background level of the IR spectrometer.   Data from the HRII
      Subframe Gain test performed in late January 2008 will be included
      in version 2.0 of this data set.
 
      HRII Dark Flush Test:  On 26 September 2008, an HRII dark frame
      flush test was performed to determine the type of IR spectrometer
      instrument operation needed to remove all traces of the residual
      (previous) image.
 
      HRII Encounter Darks Rerun:  On 02 October 2008 a set of HRII dark
      frames for several exposure IDs from the Deep Impact Tempel 1
      encounter sequence was acquired.  The exposures were those acquired
      from about 19 minutes before the impact with Tempel 1 through the
      first few hours of lookback imaging.
 
      HRII Dark Gap Test:  On 10 October 2008, an HRII dark gap test was
      performed to characterize the change in the residual image and the
      dark level in the IR spectrometer as a function of wait time and
      number of readouts after acquiring data in the subframe imaging
      modes (numbers 2 and 3).
 
 
    Required Reading
    ---------------
      The following documents are essential for the understanding and
      interpretation of this data set.  Please note the most recent
      version of these documents, including other formats such as ASCII
      text, can be found in the Deep Impact and EPOXI documentation data
      set, DI-C-HRII-HRIV-MRI-ITS-6-DOC-SET-V2.0.
 
      EPOXI_SIS.PDF
        - The Archive Volume and Data Product Software Interface
          Specifications document (SIS) describes the the data set, the
          science data products, and defines keywords in the PDS labels.
 
      CALIBRATION_PAPER_DRAFT.PDF
        - The Deep Impact instrument calibration paper by Klaasen, et al.
          (2008) [KLAASENETAL2006] describes how the instruments were
          calibrated for Deep Impact and similarly for EPOXI and explains
          the calibration process used for both missions.  The published
          version should be available online in the Review of Scientific
          Instruments by the American Institute of Physics.  The EPOXI
          archive provides only an incomplete draft.
 
      INSTRUMENTS_HAMPTON.PDF
        - The Deep Impact instruments paper by Hampton, et al. (2005)
          [HAMPTONETAL2005] provides very detailed descriptions of the
          instruments.
 
      HRII_2_EPOXI_CALIBRATIONS.TAB
        - This ASCII table provides image parameters such as the mid-obs
          Julian date, exposure time, mission activity type, and
          description or purpose for each observation (i.e., data product)
          in this data set.  This file is very useful for determining which
          data files to work with.
 
 
    Related Data Sets
    -----------------
      The following PDS data sets are related to this one and may be useful
      for calibration purposes:
 
      DIF-E-HRII-2-EPOXI-EARTH-V1.0
      DIF-E-HRII-3/4-EPOXI-EARTH-V1.0
        - Raw and calibrated HRII Earth observations
 
      DIF-C-HRII-2-EPOXI-HARTLEY2-V1.0
      DIF-C-HRII-3/4-EPOXI-HARTLEY2-V1.0
        - Raw and calibrated HRII comet Hartley 2 observations (to be
          delivered in 2011)
 
      DI-C-HRII-HRIV-MRI-ITS-6-DOC-SET-V2.0
        - Deep Impact and EPOXI documentation set
 
      DIF-C/E/X-SPICE-6-V1.0
        - EPOXI SPICE kernels
 
      DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV/MRI-6-EPOXI-TEMPS-V1.0
        - HRII, HRIV, and MRI instrument thermal telemetry data for EPOXI
          which may be useful for determining how temperature fluctuations
          affect the science instruments, in particular the IR spectrometer
 
      DIF-CAL-HRII-2-9P-CRUISE-V1.0
      DIF-CAL-HRII-2-9P-ENCOUNTER-V1.0
        - Deep Impact raw HRII calibrations data sets from 2005
 
      DIF-CAL-HRII-2-GROUND-TV1-V1.0
      DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV-2-GROUND-TV2-V1.0
      DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV/MRI-2-GROUND-TV4-V1.0
        - Deep Impact raw HRII pre-launch calibrations from 2002 and 2003
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The raw two-dimensional (wavelength and spatial/along-slit) FITS
    spectral images and PDS labels in this data set were generated by the
    Deep Impact/EPOXI data pipeline, maintained by the project&apos;s Science
    Data Center (SDC) at Cornell University.  The FITS data were assembled
    from raw telemetry packets sent down by the flyby spacecraft.
    Information from the embedded spacecraft header (the first 100 bytes of
    quadrant A image data) was extracted and stored in the primary FITS
    header.  Geometric parameters were computed using the best available
    SPICE kernels and the results were also stored in the FITS header.  If
    telemetry packets were missing, the corresponding pixels were flagged
    as missing in the quality map included as a FITS image extension.  The
    quadrant nomenclature and the image quality map are described in the
    Deep Impact instrument calibration document and the EPOXI SIS document
    included in this data set.  The SDC did not apply any type of
    correction or decompression algorithm to the raw data.
 
 
  Data
  ====
 
    FITS Images and PDS Labels
    --------------------------
      Each raw spectral image is stored as FITS.  The primary data unit
      contains the two-dimensional spectral image, with the fastest
      varying axis corresponding to increasing wavelengths from about
      1.05 to 4.8 microns and the slowest varying axis corresponding to
      the spatial or along-slit dimension.  The primary array is
      followed by one image extension that contains a two-dimensional
      pixel-by-pixel quality map.  This extension uses one byte of eight
      bit flags to indicate the quality of each pixel in the primary
      image.  The data label provides a short description of each bit.
      For more information about the FITS primary image and its
      extension or for examples of how to access and use the quality
      flags, refer to the EPOXI SIS document or the Deep Impact
      instrument calibration document.
 
      Each FITS file is accompanied by a detached PDS data label.  The
      EPOXI SIS document provides definitions for the keywords found in a
      data label.
 
 
    File Naming Convention
    ----------------------
      The naming convention for the raw data labels and FITS files is
      HIyymmddhh_eeeeeee_nnn.LBL or FIT where &apos;HI&apos; identifies the HRII
      instrument, yymmddhh provides the UTC year, month, day, and hour at
      the mid-point of the observation, eeeeeee is the exposure ID
      (OBSERVATION_ID in data labels), and nnn provides the image number
      (IMAGE_NUMBER in the data labels) within the exposure ID.
 
      Up to 999 individual images can be commanded for one exposure ID.
      Spectral scans often had 32 or more frames for one specific exposure.
      Therefore, nnn in the file name provides the sequentially increasing
      frame number within an exposure ID and corresponds to IMAGE_NUMBER in
      the data labels.  For example, if 32 frames were commanded for a scan
      with an exposure ID of 1000001, the first FITS file name would be
      HI08060416_1000001_001.FIT and the last would be
      HI08060416_1000001_032.FIT.
 
 
    Image Compression
    -----------------
      Although raw data numbers for HRII frames could be compressed on
      board the flyby spacecraft by use of a lookup table then downlinked,
      processed, and archived in the same format, all calibration-related
      spectra acquired during the time period covered by this data set
      were never compressed.  A compressed image is identified by the
      value &apos;COMPRESSED&apos; in the COMPRESSED_IMAGE_VALUE keyword in the data
      labels or the COMPRESS keyword in the FITS headers.  For more
      information about this topic, see the image compression section of
      the Deep Impact instrument calibration documents.
 
 
    Image Orientation
    -----------------
      A true-sky &apos;as seen by the observer&apos; view is achieved by displaying
      the image using the standard FITS convention:  the fastest-varying
      axis (samples or wavelength) increasing to the right in the display
      window and the slowest-varying axis (lines or spatial/along-slit)
      increasing to the top.  This convention is identified in the data
      labels:  the SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION keyword is set to RIGHT and
      LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION to UP.
 
      The direction to celestial north, ecliptic north, and the Sun is
      provided in data labels by CELESTIAL_NORTH_CLOCK_ANGLE,
      ECLIPTIC_NORTH_CLOCK_ANGLE, and SUN_DIRECTION_CLOCK_ANGLE keywords
      and are measured clockwise from the top of the image when is
      displayed in the correct orientation as defined by
      SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION and LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION.  Please note
      the aspect of the North celestial pole in an image can be computed
      by adding 90 degrees to the boresight declination given by
      DECLINATION in the data labels.
 
      For a comparison of the orientation FITS image data from the three
      science instruments, see the quadrant nomenclature section of the
      Deep Impact instrument calibration document.  Also the EPOXI SIS
      has a brief discussion of this topic.
 
 
    IR Slit Location
    ----------------
      For a comparison of the relative locations of the IR slit with
      respect to the fields of view of the Medium Resolution Instrument
      Visible CCD (MRI) and the High Resolution Instrument Visible CCD
      (HRIV), see the relative boresight alignments section of the
      Deep Impact instrument calibration document.
 
 
    Timing for Spectra
    ------------------
      It is important to note that the readout order of the IR detector
      affects the timing of the spectra.  When a HRII spectral image is
      displayed using the true-sky convention, the wavelength increases
      horizontally to the right and the spatial or along-slit direction
      is vertical.  In this orientation, the IR detector was read out
      from the left and right edges and toward the center and starting
      with the first row at the bottom and ending with the last row at
      the top of the display.  Since the detector is reset and read out
      on a pixel-by-pixel basis, the read out order affects the time at
      which each pixel is exposed, although each pixel has the same
      exposure duration.  Additionally, the end of the spectrometer slit
      that always points roughly towards the sun is the first line to be
      readout and the last line to be read out is furthest from the sun,
      assuming the spacecraft is in its usual orientation with the solar
      pointing roughly toward the sun.  For more information about the
      timing of the spectra, see the IR focal plane and quadrant
      nomenclature sections of the Deep Impact instrument calibration
      document.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
    Data Units
    ----------
      Raw image data are in units of raw data numbers.
 
 
    Target Name and Description
    ---------------------------
      The TARGET_NAME keyword in the data labels is set to the intended
      target, &apos;CALIBRATION&apos;, for each observation in this data set. The
      TARGET_DESC keyword provides the name of the specific calibration
      target, such as &apos;DARK&apos; or &apos;VEGA&apos;.
 
 
    Imaging Modes
    -------------
      For a thorough description of the imaging modes, please see the
      Deep Impact instruments document or the Deep Impact instrument
      calibration document.  Also the EPOXI SIS has a brief discussion of
      this topic.  A summary of the imaging modes is provided here.  In
      the table below, X-Size is the spectral dimension and Y-Size is the
      spatial dimension.
 
                    X-Size  Y-Size  Bin
        Mode Name   (pix)   (pix)  Type  Comments
        ---- ------ ------  -----  ----- ---------------------------------
          1  BINFF    512     256   2x2  Binned full frame
          2  BINSF1   512     126   2x2  Binned sub-frame
          3  BINSF2   512      64   2x2  Binned sub-frame
          4  UBFF    1024     512   1x1  Unbinned full frame
          5  ALTFF    512     256   2x2  Alternate mode 1 (min. exposure
                                         time is 1/2 of mode 1)
          6  DIAG    1024     512   1x1  Diagnostic, one reset frame
                                         followed by a separate read frame
          7  MEMCK   1024     512   1x1  Memory Check
 
 
    Time- and Geometry-Related Keywords
    -----------------------------------
      All time-related keywords in the data labels, except
      EARTH_OBSERVER_MID_TIME, are based on the clock on board the flyby
      spacecraft.  EARTH_OBSERVER_MID_TIME provides the UTC when an
      Earth-based observer should have been able to see an event recorded
      by the instrument.
 
      The SDC pipeline was not able to automatically determine the proper
      geometric information for the target of choice in some cases.  When
      these parameters could not be computed, the corresponding keywords
      in the data labels are set to a value of unknown, &apos;UNK&apos;.  Also if
      GEOMETRY_QUALITY_FLAG is set to &apos;BAD&apos; or GEOMETRY_TYPE is set to
      &apos;PREDICTED&apos; in the PDS labels, then this indicates the geometry
      values may not be accurate and should be used with caution.  The
      value &apos;N/A&apos; is used for some geometry-related keywords in the data
      labels because these parameters are not applicable for certain
      calibration targets.
 
      Observational geometry parameters provided in the data labels were
      computed at the epoch specified by the mid-obs UTC, IMAGE_MID_TIME,
      in the data labels.  The exceptions are the target-to-sun values
      that were calculated for the time when the light arrived at the
      target and the earth-observer-to-target values that were calculated
      for the time when the light left the target.
 
      The flyby spacecraft clock SPICE kernels (SCLK) used to convert to
      UTC and to calculate geometry-related parameters for this data set
      have a known accuracy of no better than 0.5 seconds.  However as
      this data set was being produced, the mission operations team
      figured out how to correct raw clock correlation data for the
      flyby spacecraft to allow timing fits that are accurate to at
      least the sub-second level.  The project plans to generate a
      complete, corrected set of correlations since launch.  This will
      ultimately result in a future version of a SCLK kernel that will
      retroactively change correlation for **all** Deep Impact and EPOXI
      data.  When this kernel is available, it will be added to the
      SPICE data sets for the two missions and posted on the NAIF/SPICE
      web site at http://naif.jpl.nasa.gov/naif/.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    The geometric parameters included in the data labels and FITS headers
    were computed using the best available SPICE kernels at the time the
    data products were generated.  NAIF used these kernels to produce the
    EPOXI SPICE data set, DIF-C/E/X-SPICE-6-V1.0.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    Earth Mean Equator and Vernal Equinox of J2000 (EME J2000) is the
    inertial reference system used to specify observational geometry
    parameters in the data labels.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The observations in this data set are in standard FITS format with PDS
    labels, and can be viewed by a number of PDS-provided and commercial
    programs.  For this reason no special software is provided with this
    data set.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The FITS files in this data set were reviewed internally by the EPOXI
    project and were used extensively by the science teams to improve
    the calibration of instrument.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    This data set is archived at the PDS Small Bodies Node (SBN) and the
    Multi-Mission Archive at STScI (MAST).  It passed a peer review held
    by SBN on 23 July 2009; MAST personnel participated.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    There are no unexpected gaps in this data set.  All calibration
    observations received on the ground were processed and included in this
    data set.
 
    Horizontal striping through some images indicates missing data.  The
    image quality map extension identifies where pixels are missing.  If
    the second most-significant bit of a pixel in the image quality map is
    turned on, then data for the corresponding image pixel is missing.  For
    more information, refer to EPOXI SIS document.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
 
    HRI Telescope Focus
    -------------------
      Images of stars acquired early during the Deep Impact mission in 2005
      indicated the HRI telescope was out of focus.  However, this focus
      problem does not significantly affect the HRII instrument.  For more
      details, please see the instrument calibration paper by Klaasen,
      et al. (2008) [KLAASENETAL2006].
 
 
    Displaying Images
    -----------------
      Flight software writes an image header over the first 100 bytes of
      quadrant A.  These image header pixels were included in the raw FITS
      images.  Since the values in these pixels vary dramatically, it is
      recommended that the values of the MINIMUM and MAXIMUM keywords in
      the data label (or the MINPVAL and MAXPVAL in the FITS header) be
      used to scale an image for display because these values exclude the
      header bytes as well as the reference rows and columns located around
      the edge of the spectral image.  For more information, see the
      quadrant nomenclature section of the Deep Impact instrument
      calibration document or the EPOXI SIS document.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SUPERSEDED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

