<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.nh-x-swap-2-launch-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>NEW HORIZONS SWAP POST-LAUNCH CHECKOUT V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.new_horizons::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.nh::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:swap.nh::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:plasma_stream.solar_wind::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.nh-x-swap-2-launch-v1.0__browserp_nh-x-swap-2-launch-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>NH-X-SWAP-2-LAUNCH-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>NEW HORIZONS SWAP POST-LAUNCH CHECKOUT V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2007-12-13</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2006-01-19T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2007-01-01T00:00:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JOSEPH PETERSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            McComas, D., NEW HORIZONS SWAP POST-LAUNCH CHECKOUT V1.0,
            NH-X-SWAP-2-LAUNCH-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2007.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw data taken by New Horizons Solar Wind Around Pluto instrument
            during the LAUNCH mission phase.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains Raw data taken by the New Horizons Solar
            Wind Around Pluto instrument during the post-launch checkout
            mission phase.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
 
      This data set contains Raw data taken by New Horizons
        Solar Wind Around Pluto
      instrument during the LAUNCH mission phase.
 
      During Post-Launch mission phase, the SWAP team ran a series of
      engineering tests and some preliminary science observations.
      Below is a list and dates for these various commissioning tests.
      The first solar wind observations occurred in SWAP-009.
      SWAP-006 provided the first count rate measurements taken in
      engineering mode (not sweeping).  In this test the ESA and
      deflector voltages were varied.  SWAP-007 was a sequenced
      version of the test performed in SWAP-006.  SWAP-009 part 5 was
      a test performed in engineering mode stepping through some of
      the same ESA and deflector voltages used in SWAP-006 and -007.
      The first sweeping science observations were performed in
      SWAP-008 where the science team turned the instrument away from
      the Sun and took observations using voltages planned for Pluto.
      The first solar wind observations were performed in SWAP-009
      part 2, which had the RPA Voltage set to 103% of ESA energy.
      This resulted in an automatic shut down since these voltage
      settings were not sufficient to reduce the passband to the point
      where the detected count rates were safe.  In SWAP-009 part 6
      the team adjusted the percent crossing to 105% and then took
      small amounts of data across many days.  Observations in
      SWAP-009 part 6 consist of 6 minutes of data on each given day.
      Only parts 2, 5 &amp; 6 of SWAP-009 were run; parts 1, 3 &amp; 4 were
      never run and are not included here.
 
      SWAP-001 Aliveness Test (Feb 27, 2006)
      SWAP-002 Low Voltage Functional (Feb 27, 2006)
      SWAP-004 Memory Test (Feb 28, 2006)
      SWAP-005 Door Opening (March 13th, 2006)
      SWAP-006 High Voltage Ramp (March 28 &amp; 30 2006)
      SWAP-007 Sequenced High Voltage Ramp (June 5, 2006)
      SWAP-008 High Voltage Science With No Solar wind (Sept 1, 2006)
      SWAP-009 Solar Wind Measurements and DFL-ESA test
 
      Load    Date                 SC Time        MET
      - Test Name, Part Number (Description)
 
      06265  September 27, 2006    267 20:00:07   21433924
      - SWAP-009 pt 2 (First HVSCI 103% crossing)
 
      06275  October 7, 2006       280 10:00:02   22521119
      - SWAP-009 pt 5 (DFL-ESA)
 
      06298  November 1, 2006      305 02:02:43   24652480
      - SWAP-009 Pt 6 (HVSCI 105% crossing)
 
      06298  November 2, 2006      306 02:02:43   24738880
      - SWAP-009 Pt 6 (HVSCI 105% crossing)
 
      06298  November 3, 2006      307 03:03:31   24828928
      - SWAP-009 Pt 6 (HVSCI 105% crossing)
 
      06298  November 4, 2006      308 03:03:31   24915328
      - SWAP-009 Pt 6 (HVSCI 105% crossing)
 
      06298  November 5, 2006      309 03:03:31   25001728
      - SWAP-009 Pt 6 (HVSCI 105% crossing)
 
      06309  November 12, 2006     316 00:03:15   25595712
      - SWAP-009 Pt 6 (HVSCI 105% crossing)
 
      06309  November 13, 2006     317 00:03:15   25682112
      - SWAP-009 Pt 6 (HVSCI 105% crossing)
 
      06309  November 14, 2006     318 00:03:15   25768512
      - SWAP-009 Pt 6 (HVSCI 105% crossing)
 
      06309  November 15, 2006     319 01:02:59   25858496
      - SWAP-009 Pt 6 (HVSCI 105% crossing)
 
      06309  November 16, 2006     320 01:02:59   25944896
      - SWAP-009 Pt 6 (HVSCI 105% crossing)
 
      06309  November 17, 2006     321 01:02:59   26031296
      - SWAP-009 Pt 6 (HVSCI 105% crossing)
 
      06322  November 30, 2006     334 10:02:43   27186880
      - SWAP-009 Pt 6 (HVSCI 105% crossing)
 
      06322  December 1, 2006      335 10:02:43   27273280
      - SWAP-009 Pt 6 (HVSCI 105% crossing)
 
      06322  December 2, 2006      336 10:02:43   27359680
      - SWAP-009 Pt 6 (HVSCI 105% crossing)
 
      06322  December 3, 2006      337 11:03:31   27449728
      - SWAP-009 Pt 6 (HVSCI 105% crossing)
 
      06322  December 4, 2006      338 11:03:31   27536128
      - SWAP-009 Pt 6 (HVSCI 105% crossing)
 
      06322  December 5, 2006      339 11:03:31   27622528
      - SWAP-009 Pt 6 (HVSCI 105% crossing)
 
      06340  December 9, 2006      343 04:03:15   27942912
      - SWAP-009 Pt 6 (HVSCI 105% crossing)
 
      06340  December 10, 2006     344 04:03:15   28029312
      - SWAP-009 Pt 6 (HVSCI 105% crossing)
 
      06340  December 11, 2006     345 04:03:15   28115712
      - SWAP-009 Pt 6 (HVSCI 105% crossing)
 
      Every observation provided in this data set was taken as a part of a
      particular sequence.  A list of these sequences follows:
 
      Sequence IDs &amp; start times (end times are the start times
      of the following Sequence IDs) for the SWAP instrument
      during the LAUNCH phase of the New Horizons Mission
      =========================================================
 
      Sequence ID:  COSW_CHECKOUT
      Start UTC:    2006-01-18T00:00:00
      Description:  COMMISSIONING:  Turn-on &amp; checkout
 
      Sequence ID:  COSW_SCIENCE
      Start UTC:    2006-04-01T00:00:00
      Description:  COMMISSIONING:  Science
 
      Sequence ID:  JESW_PLACEHOLDER
      Start UTC:    2007-01-01T00:00:00
      Description:  The SWAP instrument did not have any sequenced data
                    taken during Jupiter encounter.  This entry is only a
                    placeholder to cover any data that exist.
 
      For the list of observations and their parameters, refer to
      the data set index table (typically INDEX.TAB &amp; CUMINDEX.TAB,
      initially in the /INDEX/ area of the data set).
 
 
    Time
    ====
 
      There are several time systems, or units, in use in this dataset:
      New Horizons spacecraft MET (Mission Event Time or Mission Elapsed
      Time), UTC (Coordinated Universal Time), and TDB Barycentric
      Dynamical Time.
 
      This section will give a summary description of the relationship
      between these time systems.  For a complete explanation of these
      time systems the reader is referred to the documentation
      distributed with the NAIF/SPICE toolkit from the NAIF PDS node.
 
      The most common time unit associated with the data is is the
      spacecraft MET.  MET is a 32-bit counter on the New Horizons
      spacecraft that runs at a rate of about one increment per second
      starting from a value of zero at
 
        19.January, 2006 18:08:02 UTC
 
      or
 
        JD2453755.256337 TDB.
 
      The leapsecond adjustment (DELTA_ET = ET - UTC) over this dataset
      is 65.184s.
 
      The data labels for any given product in this dataset usually
      contain at least one pair of common UTC and MET representations
      of the time at the middle of the observation.  Other portions
      of the products, for example tables of data taken over periods
      of up to a day or more, will only have the MET time associated
      with a given row of the table.
 
      For the data user&apos;s use in interpreting these times, a reasonable
      approximation (+/- 1s) of the conversion between Julian Day (TDB)
      and MET is as follows:
 
        JD TDB = 2453755.256337 + ( MET / 86399.9998693 )
 
      For more accurate calculations the reader is referred to the
      NAIF/SPICE documentation as mentioned above.
 
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      The data in this data set were created by a software data
      processing pipeline on the Science Operation Center (SOC) at
      the Southwest Research Institute (SWRI), Department of Space Studies.
      This SOC pipeline assembled data as FITS files from raw telemetry
      packets sent down by the spacecraft and populated the data labels
      with housekeeping and engineering values, and computed geometry
      parameters using SPICE kernels. The pipeline did not resample
      the data.
 
 
    Data
    ====
 
      The observations in this data set are stored in data files using
      standard Flexible Image Transport Sytem (FITS) format.  Each FITS
      file has a corresponding detached PDS label file, named according
      to a common convention.  The FITS files have image and/or table
      extensions; see the PDS label plus the DOCUMENT files for a
      description of these extensions and their contents.
 
 
      This Data section comprises the following sub-topics:
 
      - Filename/Product IDs
      - CODMAC Level 2 SWAP data details
      - Instrument description
      - Visit Description, Visit Number, and Target in the Data Labels
      - Unresolved Liens on the Data
 
 
      Filename/Product IDs
      --------------------
 
        The filenames and product IDs of observations adhere to a
        common convention e.g.
 
         ALI_0123456789_0X0AB_ENG_1.FIT
         ^^^ ^^^^^^^^^^ ^^^^^ ^^^ ^\__/
         |        |       |    |  | ^^
         |        |       |    |  |  |
         |        |       |    |  |  +--File type (includes dot)
         |        |       |    |  |     - .FIT for FITS file
         |        |       |    |  |     - .LBL for PDS label
         |        |       |    |  |     - not part of product ID
         |        |       |    |  |
         |        |       |    |  +-- Version number from the SOC
         |        |       |    |      (Science Operations Center)
         |        |       |    |
         |        |       |    +--ENG for CODMAC Level 2 data *
         |        |       |       SCI for CODMAC Level 3 data *
         |        |       |
         |        |       +--Application ID (ApID) of the telemetry data
         |        |          packet from which the data come
         |        |
         |        +--MET (Mission Event Time) i.e. Spacecraft Clock
         |
         +--Instrument/observation designator
 
          * For those datasets where the NH project is delivering
            CODMAC Level 1 &amp; 2 data (REX &amp; PEPSSI), ENG and SCI apply
            to CODMAC Level 1 &amp; 2 data, respectively.
 
 
        Instrument   Instrument/observation designators  ApIDs
        ===========  ==================================  =============
         SWAP         SWA                                0X584 - 0X586
 
         * Not all values in this range are used
 
         There are other ApIDs that contain housekeeping values and
         other values.  See the documentation for more details.
 
 
        Here is a summary of the types of files generated by each APiD:
 
 
      ApIDs   Data product description
      =====   ========================
      0x584 - SWAP Science Real-Time
      0x585 - SWAP Science Summary
      0x586 - SWAP Science Histogram Header
      0x587 - SWAP Science Histogram Data
 
 
 
      Instrument description
      ----------------------
 
        Refer to the following files for a description of this instrument.
 
        CATALOG
 
          SWAP.CAT
 
        DOCUMENTS
 
          SWAP_SSR.*
          NH_SWAP_V###_TI.TXT  (### is a version number)
          SOC_INST_ICD.*
 
 
      Visit Description, Visit Number, and Target in the Data Labels
      ---------------------------------------------------------------
 
        The observation sequences were defined in Science Activity
        Planning (SAP) documents, and grouped by Visit Description and
        Visit Number.  The SAPs are spreadsheets with one Visit Description
        &amp; Number per row.  A nominal target is also included on each row
        and included in the data labels, but does not always match with the
        TARGET_NAME field&apos;s value in the data labels.  In some cases, the
        target was designated as RA,DEC pointing values in the form
        ``RADEC=123.45,-12.34&apos;&apos; indicating Right Ascension and Declination,
        in degrees, of the target from the spacecraft in the Earth
        Equatorial J2000 inertial reference frame.  This indicates either
        that the target was either a star, or that the target&apos;s ephemeris
        was not loaded into the spacecraft&apos;s attitude and control system
        which in turn meant the spacecraft could not be pointed at the
        target by a body identifier and an inertial pointing value had to
        be specified as Right Ascension and Declination values.  The PDS
        standards do not allow putting a value like RADEC=... in the PDS
        TARGET_NAME keyword&apos;s value; in those cases the PDS TARGET_NAME
        value is set to CALIBRATION.
 
 
      Unresolved Liens on the Data
      ----------------------------
 
        None exist at the present time.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
 
      The geometry items included in the data labels were computed
      using the SPICE kernels archived in the New Horizons SPICE
      data set, NH-X-SPICE-6-LAUNCH-V1.0.
 
 
    Reference Frame
    ===============
 
 
      Geometric Parameter Reference Frame
      -----------------------------------
        Earth Mean Equator and Vernal Equinox of J2000 (EMEJ2000) is the
        inertial reference frame used to specify observational geometry
        items provided in the data labels.  Geometric parameters are based
        on best available SPICE data at time of data creation.
 
 
      Epoch of Geometric Parameters
      -----------------------------
        All geometric parameters provided in the data labels were
        computed at the epoch midway between the START_TIME and
        STOP_TIME label fields.
 
 
 
    Software
    ========
 
      The observations in this data set are in standard FITS format
      with PDS labels, and can be viewed by a number of PDS-provided
      and commercial programs. For this reason no special software is
      provided with this data set.
 
 
    Contact Information
    ===================
 
      For any questions regarding the data format of the archive,
      contact the person whose PDS_USER_ID is DMCCOMAS
      as described in PERSONNEL.CAT.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      During the processing of the data in preparation for
      delivery with this volume, the packet data associated with each
      observation were used only if they passed a rigorous verification
      process including standard checksums.
    Review
    ======
      The data have been reviewed and validated by the instrument team
      members, as well as by SOC personnel.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SUPERSEDED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>PSFP-00269</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

