<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.sdu-c-dfmi-2-edr-wild2-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>STARDUST DFMI WILD 2 ENCOUNTER EDR DATA</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.stardust::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.sdu::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:dfmi.sdu::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.81p-wild_2_1978_a2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.sdu-c-dfmi-2-edr-wild2-v1.0__browserp_sdu-c-dfmi-2-edr-wild2-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tuzzolino, A.J., T.E. Economou, R.B. McKibben, J.A. Simpson, J.A.M. McDonnell,
                   M.J. Burchell, B.A.M. Vaughan, P. Tsou, M.S. Hanner, B.C. Clark, and D.E.
                   Brownlee, Dust Flux Monitor Instrument for the Stardust mission to comet Wild
                   2, J. Geophys. Res., 108, (E10), 8115, 2003, doi:10.1029/2003JE002086.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TUZZOLINOETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>SDU-C-DFMI-2-EDR-WILD2-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>STARDUST DFMI WILD 2 ENCOUNTER EDR DATA</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2004-07-02</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-01-02T19:08:15.442Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2004-01-02T19:41:17.725Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STARDUST DATA MANAGEMENT AND ARCHIVE TEAM</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Semenov, B.V., A.J. Tuzzolino, J.A.M. McDonnell, H.W. Taylor, and
            C.H. Acton, STARDUST DFMI WILD 2 ENCOUNTER EDR DATA,
            SDU-C-DFMI-2-EDR-WILD2-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            EDR data collected by the STARDUST Dust Flux Monitor Instrument
            (DFMI) during Wild 2 encounter.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains raw data collected by the Dust Flux
            Monitor Instrument (DFMI) flown on board the STARDUST spacecraft
            during the Wild 2 comet encounter on January 2, 2004. The data in
            this archive are organized into one table in standard PDS format.
            This table records dust events which resulted from the encounter
            with the particles surrounding comet Wild 2. The data in the
            table spans a 33 minute period surrounding the encounter with
            Wild 2.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview:
    =================
      This data set contains raw data collected by the Dust Flux
      Monitor Instrument (DFMI) flown on board the STARDUST spacecraft
      during the Wild 2 comet encounter on January 2, 2004. The data in
      this archive are organized into one table in standard PDS format.
      This table records dust events which resulted from the encounter
      with the particles surrounding comet Wild 2. The data in the
      table spans a 33 minute period surrounding the encounter with
      Wild 2.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      The primary data parameters contained in the DFMI data table are
      counts of the particle impacts measured by the instrument
      sensors.
 
      Note Regarding Acoustic Sensor Counts
      -------------------------------------
      At the external peer review reviewers noted that the acoustic
      sensor values around close approach, particularly the high and
      low bumpers, did not seem reasonble because the cumulative count
      was not strictly monotonically increasing.
 
      The DFMI team provided the following clarification:
 
        The acoustic sensor counters counted the number of time
        intervals that the signal from the sensor exceeded a certain
        threshold.  This meant that a large impact would produce a
        large number of counts and a small one a small number.  Since
        the count rate was generally expected to be very low, the
        possibility of confusion (i.e. not knowing if the number of
        counts was due to one, two or more actual impacts) was not
        expected to be a major problem.  The strength of this approach
        was that an indication of the mass of particles could be
        obtained even when the peak signal from the sensor saturated
        the instrument. The disadvantage was the possibility of multiple
        impacts in a counting period (0.1 to 1 sec depending on PVDF
        trigger) and the possibility of multiple counter overflow. As
        the acoustic subsystem was a last minute addition after the data
        rates had already been fixed, the counters had a full range of
        only 0 to 255. This explains the steps in the counts.  The
        counters start at zero and increment each time there is an
        impact.  Several times during the encounter (~9), the counters
        overflow. From the statistical analysis it looks as if there are
        no multiple overflows (i.e., counts greater than 256 within a
        time interval).
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The Stardust DFMI instrument output consisted of binary data
      records containing counter values for each of the sensor
      channels. On board the spacecraft these records were packetized
      by the spacecraft&apos;s flight software and downlinked within packets
      in the spacecraft telemetry stream.
 
      A suite of software -- developed and run by the Stardust Data
      Management and Archive Team (DMA) and collectively referred to as
      Stardust Science Telemetry Processing Software -- retrieved
      packets with DFMI data from the Telemetry Data Server(s)(TDS)
      used by the Stardust Project, stripped off ground system and
      spacecraft packet headers, extracted counter values and
      housekeeping information from the packets, augmented them with a
      number of geometry parameters computed using mission SPICE
      geometry data and operating temperature information extracted
      from channelized telemetry, and output all the above-mentioned
      parameters in PDS text table format.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      The DFMI data file provided in this data set contains counts of
      the particle impacts measured by the instrument sensors,
      housekeeping values downlinked in the same packets as counts,
      housekeeping values downlinked in the channelized telemetry, and
      a number of geometry parameters computed using SPICE kernels.
 
      This file is a plain ASCII text file containing a single
      PDS-style table with fixed-width, comma-delimited columns. The
      table is preceded by a CSV header. The file is accompanied by a
      detached PDS label, described in detail in the ONLABELS.TXT
      document included in the archive. The format of the table columns
      is defined by an external table format file, pointed to by the
      label.
 
 
    Calibration
    ===========
      The best available calibration data as of this writing (October
      2005) are the values listed in Table 4 of Tuzzolino, et al. (2003).
 
      The DFMI team note:
 
        The main uncertainty in calibration comes from the fact that
        the calibration was done for soda lime glass and aluminum
        particles but real particles are of different composition and
        we do not know how well this calibration reproduces, say,
        organic, ice, or carbon particles. Also, the calibration
        samples were spheres whereas the real particles are irregular.
        The influence of this is also hard to estimate quantitatively.
        The team is convinced that the slope of the calibration lines
        is correct but the reference point can be shifted up or down
        by the way they cannot estimate.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      Each of the records in the DFMI table includes a number of
      derived geometry parameters. These parameters were computed using
      the following SPICE kernels, archived in the Stardust SPICE data
      set, SDU-C-SPICE-6-V1.0:
 
        Kernel Type   File Name
        ------------  ------------------------
        LSK           naif0007.tls
        PCK           pck00007.tpc
        SCLK          sdu_sclkscet_00105.tsc
        FK            sdu_v17.tf
        SPKs          sdu_l_2003_w2.bsp
                      sdu_w2_opnav.bsp
        CKs           sdu_sc_rec_2003_w2_v2.bc
                      sdu_sc_rec_w2_opnav.bc
        ------------  ------------------------
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      The geometry items provided in the EDR table are relative to the
      ecliptic reference frame of J2000 (Ecliptic North/Equinox vector
      of 2000 JAN 01 12:00 TDB.)
 
 
    Software
    ========
      The data in this data set are in standard PDS format and,
      therefore, can be displayed by a number of PDS-provided tools or
      loaded into commercial programs that support comma-delimited
      formats. For this reason no special processing software is
      included in this data set.
 
 
    Contact Information
    ===================
      For any questions regarding the data in this archive, contact:
 
        Dr. Tony Tuzzolino, Stardust DFMI Science Lead
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      During the processing of the data in preparation for delivery
      with this volume, the structure of each data packet was verified.
      This verification included detection of both the sync word and
      the length of each packet, which assured that all packets were
      complete and not damaged. Samples of the data were plotted to
      help validate them.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This data was reviewed by the DFMI science team members as part
      of the post-encounter data analysis activities.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      This set includes all data produced by the DFMI instrument during
      the time it was on for the Wild 2 encounter. None of the packets
      used in the production of this data were damaged in any way.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      None.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

