<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.stardust-c-e-l-nc-2-edr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>STARDUST NAVCAM EARLY CRUISE IMAGES</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.stardust::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.sdu::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:navcam.sdu::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calimg::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.stardust-c-e-l-nc-2-edr-v1.0__browserp_stardust-c-e-l-nc-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>STARDUST-C/E/L-NC-2-EDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>STARDUST NAVCAM EARLY CRUISE IMAGES</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2001-11-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1999-03-19T01:44:45.596Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2001-10-29T20:45:33.869Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>APPLIED COHERENT TECHNOLOGY CORPORATION</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Hash, C., R. L. Newburn, B. Semenov, STARDUST NAVCAM EARLY CRUISE
            IMAGES, STARDUST-C/E/L-NC-2-EDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2001.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Early cruise images from the Stardust navigation camera. These
            images are of no clear scientific or engineering use.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This volume contains the results of the early cruise images of
            the Stardust Navigation Camera. These images are of no clear
            scientific or engineering use. They were acquired to ascertain
            the state of the camera during a time of successive
            contaminations and decontamination actions, as described in
            detail below. None are considered useful for calibration of
            future scientific images, given the nearly continuous changes in
            the state of the camera during this period.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This volume contains the results of the early cruise images of the
    Stardust Navigation Camera.  These images are of no clear scientific or
    engineering use. They were acquired to ascertain the state of the
    camera during a time of successive contaminations and decontamination
    actions, as described in detail below. None are considered useful for
    calibration of future scientific images, given the nearly continuous
    changes in the state of the camera during this period.
 
    A total of 203 images have been acquired by the STARDUST mission as of
    29 October 2001. Some of these were taken for geometric and photometric
    calibration, but the majority were acquired to check on the state of
    the camera during decontamination procedures made necessary by
    contamination from unknown sources near the time of launch. As of this
    date, the camera is exhibiting near theoretical performance, except for
    a filter wheel failure. On February 26, 2001, the filter  wheel
    suddenly failed to advance on command, remaining in the OpNav (#0)
    position. Fortunately OpNav is one of the two broadband filters, and
    &gt;95% of the mission can still be accomplished without difficulty. There
    simply will be no composite color images of the comet nucleus.
 
    One or more images have been acquired on 31 different dates. A very
    brief description of the rationale for each session and the results
    obtained follows.
 
    #1 - 3/19/99   A series of 27 images was planned to thoroughly check
    out the camera. The spacecraft safed itself after three images, a bias
    (zero exposure) frame and two narrow band frames taken at 100 ms
    exposure. None showed anything, which seemed strange. (Images 1-3)
 
    #2 - 10/21/99   Various spacecraft software conflicts having been
    resolved, it became possible to attempt a new camera checkout, this
    time consisting of a bias frame and one image through each of the eight
    filters, the latter taken with a 500 ms exposure time. Only the two
    broadband images showed stars, and these were weak and very diffuse.
    (Images 100-108)
 
    #3 - 2/22/00   Two 200 ms calibration lamp images were taken through
    the OpNav filter. These were saturated, proving there was nothing wrong
    with the exposure times and the problem was probably more one of
    diffusion than absorption. (Images 110-111)
 
    #4 - 2/29/00   Two additional calibration lamp images were acquired
    through the OpNav filter, this time with a 20 ms exposure. The
    intensity was all there, but the lamp images were severely diffused,
    like from the effect of a frost-covered windshield. These images gave
    information only about conditions downstream from the lamp, telling
    nothing about the condition of the scan mirror or the periscope.
    (Images 112-113)
 
    #5 - 5/30/00   Twenty-eight windowed images (351x351 pixels) were
    acquired, six of them bias frames and 20 of them through the two wide
    band filters. Of those 20, 18 were of the 0 magnitude star Vega and two
    of the calibration lamp. The Vega images were taken half through the
    periscope and half not, using various exposure times. The periscope
    frames showed severe scattered light but no Vega images, very possibly
    because the geometrically uncalibrated system missed the star. The
    frames off the periscope showed huge diffuse images of Vega near the
    edge of the field. The calibration lamp images looked identical to
    those taken in February. (Images 114-141)
 
    #6 - 8/8/00   A single windowed bias frame was acquired to check upon
    the effects, if any, of a large solar flare the previous week. There
    were no obvious effects. (Image 142)
 
    #7 - 8/16/00   It was decided to turn on the CCD heater to see if that
    would remove any of the contamination on the optics. Images of the
    calibration lamp were taken in pairs, a full frame using the OpNav
    filter and a windowed frame using the HiRes (#7) filter, at zero hours,
    1, 2, 4, 8, 16, 32, 56, 100, and 143 hours, 20 images in all. The
    temperature of the CCD was about 9C during this period. Each image
    showed changes, but contamination clearly remained at the conclusion of
    the heating. (Images 143-162)
 
    #8 - 8/30/00   A final pair of calibration lamp frames was acquired
    after the CCD had cooled back to its normal operating temperature near
    -35C. The images were different, but still diffuse. (Images 163-164)
 
    #9 - 9/12/00   Five star fields were obtained using the OpNav filter
    and different scan mirror angles. One spacecraft axis was not properly
    clamped, so there was smear on all images. (Images 165-169)
 
    #10 - 9/26/00   Sequence #9 was repeated with three identical star
    field and two new ones. The images appeared somewhat more diffuse than
    those taken pre-heating, but the transmission seemed better, frame
    limits being about one magnitude fainter. (Images 170-174)
 
    #11 - 10/17/00   Sixteen frames were taken of the Pleiades (M45) open
    cluster to attempt to determine the uniformity of the contamination and
    to see if the smaller intrinsic point spread of the HiRes filter would
    help us go fainter. Unfortunately there were high drift rates on the
    three HiRes images and no conclusion was reached. Contamination across
    the frame varied by no more than half a magnitude, but huge scattered
    light halos dominated every star image. One compressed frame was
    acquired, and it showed the compressor chip was working properly.
    (Images 175-190)
 
    #12 - 11/27/00   A single OpNav frame of the calibration lamp was taken
    as a baseline for a new heating test. This time, both CCD and scan
    mechanism heaters were turned on and brought the CCD up to about 12C
    (the spacecraft was now much nearer perihelion). On December 5 the Sun
    was turned directly on the CCD radiator for about 30 minutes, bringing
    the CCD temperature up to 24C. This was done as part of a scheduled
    trajectory correction maneuver. All heaters were turned off on December
    18, but navigation studies prevented any further image acquisition
    until January. (Image 191)
 
    #13 - 1/5/01   One calibration lamp and four star field frames were
    acquired using the OpNav filter and 1000 ms exposures. The cal lamp
    frame showed the lamp filament for the first time since launch. The
    star frames showed sharper images and reached at least magnitude 9.0.
    There was still a very shallow skirt of scattered light around star
    images, however, and we were at least one full magnitude from the
    performance expected of the camera. (Images 192-196)
 
    #14 - 1/16/01   Some 16 hours after Earth Gravity Assist we acquired 25
    frames, five Lunar and two bias frames uncompressed and 16 Lunar and
    two bias frames compressed. These were taken at about 100,000 km from
    the Moon while flying nearly over its north pole, seeing about two-
    thirds front side and one-third back side in a half illuminated image.
    The wide band filters gave partially saturated images even at the
    minimum possible 5 ms exposure. The narrow band images were sharp but
    showed a halo of scattered light, as expected from the results of the
    previous sequence. It was intended that these Lunar images be used to
    recalibrate the camera. (Images 197-221)
 
    #15 - 2/26/01   A series of 21 compressed full frame images were taken
    for the purpose of geometric calibration of the scan mirror. Nineteen
    were OpNav images taken at 10 degree intervals from 0 degrees to 180
    degrees. Two were HiRes images taken at 80 degrees and 90 degrees,
    again to attempt a comparison of performance of OpNav and HiRes
    filters. It was immediately obvious that recontamination had occurred
    and we were back to the level of the previous Fall as far as scattered
    light was concerned. The images were useless for calibration, and any
    attempt at photometric calibration from the lunar images taken in
    January had been rendered moot. EVRs received, when the filter wheel
    was commanded back to its stowed position, said that it had not moved
    and still was in the OpNav position. (Images 222-242)
 
    #16 - 3/1/01   Three frames were taken at this time, an uncompressed
    cal lamp frame and compressed and uncompressed star fields, the former
    to verify the filter wheel position and the later the contamination
    state. The first showed that indeed we had not moved from the OpNav
    filter position and that the cal lamp filament had once again
    disappeared. The later indeed showed renewed contamination. (Images
    243-245)
 
    #17 - 3/13/01   A series of nine images had already been planned to
    determine exactly where we come off the periscope and the extent of
    periscope contamination. A tenth was added as final verification that
    we were stuck in the OpNav position (confirmed), and this resulted in
    an absolute flight rule forbidding any further attempts to move the
    filter wheel, since getting stick in a narrow band filter would
    severely damage the mission by causing both a greater flyby distance
    and loss of all useful nucleus images. Images of a bright star (Spica)
    showed that we were getting about half the expected light through the
    periscope, so indeed there is additional contamination on the periscope
    mirrors. These also showed that we are fully off the periscope at a 20
    degree mirror angle but not 15 degrees and that there was a great deal
    of scattered light into the periscope at the spacecraft attitude at
    which the images were acquired. (Images 246-255)
 
    #18 - 3/22/01   On this date one cal lamp and one star field were taken
    as baseline for a third heating cycle. Immediately following these
    exposures, the CCD heater was turned on and the scan mechanism heater
    was turned up once again. (Images 256-257)
 
    #19 - 3/27/01   One set of images, cal lamp plus star field, was taken
    immediately prior to performing a maneuver to once again point the CCD
    radiator at the Sun. This was a hot pair taken at 12C.  The camera
    reached about 21C, and 45 minutes later, while still at 21C, a further
    pair of images was taken. A final pair was taken 12 hours later when
    the camera was back at 12C.  To everyone&apos;s surprise, the first pair,
    taken BEFORE the camera radiator was pointed at the Sun, was noisy, as
    one would expect with the camera hot, but very clean. There was in fact
    no significant difference in the three pairs of images. All looked very
    good except for the hot pixels. (Images 258-263)
 
    #20 - 4/2/01   The CCD and scan mechanism heaters were left on
    following the March 27 heating cycle. A pair of images was taken during
    this and each successive DSN pass. No change was seen. (Images 264-265)
 
    #21 - 4/10/01   Another pair of images was acquired. (Images 266-267)
 
    #22 - 4/18/01   Another pair of images was acquired. (Images 268-269)
 
    #23 - 4/25/01   Another pair of images was acquired, and the heaters
    were returned to their normal state on April 29, CCD off and scan
    mechanism heating as needed for operation. (Images 270-271)
 
    #24 - 4/30/01   Another pair of images was acquired, this time with the
    CCD back down to its normal operating temperature at -36C. Without all
    of the hot pixels, we could now see that we were in our cleanest state
    since launch, reaching somewhere near 10th magnitude without special
    filtering. Since this state was reached immediately after heating to
    only 8C, it appears that this recontamination was of a different nature
    than the original contamination, perhaps simply water vapor released
    when the spacecraft was hottest near perihelion. (Images 272-273)
 
    #25 - 5/7/01   Another pair of images was acquired to check for any
    recontamination. (Images 274-275)
 
    #26 - 5/17/01   Another pair of images was acquired to check for any
    recontamination. (Images 276-277)
 
    #27 - 5/25/01   Another pair of images was acquired to check for any
    recontamination. (Images 278-279)
 
    #28 - 5/31/01   Another pair of images was acquired to check for any
    recontamination. (Images 280-281)
 
    #29 - 6/8/01   Sixteen full frame uncompressed images were taken of the
    encounter background field with exposures of one, three, and five
    seconds, at various mirror settings, and with the spacecraft in
    encounter attitude for periscope images, to check for scattered light.
    With a 0 degree mirror angle, there was about 200 dn /s of scattered
    light in the upper left corner, the worst part of the frame. With a 10
    degree mirror angle, there was about 100 dn/s of scattered light in the
    upper left corner. At 20 degrees, and clear of the periscope, there was
    no scattered light detected. Processing of a five second exposure clear
    of the periscope indicated we reached magnitude 11.7 with a signal to
    noise ratio of three. There has been no further evidence of
    contamination since the third heating cycle began on March 22. (Images
    282-297)
 
    #30 - 8/29/01   Two images (298,299) were acquired to check for any
    recontamination of the camera and to furnish additional geometric
    calibrations. Both proved excellent, showing no new contamination for
    the past four months. No additional imaging is planned until the
    windowing software patch is available or until standard maintenance
    requires a camera status check (in about six months). Useful unwindowed
    imaging will not be possible for a year or more, that is, until we have
    more power and higher data rate as we begin to approach Sun and Earth
    once again. (Images 298-299)
 
    #31 - 10/29/01   In anticipation of a long period with no imaging while
    the spacecraft was near aphelion, a final check was made on the state
    of the camera. This was used as an opportunity to place the spacecraft
    in the attitude relative to the Sun that it will have on approach, if
    an engineering readiness test is performed on the asteroid Annefrank in
    November 2002, as a check for scattered light. The single 1000 ms image
    remained free of significant contamination and showed no scattered
    light. (Image 300)
 
    The images on this calibration volume are in standard PDS format.  Each
    file includes an attached PDS label at the beginning of the file,
    followed by a histogram, and ending with the image itself.  The PDS
    label contains two OBJECT definitions, which describe the storage
    requirements for both the histogram and image objects.  The label also
    describes the circumstances surrounding the collection of the
    calibration image.  This meta-data is in keyword and value pairs and
    each of these keywords is described at the end of this document.
 
  Camera Description
  ------------------
    The camera has a 1024x1024 array as the active portion of the CCD.
    The images that are stored on this volume, however, contain more
    than just the active portion of the CCD.  Each line contains a sync
    pattern, a line counter, 12 baseline stabilization pixels, the 1024
    pixels from the active portion of the CCD, and finally 8 over-clock
    pixels used to measure the quantum efficiency. The number of rows
    for each image is always 1024, no matter what compression mode is
    used, but the number of columns for each image depends on the
    compression mode used.
 
  Compression Modes
  -----------------
    The NAVCAM images can be either 8-bit or 12-bit data.  The 12-bit data
    is commonly referred to as &apos;uncompressed data&apos;, while the 8-bit is
    referred to as &apos;compressed data&apos;.  This compression is accomplished by
    a 12-bit to 8-bit square-root look-up-table compression method, which
    is implemented in the hardware of the camera electronics.  This
    compression is lossy and the estimate of the 12-bit image can be
    recovered using the look-up table mentioned in Appendix 3 of the
    Calibration Document.  Both the image and histogram portions of the
    data file require different amounts of storage space, dependent on the
    compression mode used.
 
  Pixel storage requirements
  --------------------------
    In uncompressed mode with 12-bit data, the pixels are expressed in two
    bytes, as 16 bits per pixel.  The upper nibble of the most significant
    byte is always zero for these images.  In compressed mode with 8-bit
    data, the pixels are expressed in a single byte.
 
 
  Number of Columns within each Row
  ---------------------------------
    The general form of each line for each image is fixed.  The row of
    data from the camera can be categorized into five different regions:
 
        1. Sync Pattern          Always 2 bytes, with value   0x0000
        2. Line Counter          Always 2 bytes, values from 0 to 1023
        3. 8 BLS pixels         *Baseline Stabilization pixels, either 1 or
                                    2 bytes per pixel
        4. 1024 image pixels    *Either 1 or 2 bytes per pixel
        5. 12 over-clock pixels *Used to measure quantum efficiency, either
                                    1 or 2 bytes per pixel
 
    * The pixels are either 1 or 2 bytes per pixel dependent on the
      compression mode.  Uncompressed, 12-bit images require 2 bytes per
      pixel, while compressed 8-bit images require 1 byte per pixel.
 
    For the uncompressed, 12-bit data, each row contains 1046 &apos;pixels&apos; of
    data, which is exactly 2092 bytes.  This is 2 bytes for the sync, 2
    bytes for the line counter, 8 pixels at 2 bytes per pixel, 1024 pixels
    at 2 bytes per pixel and, finally, 12 pixels at 2 bytes per pixel.  In
    equation form:
 
        bytes_per_uncompressed_line = 2 + 2 + 2 * ( 8 + 1024 + 12 ) = 2092
 
    For the compressed, 8-bit data, each row contains 1048 &apos;pixels&apos; of
    data, which is exactly 1048 bytes.  This is 2 bytes for the sync, 2
    bytes for the line counter, 8 pixels at 1 byte per pixel, 1024 pixels
    at 1 bytes per pixel and, finally, 12 pixels at 1 bytes per pixel.  In
    equation form:
 
        bytes_per_compressed_line = 2 + 2 + 1 * ( 8 + 1024 + 12 ) = 1048
 
  Reading with RAW image readers
  ------------------------------
    When using any of the supported PDS readers, this extra data at the
    beginning and end of the line is not displayed, but when reading these
    images with a raw raster-scan style reader, this extra data at the
    beginning and ending of each line must be taken into account.
 
  Values to use when reading images with a RAW readers
  ----------------------------------------------------
    Compression Mode    # Rows  # Columns   Data Type
    -----------------   ------  ---------   ------------------------------
      Compressed         1024    1048        BYTE data
      Uncompressed       1024    1046        MSB_Unsigned_integer (16-bit)
 
  Finding the offset to the data within the file
  ----------------------------------------------
    When trying to read the histogram or image arrays from the file
    using a RAW reader, the reader must first skip all of the information
    before the object to be read.  As an example, to read the image object
    using a raw reader, the reader must first skip the PDS attached header,
    as well as the histogram data.  To determine the amount of data to
    skip, examine two keyword pairs from the attached label.
 
    To advance to the beginning of the histogram data, examine the
    following keywords:
            RECORD_BYTES         = 2092
            ^IMAGE_HISTOGRAM     = 3
    The first keyword defines the number of bytes within each record, while
    the second keyword indicates at which record the data begins.  In this
    example, the data starts in record #3.  This indicates that 2 other
    records contain data prior to the start of the histogram data.  To
    compute the data offset, account for 2 records of data:  in this
    example, the offset is (3-1)*2092 = 4184.
 
    To advance to the beginning of the image data, examine the following
    keywords:
            RECORD_BYTES         = 2092
            ^IMAGE               = 11
    As in the previous example, the first keyword defines the number of
    bytes within each record.  The second keyword indicates the record at
    which the image data begins.  To compute the data offset, follow the
    example above:
            Offset = ( ^image_histogram - 1 ) * record_bytes.
        Ex: Offset = ( 11 - 1) * 2092 = 20920
 
  Flip Required to Achieve ``As Seen By Observer&apos;&apos; Display
  --------------------------------------------------------
    Since the optical path of the camera includes a mirror and the flight
    and image production s/w do not compensate for the flip that this
    mirror introduces, the images displayed in normal left-to-right sample,
    top-to-bottom line fashion have to be transposed (flipped about left-
    top/right-bottom diagonal) in order to appear ``as observer located on
    the s/c would see it&apos;&apos;.
 
  A Sample PDS Attached Image Label
  ---------------------------------
    PDS_VERSION_ID       = PDS3
    /*** FILE FORMAT ***/
    RECORD_TYPE          = FIXED_LENGTH
    RECORD_BYTES         = 2092
    FILE_RECORDS         = 1032
    /*** POINTERS TO OBJECTS IN FILE ***/
    ^IMAGE_HISTOGRAM     = (&apos;N0164C171.RAW&apos;,1)
    ^IMAGE               = (&apos;N0164C171.RAW&apos;,9)
    /*** GENERAL DATA DESCRIPTION PARAMETERS ***/
    MISSION_NAME         = &apos;STARDUST&apos;
    SPACECRAFT_NAME      = &apos;STARDUST&apos;
    DATA_SET_ID          = &apos;STARDUST-C/E/L-NC-2-EDR-V1.0&apos;
    PRODUCT_ID           = &apos;N0164C171.IMG&apos;
    PRODUCER_INSTITUTION_NAME = &apos;JPL/ACT&apos;
    PRODUCT_TYPE         = &apos;EDR&apos;
    SOFTWARE_NAME        = &apos;ACT DMAPKTDECOM 1.0&apos;
    MISSION_PHASE_NAME   = &apos;Cruise 1&apos;
    TARGET_NAME          = &apos;N/A&apos;
    FRAME_SEQUENCE_NUMBER = 164
    /*** TIME PARAMETERS ***/
    PRODUCT_CREATION_TIME = 2000-09-15T01:26:31
    START_TIME           = 2000-08-30T17:30:53.994
    STOP_TIME            = &apos;N/A&apos;
    SPACECRAFT_CLOCK_START_COUNT = &apos;0652123932:172&apos;
    SPACECRAFT_CLOCK_STOP_COUNT = &apos;N/A&apos;
    TIME_FROM_CLOSEST_APPROACH = -1220.075 &lt;DAYS&gt;
    /*** CAMERA RELATED PARAMETERS ***/
    INSTRUMENT_NAME      = &apos;NAVIGATION CAMERA&apos;
    INSTRUMENT_HOST_NAME = &apos;STARDUST&apos;
    INSTRUMENT_ID        = &apos;NC&apos;
    DATA_STREAM_TYPE     = &apos;CRUISE&apos;
    TELEMETRY_MUX_MODE_ID = 1
    FILTER_WHEEL_IN_MOTION_MODE_ID = 0
    EXPOSURE_ENABLE_MODE_ID = 0
    EXPOSURE_DURATION    = 150 &lt;MS&gt;
    CCD_HEATER_MODE_ID   = 0
    SLEEP_MODE_ID        = 0
    CAL_LAMP_MODE_ID     = 1
    QUANTIZATION_MODE_ID = 0
    FIFO_EMPTY_MODE_ID   = 1
    FIFO_FULL_MODE_ID    = 0
    BULB_MODE_ID         = 0
    FILTER_STEPS         = 7
    FILTER_PARITY        = 0
    FILTER_NUMBER        = 7
    FILTER_NAME          = &apos;HiRes&apos;
    CENTER_FILTER_WAVELENGTH =             596.4 &lt;NM&gt;
    FILTER_FWHM          =               200 &lt;NM&gt;
    NAVCAM_DIGITAL_TELEMETRY = 16#849ea1b0c0d5e7f7#
    SCAN_MIRROR_ANGLE    = -0.012817 &lt;DEG&gt;
    SCAN_MIRROR_LAST_COMMANDED_VELOCITY =         0 &lt;DEG/SEC&gt;
    SCAN_MIRROR_MOTOR_MODE_ID = 0
    /*** TEMPERATURE PARAMETERS IN &lt;K&gt; ***/
    FOCAL_PLANE_TEMPERATURE =           234.713 &lt;K&gt;
    SCAN_MIRROR_TEMPERATURE =           265.614 &lt;K&gt;
    NOTE = &apos;
         EARTH MEAN EQUATOR AND VERNAL EQUINOX J2000 COORDINATES ARE
         THE INTERTIAL REFERENCE SYSTEM USED TO SPECIFY OBSERVATIONAL
         GEOMETRY.  LATITUDE AND LONGITUDE COORDINATES OF TARGET ARE
         GEOCENTRIC.  GEOMETRIC PARAMETERS ARE BASED ON BEST AVAILABLE
         DATA AT TIME OF PRODUCT CREATION.  REFER TO EDR SPICE DATA
         BASE FOR THE MOST CURRENT OBSERVATIONAL GEOMETRY DATA.&apos;
    /*** LINE-OF-SITE ON CELESTIAL SPHERE: Angles in &lt;deg&gt; ***/
    RIGHT_ASCENSION      =            325.41 &lt;DEG&gt;
    DECLINATION          =          -12.7562 &lt;DEG&gt;
    TWIST_ANGLE          =             1E+32 &lt;DEG&gt;
    RETICLE_POINT_RA     = ( 324.357, 323.094, 326.444, 327.744)
    RETICLE_POINT_DEC    = (-15.0215,-11.7291,-10.4868, -13.763)
    EMEJ2000_SC_QUATERNION = (  0.79995, -0.18296, -0.25495,  0.51148)
    /*** TARGET PARAMETERS: Position &lt;km&gt;, Velocity &lt;km/s&gt; ***/
    SC_TARGET_POSITION_VECTOR = (       -1E+32,       -1E+32,       -1E+32)
    SC_TARGET_VELOCITY_VECTOR = (       -1E+32,       -1E+32,       -1E+32)
    TARGET_CENTER_DISTANCE =            -1E+32 &lt;KM&gt;
    SUN_TARGET_POSITION_VECTOR = (       -1E+32,       -1E+32,      -1E+32)
    SUN_TARGET_VELOCITY_VECTOR = (       -1E+32,       -1E+32,      -1E+32)
    SUN_TARGET_CENTER_DISTANCE =            -1E+32 &lt;KM&gt;
    /*** TARGET WITHIN SENSOR FOV: Angles &lt;deg&gt; ***/
    CENTER_LATITUDE      =            -1E+32 &lt;DEG&gt;
    CENTER_LONGITUDE     =            -1E+32 &lt;DEG&gt;
    HORIZONTAL_PIXEL_SCALE =            -1E+32 &lt;KM&gt;
    VERTICAL_PIXEL_SCALE =            -1E+32 &lt;KM&gt;
    SMEAR_MAGNITUDE      =         0.0749415 &lt;PIXELS&gt;
    SMEAR_AZIMUTH        =           59.2858 &lt;DEG&gt;
    RETICLE_POINT_LATITUDE = (   -1E+32,    -1E+32,    -1E+32,    -1E+32)
    RETICLE_POINT_LONGITUDE = (   -1E+32,    -1E+32,    -1E+32,    -1E+32)
    /*** SPACECRAFT POSITION WITH RESPECT TO BODY ***/
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LATITUDE =            -1E+32 &lt;DEG&gt;
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LONGITUDE =            -1E+32 &lt;DEG&gt;
    SPACECRAFT_ALTITUDE  =            -1E+32 &lt;KM&gt;
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_AZIMUTH =            -1E+32 &lt;DEG&gt;
    /*** VIEWING AND LIGHTING GEOMETRY (SUN ON TARGET) ***/
    PHASE_ANGLE          =            -1E+32 &lt;DEG&gt;
    INCIDENCE_ANGLE      =            -1E+32 &lt;DEG&gt;
    EMISSION_ANGLE       =            -1E+32 &lt;DEG&gt;
    /*** DESCRIPTION OF OBJECTS CONTAINED IN THE FILE ***/
    OBJECT = IMAGE_HISTOGRAM
      ITEMS     = 4096
      DATA_TYPE = MSB_UNSIGNED_INTEGER
      ITEM_BITS = 32
    END_OBJECT = IMAGE_HISTOGRAM
    OBJECT = IMAGE
      LINES              = 1024
      LINE_SAMPLES       = 1024
      SAMPLE_TYPE        = MSB_UNSIGNED_INTEGER
      SAMPLE_BITS        = 16
      SAMPLE_BIT_MASK    = 2#0000111111111111#
      MAXIMUM            = 3994
      MINIMUM            = 0
      LINE_PREFIX_BYTES  = 20
      LINE_SUFFIX_BYTES  = 24
      MEAN               = 243.533
      STANDARD_DEVIATION = 670.976
      SATURATED_PIXELS   = 0
      CHECKSUM           = 255362468
      OBJECT = WINDOW
        WINDOW_DESC       = &apos;HEATING TEST&apos;
        TARGET_NAME       = &apos;COLD AGAIN IMAGE&apos;
        FIRST_LINE        = 336
        FIRST_LINE_SAMPLE = 336
        LINES             = 351
        LINE_SAMPLES      = 351
      END_OBJECT = WINDOW
    END_OBJECT = IMAGE
    END
 
    General notes regarding label
    -----------------------------
       * Strings appear in quotes.
       * Integers and PDS Times do not take quotes.
       * Lists are enclosed within {} type brackets.
       * If a field is unknown, &apos;UNK&apos; may be entered.
       * If a field is not applicable, &apos;N/A&apos; may be entered.
       * Fields can spill freely, with or without white space, onto
         following lines.
       * Not all images contain the WINDOW object as part of the
         image object.  This subobject is only present when windowed
         data is present in the image.  Images which are full-frame do not
         have the WINDOW subobject.
 
  Definition of Keywords/Values from the PDS Data Dictionary
  ----------------------------------------------------------
       PDS_VERSION_ID             The pds_version_id Keywords indicates the
                                  version number of the PDS standards
                                  documents that is valid when a data
                                  product label is created.  Values for the
                                  PDS_VERSION_ID are formed by appending
                                  the integer for the latest version number
                                  to the letters &apos;PDS&apos;.  Examples: PDS3,
                                  PDS4.
 
       RECORD_TYPE                The record_type keyword indicates the
                                  record format of a file.  Note:  In the
                                  PDS, when record_type is used in a
                                  detached label file it always describes
                                  its corresponding detached data file, not
                                  the label file itself.  The use of
                                  record_type along with other file-related
                                  data elements is fully described in the
                                  PDS Standards Reference.
 
       RECORD_BYTES               The record_bytes keyword indicates the
                                  number of bytes in a physical file
                                  record, including record terminators and
                                  separators.
 
       FILE_RECORDS               The file_records keyword indicates the
                                  number of physical file records,
                                  including both label records and data
                                  records.
 
       ^IMAGE_HISTOGRAM           The image_histogram object represents a
                                  pointer to the image histogram.  The
                                  value is in &apos;RECORD_BYTE&apos; units.  This
                                  represents the record at which the
                                  histogram data begins.  Because of this
                                  fact, account for one less than the
                                  number of records shown.  As an example,
                                  if the pointer value is 4, and the bytes
                                  per record is 2092, the image histogram
                                  data starts at (4-1)*2092 = 6276 bytes.
 
       ^IMAGE                     The ^image pointer represents a byte
                                  offset to the image data.  The value is
                                  in &apos;RECORD_BYTE&apos; units.  This represents
                                  the record at which the image data
                                  begins. Because of this fact, account for
                                  one less than the number of records
                                  shown. As an example, if the pointer
                                  value is 11, and the bytes per record is
                                  2092, the image histogram data starts at
                                  byte 29020.
 
       MISSION_NAME               The mission_name element identifies a
                                  major planetary mission or project.  A
                                  given planetary mission may be associated
                                  with one or more spacecraft.
 
       SPACECRAFT_NAME            The spacecraft_name element provides the
                                  full, unabbreviated name of a spacecraft.
 
       DATA_SET_ID                The data_set_id element is a unique
                                  alphanumeric identifier for a data set or
                                  a data product.  The data_set_id value
                                  for a given data set or product is
                                  constructed according to flight project
                                  naming conventions.  In most cases the
                                  data_set_id is an abbreviation of the
                                  data_set_name.  Example value:
                                  STARDUST-C/E/L-NC-2-EDR-V1.0.  Note:  In
                                  the PDS, the values for both data_set_id
                                  and data_set_name are constructed
                                  according to standards outlined in the
                                  Standards Reference.
 
       PRODUCT_ID                 The product_id data element represents a
                                  permanent, unique identifier assigned to
                                  a data product by its producer.  Note:
                                  In the PDS, the value assigned to
                                  product_id must be unique within its data
                                  set.  This value represents the actual
                                  name of the image file on the archive.
                                  The output directory is also available.
 
       PRODUCER_INSTITUTION_NAME  The producer_institution_name element
                                  identifies a university, research center,
                                  NASA center or other institution
                                  associated with the production of a data
                                  set.  This would generally be an
                                  institution associated with the element
                                  producer_full_name.  In this dataset,
                                  this field has the value &apos;JPL/ACT&apos;,
                                  described as:
                                     JPL = Jet Propulsion Laboratory.
                                     ACT = Applied Coherent Technology Corp
 
       PRODUCT_TYPE               The product_type data element identifies
                                  the type or category of a data product
                                  within a data set.  Examples: EDR, UDR.
 
       SOFTWARE_NAME              The software_name element identifies data
                                  processing software such as a program or
                                  a program library.
 
       MISSION_PHASE_NAME         The mission_phase_name element provides
                                  the commonly-used identifier of a mission
                                  phase.
 
       TARGET_NAME                The target_name element identifies a
                                  target.  The target may be a planet,
                                  satellite, ring, region, feature,
                                  asteroid or comet. See target_type.
 
       FRAME_SEQUENCE_NUMBER      The frame_sequence_number element
                                  indicates the location within a cycle at
                                  which a specific frame occurs.  Frames
                                  are repeated in a specific order within
                                  each cycle.  In this dataset, this value
                                  represents a uniquely sequential
                                  identifier assigned to each image of the
                                  archive.
 
       PRODUCT_CREATION_TIME      The product_creation_time element defines
                                  the UTC system format time when a product
                                  was created.  Formation rule:
                                                 YYYY-MM-DDThh:mm:ss.
 
       START_TIME                 The start_time element provides the date
                                  and time of the beginning of an event or
                                  observation (whether it be a spacecraft,
                                  ground-based, or system event) in UTC
                                  system format.  Formation rule:
                                                 YYYY-MM-DDThh:mm:ss.
 
       STOP_TIME                  The stop_time element provides the date
                                  and time of the end of an observation or
                                  event (whether it be a spacecraft,
                                  ground-based, or system event) in UTC
                                  system format.  Formation rule:
                                                 YYYY-MM-DDThh:mm:ss.
 
       SPACECRAFT_CLOCK_START_COUNT
                                  The spacecraft_clock_start_count element
                                  provides the value of the spacecraft
                                  clock at the beginning of a time period
                                  of interest.
 
       SPACECRAFT_CLOCK_STOP_COUNT
                                  The spacecraft_clock_stop_count element
                                  provides the value of the spacecraft
                                  clock  at the end of a time period of
                                  interest.
 
       TIME_FROM_CLOSEST_APPROACH
                                  The time_from_closest_approach element
                                  provides the time with respect to
                                  periapsis or closest approach.
 
       INSTRUMENT_NAME            The instrument_name element provides the
                                  full name of an instrument.  Note: that
                                  the associated instrument_id element
                                  provides an abbreviated name or acronym
                                  for the instrument.
 
       INSTRUMENT_HOST_NAME       The instrument_host_name element provides
                                  the full name of the host on which an
                                  instrument is based.  This host can be
                                  either a spacecraft or an earth base.
                                  Thus, the instrument_host_name element
                                  can contain values which are either
                                  spacecraft_name values or earth_base_name
                                  values.
 
       INSTRUMENT_ID              The instrument_id element provides an
                                  abbreviated name or acronym which
                                  identifies an instrument.  Note:  The
                                  instrument_id is not a unique identifier
                                  for a given instrument.  Note also that
                                  the associated instrument_name element
                                  provides the full name of the instrument.
 
       DATA_STREAM_TYPE           The data_stream_type element identifies a
                                  particular type of data stream to which
                                  the given data product is related.  The
                                  images on this archive will be
                                  categorized as either &apos;Cruise&apos; or
                                  &apos;Encounter&apos; images, indicating the
                                  configuration of the spacecraft when the
                                  images were acquired.
 
 
       EXPOSURE_DURATION          The exposure_duration element provides
                                  the value of the time interval between
                                  the opening and closing of an instrument
                                  aperture (such as a camera shutter).
 
       TELEMETRY_MUX_MODE_ID      The telemetry_mux_mode_id element
                                  indicates that the NAVCAM telemetry
                                  multiplexor has sampled all digital
                                  engineering measurements.  This value
                                  should always be 1 by the nature of the
                                  timing of the sampling of the
                                  multiplexor.
 
       FILTER_WHEEL_IN_MOTION_MODE_ID
                                  The filter_wheel_in_motion_mode_id
                                  indicates that the filter wheel is in
                                  motion.  Upon completion of the movement
                                  of the filter wheel, this value is set to
                                  a 0.
 
       EXPOSURE_ENABLE_MODE_ID    The exposure_enable_mode_id element
                                  indicates that the shutter has been
                                  enabled to open, and if successfully
                                  closed, should have a value of 0.
 
       EXPOSURE_DURATION          Exposure duration (integration time) of
                                  the image observation expressed in
                                  milliseconds.
 
       CCD_HEATER_MODE_ID         The ccd_heater_mode_id element indicates
                                  if the CCD heater is on, with a value of
                                  1, or off, with a value of 0.  This value
                                  is controlled independently by spacecraft
                                  commands.
 
       SLEEP_MODE_ID              The sleep_mode_id element indicates if
                                  the camera is in sleep mode, or in a low-
                                  power state.  A value of 1 indicates that
                                  sleep mode is enables and a value of 0
                                  indicates that sleep mode is disables.
                                  Once sleep mode has been enabled, it can
                                  only be disabled by cycling power to the
                                  NAVCAM.
 
       CAL_LAMP_MODE_ID           The cal_lam_mode_id element provides the
                                  value of the calibration lamp mode at the
                                  time the image was acquired.  This value
                                  indicates whether the calibration lamp
                                  was on or off at the time the image was
                                  acquired.
 
       QUANTIZATION_MODE_ID       The quantization_mode_id element provides
                                  the identifier for the quantization mode
                                  used when the image was acquired.  This
                                  value indicates if the original data was
                                  quantized at the time the data was
                                  acquired.  A value of &apos;off&apos; indicates
                                  that the data was not quantized, while a
                                  value of &apos;on&apos; indicates that the data was
                                  quantized.  In this dataset, this value
                                  indicates that the image was compressed
                                  with a hardware square-root compression
                                  technique prior to transmission.
 
       FIFO_EMPTY_MODE_ID         The fifo_empty_mode_id indicates if the
                                  readout FIFO is empty or not.  When this
                                  value is set to 1, the FIFO is empty and
                                  when it is 0, the FIFO is not empty.
 
       FIFO_FULL_MODE_ID          The fifo_full_mode_id indicates if the
                                  readout FIFO is full or not.  When this
                                  value is set to 1, the FIFO is full and
                                  when it is 0, the FIFO is not full.  When
                                  the FIFO becomes full, pixel data is
                                  overwritten in the NAVCAM&apos;s FIFO.  This
                                  value represents the state of the FIFO
                                  just before the new image was taken and
                                  represents the previous image&apos;s success.
 
       BULB_MODE_ID               The bulb_mode_id element indicates if the
                                  shutter has been commanded open.  As long
                                  as this value remains a 1, the shutter
                                  will remain open.  This value is
                                  controlled only by spacecraft commands.
                                  When a command is received from the
                                  spacecraft to set the bulb_mode value to
                                  0, the shutter is closed.  No image is
                                  acquired as a result of a bulb_mode off
                                  command.  This value is used to take
                                  images whose exposure duration must be
                                  longer than 20 seconds.
 
       FILTER_STEPS               The filter_steps element indicates how
                                  many filters were traversed to reach the
                                  filter of interest.  To move from one
                                  filter to the next takes one second, so a
                                  three step move would take three seconds.
 
       FILTER_PARITY              The filter_parity element is an odd
                                  parity bit to allow for identification of
                                  a faulty bit amongst one of the three
                                  bits needed to represent the filter
                                  number.
 
       FILTER_NUMBER              The filter_number element provides the
                                  number of an instrument filter through
                                  which an image or measurement was
                                  acquired or which is associated with a
                                  given instrument mode.  Note: that the
                                  filter_number is unique, while the
                                  filter_name is not.
 
       FILTER_NAME                The filter_name element provides the
                                  commonly-used name of the instrument
                                  filter through which an image or
                                  measurement was acquired or which is
                                  associated with a given instrument mode.
                                  Example values:  RED, GREEN.  See also
                                  filter_number.
 
       CENTER_FILTER_WAVELENGTH   The center_filter_wavelength element
                                  provides the mid_point wavelength value
                                  between the minimum and maximum
                                  instrument filter wavelength values.
 
        FILTER_FWHM               The filter_fwhm element provides the
                                  measurement for the Full-width, half-max
                                  value associated with the filter.  This
                                  is the width of the filter transmission
                                  curve at the point of half of the maximum
                                  transmission value.
 
       NAVCAM_DIGITAL_TELEMETRY   The navcam_digital_telemetry element is
                                  used to indicate the eight bytes returned
                                  from the camera at the completion of the
                                  acquisition of an image.  The upper
                                  nibbles of each of the eight bytes should
                                  follow the pattern of 0x89abcdef.  This
                                  is a check that can be used to determine
                                  if the camera is functioning properly.
                                  The lower nibbles of each of the eight
                                  bytes were used in determining many of
                                  the other parameters given in the other
                                  columns of data.
 
       SCAN_MIRROR_ANGLE          The scan_mirror_angle element indicates
                                  the angle of the scan mirror at the
                                  instant the image was taken. The mirror
                                  sweeps through the plane formed by the
                                  spacecraft X and Z axes.  When the mirror
                                  is at 0 degrees, the light path is
                                  essentially from the +X axis.  As the
                                  mirror rotates to +90 degrees, the light
                                  path is from the -Z axis.  When the
                                  mirror moves on to +180 degrees, the
                                  light path is in the direction of the -X
                                  axis.  The range of the mirror is
                                  approximately 0 degrees to +200 degrees.
 
       SCAN_MIRROR_LAST_COMMANDED_VELOCITY
                                  The scan_mirror_last_commanded_velocity
                                  element indicates the last commanded
                                  velocity for the scan mirror. The scan
                                  mirror is not commanded to a position,
                                  but rather is reset to an initial
                                  position and is then commanded at a
                                  specific velocity for a specific amount
                                  of time.  The value given here is that
                                  commanded velocity.
 
       SCAN_MIRROR_MOTOR_MODE_ID  The scan_mirror_motor_mode_id indicates
                                  if the scan mirror motor is either on or
                                  off.  When the value is a 1, the motor is
                                  on.  When the value is a 0, the motor is
                                  off.
 
       FOCAL_PLANE_TEMPERATURE    The focal_plane_temperature element
                                  provides the temperature of the focal
                                  plane array in degrees Kelvin at the time
                                  the observation was made.
 
       SCAN_MIRROR_TEMPERATURE    The scan_mirror_temperature element
                                  provides the temperature of the scan
                                  mirror in degrees Kelvin at the time the
                                  observation was made.
 
       RIGHT_ASCENSION            The right_ascension element provides the
                                  right ascension value. Right_ascension is
                                  defined as the arc of the celestial
                                  equator between the vernal equinox and
                                  the point where the hour circle through
                                  the given body intersects the Earth&apos;s
                                  mean equator (reckoned eastward).
 
       DECLINATION                The declination element provides the
                                  value of an angle, corresponding to
                                  latitude, used to fix position on the
                                  celestial sphere.  Declination is
                                  measured positive north and negative
                                  south of the celestial equator, and is
                                  defined relative to a specified reference
                                  period or epoch.
 
       TWIST_ANGLE                The twist_angle element provides the
                                  angle of rotation about an optical axis
                                  relative to celestial coordinates.  The
                                  RIGHT_ASCENSION, DECLINATION and
                                  TWIST_ANGLE elements define the pointing
                                  direction and orientation of an image or
                                  scan platform.
 
       RETICLE_POINT_RA           These parameters refer to the right
                                  ascension of the principal points of the
                                  camera.  For the left pixel of the camera
                                  (line 1, sample 1), the upper right pixel
                                  (line 1 , last sample), lower left (last
                                  line, sample 1), and lower right(last
                                  line, last sample).
 
       RETICLE_POINT_DEC          These parameters refer to the declination
                                  of the principal points of the camera.
                                  For the left pixel of the camera (line 1,
                                  sample 1), the upper right pixel (line 1,
                                  last sample), lower left (last line,
                                  sample 1), and lower right(last line,
                                  last sample).
 
       EMEJ2000_SC_QUATERNION     The emej2000_sc_quaternion element
                                  identifies the quaternion required to
                                  rotate a vector in Earth-Mean-Equator
                                  J2000 coordinates into the spacecraft
                                  frame.
 
       SC_TARGET_POSITION_VECTOR  The sc_target_position_vector element
                                  indicates the x-, y-, z- components of
                                  the position vector from observer to
                                  target center expressed in J2000
                                  coordinates, and corrected for light time
                                  and stellar aberration, evaluated at
                                  epoch at which image was taken.
 
       SC_TARGET_VELOCITY_VECTOR  The sc_target_velocity_vector element
                                  indicates the x-, y-, z- components of
                                  the velocity vector from observer to
                                  target center expressed in J2000
                                  coordinates, and corrected for light time
                                  and stellar aberration, evaluated at
                                  epoch at which image was taken.
 
       TARGET_CENTER_DISTANCE     The target_center_distance element
                                  provides the distance between an
                                  instrument and the center of mass of the
                                  named target.
 
       SUN_TARGET_POSITION_VECTOR The sun_target_position_vector element
                                  indicates the x-, y-, z- components of
                                  the position vector from sun to target
                                  center expressed in J2000 coordinates,
                                  and corrected for light time and stellar
                                  aberration, evaluated at epoch at which
                                  image was taken.
 
       SUN_TARGET_VELOCITY_VECTOR The sun_target_velocity_vector element
                                  indicates the x-, y-, z- components of
                                  the velocity vector from sun to target
                                  center expressed in J2000 coordinates,
                                  and corrected for light time and stellar
                                  aberration, evaluated at epoch at which
                                  image was taken.
 
       SUN_TARGET_CENTER_DISTANCE The sun_target_center_distance element
                                  provides the distance between the sun and
                                  the center of mass of the named target.
 
       CENTER_LATITUDE            The center_latitude element provides the
                                  latitude of the surface intercept point
                                  of the boresight of the camera.
 
       CENTER_LONGITUDE           The center_longitude element provides the
                                  longitude of the surface intercept point
                                  of the boresight of the camera.
 
       HORIZONTAL_PIXEL_SCALE     The horizontal_pixel_scale element
                                  indicates the horizontal picture scale.
 
       VERTICAL_PIXEL_SCALE       The vertical_pixel_scale element
                                  indicates the vertical  picture scale.
 
       SMEAR_MAGNITUDE            The smear_magnitude element indicates how
                                  far an image was smeared during an
                                  exposure.
 
       SMEAR_AZIMUTH              The smear_azimuth element indicates the
                                  direction in which an image was smeared.
                                  The values of this angle increment in a
                                  clockwise direction from a horizontal
                                  reference line.
 
       RETICLE_POINT_LATITUDE     The reticle_point_latitude element
                                  provides the latitude of the surface
                                  intercept points of the principle points
                                  of the camera, defined as the upper left
                                  pixel of the camera (line 1,sample 1),
                                  the upper right pixel (line 1, last
                                  sample), lower left (last line, sample
                                  1), and lower right (last line, last
                                  sample).
 
       RETICLE_POINT_LONGITUDE    The reticle_point_longitude element
                                  provides the longitude of the surface
                                  intercept points of the principle points
                                  of the camera, defined as the upper left
                                  pixel of the camera (line 1, sample 1),
                                  the upper right pixel (line 1, last
                                  sample), lower left (last line, sample
                                  1), and lower right (last line, last
                                  sample).
 
       SUB_SPACECRAFT_LATITUDE    The sub_spacecraft_latitude element
                                  provides the latitude of the
                                  sub-spacecraft point.  The sub-spacecraft
                                  point is that point on a body which lies
                                  directly beneath the spacecraft.
 
       SUB_SPACECRAFT_LONGITUDE   The sub_spacecraft_longitude element
                                  provides the longitude of the
                                  sub-spacecraft point.  The sub-spacecraft
                                  point is that point on a body which lies
                                  directly beneath the spacecraft.
 
       SPACECRAFT_ALTITUDE        The sub_spacecraft_azimuth element
                                  provides the value of the angle between
                                  the line from the center of an image to
                                  the sub-spacecraft point and a horizontal
                                  reference line (in the image plane)
                                  extending from the image center to the
                                  middle right edge of the image.  The
                                  values of this angle increase in a
                                  clockwise direction.
 
       SUB_SPACECRAFT_AZIMUTH     The spacecraft_altitude element provides
                                  the distance from the spacecraft to a
                                  reference surface of the target body
                                  measured normal to that surface.
 
       PHASE_ANGLE                The phase_angle element provides a
                                  measure of the relationship between the
                                  instrument viewing position and incident
                                  illumination (such as solar light).
                                  Phase_angle is measured at the target; it
                                  is the angle between a vector to the
                                  illumination source and a vector to the
                                  instrument.  If not specified, the target
                                  is assumed to be at the center of the
                                  instrument field of view.  If
                                  illumination is from behind the
                                  instrument, phase_angle will be small.
 
       INCIDENCE_ANGLE            The incidence_angle element provides a
                                  measure of the lighting condition at the
                                  intercept point.  Incidence angle is the
                                  angle between the local vertical at the
                                  intercept point (surface) and a vector
                                  from the intercept point to the sun.  The
                                  incidence_angle varies from 0 degrees
                                  when the intercept point coincides with
                                  the sub_solar point to 90 degrees when
                                  the intercept point is at the terminator
                                  (i.e., in the shadowed or dark portion of
                                   the target body).  Thus, higher values
                                  to the middle right edge of the image.
                                  The values of this angle increase in a
                                  clockwise direction.  of incidence_angle
                                  indicate the existence of a greater
                                  number of surface shadows.
 
       EMISSION_ANGLE             The emission_angle element provides the
                                  value of the angle between the surface
                                  normal vector at the intercept point and
                                  a vector from the intercept point to the
                                  spacecraft.  The emission_angle varies
                                  from 0 degrees when the spacecraft is
                                  viewing the sub-spacecraft point (nadir
                                  viewing) to 90 degrees when the intercept
                                  is tangent to the surface of the target
                                  body.  Thus, higher values of
                                  emission_angle indicate more oblique
                                  viewing of the target.  Values in the
                                  range of 90 to 180 degrees are possible
                                  for ring data.
 
       OBJECT = IMAGE_HISTOGRAM   The histogram object is a sequence of
                                  numeric values that provides the number
                                  of occurrences of a data value or a range
                                  of data values in a data object.  The
                                  number of items in a histogram will
                                  normally be equal to the number of
                                  distinct values allowed in a field of the
                                  data object.  (For example, an 8-bit
                                  integer field can have 256 values.
                                  This would result in a 256-item
                                  histogram.)  Histograms may be used to
                                  bin data, in which case an offset and
                                  scaling factor indicate the dynamic range
                                  of the data represented.  The following
                                  equation allows the calculation of the
                                  range of each &apos;bin&apos; in the histogram.
                                  &apos;bin lower boundary&apos; = (&apos;bin element&apos;
                                  * scaling_factor) + offset.
 
       ITEMS                      The items element defines the number of
                                  multiple, identical occurrences of an
                                  single object, such as a column.  See
                                  also: repetitions.  Note:  In the PDS,
                                  the data element ITEMS is used for
                                  multiple occurrences of a single object,
                                  such as a column.  REPETITIONS is used
                                  for multiple occurrences of a repeating
                                  group of objects, such as a container.
                                  For a fuller description of the use of
                                  these data elements, please refer to the
                                  Standards Reference.
 
       DATA_TYPE                  The data_type element supplies the
                                  internal representation and/or
                                  mathematical properties of a value being
                                  stored.  See also: bit_data_type,
                                  general_data_type.  Note:  In the PDS,
                                  users may find a bit-level description of
                                  each data type in the Standards Reference
                                  document.
 
       ITEM_BITS                  The item_bits element indicates the
                                  number of bits allocated for a particular
                                  bit data item.  Note:  In the PDS, the
                                  item_bits element is used when the items
                                  element specifies multiple occurrences of
                                  an implied item within a BIT_COLUMN
                                  object definition.
 
       END_OBJECT                 The end_object element terminates the
                                  object
 
       OBJECT = IMAGE             A regular array of sample values. Image
                                  objects are normally processed with
                                  special display tools to produce a visual
                                  representation of the sample values. This
                                  is done by assigning brightness levels or
                                  display colors to the various sample
                                  values.  Images are composed of LINES and
                                  SAMPLES.  They may contain multiple
                                  bands, in one of several storage orders.
 
                                  Note: Additional engineering values may
                                  be prepended or appended to each LINE of
                                  an image, and are stored as concatenated
                                  TABLE objects, which must be named
                                  LINE_PREFIX and LINE_SUFFIX.  IMAGE
                                  objects may be associated with other
                                  objects, including HISTOGRAMs, PALETTEs,
                                  HISTORY, and TABLEs which contain
                                  statistics, display parameters,
                                  engineering values, or other ancillary
                                  data.
 
       LINES                      The lines element indicates the total
                                  number of data instances along the
                                  vertical axis of an image.  Note:  In PDS
                                  label convention, the number of lines is
                                  stored in a 32-bit integer field.  The
                                  minimum value of 0 indicates no data
                                  received.
 
       LINE_SAMPLES               The line_samples element indicates the
                                  total number of data instances along the
                                  horizontal axis of an image.
 
       SAMPLE_TYPE                The sample_type element indicates the
                                  data storage representation of sample
                                  value.
 
       SAMPLE_BITS                The sample_bits element indicates the
                                  stored number of bits, or units of binary
                                  information, contained in a line_sample
                                  value.
 
       SAMPLE_BIT_MASK            The sample_bit_mask element identifies
                                  the active bits in a sample.  Note:  In
                                  the PDS, the domain of sample_bit_mask is
                                  dependent upon the currently-described
                                  value in the sample_bits element and only
                                  applies to integer values.  For an 8-bit
                                  sample where all bits are active the
                                  sample_bit_mask would be 2#11111111#.
 
       MAXIMUM                    The maximum element indicates the largest
                                  value occurring in a given instance of
                                  the data object.
 
       MINIMUM                    The minimum element indicates the
                                  smallest value occurring in a given
                                  instance of the data object.
 
       LINE_PREFIX_BYTES          The line_prefix_bytes element indicates
                                  the number of non-image bytes at the
                                  beginning of each line. The value must
                                  represent an integral number of bytes.
 
       LINE_SUFFIX_BYTES          The line_suffix_bytes element indicates
                                  the number of non-image bytes at the end
                                  of each line. This value must be an
                                  integral number of bytes.
 
       MEAN                       The mean element provides the average of
                                  the DN values in the image array.
 
       STANDARD_DEVIATION         The standard_deviation element provides
                                  the standard deviation of the DN values
                                  in the image array.
 
       SATURATED_PIXELS           The saturated_pixels element provides a
                                  count of the number of pixels in the
                                  array which at the maximum DN value.  For
                                  this dataset, the non-quantized data has
                                  a maximum value of 4095, while the
                                  quantized data has a maximum value of
                                  255.
 
      OBJECT = WINDOW             This object is a subobject of the image
                                  object and indicates that this image
                                  contains only a small portion of the
                                  original image.  The small portion was
                                  transmitted to the ground, most likely,
                                  in an attempt to conserve bandwidth.  The
                                  windowed data allows for the inspection
                                  of certain conditions on the spacecraft
                                  without the need to transmit the entire
                                  image to the ground.
 
        WINDOW_DESC               The window_desc value is the description
                                  of the windowed data.  It attempts to
                                  describe the circumstances around which
                                  this image data was collected.
 
        TARGET_NAME               The target_name element attempts to
                                  describe the item that was being observed
                                  at the time the image was acquired.
 
        FIRST_LINE                The first_line element indicates the
                                  first line where valid data begins in the
                                  image.  The full image was first padded
                                  with zeros and then this window of data
                                  was overlaid, forming an image of normal
                                  dimensions.
 
        FIRST_LINE_SAMPLE         The first_line_sample element indicates
                                  the leftmost column that contains valid
                                  data.  This value, paired with the
                                  first_line element create the
                                  upper-leftmost pixel of valid image data.
 
        LINES                     The lines element indicates the number of
                                  rows of image data associated with this
                                  window.
 
        LINE_SAMPLES              The line_samples element indicates the
                                  number of columns of image data
                                  associated with this window.
 
       END_OBJECT                 The end_object element terminates the
                                  object.
 
       CHECKSUM                   The checksum element represents an
                                  unsigned 32-bit sum of all data values in
                                  a data object.
 
       END                        End of the PDS Label.
 
 
    Contact Information
    ===================
        For any questions regarding the data format of the archive,
        contact:
 
        Christopher Hash
        Applied Coherent Technology Corp
        112 Elden Street, Suite K
        Herndon, VA 20170
        (703) 742-0294
        chash@actgate.com
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Note Overview
  ==============================
    The data collected here has been prepared with the highest concern
    for the perfectness of the data delivered.  During the processing of
    the image data in preparation for delivery with this volume, the
    structure of each image was verified.  This verification included
    detection of both the sync word and the line count bytes at the
    beginning of each line.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SAFED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

