<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mgs-m-rss-1-cru-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MARS GLOBAL SURVEYOR RAW DATA SET - CRUISE V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_global_surveyor::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mgs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.mgs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-rss-1-cru-v1.0__browserp_geo_mgs-m-rss-1-cru-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-rss-1-cru-v1.0__dvo_atmos_mgs-m-rss-1-cru-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-rss-1-cru-v1.0__dvo_geo_mgs-m-rss-1-cru-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tyler, G.L., G. Balmino, D.P. Hinson, W.L. Sjogren, D.E. Smith, R. Woo, S.W.
                   Asmar, M.J. Connally, C.L. Hamilton, and R.A. Simpson, Radio Science
                   Investigations with Mars Observer, Journal of Geophysical Research, 97,
                   7759-7779, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TYLERETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MGS-M-RSS-1-CRU-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MARS GLOBAL SURVEYOR RAW DATA SET - CRUISE V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1997-12-31</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1996-11-06</start_time>
        <stop_time>1997-09-02</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>RICHARD A. SIMPSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Simpson, R. A., MARS GLOBAL SURVEYOR RAW DATA SET - CRUISE V1.0,
            MGS-M-RSS-1-CRU-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 1997
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This archive contains raw radio science data and ancillary files
            acquired during the cruise phase of the Mars Global Surveyor
            (MGS) mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Mars Global Surveyor (MGS) Radio Science (RS) Raw Data
            Archive (RDA) is a time-ordered collection of raw and partially
            processed data collected during the MGS Mission to Mars. For more
            information on the investigations proposed see [TYLERETAL1992].
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Mars Global Surveyor (MGS) Radio Science (RS) Raw Data
      Archive (RDA) is a time-ordered collection of raw and partially
      processed data collected during the MGS Mission to Mars.
      For more information on the investigations proposed see
      [TYLERETAL1992].
 
      This data set was collected while the spacecraft was en route
      from Earth to Mars (the MGS Cruise Phase); it can serve as
      calibration for later Mars observations.  During Cruise,
      the spacecraft was far from other bodies, so evolution of
      its trajectory was very smooth.  Range and Doppler behavior
      could be predicted long in advance, and variability resulted
      from intrinsic limitations of the equipment (including
      unmodeled spacecraft activity) -- not from the phenomena
      being measured.  Some of the Cruise data have intrinsic
      science value of their own.  Approximately halfway through
      Cruise, three weeks of spacecraft and ground system time
      was devoted to a search for gravitational waves, presumably
      originating outside the solar system.
 
      Two types of measurements were conducted during Cruise; these
      are known as closed-loop and open-loop recordings.  The closed-
      loop system uses a phase-lock loop in the receiver to track the
      downlink signal, reporting both amplitude and frequency at
      intervals typically of once per second.  In the open-loop
      system, the signal is simply converted to a baseband frequency
      range; the entire passband is sampled and recorded for later
      processing.  Typical open-loop sampling rates for MGS were
      5000 samples per second.  Closed-loop data are efficient for
      characterizing slowly changing signals; open-loop data
      (because of their much higher volume) are collected only
      when the signal is very dynamic -- such as during an
      occultation.
 
      The data set includes three primary data types.  Archival
      Tracking Data Files (ATDFs or TDFs) are the most primitive (and
      most voluminous) product of the closed-loop system.  Orbit Data
      Files (ODFs) are edited versions of ATDFs, specifically
      targeted to spacecraft navigators and scientists interested in
      gravity fields.  Original Data Records (ODRs) are the primary
      data type from the open-loop system.
 
      Typical users of these data might analyze range and Doppler
      measurements in ATDFs or ODFs to derive the spacecraft
      trajectory during Cruise.  Relevant questions would include the
      measurement uncertainties in range and Doppler at different DSN
      antennas; these would set constraints on any model of Mars&apos;
      gravity field developed later, for example.  Users of ODRs
      could identify and characterize anomalous signals within the
      recorded passband, derive the drift of the USO during Cruise,
      and calculate Allan Deviation for various radio science
      configurations.  Data collected during the Gravitational Wave
      Experiment could be searched for evidence of gravitational
      waves.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      The ATDF is the primary output from the closed-loop system.
      Its format and content changed on 15 April 1997.  ATDFs
      generated before 15 April had 117 defined fields in the data
      records; ATDFs generated beginning on 15 April had 150 fields,
      though not all had been assigned.  Though the general nature of
      the ATDF parameters in the new version remained the same --
      status flags, Doppler residuals, range measurements, signal
      strength  estimates, etc. -- the scope of the measurements and
      their accuracies improved considerably.  Each ATDF in the data
      set is accompanied by a full PDS label which defines both the
      content and the format (at the bit level) of the file.
      ATDF data types include:
           High- or low-rate Doppler
           Uplink phase
           Differential Range vs Integrated Doppler (DRVID)
           Range
           Allan deviation
           Smoothed noise
           High or low-rate downlink phase
      Other information included in ATDF data records is date and
      time; spacecraft ID; ground station and its configuration;
      status flags and values reported by various ground systems;
      calibration values, noise estimates, and tolerances (station
      delay, transmitter power, etc.); and signal strength;
 
      The ODF is an edited version of the ATDF; it is a smaller file,
      issued more frequently than the ATDF.  It contains the most
      important information (range and Doppler) needed by spacecraft
      navigators and investigators interested in determining
      gravitational fields of bodies such as Mars.  Like the ATDF,
      its format and content were also upgraded effective 15 April
      1997.  Each ODF is accompanied by a full PDS label which
      describes both the content and format of the associated file.
      ODF data types include:
           Narrowband spacecraft VLBI, Doppler mode (cycles)
           Narrowband spacecraft VLBI, phase mode (cycles)
           Narrowband quasar VLBI, Doppler mode (cycles)
           Narrowband quasar VLBI, phase mode (cycles)
           Wideband spacecraft VLBI (nanoseconds)
           Wideband quasar VLBI (nanoseconds)
           One-way Doppler (Hertz)
           Two-way Doppler (Hertz)
           Three-way Doppler (Hertz)
           One-way total count phase (cycles)
           Two-way total count phase (cycles)
           Three-way total count phase (cycles)
           PRA planetary operational discrete spectrum range (range
                units)
           SRA planetary operational discrete spectrum range (range
                units)
           RE[GSTDN] range (nanoseconds)
           Azimuth angle (degrees)
           Elevation angle (degrees)
           Hour angle (degrees)
           Declination angle (degrees)
 
      Open loop data records (ODRs) contain 8- or 12-bit samples of
      receiver output.  Each block of (typically) 1000 data samples
      is accompanied by a 166 byte header.  Each ODR is accompanied
      by a full PDS label which describes both the content and format
      of the file at the bit level.  Header information includes:
           Date and time of first data sample
           Sample rate and channel assignments
           Receiver local oscillator (POCA) frequency
           Attenuator settings
           RMS voltages at several stages in the receiving chain
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      ATDFs are screened for &apos;bad&apos; data points, which are removed
      before the file is released by the JPL Radio Metric Data
      Conditioning Team (RMDCT).
 
      ODFs are abstracted from subsets of ATDF data.
 
      The open-loop format delivered to Stanford is usually the ODS
      (packet data).  In some cases where the Ground Data System
      (GDS) corrupted the ODS during delivery (or lost it entirely),
      data have been recovered from tape in ODR format.  ODS packets
      have been converted to ODR format for consistency in subsequent
      processing and archive; headers applied by GDS for ODS handling
      have not been preserved.  The resultant ODR (whether from ODS
      conversion or from backup tape) accurately represents the
      output of the DSCC Spectrum Processing (DSP) Subsystem at the
      DSN station.  A full PDS label accompanies each ODR file and
      gives a bit level description of the content and format.
 
      A 32-byte label at the beginning of each ODR tape is not
      included in the data file.  The 32-byte label gives the version
      of the data taking software; this information has been copied
      to the PDS label that accompanies the data file.   The software
      version recorded in the &apos;NOTE&apos; keyword is more likely to be
      accurate than the version recorded with the &apos;SOFTWARE_VERSION&apos;
      keyword.  Because the 32-byte label is no longer part of the
      data stream, users can treat the remaining file as an integral
      number of fixed-length records.  The 32-byte label was never
      defined in the ODS.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      Data are stored on CD-WO volumes approximately chronologically.
      Files which were delayed in delivery to Stanford may be out of
      order, however.  Users should consult listings in the
      INDEX/CUMINDEX.TAB file to ascertain full coverage of each file
      type.
 
      ATDFs were delivered irregularly during MGS Cruise; a full set
      is not available.  ATDFs were obtained for most USO tests and
      during the Gravitational Wave Experiment (GWE) in late April
      and early May 1997.  ATDFs are stored in the TDF directory on
      archival volumes.  File names are of the form   ydddeeeC.TDF
      where  y  is the one-digit year of the first data,  ddd  is the
      three-digit day-of-year of the first data,  eee  is the three-
      digit day-of-year of the last data, and  C  is a single letter
      (beginning with &apos;A&apos;) denoting the sequence in which files with
      the same  ydddeee  were handled.  Generally  ydddeeeB.TDF  is
      a revised version of  ydddeeeA.TDF.  The PDS label has file
      name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical ATDF file sizes are 39 Mbytes.
 
      ODFs were issued approximately daily throughout MGS Cruise; in
      some cases special ODFs were also created.  Most of the ODFs
      which were released are included in the archival data set.
      ODFs are stored in the ODF directory.  File names are of the
      form   ydddeeeC.ODF  where  y  is the one-digit year of the
      first data,  ddd  is the three-digit day-of-year of the first
      data,  eee  is the three-digit day-of-year of the last data,
      and  C  is a single letter (beginning with &apos;A&apos;) denoting the
      sequence in which files with the same  ydddeee  were handled.
      In most cases  ydddeeeB.ODF  is NOT simply a revised version
      of  ydddeeeA.ODF;  there were many requests for special ODF
      processing during MGS Cruise -- to obtain higher time
      resolution over short intervals, for example.  The PDS label
      has file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical ODF file sizes are
      small multiples of 8064 bytes (e.g., less than 100 kB).
 
      Original Data Records (ODRs) were produced whenever the DSP
      was set to &apos;run&apos; mode.  These files are stored in the ODR
      directory.  In most cases, the entire DSP run was collected
      into a single ODR file.  But in other cases, it was more
      convenient to subdivide the DSP data; queries were issued for
      shorter time spans, and separate files were produced.  File
      names are of the form  ydddhhmm.ODR  where  y  is the one-digit
      year of the first data,  ddd  is the day-of-year of the first
      data,  hh  is the hour on which the first sample was taken, and
      mm  was the minute on which the first sample was taken.  In
      cases were two files had the same nominal  ydddhhmm  (for
      example, two DSN stations began recording at the same time),
      the less significant digit in  mm  of the second file was
      converted to a letter (&apos;0&apos; became &apos;A&apos;, &apos;1&apos; became &apos;B&apos;, ...,
      &apos;9&apos; became &apos;J&apos;).  In cases where three files had the same
      ydddhhmm, the less significant  mm  digit was converted to
      &apos;K&apos;, &apos;M&apos;, etc.  For data collected during MGS Cruise, multiple
      ydddhhmm  instances occurred primarily from multiple queries
      for the same data, or from early data obtained as ODS and
      later data obtained as ODR from tape backup.  The PDS label
      has file name  ydddhhmm.LBL.
 
      At 5000 samples per second, a two-hour USO test would yield
      a 60 MB ODR -- one X-band (RCP) channel; 5 records per second,
      each with 1000 12-bit samples and a 166-byte header.  At
      200 samples per second, an eight-hour GWE run would yield
      a 33 MB ODR -- four channels (one X-RCP, the others null); 2
      records per second with 100 8-bit samples per channel and a
      166-byte header.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      An extensive set of ancillary files is needed for proper
      analysis and interpretation of the radio data (file types
      TDF, ODF, and ODR).  These are organized in parallel
      directories and stored approximately chronologically.
      When a file type was not represented on a CD-WO volume, the
      corresponding directory was omitted.  With the exception of
      files stored in the CALIB directory, ancillary files
      appeared on only one CD-WO volume.  Users should refer to
      the INDEX/CUMINDEX.TAB listing to locate ancillary files.
 
      Files in the CALIB Directory
      ----------------------------
        Files in the CALIB directory are those likely to have wide
        applicability in working with the raw data.  They help
        unpack and allow use of the raw data, rather than being
        &apos;instrument&apos; calibration data per se.  They include
        decommutation maps, clock conversion files, files of
        planetary constants, leapsecond files, and files needed for
        display of data on the MGS Science Operations Planning
        Computer (SOPC).  Each file is accompanied by a PDS minimal
        label.
 
        Clock Conversion files are produced by the JPL/PDS
        Navigation Ancillary Information Facility (NAIF) for use
        with NAIF-developed and MGS-provided software.  These are
        ASCII files of variable length records.  Each record is
        delimited by an ASCII carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13)
        line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10), which may need to be
        converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt; before the file is used
        on the local machine.  File names have the form  ydddeeeC.SCK
        where  y  is the one-digit year of the first date covered,
        ddd  is the day-of-year of the first date covered,  eee
        is the day-of-year of the last date covered, and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file
        with the same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos;
        and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers
        of similar coverage files.
 
        Planetary Constants files are produced by the JPL/PDS
        Navigation Ancillary Information Facility (NAIF) for use
        with NAIF-developed and MGS-provided software.  These are
        ASCII files of variable length records.  Each record is
        delimited by an ASCII carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13)
        line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10), which may need to be
        converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt; before the file is used
        on the local machine.  File names have the form  PCKydddC.TPC
        where  y  is the one-digit year of the file creation date,
        ddd  is the day-of-year of the file creation date, and  C
        is a character denoting sequence when more than one file with
        with the same  yddd  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos;
        and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers
        of similar coverage files.
 
        Leapsecond files are produced by the JPL/PDS
        Navigation Ancillary Information Facility (NAIF) for use
        with NAIF-developed and MGS-provided software.  These are
        ASCII files of variable length records.  Each record is
        delimited by an ASCII carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13)
        line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10), which may need to be
        converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt; before the file is used
        on the local machine.  File names have the form  LSKydddC.TLS
        where  y  is the one-digit year of the file creation date,
        ddd  is the day-of-year of the file creation date, and  C
        is a character denoting sequence when more than one file
        with the same  yddd  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos;
        and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers
        of similar coverage files.
 
        Channel Conversion Language files come in three types --
        source, dependency, and binary.  File names are of the
        forms  CCLydddS.SRC,  CCLydddD.BIN,  and  CCLydddB.BIN,
        respectively, where  y  is the one-digit year of the file
        creation date and  ddd  is the day-of-year of the file
        creation date.  Source files are ASCII files of variable
        length records.  Each record is delimited by an ASCII
        carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII
        10), which may need to be converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt;
        before the file is used on the local machine.  Dependency and
        binary files are identical to those used on the SOPC.  Source
        and binary files are typically 500 kB; dependency files are
        typically 15 kB.  Channel Conversion Language files are used
        in converting raw binary data in telemetry streams to
        meaningful numbers.
 
        Channel Parameter Table files come in two types -- source and
        binary.  File names are of the forms  CPTydddS.SRC  and
        CCLydddB.BIN, respectively, where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the file creation date and  ddd  is the day-of-year of the
        file creation date.  Source files are ASCII files of variable
        length records.  Each record is delimited by an ASCII
        carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII
        10), which may need to be converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt;
        before the file is used on the local machine.  Binary files
        are identical to those used on the SOPC.  Source and binary
        files are typically less than 1 MB.  Channel Parameter Table
        files are used in converting raw binary data in telemetry
        streams to meaningful numbers.
 
        Template Description Language files come in two types --
        source and binary.  File names are of the forms  TDLydddS.SRC
        and  TDLydddB.BIN, respectively, where  y  is the one-digit
        year of the file creation date and  ddd  is the day-of-year
        of the file creation date.  Source files are ASCII files of
        variable length records.  Each record is delimited by an
        ASCII carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt;
        (ASCII 10), which may need to be converted to either &lt;CR&gt;
        or &lt;LF&gt; before the file is used on the local machine.  Binary
        files are identical to those used on the SOPC.  Source and
        binary files are typically less than 1 MB.  Template
        Description Language files are used during display of data on
        the SOPC.
 
        Decommutation Map files come in two types -- source and
        binary.  File names are of the forms  DCSxxxxx.SRC  and
        DCOxxxxx.BIN, respectively, where  xxxxx  is a mnemonic for
        the map.  Only four Decommutation Map files were used during
        MGS Cruise.  DCSM515A.SRC  and  DCOM515A.BIN  were the source
        and binary maps, respectively, for DSN Monitor 5-15 data.
        DCSSCR14.SRC  and  DCOSCR14.BIN  were the source and binary
        maps, respectively, for spacecraft engineering data.
        Source files are ASCII files of variable length records.
        Each record is delimited by an ASCII carriage-return &lt;CR&gt;
        (ASCII 13) line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10), which may need to
        be converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt; before the file is
        used on the local machine.  Binary files are identical to
        those used on the SOPC.  Source and binary files are
        typically less than 200 kB.  Decommutation Map files are used
        in converting raw binary packet data to channelized formats.
        On the SOPC, they are used with the MGS-provided program
        mapx.
 
      Angular Momentum Desaturation Files (AMD Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Angular Momentum Desaturation files are produced by the MGS
        Spacecraft Team (SCT).  Each file documents a set of AMD
        events on the spacecraft.  These are ASCII files of variable
        length records.  Each record is delimited by an ASCII
        carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII
        10), which may need to be converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt;
        before the file is used on the local machine.  File names
        have the form  ydddeeeC.AMD  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee
        is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each AMD file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are less than 1500
        bytes.
 
      Channelized Engineering Data Files (ECH Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Channelized Engineering Data files are produced by the MGS
        query server, operating on telemetry packets stored in the
        MGS Central Data Base (CDB).  These are binary files, usually
        representing the collection of raw spacecraft engineering
        data received from a 24 hour period; they are not readily
        interpretable by end users.  File names have the form
        ydddeeeC.ECH  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee
        is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each ECH file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  File sizes can be as large as 200 MB.
        In general, an ECH file can be derived from the corresponding
        EPK file using MGS-provided software and a decommutation map.
 
        Also in some ECH directories are ASCII tables of extracted
        channel values--channelized state vectors, or CSV files.
        These are values for a limited number of potentially
        useful ECH channels that have been saved in tabular form.
        CSV files in the ECH directory have names of the form
        CSVydddC.ECH  where  y,  ddd,  and  C  are the same as for
        the corresponding ECH file.  Each CSV file is accompanied
        by a detached PDS label with name  CSVydddC.LBL  which
        completely describes the format and content of the CSV file.
 
      Engineering Channelized Data Summary Files (ECS Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Engineering Channelized Summary Data Files are created at
        Stanford during ingestion of spacecraft engineering data.
        Each file contains a summary line for each channel processed
        from the previous day&apos;s telemetry.  The ECS file thus gives
        a snapshot (mean and standard deviation) of each channel
        on each day.  ECS files are PDS TABLE objects; each is
        fully described as to format and content by a detached PDS
        label.  File names are of the form  ydddeeeA.ECS  where
        y  is the one-digit year of the first data,  ddd  is the
        three-digit day-of-year of the first data,  eee  is the
        three-digit day-of-year of the last data,  and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file with
        the same  ydddeee  is handled.  File sizes vary depending
        on the number of channels processed; typical growth is
        4000 bytes per day.
 
      Experimenters Notebook Files (ENB Directory)
      --------------------------------------------
        Experimenters Notebook files are e-mail messages and other
        notes collected during and shortly after data acquisition.
        They document expectations of various measurements and
        anomalies discovered in subsequent analysis.  File names
        have the form  ENByyddd.TXT,  where  yy  is the two-digit
        year and  ddd  is the three-digit day-of-year.  In general
        the messages in file  ENByyddd.TXT  refer to activities on
        that date regardless of when the message was sent.
        Alternatively, the characters  yyddd  may be used to
        indicate very tersely the subject matter of a collection
        of messages.  These are ASCII files with variable length
        records.  Each record is delimited by an ASCII
        carriage-return line-feed pair.
 
      Earth Orientation Parameter Files (EOP Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Earth Orientation Parameter files are produced by the Time
        and Earth Motion Precision Observation (TEMPO) Group at JPL.
        They document and predict Earth rotation (rate and axis).
        These are ASCII files of variable length records.  Each
        record is delimited by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).
        File names have the form  ydddzeee.EOP  where  y  is
        the one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is
        the day-of-year of the first data in the file,  z  is the
        one-digit year of the last data, and  eee  is the day-of-year
        of the last data in the file.  EOP files are typically
        released on Tuesdays and Fridays.  There are both &apos;long&apos;
        and &apos;short&apos; versions.  The long file covers past motion
        since about 1962 and a prediction for about three months into
        the future; these files have typical sizes of 860 kB.  The
        short file covers the most recent nine months of past motion
        and a prediction for three months into the future; these
        files are typically 30 kB.  Each EOP file is accompanied
        by a PDS minimal label with file name  ydddzeee.LBL.
 
      Engineering Packet Data Files (EPK Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Engineering Packet Data files are produced by the MGS
        query server, operating on telemetry packets stored in the
        MGS Central Data Base (CDB).  These are binary files, usually
        representing the collection of raw spacecraft engineering
        data received from a 24 hour period; they are not readily
        interpretable by end users.  File names have the form
        ydddeeeC.EPK  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee
        is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each EPK file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  File sizes can be as large as 100 MB.
 
      Filtered Body Rate Files (FBR Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Filtered Body Rate Files were created at Stanford from
        body rate data in the spacecraft engineering telemetry
        stream.  They give spacecraft attitude as a function of
        time.  FBR files are PDS TABLE objects; each is
        fully described as to format and content by a detached PDS
        label.  File names are of the form  ydddeeeC.FBR  where
        y  is the one-digit year of the first data,  ddd  is the
        three-digit day-of-year of the first data,  eee  is the
        three-digit day-of-year of the last data,  and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file with
        the same  ydddeee  is handled.  File sizes vary depending
        on the time interval covered.
 
      Daily Health Report Files (HEA Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Daily Health Report Files were created at Stanford; they
        summarize spacecraft engineering data of interest for Radio
        Science, list recently acquired radio data, summarize any
        analysis performed on recent radio data, summarize anomalies
        in recent radio science operations, and list files that have
        been obtained from the MGS CDB or other sources.  Daily
        Health Report Files are PDS TEXT objects; each has an
        attached PDS label.  File names are of the form  HEAydddC.TXT
        where  y  is the one-digit year of the report,  ddd  is the
        three-digit day-of-year of the report,  and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file with
        the same  ydddeee  is generated.  The first report on a day
        would be  HEAydddA.TXT;  subsequent revisions or updates
        would be  HEAydddB.TXT,  HEAydddC.TXT,  etc.
 
        Some Health Reports are accompanied by plots, saved as
        Type 1 PostScript files.  File names for these plot files
        have names of the form  HEAydddC.PSn  where  y  and  ddd
        are as defined above and  n  is the figure number.
 
        Both Health Reports themselves and accompanying PostScript
        files have variable length records delimited by carriage-
        return (ASCII 13) line-feed (ASCII 10) pairs.
 
      Ionosphere Calibration Files (ION Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Ionosphere Calibration files are produced by the
        Tracking System Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL.
        They document and predict Earth ionospheric conditions.
        These are ASCII files of variable length records.  Each
        record is delimited by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).
        File names have the form  ydddeeeC.ION  where  y  is
        the one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is
        the day-of-year of the first data in the file,  eee  is the
        day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file with the
        same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses
        to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage
        files.  Frequently, ION files are released at one week
        intervals to cover a single month;  ydddeeeA.ION  would be
        the file released during the first week,  ydddeeeB.ION  would
        be the file released during the second week, etc.  Each ION
        file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are less than 50 kB.
 
      Light Time Files (LIT Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Light Time files are produced by the MGS Navigation Team
        (NAV).  They give radio propagation time from the spacecraft
        to Earth vs time.  These are ASCII files of fixed
        length records.  Each record is delimited by an ASCII
        carriage-return &lt;CR&gt; (ASCII 13) line-feed pair &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII
        10), which may need to be converted to either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt;
        before the file is used on the local machine.  File names
        have the form  ydddeeeC.LIT  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee
        is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each LIT file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are less than 1 MB.
 
      Channelized DSN Monitor Data Files (MCH Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Channelized DSN Monitor Data files are produced by the MGS
        query server, operating on DSN Monitor packets stored in the
        MGS Central Data Base (CDB).  These are binary files, usually
        representing the collection of DSN Monitor
        data received from a 24 hour period; they are not readily
        interpretable by end users.  File names have the form
        ydddeeeC.MCH  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee
        is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each MCH file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  File sizes can be as large as 30 MB.
        In general, an MCH file can be derived from the corresponding
        MPK file using MGS-provided software and a decommutation
        map.
 
        Also in some MCH directories are ASCII tables of extracted
        channel values--channelized state vectors, or CSV files.
        These are values for a limited number of potentially
        useful MCH channels that have been saved in tabular form.
        CSV files in the MCH directory have names of the form
        CSVydddC.MCH  where  y,  ddd,  and  C  are the same as for
        the corresponding MCH file.  Each CSV file is accompanied
        by a detached PDS label with name  CSVydddC.LBL  which
        completely describes the format and content of the CSV file.
 
      Maneuver Implementation/Reconstruction Files (MIF Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Maneuver Implementation/Reconstruction files are produced by
        the MGS Spacecraft Team (SCT); they document spacecraft
        maneuver events.  These are ASCII files of
        variable length records.  Each record is delimited by an
        ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).  File names
        have the form  ydddeeeC.MIF  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee
        is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each MIF file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are 2327 bytes.
 
      Maneuver Performance Data Files (MPD Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Maneuver Performance Data files are produced by
        the MGS Spacecraft Team (SCT).  They contain estimates of
        spacecraft mass and center of mass; moments of inertia;
        thruster locations, directions, and magnitudes; and
        propellant flow rate.  These are ASCII files of
        variable length records.  Each record is delimited by an
        ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).  File names
        have the form  ydddeeeC.MPD  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee
        is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each MPD file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are 4 kB.
 
      DSN Monitor Packet Data Files (MPK Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        DSN Monitor Packet Data files are produced by the MGS
        query server, operating on DSN Monitor packets stored in the
        MGS Central Data Base (CDB).  Monitor data are records of
        DSN status and radio measurements.  These are binary files,
        usually representing the collection of DSN Monitor
        data received from a 24 hour period; they are not readily
        interpretable by end users.  File names have the form
        ydddeeeC.MPK  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee
        is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each MPK file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  File sizes can be as large as 30 MB.
 
      Orbit Propagation and Time Generation Files (OPT Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Orbit Propagation and Time Generation files are produced by
        the MGS Navigation Team (NAV).  They contain estimates of
        event timing (e.g., equator crossings) that depend on
        precise knowledge of the spacecraft orbit.  These are ASCII
        files of variable length records.  Each record is delimited
        by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).  File names
        have the form  ydddeeeC.OPT  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee
        is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;,
        etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.
        Each OPT file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file
        name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are less than 1 MB.
 
      Space Flight Operation Schedule Files (SFO Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Space Flight Operations Schedule Files are produced by the
        MGS Mission Control Team (MCT), usually in parallel with
        a corresponding Sequence of Event (SOE) file.  They
        graphically present parts of the SOE.  These are
        ASCII files of variable length records in a special format
        that allows use with the MGS-provided  sfosedt  program.
        Each record is delimited by a carriage-return (ASCII 13)
        line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10) pair, which may need to be removed
        before the file is used on the local machine.  File names
        have the form  ydddeeeC.SFO  where  y  is the one-digit year
        of the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of
        the first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the
        last data in the file, and  C  is a character denoting
        sequence when more than one file with the same  ydddeee  is
        handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc.
        with increasing numbers of similar coverage files.  Each SFO
        file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are less than 100 kB.
 
      Sequence of Event Files (SOE Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Sequence of Event Files are produced by the MGS Mission
        Control Team (MCT).  These are ASCII files of variable length
        records in a special format that allows use with the
        MGS-provided  soeedt  program.  Each record is delimited
        by a carriage-return (ASCII 13) line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10)
        pair, which may need to be removed before the file is used on
        the local machine.  File names have the form  ydddeeeC.SOE
        where  y  is the one-digit year of the first data in the
        file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of the first data in the file,
        eee  is the day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C
        is a character denoting sequence when more than one file
        with the same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and
        progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of
        similar coverage files.  Each SOE file is accompanied by a
        PDS minimal label with file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file
        sizes are less than 1 MB.
 
      Spacecraft/Planetary Ephemeris (SPK) Files (SPK Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Spacecraft/Planetary Ephemeris Files (also known as SP
        kernels or SPK files) are produced by the MGS Navigation Team
        (NAV).  These files give spacecraft and planetary ephemerides.
        These are ASCII files of variable length records in
        a special NAIF &apos;transfer&apos; format.  Each record is delimited
        by a carriage-return (ASCII 13) line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10)
        pair, which may need to be removed before the file is used on
        the local machine.  After delimiter conversion (if needed)
        the file would ordinarily be passed through the NAIF utility
        SPACIT  or  TOBIN  to convert it to the local binary format.
        File names have the form  ydddeeeC.SPK  where  y  is the
        one-digit year of the first data in the
        file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of the first data in the file,
        eee  is the day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C
        is a character denoting sequence when more than one file
        with the same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and
        progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of
        similar coverage files.  Each SPK file is accompanied by a
        PDS minimal label with file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file
        sizes are less than 5 MB.
 
      Spacecraft Attitude (CK) Files (TCK Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Spacecraft Attitude Files (also known as C
        kernels or CK files) are produced by the MGS Spacecraft Team
        (SCT).  These are ASCII files of variable length records in
        a special NAIF &apos;transfer&apos; format.  Each record is delimited
        by a carriage-return (ASCII 13) line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10)
        pair, which may need to be removed before the file is used on
        the local machine.  After delimiter conversion (if needed)
        the file would ordinarily be passed through the NAIF utility
        SPACIT  or  TOBIN  to convert it to the local binary format.
        File names have the form  ydddeeeC.TCK  where  y  is the
        one-digit year of the first data in the
        file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of the first data in the file,
        eee  is the day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C
        is a character denoting sequence when more than one file
        with the same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and
        progresses to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of
        similar coverage files.  Each TCK file is accompanied by a
        PDS minimal label with file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file
        sizes are less than 5 MB.
 
      Troposphere Calibration Files (TRO Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Troposphere Calibration files are produced by the
        Tracking System Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL.
        They document and predict Earth tropospheric conditions.
        These are ASCII files of variable length records.  Each
        record is delimited by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).
        File names have the form  ydddeeeC.TRO  where  y  is
        the one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is
        the day-of-year of the first data in the file,  eee  is the
        day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file with the
        same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses
        to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage
        files.  TRO files are typically released at the beginning of
        a month and cover the previous month.  Each TRO file is
        accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are less than 50 kB.
 
      UltraStable Oscillator Files (USO Directory)
      --------------------------------------------
        UltraStable Oscillator (USO) files are calibration data
        derived from open-loop radio measurments.  Files are PDS
        table objects with detached labels.  Examples include USO
        Allan Deviation (type A files) and the piecewise-continuous
        linear model of USO frequency (type M files).  File names
        are of the form  USOtyddd.TAB,  where  t  is the file type
        (see above),  y  is the one-digit year in which the file was
        created, and  ddd  is the three-digit day-of-year in which
        the file was created.  Each USO file is accompanied by a
        detached PDS label with name  USOtyddd.LBL  which completely
        describes the content and format of the file.
 
      DSN Weather Files (WEA Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        DSN Weather files are produced by the Tracking System
        Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL.  Files give weather
        calibration information for DSN complexes.  These are ASCII
        files of variable length records.  Each record is delimited
        by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).  File names have
        the form  ydddeeeD.WEA  where  y  is the one-digit year of
        the first data in the file,  ddd  is the day-of-year of the
        first data in the file,  eee  is the day-of-year of the last
        data in the file, and  D  is a single digit denoting the
        DSN complex at which the data were acquired (&apos;1&apos; for
        Goldstone, &apos;4&apos; for Canberra, or &apos;6&apos; for Madrid).  WEA files
        are typically released weekly and contain all weather data
        for the complex since 1 January.  Each WEA file is
        accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        ydddeeeC.LBL.  The files grow at the rate of approximately
        90 kB per month.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      SPK ephemeris files and TCK files were produced for the
      J2000 inertial reference frame.  NAIF reader routines may be
      used to convert these to other coordinate systems.
 
      Other data types are not dependent on definition of a
      coordinate system.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      Software for parsing, reducing, and analyzing data such as
      these has been developed at Stanford University and elsewhere.
      Because such software must usually operate at the bit-level and
      is written for a narrow range of platforms, it is not suitable
      for general distribution.  No software is included with this
      archival data set.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The archival data set is written on CD-WO media using the
      Young Minds CD Studio authoring system.  The CD-WO volumes
      conform to ISO 9660 standards.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this archival data set have been processed as part of
      health monitoring activities of the MGS Radio Science Team.
      In general, this is a good data set.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was reviewed by the MGS Radio Science
      Team prior to submission to the Planetary Data System (PDS).
      The MGS Science Data Validation Team (SDVT) set standards and
      procedures.
 
      Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data
      set, key elements of the archive were distributed for
      preliminary review.  These included electronic versions of
      example PDS labels, CATALOG files, and Software Interface
      Specifications.  These materials were distributed to PDS
      personnel, the experiment investigator, and others,
      as appropriate.
 
      ODR files on the CD-WO volumes were checked using Stanford
      parsing and reduction software to ensure that they were both
      complete and accurate replicas of the data contained in the
      original files.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Significant events for Radio Science during MGS Cruise were as
      follows:
 
         YY/DDD Start DSP Stop DSP  Comments
         ------  -------- --------  ----------------
         96/326  15:22:00 16:53:00  TCM-1
         96/332  04:46:00 07:00:25  USO Test #1
         96/345  10:00:00 12:00:00  USO Test #2 (no open-loop data)
         96/353  10:00:00 12:00:00  USO Test #3 (no open loop data)
         97/009                     Switch from LGT to HGA
         97/016  06:30:00 08:30:00  USO Test #4
         97/030  10:00:00 12:00:00  USO Test #5
         97/043  12:45:00 14:45:00  USO test #6 (tape data only)
         97/049  19:01:27 21:01:27  USO test #7
         97/061  12:31:50 16:31:51  USO test #8 (4 hrs)
         97/072  11:32:16 13:32:16  USO Test #9
         97/088  04:19:36 07:19:36  KaBLE/USO test
         97/092  05:57:30 07:00:00  USO Test #10 (1 hr; DSP error)
         97/104                     Begin GWE
         97/124                     End GWE
         97/126 (approx)            S/C enters safe mode
         97/142 (approx)            S/C exits safe mode
         97/162  02:00:00 04:00:00  USO test #11
         97/189  14:00:00 20:30:00  RS ORT #1
         97/193  20:30:00 02:10:00  RS ORT #2
         97/198  00:10:39 02:10:39  USO Test #12
         97/204  22:00:00 04:30:00  RS ORT #3
         97/220  05:15:00 11:45:00  RS ORT #4
         97/220  14:00:00 16:00:00  USO Test #13
         97/224  00:40:00 12:35:00  RS ORT #5
         97/237  12:00:00 01:00:00  TCM-4
 
      Quality of data was affected by anomalous conditions.  Examples
      include:
 
      Open-Loop (ODR) Data Anomalies
      ------------------------------
        1. Presence of 60 and/or 180 Hz spurs around carrier
        2. Presence of 30, 420, 540 Hz and higher spurs (infrequent)
        3. 650 Hz carrier sidebands (present when telemetry is ON)
        4. Missing data records (frequent)
        5. Amplitude modulation on various time scales of a few
             seconds and longer; modulation with a period of about
             33 secs was common unless spacecraft activities had been
             largely limited to radio science support
        6. Amplitude modulation with 100 minute period (resulting
             from spacecraft spin while in Cruise)
        7. Incorrect POCA values and/or POCA values out of
             sequence(common)
        8. Small spurs at 30, 48, 75 Hz from carrier (uncommon)
        9. Incorrect attenuator settings, DSP configuration
             (uncommon)
       10. Image of carrier in power spectra (common at 200 sps
             sampling rate)
       11. Spikes in frequency residuals at 209 sec intervals
             (when ranging ON)
       12. 60 Hz comb in power spectra, tracking carrier (seen once)
 
      Closed-Loop Data Anomalies (mostly observed in ODF)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        1. Interference from Goldstone Solar System Radar
             (infrequent)
        2. Discontinuities among range results at different stations
        3. Excessive Doppler noise in DSS 45 data
 
      Note that the official end of the Cruise Phase has been defined
      as 1997-09-12; when this data set was assembled, the end date
      was understood to be 1997-09-02.  If a complete understanding of
      Cruise data is required, users may wish to investigate the first
      few volumes in the  MGS-M-RSS-1-MOI-V1.0  data set.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The limitations in this data set follow from the quality of
      the execution, which is described above under Data Coverage
      and Quality.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>96-062A-04A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

