<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.phb2-m-ts-2-therm-vis-imgedr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>PHOBOS 2 MARS TERMOSCAN THERMAL/VISIBLE IMAGING EDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.phobos_2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.phb2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:ts.phb2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.phb2-m-ts-2-therm-vis-imgedr-v1.0__browserp_phb2-m-ts-2-therm-vis-imgedr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Murray, B., Naraeva, M. K., Selivanov, A. S., Betts, B. H., Svitek, T.,
                   Kharlamov, V. D., Romanov, A. V., Santee, M. L., Gektin, Y. M., Fomin, D. A.,
                   Paige, D. A., Panfilov, A. S., Crisp, D., Head, J. W., Murchie, S. L. and
                   Martin, T. Z., Preliminary Assessment of Termoskan Observations of Mars,
                   Planetary and Space Sciences, volume 39, no. 1-2, 1991, pp 237-265.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MURRAYETAL1991</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>PHB2-M-TS-2-THERM/VIS-IMGEDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>PHOBOS 2 MARS TERMOSCAN THERMAL/VISIBLE IMAGING EDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1992</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1989-02-11T10:55:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1989-03-26T17:49:50Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>Yuri Gektin</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>Unknown</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Visible and IR thermal flux images from the Termosan instrument
            aboard the Phobos-2 spacecraft. These data are saved for
            historical reasons.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            In February and March, 1989, the Termoskan instrument on board
            the Phobos &apos;88 spacecraft of the USSR acquired a limited set
            of very high resolution simultaneous observations of the
            reflected solar flux (hereafter referred to as the visible
            channel) and emitted thermal flux (thermal infrared (IR)) from
            Mars&apos;s equatorial region. These are, so far, the highest
            spatial resolution thermal data ever obtained for Mars. Four
            slightly overlapping thermal panoramas (also called scans or
            swaths) cover a large portion of the equatorial region from 30
            deg.S to 6 deg.N latitude. Simultaneous visible panoramas were
            taken during each of the four observing sessions; due to
            spacecraft memory limitations, visible channel processing was
            stopped early relative to the thermal channel for 2 of the
            sessions (2 and 4). Thus, the visible channel panoramas are
            shorter than the thermal panoramas for these sessions. These data
            are saved for historical reasons; they are not considered to be
            of archival quality.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      N.B.: These data are saved for historical reasons; they are not
      considered to be of archival quality.
 
      The &apos;edited data&apos; referenced here are in the PDS data set
      PHB2-M-TS-2-EDITED-THRM/VIS-IMG-EDR-V1.0.
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
      In February and March, 1989, the Termoskan instrument on board the
      Phobos &apos;88 spacecraft of the USSR acquired a limited set of very
      high resolution simultaneous observations of the reflected solar
      flux (hereafter referred to as the visible channel) and emitted
      thermal flux (thermal infrared (IR)) from Mars&apos;s equatorial
      region.  These are, so far, the highest spatial resolution thermal
      data ever obtained for Mars.  Four slightly overlapping thermal
      panoramas (also called scans or swaths) cover a large portion of
      the equatorial region from 30 deg.S to 6 deg.N latitude.
      Simultaneous visible panoramas were taken during each of the four
      observing sessions; due to spacecraft memory limitations, visible
      channel processing was stopped early relative to the thermal
      channel for 2 of the sessions (2 and 4).  Thus, the visible
      channel panoramas are shorter than the thermal panoramas for these
      sessions.
 
      The instrument was fixed to the spacecraft with the optical axis
      pointing in the anti-solar direction.  As a consequence, all
      observations are at approximately zero degrees phase angle and
      only daytime observations were acquired.  Scan lines were acquired
      approximately going from North to South on the planet at a rate of
      1 line per second.
 
      In the first session (taken Feb 11, 1989), the periapse altitude
      of the spacecraft&apos;s elliptical orbit was 1150 km and the
      resolution at nadir was approximately 300 m per pixel.  The
      thermal and visible channel panoramas from this session exhibit
      longitudinal gaps of varying size between scan lines. Within each
      scan line (acquired in the North-South direction), however, full
      resolution and coverage were maintained.  In the remaining three
      sessions (one taken on March 1, 1989 and two on March 26, 1989),
      the panoramas were acquired from a circular orbit of altitude 6300
      km with a resolution at nadir of approximately 1.8 km per pixel.
      In these panoramas, line and frame scanning correspond; therefore,
      there are not significant gaps between scan lines and geometrical
      distortions primarily occur only because of the sphericity of the
      planet.
 
      Each image consists of 384 samples.  The number of lines varies
      depending upon how long the instrument was on in any given
      panorama.  The data is 8 bit data with dn values ranging from 0 to
      255 for both the thermal and the visible channels.  West is
      towards the top of each image file and North is to the right.
 
      All of the Termoskan data is contained in the 23 files of this
      data set. These files were delivered by the Institute of Space
      Devices Engineering (ISDE) (Moscow) to Caltech (Pasadena) in
      April, 1990 (except for session 1 which was delivered a few months
      earlier).  The only difference between the files included here and
      those delivered from the Institute of Space Devices is that I have
      mirror flipped some of the files (resulting files all with the
      extension img: pan1irr1, pan1irr2, pan1vir1, pan1vir2, pan3irr1,
      pan3irr2, pan3irr3, pan3irr4, pan4vir1, and pan4vir2) as
      necessary.  This was needed because some, but not all, of the
      image files were delivered from ISDE with the images appearing as
      Mars would appear if you saw it in a mirror.
 
      Each of the thermal channel files in this data set has 512 samples
      because in addition to the 384 data pixels per line there are also
      126 pixels on one side of the image used for temperature stripes -
      each stripe representing the dn level for an additional 10 K.  The
      visible channel files  each have 384 pixels (except for session 1
      which has filler pixels to 512 samples).
 
      Each of these files are fragments of larger panoramas.  The pixels
      in the thermal channel files and visible channel files are not
      aligned (do not correspond to the same location on Mars) in this
      data set.  See confidence level notes for more details and see the
      edited data set for complete panoramas that have been corrected so
      as to have the thermal data aligned geometrically with the visible
      channel data.
 
      PDS1 Data Set Parameters
      ========================
      SAMPLING_PARAMETER_NAME = PIXEL
      SAMPLING_PARAMETER_RESOLUTION = 1
      MINIMUM_SAMPLING_PARAMETER = N/A
      MAXIMUM_SAMPLING_PARAMETER = 384
      SAMPLING_PARAMETER_INTERVAL = 1&lt;SECOND&gt;
      MINIMUM_AVAILABLE_SAMPLING_INT = N/A
      SAMPLING_PARAMETER_UNIT = N/A
      DATA_SET_PARAMETER_NAME = DN
      NOISE_LEVEL             = N/A
      DATA_SET_PARAMETER_UNIT = DIMENSIONLESS
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
      Confidence Level Overview
      =========================
      A given line and sample in the raw thermal files will not
      correspond to the same location on Mars as the same line and
      sample in any of the visible channel files. Various quirks within
      the data and the raw data files that cause misalignment of the
      thermal and visible images are taken into account in the edited
      data set (file names ending in ed) but not in this raw data set.
      These include the following.  Part of the misalignment problem is
      just due to the different raw files being of different length.  In
      addition there are: offsets at the beginning of the scans,
      probably caused by data lines added to the files on Earth; dropped
      (missing) data lines in some of the thermal data and in some of
      the visible data (in most of the raw data no gaps are left to
      distinguish these missing lines); 2 to 3 pixel offsets in the N-S
      direction between the thermal and visible channels (caused at the
      spacecraft), i.e., pixels need to be added to the beginning of
      each thermal line to make the thermal samples line up with the
      visible channel samples.
 
      In addition to the alignment problems, the following occur in the
      data: noise in every eighth sample of the thermal channel
      amounting to a positive 1 or 2 dn increase (probably tied somehow
      into the calibration that was going on at a similar rate);
      sporadic single pixel spikes that occur occasionally within the
      data; occasional partial lines which appear corrupted; occasional
      whole lines with single dn values that appear to preserve
      geometry, but have no value as data; depending upon the panorama
      either the first or last of the 384 sample pixels is corrupted in
      the thermal channel, leaving at most 383 good samples per line;
      and two bright West-East lines (affecting the same samples in each
      line) in visible panorama 1 (possibly caused by reflections off
      the spacecraft?).  The thermal channel appears to be very well
      calibrated to at least 3 K (Murray, et al. 1991).
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SAFED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

