<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dif-c-rss-1-9p-encounter-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DEEP IMPACT 9P/TEMPEL 1 ENCOUNTER - RADIO SCIENCE DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_impact::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.9p-tempel_1_1867_g1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dif-c-rss-1-9p-encounter-v1.0__browserp_dif-c-rss-1-9p-encounter-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Yeomans, D.K., J.D. Giorgini, and S.R. Chesley, The History and Dynamics of
                   Comet 9P/Tempel 1, Space Science Reviews, 117, 123-135, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3392-6.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.YEOMANSETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DIF-C-RSS-1-9P-ENCOUNTER-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DEEP IMPACT 9P/TEMPEL 1 ENCOUNTER - RADIO SCIENCE DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2006-06-28</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2005-06-27</start_time>
        <stop_time>2005-07-11</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JON D. GIORGINI</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            ABSTRACT_DESC and keywords andGiorgini, J. D. and D. K. Yeomans,
            DEEP IMPACT 9P/TEMPEL 1 ENCOUNTER - RADIO SCIENCE DATA V1.0,
            DIF-C-RSS-1-9P-ENCOUNTER-V1.0. NASA Planetary Data System, 2006.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw radio science data from the Deep Impact flyby spacecraft,
            collected during the encounter with comet 9P/Tempel 1.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains raw radio science data from the Deep
            Impact flyby spacecraft, collected during the encounter with
            comet 9P/Tempel 1.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Deep Impact (DI) comet Tempel 1 Radio Science
      (RS) Data Set is a time-ordered collection of raw and partially
      processed data collected during the DI flyby of the
      comet Tempel 1. Because the DI spacecraft flyby occurred at a
      close approach distance of 500 km and at a relatively high
      relative encounter velocity (10.1 km/s), there was no comet
      gravity signal in the tracking data and hence no gravity
      science.  In addition, there was no evidence in the spacecraft
      tracking data for dust or gas drag near the time of closest
      approach.  For information on the comet dynamics, see reference
      Yeomans, et al. (2005) [YEOMANSETAL2005].
 
 
      The radiometric data also supported DI Navigation.
 
      The data set includes:
 
        Directory   Description
        ---------   -----------
           ODF      Orbit Data Files containing closed-loop (two-way)
                     Doppler and sequential range measurements.
           EOP      Earth-Orientation Parameter file
           ION      Ionosphere calibration file
           TRO      Troposphere calibration files
 
 
      Typical users of these data might analyze range and Doppler
      measurements in the ODF to derive the DI trajectory during
      the comet Tempel 1 flyby.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      The ODF contains the most important information (range and
      Doppler) needed by spacecraft navigators. Each ODF
      is accompanied by a full PDS label which describes both the
      content and format of the associated file.  ODF data types
      can include those listed below. Only those marked below with an
      asterisk are present in this data set ODF.
 
           Narrowband spacecraft VLBI, Doppler mode (cycles)
           Narrowband spacecraft VLBI, phase mode (cycles)
           Narrowband quasar VLBI, Doppler mode (cycles)
           Narrowband quasar VLBI, phase mode (cycles)
           Wideband spacecraft VLBI (nanoseconds)
           Wideband quasar VLBI (nanoseconds)
        *  One-way Doppler (Hertz)
        *  Two-way Doppler (Hertz)
        *  Three-way Doppler (Hertz)
           One-way total count phase (cycles)
           Two-way total count phase (cycles)
           Three-way total count phase (cycles)
           PRA planetary operational discrete spectrum range (range
                units)
        *  SRA planetary operational discrete spectrum range (range
                units)
           RE[GSTDN] range (nanoseconds)
           Azimuth angle (degrees)
           Elevation angle (degrees)
           Hour angle (degrees)
           Declination angle (degrees)
           X angle (where +X is east) (degrees)
           Y angle (where +X is east) (degrees)
           X angle (where +X is south) (degrees)
           Y angle (where +X is south) (degrees)
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      ODF&apos;s are screened for &apos;bad&apos; data points, which are removed
      prior to analysis by the navigation or radio science teams.
      However, all data are included in these archived ODF&apos;s files,
      including &apos;bad&apos; data that may have been excluded during radio
      science or navigation analysis.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      ODFs were issued approximately daily during the flyby phase,
      occasionally more often to support critical events such as
      engine-firings (for maneuvers).
 
      These ODFs are stored in the ODF directory. File name is of the
      form  ydddeeeC.ODF  where  y  is the one-digit year (2005
      implicit) of the first data, ddd is the three-digit day-of-year
      of the first data,  eee  is the three-digit day-of-year of the
      last data. Symbol C denotes an alphabetic character
      distinguishing separate files issued during the same day.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      Ancillary files are needed for proper analysis and
      interpretation of the radio data (file type ODF). These are
      organized in parallel directories and stored approximately
      chronologically.
 
      Earth Orientation Parameter Files (EOP Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Earth Orientation Parameter files are produced by the Time
        and Earth Motion Precision Observation (TEMPO) Group at JPL.
        They are ASCII files with variable length records.  Each
        record is delimited by an ASCII carriage-return &lt;CR&gt;
        (ASCII 13) and an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).
        EOP files, issued three times a week, include results based
        on fits to historical data as well as extrapolated predictions
        into the future.  Subsequent file releases gradually replaced
        predict-intervals with data-based actual values. In this
        archive, one file has been selected such that it covers
        the DI flyby phase with data-based actual values.
        The file name has the form ydddzeee.EOP  where  y  is
        the one-digit year of the first data in the file (2000 is
        implicit),  ddd  is the day-of-year of the first data in the
        file,  z  is the one-digit year of the last data, and  eee  is
        the day-of-year of the last data in the file.  The file
        covers the previous nine months of past motion,  with
        prediction for three months into the future; files are
        typically 30 KB.  The EOP file is accompanied by a PDS
        minimal label with file name  ydddzeee.LBL.
 
 
      Ionosphere Calibration Files (ION Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Ionosphere Calibration files are produced by the
        Tracking System Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL.
        These are ASCII files of variable length records.  Each
        record is delimited by an ASCII carriage-return &lt;CR&gt;
        (ASCII 13) and an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).
        The file name has the form  ydddzeee.ION  where  y  is
        the one-digit year of the first data in the file (2000 is
        implicit),  ddd  is the day-of-year of the first data in the
        file, z  is the one-digit year of the last data in the file
        (2000 is implicit), and  eee  is the day-of-year of the last
        data in the file. ION files were released at one week
        intervals to cover a single month and included predicts for
        the rest of the month. The single file archived here is a
        concatenation of file releases that were issued at the start
        of a month, containing actual measured values for the month
        just past.  The ION file is accompanied by a PDS minimal
        label with file name ydddzeee.LBL.
 
 
      Troposphere Calibration Files (TRO Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Troposphere Calibration files are produced by the
        Tracking System Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL.
        These are ASCII files of variable length records.  Each
        record is delimited by an ASCII carriage-return &lt;CR&gt;
        (ASCII 13) and an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).
        File names have the form  ydddzeee.TRO  where  y  is
        the one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is
        the day-of-year of the first data in the file,  z  is the
        one-digit year of the last data in the file and  eee  is the
        day-of-year of the last data in the file. File 51525213.TRO
        contains measured data from 2005-June-01 to 2005-Aug-01. It is
        a concatenation of individual files released at the beginning
        of each month, covering the previous month. File 20018001.TRO
        contains a seasonal/cyclical adjustment for each site,
        interpreted by software as being applicable from 1972-Jan-1
        to 2048-Jan-1. Each TRO file is accompanied by a PDS minimal
        label with file name  ydddzeee.LBL.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      Analysis was conducted in the frame of the DE-405 solar system
      model, aligned with the 1993 ICRF/J2000 reference frame.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      Software for parsing, reducing, and analyzing data such as
      these has been developed at several institutions and elsewhere.
      Because such software must usually operate at the bit-level and
      is written for a narrow range of platforms, it is not suitable
      for general distribution.  No software is included with this
      archival data set.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this archival data set have been processed as part of
      the activities of the DI Navigation Team. This is an
      excellent data set.
 
    Review
    ======
 
      Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data
      set, key elements of the archive were distributed for
      preliminary review.  These included electronic versions of
      example PDS labels, CATALOG files, and Software Interface
      Specifications (SIS).  These materials were distributed to PDS
      personnel, the experiment investigator, and others,
      as appropriate.
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Significant events for Radio Science during Tempel 1 flyby phase
      are as follows:
 
        Summary of DI Maneuvers at comet Tempel 1
        2005 June 23 to 2005 July 11
 
                         Time    lng     DV      R.A.    Dec.  PreTCM PostTCM
        Event     Date   (UTC)  (sec)   (m/s)   (deg.)  (deg.)  (kg)   (kg)
        -----     ------------ ------- ------- ------- ------- ------ ------
        TCM-3B    23 Jun 19:00  62.448   6.002  22.281 -24.717 958.40 955.47
        TCM-5.1    3 Jul 00:00  20.912   0.322 110.460   1.785 955.42 955.43
        Divert-D.1 3 Jul 06:12 658.470 102.569  23.976 -27.448 583.67 558.04
 
        Table Column meanings:
 
          lng: solved-for duration of engine firing in seconds
          DV: solved-for velocity change (delta-V) in m/s
          DV, R.A. and Dec. are achieved maneuver parameters w.r.t.
          EME2000.  Right Ascension and Declination describe the
          orientation of the maneuver velocity in the EME2000 frame.
          Right Ascension is angle between coordinate system X-axis
          and the maneuver (delta V) vector projected on the
          Equatorial Plane and Declination is the angle between
          equatorial plane and the maneuver vector.
          PreTCM: mass before the trajectory correction maneauver (TCM) in kg
          PostTCM: mass after the TCM in kg.
          PreTCM and PostTCM masses were obtained from the attitidue control
          system after each maneauver.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The limitations in this data set derive from tracking geometry
      and measurement data types.  There are no known general or
      systematic defects in the data.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

