<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.go-j-mag-2-redr-raw-data-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GALILEO ORBITER JUPITER RAW MAGNETOMETER DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.galileo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mag.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:plasma_cloud.io_plasma_torus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.amalthea::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.callisto::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.europa::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.ganymede::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.io::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-j-mag-2-redr-raw-data-v1.0__browserp_go-j-mag-2-redr-raw-data-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kivelson, M.G., K.K. Khurana, J.D. Means, C.T. Russell, and R.C. Snare, The
                   Galileo Magnetic Field Investigation, Space Science Reviews, 60, 1-4, 357, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KIVELSONETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GO-J-MAG-2-REDR-RAW-DATA-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GALILEO ORBITER JUPITER RAW MAGNETOMETER DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1997-07-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1995-11-06T00:21Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2003-09-21T18:45Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. MARGARET G. KIVELSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            added ABSTRACT_DESC, , DATA_SET_MISSION OBJECT = DATA_SET OBJECT
            = DATA_SET_INFORMATION DATA_SET_NAME =Kivelson, M.G., Khurana,
            K.K., Russell, C.T., Walker, R.J., Joy, S.P.,Green, J., GO JUP/SW
            MAG EDR JUPAPPROACH/IO/JUP OPTAVG MRO V1.0,
            GO-J/SW-MAG-2-EDR-JA/I0/J0-OPTAVMRO-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 1995.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            All edited raw Galileo Magnetometer data aquired at Jupiter. Data
            are properly time tagged and include everything needed for
            determining and applying a calibration.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains raw magnetic field data acquired by the
            Galileo Orbiter magnetometer at Jupiter. The data set covers the
            time period from 1995-11-06T00:21:30 UT (Jupiter approach) until
            the end of mission (March 2003). The raw magnetometer data set
            includes various forms of data: recorded high time resolution,
            real-time survey (RTS), optimal averager (opt/avg), snapshot, and
            the calibration parameters required to generate processed data
            products. In addition corrected rotor angles and spacecraft
            relative clock and cone angles are provided to simplify future
            calibration and reprocessing of the data.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
       Data Set Overview
       =================
 
       This data set contains raw magnetic field data acquired by the
       Galileo Orbiter magnetometer at Jupiter. The data set covers the
       time period from 1995-11-06T00:21:30 UT (Jupiter approach) until
       the end of mission (March 2003). The raw magnetometer data set
       includes various forms of data: recorded high time resolution,
       real-time survey (RTS), optimal averager (opt/avg), snapshot, and
       the calibration parameters required to generate processed data
       products. In addition corrected rotor angles and spacecraft
       relative clock and cone angles are provided to simplify future
       calibration and reprocessing of the data. These data have been
       extracted from the packetized telemetry stream, time-tagged and
       time-ordered, and had duplicate records removed. Obviously
       corrupted data (e.g. spikes) have also been removed. MAG data are
       uncalibrated and provided in data numbers.
 
 
       Parameters
       ==========
 
       Data Sampling:
 
       Data acquisition strategies varied throughout the mission. High
       time resolution data were acquired only for short intervals near
       targeted satellite encounters and occasionally elsewhere in the
       magnetosphere. These data were recorded to tape and played back
       during the &apos;cruise&apos; portion of each orbit. During the Jupiter
       Approach period, most fields and particles (MWG) instruments were
       off. The magnetometer, on the other hand, acquired low resolution
       (opt/avg) data. During the bulk of the prime mission, the MWG
       instruments were allowed to acquire continuous RTS data whenever
       the spacecraft was inside 50 Jovian radii (Rj). When the MWG was
       not returning RTS data, MAG used its opt/avg capability to
       acquire low time resolution averages of the field. In general,
       these are ~32 minute averages, although some higher rate data
       (1-8 minute) were used to fill small gaps in RTS data coverage.
 
       RTS, opt/avg, and snapshot data were all stored in the MAG
       internal memory buffer. RTS data were continuously averaged at
       MAG memory address 4800 and transmitted to Earth in real-time.
       When an Opt/Avg ON command was given data were stored in the MAG
       memory buffer beginning at address 4800 and continuing to higher
       addresses until Opt/Avg OFF was commanded, another Opt/Avg ON was
       commanded and the MAG buffer began filling at 4800 again, or the
       MAG memory buffer filled. Opt/avg data was returned to Earth via
       Memory Read-Out (MRO) as telemetry permitted. Since RTS and
       opt/avg data used the MAG memory buffer in different ways, they
       could not be collected simultaneously. Snapshot data, which
       completely filled the MAG memory buffer, could likewise not be
       collected simultaneously with opt/avg, and caused periodic spikes
       in RTS data. Snapshot corruption of RTS data is discussed in more
       detail in the &apos;Data Quality and Coverage&apos; section of this
       document. For a more detailed discussion how MAG RTS, opt/avg,
       and snapshot data are collected, please refer to
       [KIVELSONETAL1992].
 
       When high-resolution data were available, but the RTS data were
       either lost or corrupted, simulated RTS (sRTS) data have been
       generated from the high-resolution data. sRTS data were averaged
       down to the RTS rate, then interpolated to be continuous with the
       existing RTS data.
 
       During the prime mission, the RTS data rate varied, depending the
       downlink capability. MAG has several different possible
       RTS data rates depending on the telemetry format:
 
       ----------------------------------------------------------------
       Table 1.               MAG RTS Rates
       ----------------------------------------------------------------
        Format     MAG bit rate    Time between samples    Corner Freq.
                     (bps)         (seconds)    (mf)         (Hz)
       ----------------------------------------------------------------
          A-D         2               24         36          1/34
          E           4               12         18          1/34
          F           6                8         12          1/17
          G           8                6          9          1/17
          H          12                4          6          1/17
          I          18               8/3         4          1/17
 
       Similarly, the opt/avg data can be acquired at different rates.
       The relatively high data rates fill the MAG internal memory
       buffer more quickly and are only used to cover short data
       disruptions.
 
       ----------------------------------------------------------------
       Table 2.          Optimal Averager Data Rates
       ----------------------------------------------------------------
       Time between samples     Buffer fill time     Corner Freq.
        (RIM)   (hh:mm:ss.ss)     (day/hh:mm)            (Hz)
       ----------------------------------------------------------------
           1     00:01:00.67         03:22             1/67
           2     00:02:01.33         06:44             1/134
           4     00:04:02.67         13:29             1/268
           8     00:08:05.33       1/02:58             1/536
          16     00:16:10.67       2/05:56             1/1072
          32     00:32:21.33       4/11:51             1/2144
 
       The instrument has the ability to acquire longer time averages,
       but these modes were not used at Jupiter.
 
       After the prime mission ended (December 1997), RTS data
       acquisition was limited to a few days near perijove with the
       exception of a few orbits. When RTS data were acquired, they were
       acquired exclusively in the 2 bps (24 sec/sample) telemetry
       formats. There were no modifications to the opt/avg data
       acquisition strategy associated with the end of the prime
       mission.
 
       Both the opt/avg and the RTS data processor compute field
       averages by applying a recursive filter and decimate algorithm to
       the data. The instrument applies a calibration, decimates vectors
       down to minor frame (mf) samples (2/3 second) and despins the
       data using the spin angle value broadcast on the spacecraft bus.
       The corner frequencies of the recursive filter are provided in
       tables 1 and 2 for the various sample durations. BOTH RTS AND THE
       OPT/AVG DATA ARE TIME TAGGED AT THE TIME OF DECIMATION (END OF
       AVERAGE) IN SPACECRAFT EVENT TIME (UTC). Averaged data overlay
       high time resolution data acquired at the same time best when
       these data are shifted in time by about 1/3 of the average
       length.
 
       MAG uses fixed gains to acquire data [KIVELSONETAL1992]. Gain
       states must be changed manually by sending a gain change command
       to the instrument. There are 3 ranges of field strengths that the
       instrument can measure:
 
       ----------------------------------------------------------------
       Table 3.    Magnetometer Ranges
       ----------------------------------------------------------------
       Field Range (nT)     Magnetometer, range
         min      max
       ----------------------------------------------------------------
         1/64  -    32      Outboard low field
          1/4  -   512      Outboard high field, Inboard low field
            8  - 16384      Inboard high field
 
       The outboard magnetometer, low field mode was used to acquire
       data beyond 60 Rj and the inboard magnetometer, high field
       mode was used to acquire data inside of 9 Rj. During the prime
       mission, the both the inboard low field and the outboard high
       field modes were used to acquire data between 9-60 Rj. As the
       outboard magnetometer is further out from the main body of the
       spacecraft on the boom than the inboard magnetometer it is
       impacted less by spacecraft fields. For this reason it was
       initially preferred over the inboard magnetometer. However, the
       outboard magnetometer began to experience abrupt changes in the
       sensor zero levels towards the end of the prime mission. As a
       result, the inboard magnetometer, low field mode was used to
       acquire data between 9-60 Rj throughout the remainder of the
       mission.
 
       The AACS data are provided at the same rate as any MAG data
       available for the same interval. MAG can be transformed from the
       various possible rotor coordinate systems by using the values of
       the rotor right ascension (RA), declination (DEC), twist, and
       spin phase (Spin) angles. Spin also allows transforming MAG data
       between spinning and despun (IRC) spacecraft coordinates.
       Calibrations to the spin plane sensors must be applied in the
       spinning reference frame. The spacecraft relative clock (clock)
       and cone (cone) give information regarding the relative positions
       of the Galileo rotor and scan platforms. Both clock and cone may
       be useful in removing spacecraft interference due to sources on
       the scan platform.
 
       Neither clock nor cone angles are returned in the spacecraft
       telemetry stream. Rather they are calculated from the rotor
       and scan platform angles that are returned. Clock and cone have
       been calculated in the following way:
 
         1) Convert Scan Platform RA, DEC, and twist into a C-Matrix
         2) Get unit vectors along platform M and L axis
         3) Convert Rotor RA, DEC, and twist to Cartesian coordinates
         4) Calculate cone angle (the angle between the Scan Platform
            the Rotor spin axis) and correct C-Matrix for cone position
         5) Convert Scan Platform C-Matrix into Stator C-Matrix
         6) Get &apos;N&apos; axis of stator
         7) Calculate clock angle (the angle between the spinangle and
            the stator N axis)
 
 
       Processing
       ==========
 
       The MAG data are raw. The data have merely been unpacked from the
       packetized telemetry and formatted into time-ordered tabular
       formats. Spikes and other obviously corrupted data have been
       removed. However, the data are &apos;processed&apos; in the instrument and
       a preliminary calibration is applied as part of that processing.
       The RTS and opt/avg data are irrecoverably altered by instrument
       processing. The only further processing that can be performed on
       these data is to change the sensor offset corrections. In the
       case of the high time resolution (LPW) data, the first step in
       any form of processing is to remove the onboard calibration and
       then apply an updated calibration. Both the onboard calibration
       and the calibration updates are provided a part of this data set.
 
       The AACS data have been interpolated to correct bad and missing
       data. These corrected AACS values have then been used in
       transforming the MAG data from spacecraft to geophysical
       coordinates.
 
 
       Data
       ====
 
       The raw telemetry data are logically separated into several data
       types. These include:
 
         MAG RAW LPW - high time resolution data, includes both recorded
                       (LPW) and record rate change coverage (RRCC) data
                       merged and properly time ordered
         MAG RAW RTS - real-time survey data, including both data
                       returned in real-time and those where the CDS
                       buffer needed to be dumped to tape in order to
                       order to prevent buffer overflow
         MAG RAW OPT AVG - data from the MAG opt/avg; data returned in
                       memory readouts (MROs) has been merged with the
                       data returned in the LPW stream
         MAG RAW ENG - MAG temperature and offset estimate data returned
                       in the engineering data stream
         MAG RAW SNAPSHOT - brief (7 sec) &apos;snapshots&apos; of the field at
                       the full instrument sample rate (30 samples/sec)
         AACS CORRECTED LPW - LPW rate corrected rotor angles and
                       uncorrected relative clock and cone angles
         AACS CORRECTED RTS - RTS rate corrected rotor angles.
 
       Each of these data types are stored in separate files. In
       general, data from a single orbit is included in a data file.
       For some of the more data rich orbits, further subdivision is
       necessary.
 
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       LPW data (SRC = spinning rotor coordinates)
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       Column   Type    Description &lt;units&gt;
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       time     char    Spacecraft event time, seconds since 1966
       sclk     char    Spacecraft clock (rim:mf:mod10:mod8)
       Bx       int     X field component in spinning coords &lt;DN&gt;
       By       int     Y (along boom) field component &lt;DN&gt;
       Bz       int     Z (spin aligned) field component &lt;DN&gt;
 
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       RTS data (IRC = inertial rotor coordinates)
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       Column   Type    Description &lt;units&gt;
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       time     char    Spacecraft event time, seconds since 1966
       sclk     char    Spacecraft clock (rim:mf:mod10:mod8)
       Bx       int     Southward field component &lt;DN&gt;
       By       int     Eastward field component &lt;DN&gt;
       Bz       int     Anti-Earthward field component &lt;DN&gt;
 
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       Opt/Avg data (IRC coordinates)
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       Column   Type    Description &lt;units&gt;
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       time     char    Spacecraft event time, seconds since 1966
       sclk     char    Spacecraft clock (rim:mf:mod10:mod8)
       Bx       int     Southward field component &lt;DN&gt;
       By       int     Eastward field component &lt;DN&gt;
       Bz       int     Anti-Earthward field component &lt;DN&gt;
 
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       Snapshot data (sensor coordinates)
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       Column   Type    Description &lt;units&gt;
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       time     char    Spacecraft event time, seconds since 1966
       sclk     char    Spacecraft clock (rim:mf:mod10:mod8)
       sen1     int     Sensor 1 field component in spinning coords &lt;DN&gt;
       sen2     int     Sensor 2 field component in spinning coords &lt;DN&gt;
       sen3     int     Sensor 3 field component in spinning coords &lt;DN&gt;
 
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       Eng data   (IRC coordinates)
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       Column    Type   Description &lt;units&gt;
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       time      char   Spacecraft event time, seconds since 1966
       sclk      char   Spacecraft clock (rim:mf:mod10:mod8)
       inb_Temp  float  Temperature of the inboard sensor &lt;K&gt;
       out_Temp  float  Temperature of the outboard sensor &lt;K&gt;
       ele_Temp  float  Temperature of the MAG electronics &lt;K&gt;
       adc_Temp  float  A/D converter temperature &lt;K&gt;
       Bx_avg    int    Average of spinning Bx (offset error) &lt;DN&gt;
       By_avg    int    Average of spinning By (offset error) &lt;DN&gt;
 
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       AACS data (LPW rate)
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       Column    Type   Description &lt;units&gt;
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       time      char   Spacecraft event time, seconds since 1966
       rotattr   float  Rotor right ascension (EME-50) &lt;radians&gt;
       rotattd   float  Rotor declination (EME-50) &lt;radians&gt;
       rotattt   float  Rotor spin phase angle (EME-50) &lt;radians&gt;
       spinangl  float  Rotor spin phase angle (ECL-50) &lt;radians&gt;
       screlclk  float  Spacecraft relative clock angle &lt;radians&gt;
       screlcon  float  Spacecraft relative cone angle &lt;radians&gt;
 
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       AACS data (RTS rate)
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       Column    Type   Description &lt;units&gt;
       ------------------------------------------------------------
       time      char   Spacecraft event time, seconds since 1966
       rotattr   float  Rotor right ascension (EME-50) &lt;radians&gt;
       rotattd   float  Rotor declination (EME-50) &lt;radians&gt;
       rotattt   float  Rotor spin phase angle (EME-50) &lt;radians&gt;
       spinangl  float  Rotor spin phase angle (ECL-50) &lt;radians&gt;
 
 
       Ancillary Data
       ==============
 
       There are several files that are provided in addition to the data
       files themselves that may be of value to the user. These include
       the following:
 
         MAG GAP LISTING - a detailed list of the timing and cause of
           data gaps
         MAG EVENT TABLE - a table of important spacecraft and
           instrument commands and events
         MAG_CALIB_SURVEY.TXT - a description of RTS and OPT AVG data
           onboard calibration procedures along with a time history
           of z-sensor offsets
         MAG_CALIB_HIGHRES.TXT - a description of high-resolution (LPW)
           data calibration procedures, including a description of the
           calibration used to process each recording
 
 
       Coordinate Systems
       ==================
 
       The data are provided in three coordinate systems, spinning
       spacecraft (LPW), despun spacecraft (RTS, opt/avg, Eng), and
       sensor coordinates (snapshot).
 
       The rotor portion of the spacecraft spins to allow the fields and
       particles instruments to see a larger fraction of the sky and to
       provide spacecraft stability. The coordinate system that is fixed
       with respect to the rotor (SRC), spins in an inertial frame. In
       this frame, the SRC Y-axis points away from the spin axis along
       the magnetometer boom. The SRC Z-axis is the rotor spin axis, and
       is positive in the opposite direction from the high gain antenna.
       X completes the right-handed set.
 
       Effects of the rotor spin can be removed by &apos;despinning&apos; the
       data by using either the &apos;rotor twist angle&apos; or the &apos;rotor spin
       angle&apos;. When the data are despun by using the spin angle, as
       broadcast on the spacecraft bus, the resulting data are in
       inertial rotor coordinates (IRC). In this frame, the X-axis
       is nearly aligned with the ecliptic normal (positive southward),
       the Z-axis points anti-earthward, and Y completes the right-handed
       set. Earthward pointing of the antenna is maintained for
       communication purposes to within ten degrees. The rotor right
       ascension, declination, and twist angle in the AACS data stream
       allow the data to be rotated into the inertial EME-50 reference
       frame.
 
       The MAG sensors are not perfectly aligned with respect to the
       rotor (spinning) coordinate system. In addition, two of the
       MAG sensors can be &apos;flipped&apos; to change which sensor is nearly
       aligned with the spin axis. Sensor 1 is fixed along the boom
       direction (SRC Y-axis). Sensors 2 and 3 flip. When the
       instrument is in the &apos;flip left&apos; state, sensor 3 is along the
       SRC Z-axis (spin axis) and sensor 1 oriented opposite the
       SRC X axis. In the flip right state, sensor 3 is along the
       SRC
 
 
       References
       ==========
 
       [KIVELSONETAL1992] The Galileo Magnetic Field Investigation,
          Space Science Rev.  60, 357, 1992
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
       Review
       ======
 
       These are raw data that have been reformatted by the instrument
       team. The team has reviewed the data and verified that they
       accurately reflect the MAG data returned by the instrument.
       After submission to the PDS, these data successfully completed
       the peer review process.
 
 
       Data Coverage and Quality
       =========================
 
       The magnetometer raw data set contains all of the data that were
       returned from the instrument. However, there are numerous gaps
       in coverage. Gaps can be caused by telemetry outages,
       insufficient downlink or uplink, conjunctions, instrument
       anomalies, spacecraft anomalies, commanding errors, etc. A
       detailed gap listing including a description of the reason for
       the gap is provided in a separate file with these data. Below is
       a list of some of the larger or more common gaps.
 
       Early in the prime mission, MAG was required to &apos;pay&apos; for the
       bits its used to return the opt/avg data by not acquiring as much
       high resolution data. MAG did not return data from the MWG
       transauroral crossing recorded interval in the C3 orbit so that
       it could have continuous coverage during that orbit. After the
       fourth orbit, the MAG opt/avg data was returned in the spacecraft
       engineering data stream at no cost to the team.
 
       JA:  Gaps in coverage due to limited telemetry
       J0:  Large gaps during probe relay and Io playback
       G1:  MAG flip/commanding anomaly, and spacecraft safing (2 and 1
            weeks respectively)
       J5:  Conjunction, limited telemetry (5 weeks)
       E6:  Instrument anomaly, radiation hit (2 weeks)
       G7:  MAG flip anomaly (1 week)
       E12: AACS anomaly (7 weeks)
       J13: Conjunction (6 weeks)
       E14: Spacecraft safing (5 days)
       E15: Ground station reallocated to SOHO for spacecraft anomaly
            recovery effort (3 days)
       E16: Spacecraft safing (4 days)
       E17: Ground station reallocated to Voyager 2 for spacecraft
            anomaly recovery effort (4 days)
       E18: Spacecraft safing, and ground station reallocated to NEAR
            for spacecraft anomaly recovery effort (2 days each)
       E19: Conjunction (3 weeks)
       I27: Conjunction (3 weeks)
       C30: Conjunction (3 weeks)
       I33: Conjunction (3 weeks)
 
       Other common causes of data gaps that are not related to
       telemetry outages and anomaly gaps are listed below. Gaps may
       have occurred throughout Jupiter Orbital Operations - whenever
       the conditions which caused them existed.
 
         Gaps between consecutive opt/avg segments: Gaps of at least two
           data vectors occurred between consecutive opt/avg data
           segments. The first and last vector in every opt/avg segment
           are underfiltered and have therefore been discarded. For the
           most common data opt/avg rate, this results in a gap of ~1
           hour. These gaps may be larger than two vectors if there is
           any delay between the MRO of the data in the buffer and the
           subsequent opt/avg ON command.
 
         Snapshot corruption of RTS data: When snapshots (see
           [KIVELSONETAL1992] for more information) were taken the
           addresses in which RTS data were averaged were overwritten
           with snapshot data. Since snapshots were written to MAG
           memory in reversed byte order, the result was a spike which
           persisted over the course of few records due to the
           application of the filter. Whenever possible RTS data
           corrupted by snapshots have been replaced with sRTS data
           which were unaffected by snapshots. When high-resolution data
           are not available, however, snapshots result in a series of
           short (3-6 vector), regularly spaced gaps in the RTS.
 
       It is difficult to define what is meant by data quality when
       discussing raw data products. These are the data returned by the
       instrument, after reformatting and the inclusion of time tags
       for each sample.
 
       SNPE_07.DAT - The first snapshot contained in the Ganymede 7 raw
         file (beginning ~1997-03-30 18:57:52.19) was shifted -.9 sec in
         order to match the LPW data. The sclk values were not updated.
 
       OPTE_09.DAT and OPTE_10.DAT - In Callisto 9 and Callisto 10
         orbits the magnetometer was commanded into opt/avg mode without
         deselecting the instrument from RTS. As a result the Command
         and Data Subsystem (CDS) overwrote the opt/avg rate filter
         constant stored that MAG memory with a RTS rate filter
         constant. This resulted in the data being under filtered
         relative to the data sample rate. This under filtering shows up
         as spin-tone in the spinning sensors in spacecraft coordinates.
         The spin-tone may be eliminated by averaging the raw data (two
         point averages on one point centers).
 
       LPWE_12.DAT - Due to a stronger than expected magnetic field near
         closest approach to Europa in the Europa 12 orbit, some of the
         magnetometer data was corrupted due to instrument saturation.
         The problem occurs 1997-Dec-16 11:53:00 - 12:05:20. For more
         information on the recovery process please refer to the file
         /CALIB/MAG/MAG_SATURATION.TXT.
 
       RTSE_17.DAT and AACS_RTS_17.DAT - Between 1998-09-26T15:46:24 and
         1998-09-26T16:42:01 the AACS data are unstable. Apparently,
         some form of AACS calibration was occurring. During this
         period, the magnetometer spin plane components appear to slowly
         rotate and then jump back to a correct orientation. This
         problem occurred on the spacecraft and has not been corrected
         in the ground system processing.
 
       AACS_RTS_19.DAT - Due to a spacecraft anomaly AACS data from
         1999-01-31 16:02:06 - 1999-02-01 01:49:37 were lost. The MAG
         data from this interval, however, were written to tape and
         returned later. Recovering the lost AACS - specifically the RA,
         and DEC - was complicated by two Science Instrument Turns
         (SITURN&apos;s) which occurred in the missing interval. In between
         the SITURN&apos;s, RA and DEC were interpolated by the following
         means:
 
         1/31 16:02:06 to 18:01:28     - set to last known value
         1/31 18:01:28 to 18:26        - linearly interpolated
         1/31 18:26    to 19:31:27     - assumed constant between
           and determined by examination
         1/31 19:31:27 to 19:49        - linearly interpolated
         1/31 19:49    to 2/1 01:49:37 - set to next known value (taken
           from high-res. data, the E19-EUR recording)
 
       AACS_LPW_21.DAT - The AACS data for this recording were seriously
         corrupted, and required special processing to correct. In order
         to correct rotor twist, and spin angle, the LPW rate data were
         discarded and the RTS rate data was interpolated to the LPW
         rate. The rotor right ascension and declination have been set
         to fixed values.
 
       AACS_LPW_22.DAT - The AACS data for this recording were seriously
         corrupted, and required special processing to correct. In order
         to correct rotor twist, and spin angle, the LPW rate data were
         discarded and the RTS rate data was interpolated to the LPW
         rate. The rotor right ascension and declination have restricted
         to a limited set of the most common values.
 
       AACS_LPW_23.DAT - The AACS data for this recording were seriously
         corrupted, and required special processing to correct. In order
         to correct rotor right ascension, declination, and twist
         angles, and the spin angle, the LPW rate data were discarded
         and the RTS rate data was interpolated to the LPW rate.
 
       AACS_RTS_23.DAT - It was necessary to interpolate the rotor twist
         and spin angles for the intervals:
           1999-09-17 05:26:41 - 06:08:30
           1999-09-27 16:06:58 - 16:28:53
         The first interval corresponds to the use of the Gyros to
         generate AACS onboard the spacecraft.
 
       RTS_25.DAT - Following recovery from spacecraft safing, MAG was
         inadvertently left in snapshot mode. As a result there are
         numerous short gaps where the RTS data were corrupted by
         snapshots, and a large gap where the OPT/AVG data were
         overwritten. This problem affects the interval
         1999-11-26 04:32 to 1999-11-29 00:54.
 
       RTS_26.DAT - The packet headers for the data from the time
         interval 2000-01-01 23:30:00.000 to 2000-01-03 14:08:39.742
         indicated that the data were sampled at 18 minor frames (mf) or
         12 seconds sampling resolution. This data rate matched the MAG
         RTS format reported in the sequence (format E). In the original
         12 second data there were a series of systematic gaps. The end
         of each gap occurred where the packet of MAG data included a
         time tag. This would be the case if an incorrect sampling rate
         were applied to the data in packets where no time tag is given,
         then the data were to jump forward to the correct time when a
         time tag was given. Accordingly the data in this interval were
         re-time tagged at 36 mf (24 second) samples. This done the data
         became continuous across what were previously gaps -- both in
         time (the data are evenly sampled), and data value (the data
         contain no steps). The reason for this discrepancy was unknown.
 
 
       Limitations
       ===========
 
       There are no particular limitations or warnings regarding the
       use of these data, in general, that are not described above.
       Users should review the PDS label files associated with
       individual data files for file (orbit) specific warnings.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>IN_PEER_REVIEW</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

