<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mgs-m-mag-1-map-highres-flux-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MGS MARS MAG MAPPING DETAIL WORD RESOLUTION V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_global_surveyor::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mgs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mag.mgs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-mag-1-map-highres-flux-v1.0__browserp_mgs-m-mag-1-map-highres-flux-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Acuna, M.H., J.E.P. Connerney, P. Wasilewski, R.P. Lin, K.A. Anderson, C.W.
                   Carlson, J. McFadden, D.W. Curtis, H. Reme, A. Cros, J.L. Medale, J.A. Sauvaud,
                   C. d&apos;Uston, S.J. Bauer, P. Cloutier, M. Mayhew, and N.F. Ness, Mars Observer
                   Magnetic Fields Investigation, J. Geophys. Res., 97, 7799-7814, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ACUNAETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MGS-M-MAG-1-MAP/HIGHRES-FLUX-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MGS MARS MAG MAPPING DETAIL WORD RESOLUTION V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2008-06-18</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1999-03-08T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. JOHN E. P. CONNERNEY</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>Unknown</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Calibrated time-ordered data tables from the Magnetometer
            instrument collected during the mapping phase and extended
            mission and expressed in payload coordinates and Sun-State
            coordinates. These are high time resolution (detail) data.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>Unknown</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  ====================================================================
  Overview:
  =========
 
    This data set contains vector magnetic field data acquired by
    the Fluxgate section of the Magnetometer / Electron
    Reflectometer instrument aboard the Mars Global Surveyor (MGS)
    spacecraft. The data are provided at a variable time resolution
    depending on the telemetry rate available to the investigation
    for the time period beginning with the prime mission mapping
    (1999-03-08). The data in the dataset cover the entire
    mapping time period (prime mission mapping and extended mission).
 
    The data are calibrated and provided in physical units (nT).
    Since high time resolution spacecraft engineering (in particular,
    measurements of power subsystem currents) data are not available,
    the calibration does not fully compensate for spacecraft fields.
    Estimates based on the linearly interpolating available spacecraft
    engineering data have been used.  The variable fields associated
    with articulation of the high gain antenna have been removed.
    The data are provided in payload coordinates and Sun-State (SS)
    coordinate system.
 
    For some applications, data processed in this manner are still
    useful.  However, for most applications, use of the fully calibrated,
    fullword data products that are also available through the PDS is
    recommended.
 
    The magnetometers on Mars Global Surveyor (MGS) are not boom
    mounted. They are mounted at the outer edge of the two solar
    panels, and both are about the same distance from the center of
    the spacecraft. In the traditional dual magnetometer technique,
    one of the two magnetometers is mounted at the end of a boom
    (outboard mag) and the other mounted closer to the spacecraft
    body (inboard mag). The data acquisition scheme usually allows
    for more rapid sampling of one or the other magnetometer to
    optimize the telemetry allocation usage. The outboard mag is
    usually describes as the the primary mag, the inboard as the
    secondary. On the Mars Observer mission, the magnetometer
    sensors were boom-mounted; Mars Global Surveyor uses flight
    spares mounted at the edge of the solar panels, approximately
    5.2 meters away from the spacecraft center. MGS data processing
    software is based upon software developed for Mars Observer.
 
    For MGS, we will preserve the terminology outboard and inboard
    mag for simplicity but we must define which is which.
 
    By definition, the MGS OUTBOARD MAG is on the S/C +Y solar panel
                   the MGS INBOARD  MAG is on the S/C -Y solar panel
 
    The bulk of the telemetry allocation is utilized by the outboard
    magnetometer.
 
 
  ====================================================================
  Sampling:
  =========
 
    The instrument samples the magnetic field at a rate of 32
    samples per second by using a clock system derived from the
    spacecraft system real-time interrupt (RTI) clock. Raw samples
    are averaged in the instrument according to the telemetry mode
    for the spacecraft and the data allocation for the MAG/ER
    investigation. The MAG investigation utilizes a data compression
    scheme to make efficient use of spacecraft telemetry while at
    the same time preserving the ability to recover gracefully from
    spacecraft telemetry errors and the like. A primary MAG full
    word sample consists of a 12 bit value for the x component, a 12
    bit sample for the y component, a 12 bit sample for the z
    component (all in sensor coordinates) and a 4 bit range word
    (bit one is an autorange/manual range switch; bits 2,3,4 are the
    0-7 range designation). Each primary MAG full word sample is
    followed by 23 difference samples in which the 6 bit difference
    from the previous value is telemetered, effectively doubling the
    data rate obtained within the telemetry allocation.
 
    Reconstructed full words are generated in ground data processing
    for high rate (detail) data. Full word samples, occur every 0.75s,
    1.5s, or 3.0s depending on the telemetry allocation.  There are
    23 detail words between full words occurring every 0.03125s, 0.0625s,
    or 0.125s depending on the telemetry allocation.
 
    Onboard averages are non-overlapping boxcar averages. Time tags
    are placed at the center of the averaging interval. The data
    rate allocation is summarized in the following table:
 
    Data Rate       Primary Samples         Secondary Samples
    (bits/sec)      (samples/second)        (samples/second)
    -----------------------------------------------------------
       324               8                       1/6
       648              16                       1/3
      1296              32                       2/3
 
    The magnetic field is sampled over a large dynamic range
    (+/- 4 nT to +/- 65536 nT) by automatically adjusting the
    instrument response (gain) in the magnetometer electronics.
    The nominal resolution of the 12-bit analog-to-digital (A/D)
    converter is provided in the following table:
 
    Range          Max Field       Resolution (12-bit)
                    (+/- nT)             (+/- nT)
    -----------------------------------------------------------
      0                4                  0.002
      1               16                  0.008
      2               64                  0.032
      3              256                  0.128
      4             1024                  0.512
      5             4096                  2.048
      6            16384                  8.192
      7            65536                 32.768
 
    Actual ranges may be expected to deviate from the nominal
    (design) range by varying amounts, ranging from as much as 5%.
 
    The instrument noise level is 0.006 nT rms over a
    10 Hz bandwidth. Note that in-flight performance is limited
    by the level of magnetic noise generated by the MGS spacecraft
    and the instruments it carries. Magnetic field fluctuations are
    best studied in either the sensor coordinate system (fixed to
    and aligned with the spacecraft solar panels) or the spacecraft
    payload coordinate system, since large differences in rms
    fluctuations can be seen in these components. The sensor y
    component evidences shows the smallest rms fluctuations of
    approximately 0.05 nT, whereas the x and z components are more
    variable with time and often exceed 0.5 nT.
 
 
  ====================================================================
  Processing:
  ===========
 
    Raw data are processed by applying a series of corrections
    which include sensor zero levels offsets, gain factors,
    scaling to physical units, and subsequent rotation into
    payload and geophysical coordinates.
 
    The instrument zero levels and gains are quite stable over large
    temperature ranges and time periods. Of more concern
    is the magnetic field generated by the spacecraft itself. In
    flight tests suggest that variation of the spacecraft field
    observed at the position of the magnetometer sensors when they
    are articulated in the frame of reference of the spacecraft
    is about 5 nT (static field). It is believed that this field is
    largely due to the TWTA amplifiers mounted on the communications
    dish (which was not deployed until after mapping orbit began).
 
    For Science Phasing orbits (SPO), the solar panels did not
    articulate and compensation for spacecraft fields can be done by
    simple adjustment to the instrument zero table; this method was
    used in the production of SPO datasets. Note that this method
    only works for SPO mission phase, and requires a stationary
    high gain antenna as well.
 
    NOTE that special spacecraft maneuvers were needed before an
    adequate spacecraft magnetic field model could be developed. These
    maneuvers were executed in late 1999 and February, 2000 (HGA
    articulation sequences). The February 2000 maneuvers resulted in
    a model for the field of the HGA.
 
 
  ====================================================================
  Spacecraft Field Estimation and Compensation:
  ============================================
 
    The spacecraft field estimation and compensation is a bit involved.
    The magnetometer measures the field due to all sources, the ambient
    field plus that of the spacecraft. The spacecraft may generate
    magnetic fields in many ways; the estimation problem is largely one
    of identifying correctly what on the spacecraft is responsible for
    the interference. It is usually very helpful to have specialized
    tests pre-launch to identify the prominent sources. Often one finds
    that it is impractical to operate the spacecraft in precisely the
    manner it will in space (e.g., powered by solar panels, power
    subsystem state, component articulations, thermal environment, and
    so on). Pre-launch tests of the MGS spacecraft identified permanent
    magnets on the High Gain Antenna (HGA) as the most significant
    source and sources associated with the power subsystem primary
    harness which were partially corrected.
 
    We categorize spacecraft sources as static or dynamic. Static
    fields are due to permanent magnetization, for example, magnets or
    magnetized objects. Magnetic fields are also produced by current
    loops, for example in power subsystems, solar arrays, batteries, and
    so on; these often scale with a known current and are called dynamic
    fields. For MGS, during mapping operations, the HGA is articulated
    in the frame of reference of the spacecraft (spacecraft payload
    coordinates, PL for short) as are the two solar panels upon which
    the magnetometer sensors are located. Each sensor also has an
    associated zero offset (for each range) vector which must also be
    estimated. Note that a spacecraft generated static magnetic field
    that is in the same reference coordinates as the sensor (sensor
    coordinates) will behave as a sensor offset.
 
    Spacecraft maneuvers conducted in February, 2000 were very helpful
    in characterizing the static field associated with the HGA. Of
    course, since the HGA is constantly articulating, the &apos;&apos;static&apos;&apos;
    field of the HGA is time variable as seen by the sensors. These
    maneuvers were designed to map the magnetic field of the HGA: the
    sensors (and solar panels) were set at fixed locations and the HGA
    was rotated in elevation several times. The field of the HGA could
    then be determined from the difference between the vector field at
    the two sensor locations. The difference must be used to eliminate
    the time variable, and mostly much larger, ambient field.
 
    A more complete model of the field at each sensor takes into account
    the possibility of a static field associated with the spacecraft
    and fixed in spacecraft pl coordinates (Bc), as well as dynamic
    fields both fixed in sensor coordinates (Bod) and fixed in
    spacecraft payload coordinates (Bcd). The former might arise
    from imperfect cancellation of current loops on the solar panels
    and the latter might arise from loops associated with power circuits
    fixed to the spacecraft body.
 
    These sources are to be characterized in flight and on orbit about
    Mars. The ambient field is large (to 250 nT) and variable, all of
    which looks like very large amplitude &apos;&apos;common mode&apos;&apos; noise to our
    sensors (in this effort; the ambient field is of course most welcome
    otherwise). So we can only use the difference between the
    measurements to characterize the spacecraft field.
 
    The magnetic field is modeled in sc payload coordinates
    (applies to both ib and ob sensors)
 
       Bpl = [ HGA ]  Bs   +  [ T ] Bo  + Ba + Bc
                           +  [ T ] Bod      + Bcd
 
       where Bpl is the field in cartesian payload coordinates,
             Bs  is the field of the HGA assembly, in cartesian
                 coordinates, in the HGA coordinate system;
 
           [HGA] is the transformation from HGA coordinates to
                 spacecraft payload coordinates.
 
             [T] is the transformation from sensor to s/c payload
                 coordinates.
 
             Bo  is the sensor zero offsets, constant (static)
 
             Ba  is the ambient field in sc payload coordinates
 
             Bc  is the spacecraft (body) field (static) in payload
                 coordinates
 
             Bod is field in sensor coordinates that scales with
                 the power system current (cartesian coordinates)
 
             Bcd is the spacecraft (body) field (dynamic) in payload
                 coordinates that scales with power system current
 
             Bod and Bcd are DYNAMIC spacecraft fields
                 we ASSUME they both scale with a spacecraft current
                 as follows:
 
             inboard  mag dynamic field scales with solar array
                 -y panel current;
             outboard mag dynamic field scales with solar array
                 +y panel current;
 
             Bcd, the spacecraft body field, scales with total current
                 (sao_i) output from the (shunted) arrays. This is the
                 current that goes into the power subsystem on the s/c
 
     we use the observation   Bpl (inboard) - Bpl (outboard)
     to remove the ambient field. Pure sensor rotations will
     constrain Bo, and coupled displacements/rotations (from
     solar panel movements) or HGA articulations will be used
     to constrain the spacecraft field Bs, modeled as an
     offset dipole about the HGA origin.
 
     A generalized inverse procedure is used to estimate the parameters
     of the various sources, e.g., the dipole coefficients of the HGA
     and the offset of the HGA source from the defined center of the
     HGA coordinate system; or scale factors (nT/A) for the x,y,z
     components of the dynamic field associated with solar panel
     current.
 
     The current spacecraft magnetic field model (that used in the
     processing of this data) is described in sc_mod.ker, provided
     with the MGS magnetometer fullword resolution data release.
     It uses an offset dipole for the HGA (tests demonstrated that no
     improvement in the fit resulted from using a higher degree and
     order spherical harmonic), referenced to the HGA coordinate system
     (which is at the end of the HGA boom, see SPICE documentation).
     We found that no additional static spacecraft field was needed
     and so this is zero in the current release. The dynamic fields
     are at present imperfectly estimated but amount to about 0.2 nT/A
     or less in each sensor.
 
     This dataset should be used in combination with the MGS magnetometer
     fullword resolution data set which includes additional variables,
     largely to let the user know exactly what spacecraft fields have been
     removed from the observations, and the calibration status of the data.
 
     In the command line variable in the attached header for these files:
 
     CMD_LINE  =  -mars -magonly -odl -detail -sc -ss time dday ob_bpl ob_b
 
     you find an option &apos;&apos;-sc&apos;&apos;, this means that the spacecraft field
     estimated using the model described in the &apos;&apos;sc_mod.ker&apos;&apos; file
     has been removed from the vector field. In addition to
     the variables ob_b (vector ambient magnetic field, ob mag) and
     posn (spacecraft position) we have added ob_bpl (ob mag in payload
     coordinates).
 
     A few plots of the HGA articulation sequences and the model fit
     to the (differenced) data are included in the fullword data set
     documentation directory.
 
 
  ====================================================================
  Media/Format:
  =============
 
    The data are provided as ASCII tables of time series data. These
    files are referred to as standard time series files (STS files),
    and all such files have a .STS suffix.  Each file has an attached
    header (called an ODL header, which represents the data producer&apos;s
    object definition language, distinct from the PDS Object Description
    Language). The header contains text describing the file processing
    and structure.
 
    The attached (machine readable) header provides sufficient
    information to understand what is in the file. A sample
    header is given below; it consists of nested OBJECT = KEYWORD
    and END_OBJECT pairs. This attached header is documentation,
    applied to the output file by the analysis program. Any
    detached header you see with these data has not been generated
    by the investigator team, but has been added by the PDS for
    compatibility purposes.
 
    The header, as well as any other non-numeric ASCII,
    can easily be stripped with the following AWK script:
 
    #
    #  script for files with odl
    #
    # this script will reject records until object
    # and end object statements are resolved (x=0)
    #
 
     /OBJECT/ &amp;&amp; !/END_OBJECT/ { ++x }
     /END_OBJECT/              { --x }
     x == 0 &amp;&amp; $0 !~ /[A-z]/   {
    #
 
     print $0
     }
 
    The attached header provides a level of traceability for the data
    product. All of the SPK and CK kernels loaded by the processing
    program, and used by the processing program to compute spacecraft
    position and attitude, can be readily identified in the
    CK_DOCUMENTATION and SPK_DOCUMENTATION objects. There are several
    of each that need be consulted to perform the necessary
    transformations. Please refer to JPL NAIF documentation for
    information regarding the SPK and CK kernels.
 
    The user may use either the attached or detached headers for
    automated plotting, depending on the software you have.
    PDS-provided software (if any) uses the detached headers (PDS
    label files). The OBJECT = RECORD / END_OBJECT nest describes the
    data in each record, but you must also be cognizant of the CMD_LINE
    keyword to interpret the vector variables. For example, the
    lines below indicate that
 
    OBJECT   =  VECTOR
      NAME   =  OB_B
      ALIAS  =  OUTBOARD_B_J2000
      TYPE   =  REAL
      OBJECT   =  SCALAR
        NAME   =  X
        FORMAT =  1X,F9.3
        UNITS  =  NT
             ...
 
    the variable ob_b (also known as outboard_b_J2000) is a
    real vector variable, consists of scalar components x, and
    so on, in units nanoteslas. Note that the instrument range
    is carried as a fourth component of the magnetic field vector, as
    this practice preserves reversibility. Range values R&gt;7 indicate
    automatic range selection on board, with the range = R-8. The
    range is coded as a four bit binary, with the most significant
    bit (8) turned on in auto range mode.
 
    The CMD_LINE options -odl -magonly -ss
    specify that odl header is requested; mag data only is
    processed, and magnetic field and position vectors are
    TRANSFORMED INTO SUN-STATE COORDINATES. This is why you need
    be cognizant of the CMD_LINE when you interpret the record.
    In the CMD_LINE, the option -Mars is implied, unless
    another body is specified, denoting that the center of Mars is
    the center of the coordinate system. If instead the option
    -phobos or -deimos appeared on the command line, the coordinate
    system is relative to these bodies instead.
 
    (In the following sample attached header, double quotation
    marks have been replaced by pairs of single quotation marks
    for the sake of PDS compatibility. A real attached header
    can contain double quotation marks.  Also, a few lines have
    been slightly condensed to reduce line length for ease of
    display in the present file.)
 
 
                       SAMPLE ATTACHED HEADER FOLLOWS
 
OBJECT      =  FILE
OBJECT   =  HEADER
  PROGRAM   =  mgan
  CMD_LINE  =  -mars -magonly -odl -detail -sc -ss time dday ob_bpl ob_b
  DATE      =  Tue Jun 26 18:41:27 2007
  HOST      =  lepmom
  COMMENT   =  This version MGAN compiled with F77 revision. 5.0 and
               spicelib MSOP_SCI V.6 (GENERIC_TOOLKIT V.N0049  on MAY 21,
               2007 by P.J. Lawton (ADNET at NASA/GSFC).
  TITLE     =  MARS GLOBAL SURVEYOR MAG/ER
OBJECT      =  CK_DOCUMENTATION
 
  MGS Solar Array Orientation CK File for Aerobraking-2
  ===========================================================================
 
  Created by Boris Semenov, NAIF/JPL April 3, 1999
 
  Orientation Data in the File
  --------------------------------------------------------
 
  This file contains orientation and angular velocity data for the Mars
  Global Surveyor (MGS) +Y and -Y nominal solar array frames --
  &apos;MGS_LEFT_SOLAR_ARRAY&apos; and &apos;MGS_RIGHT_SOLAR_ARRAY&apos; -- relative to the
  &apos;MGS_SPACECRAFT&apos; frame. The NAIF ID codes for the
  &apos;MGS_LEFT_SOLAR_ARRAY&apos; and &apos;MGS_RIGHT_SOLAR_ARRAY&apos; frames are -94001
  and -94002.
 
  This C-kernel provides the nominal orientation of the MGS solar
  arrays. However, this does NOT reflect the fact that the -Y solar
  panel did not fully deploy after launch, stopping short by
END_OBJECT
OBJECT      =  CK_DOCUMENTATION
 
  MGS Spacecraft Orientation CK File for Aerobraking-2
  ===========================================================================
 
  Created by Boris Semenov, NAIF/JPL, April 3, 1999
 
  Orientation Data in the File
  --------------------------------------------------------
 
  This file contains orientation and angular velocity data for the Mars
  Global Surveyor (MGS) spacecraft frame, &apos;MGS_SPACECRAFT&apos;, relative to
  the &apos;J2000&apos; inertial frame. The NAIF ID code for the &apos;MGS_SPACECRAFT&apos;
  frame is -94000.
 
  Status
  --------------------------------------------------------
 
  This file was created by merging daily CK files produced by the MGS
END_OBJECT
OBJECT      =  CK_DOCUMENTATION
    MGS Solar Array Orientation CK File for Mapping, Cycles 1-3
  ===========================================================================
 
    Created by Boris Semenov, NAIF/JPL, June 18, 1999
 
      Orientation Data in the File
  --------------------------------------------------------
 
    This file contains orientation and angular velocity data for the Mars
  Global Surveyor (MGS) +Y and -Y nominal solar array frames --
  &apos;MGS_LEFT_SOLAR_ARRAY&apos; and &apos;MGS_RIGHT_SOLAR_ARRAY&apos; -- relative to the
  &apos;MGS_SPACECRAFT&apos; frame. The NAIF ID codes for the
  &apos;MGS_LEFT_SOLAR_ARRAY&apos; and &apos;MGS_RIGHT_SOLAR_ARRAY&apos; frames are -94001
  and -94002.
    This C-kernel provides the nominal orientation of the MGS solar
  arrays. However, this does NOT reflect the fact that the -Y solar
  panel did not fully deploy after launch, stopping short by
END_OBJECT
OBJECT      =  CK_DOCUMENTATION
  Mars Global Surveyor High Gain Antenna Stowed Gimbal Orientation CK File
  ===========================================================================
 
  Orientation Data in the File
  --------------------------------------------------------
 
  This file contains orientation and angular rate data for the Mars
  Global Surveyor (MGS) High Gain Antenna (HGA) Elevation and Azimuth
  gimbal frames. The orientation of the &apos;MGS_HGA_EL_GIMBAL&apos; is given
  with respect to the &apos;MGS_HGA_HINGE&apos; frame; orientation of the
  &apos;MGS_HGA_AZ_GIMBAL&apos; is given with respect to the &apos;MGS_HGA_EL_GIMBAL&apos;
  frame.
 
  Status
  --------------------------------------------------------
 
  This file contains gimbal orientation for the stowed HGA position
  (EL = -95 degrees, AZ = 180 degrees) for the period of time from the
END_OBJECT
OBJECT      =  CK_DOCUMENTATION
 
 
******************************************************************************
  MGS -Y Solar Array Steady Attitude CK File
 
===========================================================================
 
  Version
  --------------------------------------------------------
 
  Version 1.1 -- by Boris Semenov, NAIF/JPL, January 17, 2000
 
  File coverage was extended to January 1, 2005. Deflection
  angle values were not changed.
 
  Version 1.0 -- by Boris Semenov, NAIF/JPL, September 16, 1998
 
  Initial Release.
 
END_OBJECT
OBJECT      =  CK_DOCUMENTATION
 
******************************************************************************
 
  Mars Global Surveyor High Gain Antenna Hinge Orientation CK File
  ==========================================================================
 
  Created by Boris Semenov, NAIF/JPL, March 30, 1999 Orientation Data in
 
  Orientation Data in the File
  --------------------------------------------------------
 
  This file contains orientation and angular rate data for the Mars
  Global Surveyor (MGS) High Gain Antenna (HGA) deployment hinge
  frame &apos;MGS_HGA_HINGE&apos; with respect to the &apos;MGS_SPACECRAFT&apos; frame.
 
  Status
  --------------------------------------------------------
 
  END_OBJECT
OBJECT      =  SPK_DOCUMENTATION
 
  Mars Global Solar Array / MAG Structures SPK File
==============================================================================
 
  This SPK file (FK) contains location of various MGS solar array structures
  and MAG sensors with respect to each other.
 
  If You&apos;re in a Hurry
  ----------------------------------------------------------------------
 
  In case you are not interested in details and just looking for the right
  NAIF code of a particular MAG sensor IT to use it in a call to SPKEZ,
  here is the list:
 
  -94051      +Y MAG Sensor ID;
  -94052      -Y MAG Sensor ID;
 
  Version and Date
END_OBJECT
OBJECT      =  SPK_DOCUMENTATION
  ; mar022-9000.bsp LOG FILE
  ;
  ; Created 1993-02-04/12:39:30.00.
  ;
  ; BEGIN NIOSPK COMMANDS
 
  LEAPSECONDS_FILE    = naf0000c.tls
  SPK_FILE            = mar022-9000.bsp
  SPK_LOG_FILE      = mar022-9000.log
  NOTE              = Made by CHA on Feb 4 1993
  SOURCE_NIO_FILE   = /scratch/naif/ephem/nio/gen/de202.nio
  BODIES          = 3, 399, 4, 10
  BEGIN_TIME      = 1990/1/01
  END_TIME        = 2000/1/01
  SOURCE_NIO_FILE   = /scratch/naif/ephem/nio/gen/mar022-9000.nio
  BODIES          = 401, 402, 499
  BEGIN_TIME      = 1990/1/01
  END_TIME        = 2000/1/01
 
  ; END NIOSPK COMMANDS
END_OBJECT
OBJECT      =  SPK_DOCUMENTATION
  Ephemeris DE403s                                        14-NOV-1995
 
  Objects In This Ephemeris
 
  Name                         Id-code
  ------------------------------------
  Sun...............................10
  Mercury Barycenter.................1
  Mercury..........................199
  Venus Barycenter...................2
  Venus............................299
  Earth Moon Barycenter..............3
  Moon.............................301
  Earth............................399
  Mars Barycenter....................4
  Mars.............................499
  Jupiter Barycenter.................5
  Saturn Barycenter..................6
  Uranus Barycenter..................7
  Neptune Barycenter.................8
END_OBJECT
OBJECT      =  SPK_DOCUMENTATION
 
  Mars Global Surveyor Antenna Structures SPK File
==============================================================================
 
  This SPK file (FK) contains location of various MGS antenna structures
  with respect to each other. If You&apos;re in a Hurry
 
  If You&apos;re in a Hurry
------------------------------------------------------------------------------
 
  In case you are not interested in details and just looking for the right
  NAIF code of a particular MGS antenna center to use it in a call to SPKEZ,
  here is the list:
 
  -94         s/c ID;
  -94000      s/c frame center ID;
  -94073      HGA center ID (reflector axis @ reflector rim plane);
  -94074      LGT1 center ID (center of the patch);
  -94075      LGT2 center ID (center of the patch);
END_OBJECT
OBJECT      =  SPK_DOCUMENTATION
 
  Mars Global Surveyor Aerobraking-2 SPK file, MGSNAV Solution
  ===========================================================================
 
  Created by Boris Semenov, NAIF/JPL, March 28, 1999
 
  Objects in the Ephemeris
  --------------------------------------------------------
 
  This file contains ephemeris data for the Mars Global Surveyor (MGS)
  spacecraft. NAIF ID code for MGS is -94.
 
  Approximate Time Coverage
  --------------------------------------------------------
 
  This file covers Aerobraking-2 (AB2) phase of the MGS mission (orbits
  573 through 1683):
 
END_OBJECT
END_OBJECT
OBJECT      =  RECORD
OBJECT   =  VECTOR
  NAME   =  TIME
  ALIAS  =  TIME
  TYPE   =  INTEGER
  OBJECT   =  SCALAR
    NAME   =  YEAR
    FORMAT =  1X,I4
  END_OBJECT
  OBJECT   =  SCALAR
    NAME   =  DOY
    FORMAT =  1X,I3
  END_OBJECT
  OBJECT   =  SCALAR
    NAME   =  HOUR
    FORMAT =  1X,I2
  END_OBJECT
  OBJECT   =  SCALAR
    NAME   =  MIN
    FORMAT =  1X,I2
  END_OBJECT
  OBJECT   =  SCALAR
    NAME   =  SEC
    FORMAT =  1X,I2
  END_OBJECT
  OBJECT   =  SCALAR
    NAME   =  MSEC
    FORMAT =  1X,I3
  END_OBJECT
END_OBJECT
OBJECT   =  SCALAR
  NAME   =  DDAY
  ALIAS  =  DECIMAL_DAY
  TYPE   =  REAL
  FORMAT =  F13.9
END_OBJECT
OBJECT   =  VECTOR
  NAME   =  OB_BPL
  ALIAS  =  OUTBOARD_B_PAYLOAD
  TYPE   =  REAL
  OBJECT   =  SCALAR
    NAME   =  X
    FORMAT =  1X,F9.3
    UNITS  =  NT
  END_OBJECT
  OBJECT   =  SCALAR
    NAME   =  Y
    FORMAT =  1X,F9.3
    UNITS  =  NT
  END_OBJECT
  OBJECT   =  SCALAR
    NAME   =  Z
    FORMAT =  1X,F9.3
    UNITS  =  NT
  END_OBJECT
  OBJECT   =  SCALAR
    NAME   =  RANGE
    FORMAT =  1X,F4.0
  END_OBJECT
END_OBJECT
OBJECT   =  VECTOR
  NAME   =  OB_B
  ALIAS  =  OUTBOARD_B_J2000
  TYPE   =  REAL
  OBJECT   =  SCALAR
    NAME   =  X
    FORMAT =  1X,F9.3
    UNITS  =  NT
  END_OBJECT
  OBJECT   =  SCALAR
    NAME   =  Y
    FORMAT =  1X,F9.3
    UNITS  =  NT
  END_OBJECT
  OBJECT   =  SCALAR
    NAME   =  Z
    FORMAT =  1X,F9.3
    UNITS  =  NT
  END_OBJECT
  OBJECT   =  SCALAR
    NAME   =  RANGE
    FORMAT =  1X,F4.0
  END_OBJECT
END_OBJECT
END_OBJECT
END_OBJECT
 
 
 
 
                       END SAMPLE ATTACHED HEADER
 
 
    The Science Team&apos;s naming convention for these files is
    mYYdDDD[pX]_TTTTTT.sts, where YY is the 2 digit year, DDD indicates
    the day of year (where Jan 1 = day 001), and TTTTTT is &apos;detail&apos;.
    The optional pX indicates which periapsis of the day is included in
    the file.  The PDS file naming convention for these data is the same
    as the science team&apos;s, but with all letters uppercase. The internal
    structure of each file is:
 
       Sample UT:     Time of the sample (UT) provided as a
                      set of integers that contain the year,
                      day of year, hour, minute, second, and
                      millisecond when the sample was
                      acquired at the spacecraft.
 
 
       Decimal Day:   Another representation of the sample
                      time as a decimal day of year (Jan 1
                      at 00:00 UT = 1.000).
 
 
       mag_vector:    Array[3] giving B-field components in the
       (OB_BPL)       order Bx, By, Bz in the payload coordinate system.
 
 
       Range:         Gain range of the instrument at the time of
       (OB_BPL)       the sample. Sample quantization is gain
                      range dependent. A negative value indicates a
                      detail word (verus fullword) entry.
 
 
       mag_vector:    Array[3] giving B-field components in the
       (OB_B)         order Bx, By, Bz in the sun-state coordinate system.
 
 
       Range:         Gain range of the instrument at the time of
       (OB_B)         the sample. Sample quantization is gain
                      range dependent. A negative value indicates a
                      detail word (verus fullword) entry.
 
 
  ======================================================================
  Coordinate Systems:
  ===================
 
    There are two principal coordinate systems used to represent
    the data in this archive: payload and sun-state (ss). Cartesian
    representations are used for both coordinate systems.
 
    The payload coordinate system is the frame of reference of the
    spacecraft.
 
    The ss coordinate system is defined using the instantaneous
    Mars-Sun vector as the primary reference vector (x direction).
    The X-axis lies along this vector and is taken to be positive
    toward the Sun. The Mars velocity vector is the second vector
    used to define the coordinate system. The negative of the velocity
    vector is used as a secondary reference vector so that the
    vector cross product of x and y yields a vector z parallel to
    the northward (upward) normal of the orbit plane of Mars. This
    system is sometimes called a Sun-State (SS) coordinate system
    since its principal vectors are the Sun vector and the Mars
    state vector.
 
 
  ======================================================================
  Ancillary Data:
  ===============
 
     Ancillary data can be found in the MGS magnetometer fullword
     resolution data set.
 
 
  ======================================================================
  Software:
  =========
 
    There is no software provided with this data archive.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  ======================================================================
  Review:
  =======
 
    The major uncertainty in these data is in the imperfect removal
    of spacecraft magnetic contamination.
 
    Since high time resolution spacecraft engineering (in particular,
    measurements of power subsystem currents) data are not available,
    the calibration does not fully compensate for spacecraft fields.
    Estimates based on the linearly interpolating available spacecraft
    engineering data have been used.  The variable fields associated
    with articulation of the high gain antenna have been removed.
 
 
  ======================================================================
  Limitations:
  ============
 
    Cruise observations indicate that the static spacecraft field
    is bounded by approximately +/- 5 nT at the sensor locations,
    as the sensors are articulated about the spacecraft body.
    For operations prior to mapping phase of the mission, the
    solar panels are largely fixed in the frame of reference of the
    spacecraft, moving only to assume the appropriate configuration
    for aerobraking near periapsis (and return). During these
    mission phases, it is possible to approximate the spacecraft
    field as a fixed offset, and remove it by adjustment of
    the sensor zero table. This is how the SPO dataset was reduced.
    The cruise observations, and SPO and aerobraking phase (AB)
    observations, were all acquired with the antenna in the stowed
    configuration. Prelaunch magnetic mapping indicated that the
    traveling wave tube amplifiers (TWTA&apos;s) on the antenna dish
    are the leading source of static magnetic field contamination.
 
    Mapping orbit data have been processed with a spacecraft magnetic
    field model used to compensate for spacecraft interference. This
    is described above. The model is deemed to be accurate at this
    time for the HGA source, but less so for the dynamic sources related
    to the power subsystem. We estimate the ambient field to be accurate
    to within 1 nT for all times when the solar panels are not
    illuminated. With illuminated solar panels the error is expected
    to be a few nT, depending on the configuration of the panels.
 
    The solar array currents in the MGS magnetometer fullword resolution
    data set should always be checked to confirm that the data are
    calibrated. When solar array currents were not available, &apos;-999&apos; was
    entered in the SAM_I, SAP_I, and/or SAO_I fields of the magnetometer
    fullword resolution data, and the data are not calibrated.
 
    The sample UT of the fullword data in these detail word data files
    may differ from the sample UT in the fullword data set by up to
    several milliseconds.  During the mission, the most recent (at that
    time) SPICE spacecraft clock (SCLK) kernel file was used for
    processing the fullword data set.  Since the end of February 2006,
    the MGS_SCLKSCET.00061.tsc (2006-02-26) version of the SCLK kernel
    file has been used for all processing.
 
  ======================================================================
  Data Coverage:
  ==============
 
    Gaps in data coverage exist for many reasons including
    telemetry outages and inadequate pointing and/or other
    engineering information. Gaps are not filled with flagged data.
 
    The reason that data are missing may include on or more of the
    following:
 
    1.) No magnetometer data available because it was not recorded
    on the MGS spacecraft, for operational reasons.
    2.) Magnetometer data was available but the solar panel CK
    kernel file was not available and observations could not be
    transformed into spacecraft payload coordinates.
    3.) Magnetometer data was available but the spacecraft CK kernel
    was not available and observations could not be transformed into
    the desired coordinate system.
    4.) Magnetometer data was available but the spacecraft SPK
    kernel was not available and the position vector could not be
    computed.
    5.) Magnetometer data was available but the spacecraft HGA kernel
    was not available and the position of the HGA could not be
    determined.
    6.) When solar array currents were not available, &apos;-999&apos; was
    entered in the SAM_I, SAP_I, and/or SAO_I fields (see the MGS
    magnetometer fullword resolution data) and the dynamic field was
    not calculated.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

