<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.near-a-rss-1-5-eros-flyby-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>NEAR EROS RADIO SCIENCE DATA SET - EROS/FLYBY V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.near_earth_asteroid_rendezvous::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.near::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.near::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.eros::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.near-a-rss-1-5-eros-flyby-v1.0__browserp_near-a-rss-1-5-eros-flyby-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Yeomans, D.K., P.G. Antreasian, A. Cheng, D.W. Dunham, R.W. Farquhar, R.W.
                   Gaskell, J.D. Giorgini, C.E. Helfrich, A.S. Konopliv, J.V. McAdams, J.K.
                   Miller, W.M. Owen, Jr., P.C. Thomas, J. Veverka, and B.G. Williams, Estimating
                   the mass of asteroid 433 Eros during the NEAR spacecraft flyby, Science, 285,
                   pp. 560-561, 1999.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.YEOMANSETAL1999</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>NEAR-A-RSS-1/5-EROS/FLYBY-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>NEAR EROS RADIO SCIENCE DATA SET - EROS/FLYBY V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1999-11-30</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1998-12-04</start_time>
        <stop_time>1999-01-03</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JON D. GIORGINI</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Yeomans D.K., Giorgini J.D., A. Konopliv, and E. Grayzeck, NEAR
            EROS RADIO SCIENCE DATA SET - EROS/FLYBY V1.0,
            NEAR-A-RSS-1/5-EROS/FLYBY-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 1999.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The NEAR Eros Radio Science Data Set is a time-ordered collection
            of raw and partially processed data collected during the NEAR
            flyby of minor planet 433 Eros.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The NEAR Eros Radio Science Data Set is a time-ordered collection
            of raw and partially processed data collected during the NEAR
            flyby of minor planet 433 Eros.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Near Earth Asteroid Rendevous (NEAR) Eros Radio Science
      (RS) Data Set is a time-ordered collection of raw and partially
      processed data collected during the NEAR flyby of minor planet
      433 Eros. For more information on the investigation conducted,
      including mass determinations results, see [YEOMANSETAL1999].
 
      Only data collected in the span after the engine abort anomaly,
      (with resumption of two-way lock-up Dec 21, 1998) and prior to
      DSM-2 burn January 3, 1999 was used for the mass estimation.
      The radio data also supported NEAR Navigation.
 
      The data set includes:
 
        Directory   Description
        ---------   -----------
           ODF      Orbit Data Files containing closed-loop (two-way)
                     Doppler and sequential range measurements.
           EOP      Earth-Orientation Parameter file
           ION      Ionosphere calibration file
           TRO      Troposphere calibration file
           TXT      Text files describing physical model inputs
                      and estimated solution parameters
 
      Typical users of these data might analyze range and Doppler
      measurements in the ODF to derive the NEAR trajectory during
      the flyby.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      The ODF contains the most important information (range and
      Doppler) needed by spacecraft navigators and those interested
      in determining gravitational parameters of Eros. Each ODF
      is accompanied by a full PDS label which describes both the
      content and format of the associated file.  ODF data types
      can include those listed below. Only those marked below with an
      asterisk are present in this data set ODF.
 
           Narrowband spacecraft VLBI, Doppler mode (cycles)
           Narrowband spacecraft VLBI, phase mode (cycles)
           Narrowband quasar VLBI, Doppler mode (cycles)
           Narrowband quasar VLBI, phase mode (cycles)
           Wideband spacecraft VLBI (nanoseconds)
           Wideband quasar VLBI (nanoseconds)
        *  One-way Doppler (Hertz)
        *  Two-way Doppler (Hertz)
        *  Three-way Doppler (Hertz)
           One-way total count phase (cycles)
           Two-way total count phase (cycles)
           Three-way total count phase (cycles)
           PRA planetary operational discrete spectrum range (range
                units)
        *  SRA planetary operational discrete spectrum range (range
                units)
           RE[GSTDN] range (nanoseconds)
           Azimuth angle (degrees)
           Elevation angle (degrees)
           Hour angle (degrees)
           Declination angle (degrees)
           X angle (where +X is east) (degrees)
           Y angle (where +X is east) (degrees)
           X angle (where +X is south) (degrees)
           Y angle (where +X is south) (degrees)
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      ODF&apos;s are screened for &apos;bad&apos; data points, which are removed
      prior to analysis by the navigation or radio science teams.
 
    Data
    ====
      ODFs were issued approximately daily prior to the NEAR Eros
      flyby, more often after the engine abort recovery.
 
      These ODFs are stored in the ODF directory. File name is of the
      form  ydddeeeC.ODF  where y  is the one-digit year (1990s
      implicit) of the first data, ddd is the three-digit day-of-year
      of the first data,  eee  is the three-digit day-of-year of the
      last data. Symbol C denotes an alphabetic character
      distinguishing separate files issued during the same day.
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      Ancillary files are needed for proper analysis and
      interpretation of the radio data (file type ODF).   These are
      organized in parallel directories and stored approximately
      chronologically.
 
 
      Earth Orientation Parameter Files (EOP Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Earth Orientation Parameter files are produced by the Time
        and Earth Motion Precision Observation (TEMPO) Group at JPL.
        These are ASCII files of variable length records.  Each
        record is delimited by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).
        File names have the form  ydddzeee.EOP  where  y  is
        the one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is
        the day-of-year of the first data in the file,  z  is the
        one-digit year of the last data, and  eee  is the day-of-year
        of the last data in the file.  The file covers the most recent
        nine months of past motion and a prediction for three months
        into the future; these files are typically 30 KB.  Each EOP
        file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        ydddzeee.LBL.
 
 
      Ionosphere Calibration Files (ION Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Ionosphere Calibration files are produced by the
        Tracking System Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL.
        These are ASCII files of variable length records.  Each
        record is delimited by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).
        File names have the form  ydddeeeC.ION  where  y  is
        the one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is
        the day-of-year of the first data in the file,  eee  is the
        day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file with the
        same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses
        to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage
        files.  Frequently, ION files are released at one week
        intervals to cover a single month;  ydddeeeA.ION  would be
        the file released during the first week,  ydddeeeB.ION  would
        be the file released during the second week, etc.  The files
        archived here are monthly files that contain actuals for the
        previous month. Each ION file is accompanied by a PDS minimal
        label with file name ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical file sizes are
        less than 50 kB.
 
 
      Troposphere Calibration Files (TRO Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Troposphere Calibration files are produced by the
        Tracking System Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL.
        These are ASCII files of variable length records.  Each
        record is delimited by an ASCII line-feed &lt;LF&gt; (ASCII 10).
        File names have the form  ydddeeeC.TRO  where  y  is
        the one-digit year of the first data in the file,  ddd  is
        the day-of-year of the first data in the file,  eee  is the
        day-of-year of the last data in the file, and  C  is a
        character denoting sequence when more than one file with the
        same  ydddeee  is handled.  C  starts from &apos;A&apos; and progresses
        to &apos;B&apos;, &apos;C&apos;, etc. with increasing numbers of similar coverage
        files.  TRO files are typically released at the beginning of
        a month and cover the previous.  Each TRO file is accompanied
        by a PDS minimal label with file name  ydddeeeC.LBL.  Typical
        file sizes are less than 50 kB.
 
 
      Text Files (TXT Directory)
      --------------------------
        Two file types are included in the TXT directory. The first
        type is NMLMODL.TXT and is accompanied by a minimal PDS label
        NMLMODL.LBL. It is the nominal set of namelist parameters
        used to define physical characteristics of the spacecraft&apos;s
        motion and tracking observables used by the JPL orbit
        determination software suite.  The second file is
        PARAMSUM.TXT, accompanied by minimal PDS label PARAMSUM.LBL,
        which is a summary of the estimated (solved-for) parameter
        set. GM9 is the solved-for Eros GM in units of km^3/s^2.
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      Analysis was conducted in the frame of the DE-403 solar system
      model, aligned with the 1993 ICRF/J2000 reference frame.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      Software for parsing, reducing, and analyzing data such as
      these has been developed at several institutions and elsewhere.
      Because such software must usually operate at the bit-level and
      is written for a narrow range of platforms, it is not suitable
      for general distribution.  No software is included with this
      archival data set.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this archival data set have been processed as part of
      the activities of the NEAR Radio Science Team. In general, this
      is a weak to fair data set. The principal limitation is the
      small amount of data prior to the flyby and immediately after a
      large, unknown delta-v thrust anomaly.
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was reviewed by the NEAR Radio Science
      Team prior to submission to the Planetary Data System (PDS).
 
      Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data
      set, key elements of the archive were distributed for
      preliminary review.  These included electronic versions of
      example PDS labels, CATALOG files, and Software Interface
      Specifications.  These materials were distributed to PDS
      personnel, the experiment investigator, and others,
      as appropriate.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Significant events for Radio Science during Eros Flyby are
      as follows:
 
         START           STOP
    YY/DDD UTC Time  YY/DDD UTC Time Comments
    ------ --------  ------ -------- ----------------
    98/354 22:00:00  98/354 22:03:20 Rendevous-1 settling burn
    98/354 22:03:20  98/355 06:40:00 Anomaly; unknown thrust vector(s)
    98/356 08:06:00                  Resume two-way Doppler (ERT)
    98/357 19:43:00                  Eros close-approach
    98/359 02:54:00                  Resumption of SRA data (ERT)
    99/003 17:00:00                  DSM-2 maneuver
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The limitations in this data set derive from tracking geometry
      and measurement data types. There are no known defects in the
      data.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>1996-008A-5</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

