<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.pvo-v-onms-5-superthermalionloc-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>PVO VENUS ONMS DERIVED SUPERTHERMAL ION LOCATION V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.pioneer_venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.pvo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:onms.pvo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.pvo-v-onms-5-superthermalionloc-v1.0__browserp_pvo-v-onms-5-superthermalionloc-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Niemann, H.B. and W.T. Kasprzak, Comparative Neutral Composition
                   Instrumentation and New Results, Advances in Space Research, vol. 2,
                   261-270, 1983.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NIEMANN-KASPRZAK1983</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Niemann, H.B., J.R.Booth, J.E. Cooley, R.E. Hartle, W.T. Kasprzak,
                   N.W.Spencer, S.H. Way, D.M. Hunten and G.R. Carignan, Pioneer Venus
                   Orbiter Neutral Gas Mass Spectrometer, IEEE Trans. on Geoscience and
                   Remote Sensing, vol. GE-18 (1), 60-65, 1980.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NIEMANNETAL1980B</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>PVO-V-ONMS-5-SUPERTHERMALIONLOC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>PVO VENUS ONMS DERIVED SUPERTHERMAL ION LOCATION V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1978-12-05T15:06:25.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1992-10-07T19:50:29.000Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. WAYNE KASPRZAK</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>TBD</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This dataset contains start and stop times/locations where
            superthermal ions were detected by the Neutral Mass Spectrometer
            instrument aboard the Pioneer Venus Orbiter.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>not applicable</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
         orbits          time
             1        1978-12-05T15:06:25.000Z
           645        1980-09-10T17:30:20.000Z
 
          4710        1991-12-29T00:40:49.000Z
          5055        1992-10-07T19:50:29.000Z
 
This dataset contains start and stop times/locations where superthermal
ions were detected by the Neutral Mass Spectrometer instrument aboard
the Pioneer Venus Orbiter. The instrument detected superthermal,
energetic or fast ions whose energy exceeds 36 eV in the spacecraft
frame of reference.  These ions were observed in early orbits during
measurements of the neutral density near periapsis, have an erratic and
unpredictable signature, and occur at too high an altitude to be due to
the neutral atmosphere. When the altitude of periapsis increased above
the point where neutral density measurements could be made, the
instrument was configured specifically to detect superthermal ions.  In
general, for orbit numbers 1 to 645, data were taken from the RPA mode.
The gas background signal with the filament on is about a factor of 10
less in this mode than in non-RPA mode, resulting in a lower detection
threshold. For orbit numbers above 923, the instrument was deliberately
configured with the filament off and non-RPA mode data was used. For
mass 16 the RPA voltage is about +3.8 volts.
 
The data reduction process has been described in Kasprzak et al. (1987).
The method used to reduce the data assumes cylindrical symmetry of the
ion source.  In actual fact, the source is asymmetrical in its angular
response (Guenther, 1989). This can introduce as much as a factor of 2
scatter in the data. No simple solution has been found for modeling this
asymmetry since the actual ion drift vector is unknown. The minimum
energy of an ion detectable by the ONMS in this ion mode is 35.9 eV. The
maximum transmission is assumed to occur about 10 V above this value.
On the nightside of Venus the spacecraft potential is negative and the
most probable ion energy is near 40 eV.
 
The ion species regularly monitored include: He+, N+, O+, N+ and/or CO+
and CO2+. Because of the paucity of data at other mass numbers only mass
16 (atomic oxygen) has been reduced to a flux and number density. As
part of the reduction process the angle in the ecliptic plane of the
apparent ion flow in spacecraft reference frame has been deduced. The
flux values are estimated in the spacecraft reference frame relative to
spacecraft ground. The density is computed from the flux by dividing it
by a speed corresponding to 40 eV. No correction has been applied to the
angle, density or flux in order to remove the effect of spacecraft
velocity.
 
The dataset fields are:
 
VARIABLE    COMMENT
--------------------------------------------------------
 ORBIT         Orbit number
 MASS          Mass number of species
                    4  He+
                   12  C+
                   14  N+
                   16  O+
                   28  CO+ and/or N2+
                   30  NO+
                   32  O2+
                   44  CO2+
 BTIME         Beginning time                 -|
 BTPER         Time from periapsis (sec)       |
 BALTIT        Altitude in (km)                |-- START
 BSZA          Solar zenith angle (deg)        |
 BLAT          Local solar time (hr)          -|
 ETIME         Ending Time                    -|
 ETPER         Time from periapsis (sec)       |
 EALTIT        Altitude in (km)                |-- FINISH
 ESZA          Solar zenith angle (deg)        |
 ELAT          Local solar time (hr)          -|
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
    In order to fit the data, a minimum of 30 points were required
    in 36 seconds. In addition, the maximum to minimum count ratio was
    required to be factor of 3 or greater in order to insure that there
    was a definitive spin modulation.  The center 12 seconds of data is
    divided by the fitting function to derive the equivalent flux for
    that point. The center of the new fitting interval is adjusted so
    that it is centered on the expected signal maximum predicted from
    the previous interval fit. As a result of this method of fitting,
    discontinuities may exist near minimum angle of attack where one
    12 second interval adjoins the next interval.
 
See Kasprzak et al. (1987).
 
Kasprzak, W.T., H.B.  Niemann and P.  Mahaffy, Observations of
Energetic Ions on the Nightside of Venus, Journal of Geophysical
Research, vol. 32, 291-298, 1987.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>78-051A-11H</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XD-B3A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

