<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.msl-m-chemin-2-edr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MSL MARS CHEMISTRY &amp; MINERALOGY X-RAY INSTRUMENT 2 EDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_science_laboratory::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.msl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:chemin.msl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.msl-m-chemin-2-edr-v1.0__browserp_msl-m-chemin-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.msl-m-chemin-2-edr-v1.0__dvo_geo_msl-m-chemin-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.msl-m-chemin-2-edr-v1.0__pds.geo.msl.analysts_notebook::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Vaniman, D., D. Bish, D. Blake, S.T. Elliott, P. Sarrazin, et al., Landed
                   XRD/XRF analysis of prime targets in search for past or present Martian life,
                   J. Geophys. Res. 103, E13, 31477-31489, 1998.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.VANIMANETAL1998</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MSL-M-CHEMIN-2-EDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MSL MARS CHEMISTRY &amp; MINERALOGY X-RAY INSTRUMENT 2 EDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2013-02-27</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2012-07-16</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID VANIMAN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Vaniman, D., Mars Science Laboratory Chemistry &amp; Mineralogy
            EDR Data V1.0, MSL-M-CHEMIN-2-EDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2012.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Unprocessed experiment data from the CheMin instrument aboard the
            Mars Science Laboratory rover.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Unprocessed experiment data from the CheMin instrument aboard the
            Mars Science Laboratory rover.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
 
      The CheMin instrument captures diffracted and fluoresced X-rays
      on a CCD detector. Up to 2730 individual images can be stored in
      the instrument, but the downlink capability of the rover does
      not support the transmission of these raw frames in their
      entirety. Processing onboard the rover is used to reduce the
      downlink data volume while preserving the scientific content of
      the data.
 
    Processing
    ==========
      CheMin EDR data products are considered CODMAC Level 2 or Edited
      Data (equivalent to NASA level 0) products. The EDR data files
      are generated from Level 1 or Raw Data, which are the
      telemetry packets within the project specific Standard
      Formatted Data Unit (SFDU) record.
 
      The CheMin EDR data products will be generated by the MIPL
      (Multimission Image Processing Laboratory) at JPL under the
      Operations Product Generation System (OPGS). The
      EDR data products will be raw uncalibrated data reconstructed
      from telemetry data products in the format described by the
      CheMin EDR SIS. Meta-data collected when the rover prepared the
      science data for downlink will be provided in PDS label.
 
      There will be multiple versions of a CheMin EDR. If telemetry
      data are missing during the initial downlink from the rover
      memory, partial data sets will be created and the missing data
      will be filled with zeroes. The data will be reprocessed after
      all data are received and the original version will be
      overwritten. There can be up to 2 EDRs created, one with a
      status of partial and the other with a complete status in the
      filename.
 
    Data
    ====
      The data types available from CheMin are described in the EDR
      SIS and are summarized as follows:
 
      1.  Diffraction - All:  Multiple (e.g., 120) raw images are
      combined into a single array with the same dimensions as the
      original images where only pixel values within a specified
      window of DN values are counted. This window will typically be
      selected to represent diffracted Co-Kalpha X-rays. This will be
      the primary data product used for diffraction studies.
 
      2.  Diffraction - Single: Same as &apos;Diffraction - All&apos; except
      pixel values within the specified window are counted only if
      they are surrounded entirely by pixels below a selected
      background threshold. This data set minimizes the contribution
      of diffracted Co-Kbeta X-rays and other extraneous events, but
      excludes many valid X-rays.
 
      3.   Diffraction - Split: Same as &apos;Diffraction-All&apos; except pixels
      are counted only if two adjacent values sum to produce a value
      that is within the specified window. This data set attempts to
      recover split events (X-rays depositing charge over multiple
      pixels) and can be used when the count-rate is low.
 
      4.  Film: Multiple (e.g., 120) raw images are summed into a
      single array. This product will have a higher background noise
      level given that all fluoresced X-rays are added in, but it will
      be the best product to use for diffraction studies if the grain
      motion is poor and there is a large occurrence of pixels
      capturing multiple diffracted X-rays within a single image.
 
      5.  Energy - All: The individual pixel values from multiple
      (e.g., 120) raw images are combined into a single energy histogram
      representing counts versus instrumental digital number (DN) energy bins.
 
      6.  Energy - Single: Same as &apos;Energy-All&apos; except pixel values
      are added to the histogram only if they are surrounded entirely
      by pixels below a selected background threshold. This will be
      the primary product used for selection of the diffraction window
      and for any chemical assessments of the data.
 
      7.  Energy - Split: Same as &apos;Energy-All&apos; except the only values
      added to the histogram are from the sum of two adjacent pixels
      which are surrounded entirely by pixels below the background
      threshold. This data set can be used to add counts to &apos;Energy-
      single&apos; when the overall count rate is low.
 
      8.  Raw frames: Unprocessed, single images are periodically
      retained for downlink to allow the science team to assess the
      performance of the onboard algorithms. One dark frame (no x-ray
      source) is collected before and after each analysis to track the
      health of the detector. CheMin can also be commanded to output
      &apos;thresholded&apos; raw data where a selected range of raw frames are
      extracted from the instrument but all pixels with values below a
      specified threshold and all pixels with values above a second
      specified threshold are set to zero. Even though data in this
      format will compress well, some valuable information will be
      discarded and the downlink requirements will still be relatively
      large. Nonetheless, this data format could be used if issues are
      identified in the onboard processing.
 
      9.  Housekeeping: A full set of parameters, temperatures,
      voltages, and other health/status data is captured periodically
      for downlink.
 
      10. CCD Frame: Individual CCD frames will be downlinked periodically
      to analyze CCD dark current, hot pixels, and overall CCD health. In
      the event that an off-nominal result is obtained such that K-alpha
      thresholds are incorrect or some other unforeseen circumstance renders
      the data reduction algorithms ineffectual, complete individual frames
      can be downlinked and processed using algorithms that can be written
      on the ground and uplinked to the rover.
 
    Data File Names
    ===============
      Data file names in the CheMin EDR and RDR archive are named according
      to the following scheme:
 
        &lt;instr&gt;&lt;config&gt;&lt;sclk&gt;&lt;prod&gt;&lt;sol&gt;&lt;site&gt;&lt;drive&gt;&lt;seq&gt;&lt;venue&gt;&lt;ver&gt;.&lt;ext&gt;
 
      where
 
       &lt;instr&gt;  = CM (CheMin)
       &lt;config&gt; = A_, B_, or __ (instrument configuration)
       &lt;sclk&gt;   = 9-character spacecraft clock count
       &lt;prod&gt;   = 3-character product type
       &lt;sol&gt;    = 4-digit sol number
       &lt;site&gt;   = 3-character site location
       &lt;drive&gt;  = 4-character drive position
       &lt;seq&gt;    = 7-character CheMin sequence identifier
       &lt;venue&gt;  = 1-character producer identifier
       &lt;ver&gt;    = 1-character version identifier
       &lt;ext&gt;    = IMG (image), DAT (binary table), CSV (ASCII delimited table)
 
      See the CheMin EDR Data Product Software Interface Specification in
      the Document directory of the archive for details about the file
      naming scheme.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      The data presented in the CheMin EDR is intended to be the least
      processed, most primitive data set released for CheMin. Data
      presented here are an accurate representation of CheMin data as
      received from the rover.
 
    Review
    ======
      The CheMin EDR products are reviewed internally by the CheMin team
      prior to release to the PDS. PDS also performs an external peer
      review of the CheMin EDR.
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      This section will be updated with the first release of CheMin EDR
      data to the PDS.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The major limitation of this data set is that this is level 0,
      minimally processed data. The data are received from the
      spacecraft telemetry and ingested into a database. If gaps
      exist in the telemetry, data are lost.
 
    Data Compression
    ===============
      No data compression is used.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

