<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ear-c-5-ddr-pcc-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>PHYSICAL CHARACTERISTICS OF COMETS</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.publit::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:compil.publit::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.comet::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-c-5-ddr-pcc-v1.0__browserp_ear-c-5-ddr-pcc-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   S.K. Vsekhsvyatskii and Il&apos;ichishina, N.I., &apos;Absolute Magnitudes of
                   Comets, 1965-1969&apos;, Soviet Astronomy - AJ [in English], Vol 15, 310-13,
                   1971.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.VSEKHSVYATSKII-1971</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   S.K. Vsekhsvyatskii and Il&apos;chishina, N.I., &apos;Fizicheskie Kharakteristiki
                   Komet, 1965-1970gg&apos; [in Russian] (Moskva: Izdatel&apos;stva Nauka), 1974.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.VSEKHSVYATSKII-1974</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   S.K. Vsekhsvyatskii, &apos;Absolute Magnitudes of 1954-1960 Comets&apos;, Soviet
                   Astronomy - AJ [in English], Vol. 6, 849- 53, 1963.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.VSEKHSVYATSKII1963</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   S.K. Vsekhsvyatskii, &apos;Physical Characteristics of Comets&apos;, trans. Israel
                   Program for Scientific Translations, NASA TT F-80 / OTS 62-11031, 1964.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.VSEKHSVYATSKII1964</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   S.K. Vsekhsvyatskii, &apos;Physical Characteristics of Comets Observed During
                   1961-1965&apos;, Soviet Astronomy - AJ [in English], Vol. 10, 1034-41, 1967.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.VSEKHSVYATSKII1967</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   S.K. Vsekhsvyatskii, &apos;Fizicheskie Kharakteristiki Komet 1971-1975gg&apos; [in
                   Russian] (Kiev: Kaukova Dumka), 1979.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.VSEKHSVYATSKII1979</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>EAR-C-5-DDR-PCC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>PHYSICAL CHARACTERISTICS OF COMETS</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1998-10-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>-0466-01-01</start_time>
        <stop_time>1975</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>MICHAEL F. A'HEARN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Vsekhsvyatskii, S. K., A.C. Raugh and M. A&apos;Hearn, PHYSICAL
            CHARACTERISTICS OF COMETS, EAR-C-5-DDR-PCC-V1.0, NASA Planetary
            Data System, 1998.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Physical characteristics of comets observed from -466 to 1975,
            compiled by S. K. Vsekhsvyatskii.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Physical characteristics of comets observed from -466 to 1975,
            compiled by S. K. Vsekhsvyatskii.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
  This dataset is a compilation of observational measurements on comet
  morphology and magnitude covering just over a thousand apparitions of
  various comets from -466 to 1975.
 
 
  Modification History
  ====================
  The data were recovered from old database files in a proprietary
  application format, investigated for accuracy and potential
  identification conflicts with the comet catalog produced by Brian
  Marsden and the Minor Planet center, and then converted to a flat
  ASCII text file for ingest into the PDS.
 
  During the verification process, the table values were compared
  against those found in the available publications (Russian original
  or English translation, as listed below). Typographical errors
  were corrected, known errata listed in the publications were applied,
  and in cases where a comet was present in two consecutive updates,
  the data from the later publication were included and preliminary
  data from the earlier publication were removed.
 
  The data were then split into two files: the first containing the
  magnitude parameters Y, Hy and H10; the second containing the head
  diameter and tail length measurements D1 and S.  Code numbers were
  added to indicate the specific reference from which the data in
  each record were drawn and notations and caveats listed in the
  published tables were recorded in a note field added to each file.
  Finally, records in the second file which did not contain any D1 or
  S entries were deleted.
 
  Finally, a separate file was added to list the references, code
  numbers, and additional comments regarding each of the source articles
  contributing to this data set.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
  Both data files list several cross-identifications for each object,
  the code number of the reference for the listed parameters, and a
  note field for caveats and clarifications.
 
  The magnitude file lists the magnitude parameters Y, Hy, and H10;
  plus the quality and tail visibility codes included in the earlier
  source articles.
 
  The physical characteristics file lists head diameter D1, tail
  length S and tail type indicator as published in the later source
  artiles.
 
  The references file lists the code number, full citation, and any
  specific notes regarding each of the originally published articles.
 
 
  Data
  ====
  The data tables were compiled from the following publications. The
  numbers are the same as those used in the data files:
 
     1. S. K. Vsekhsvyatskii, Physical Characteristics of Comets,
        NASA TT F-80 / OTS 62-11031, 1964. [VSEKHSVYATSKII1964]
 
     2. S. K. Vsekhsvyatskii, Soviet Astronomy - AJ, Vol. 6, 849,
        1963. [VSEKHSVYATSKII1963]
 
     3. S. K. Vsekhsvyatskii, Soviet Astronomy - AJ, Vol. 10, 1034,
        1967. [VSEKHSVYATSKII1967]
 
     4. S. K. Vsekhsvyatskii and N. I. Il&apos;ichishina, Soviet Astronomy -
        AJ, Vol 15, 310, 1971. [VSEKHSVYATSKII&amp;1971]
 
     5. S. K. Vsekhsvyatskii and N. I. Il&apos;ichishina, FIZICHESKIE
        KHARAKTERISTIKI KOMET 1965 - 1970 GG, Moskva, Nuaka, 1974.
        [VSEKHSVYATSKII&amp;1974]
 
     6. S. K. Vsekhsvyatskii, FIZICHESKIE KHARAKTERISTIKI KOMET 1971 -
        1975 GG, Kiev, Naukova Dumka, 1979. [VSEKHSVYATSKII1979]
 
  The data comprising this dataset were extracted from the columns
  labeled &apos;Y&apos;, &apos;H[y]&apos;, &apos;H[10]&apos;, &apos;D[1]&apos;, and &apos;S[ae]&apos; (where &apos;[]&apos; denotes
  a subscript) in the tables of the above sources.  When an object
  appeared in more than one publication, the data from the later
  publication are included and the data from the preliminary
  observations of the previous paper were omitted.  Note that because of
  this, no records in this data file came from reference 4.
 
  The comets in this table are identified using the IAU Comet
  Designation as well as by Periodic Comet Number, IAU Comet Perihelion
  Number, and IAU Comet Provisional Number. The photometric parameters
  in this table, Y and HY, were determined from a system of equations of
  the form:
 
      HY + Y*log r = m - 5*log (geocentric distance) for r = 1
 
  If there was a sufficient number of observations, the absolute
  magnitude, H10, was determined from the best data using:
 
      H10 + 10*log r = m - 5*log (geocentric distance) for r = 1.
 
  For comets before 1996, the reliability or quality of the H10 value
  is provided on a 3-point scale:
 
       1 indicates accuracy within 1.0 magnitude
       2 indicates accuracy within 0.4 - 0.6 magnitude
       3 indicates accuracy within 0.1 - 0.2 magnitude
       Blank indicates the accuracy was not published
 
  The H10 quality value was judged by S. K. Vsekhvyatskii using all
  available data and the systematic deviation may be appreciable
  for comets with large q.  For comets before 1957, the tail
  visibility is provided on a 4-point scale:
 
        0 indicates no tail was reported
        1 indicates a telescopic object
        2 indicates a naked-eye object (at least for a while)
        3 indicates a possible telescopic object
        Blank indicates the tail visibility was not published; refer
           to the TAIL LENGTH value
 
  For comets after 1956, tail visibility is superceded by the reduced
  value for maximum tail length.  The tail length was calculated by
  S. K. Vsekhsvyatskii:
 
      TAIL LENGTH = (geocentric distance)*sin C / sin (K - C)
      where C is the maximum observed tail length in angular measure,
      K is the phase angle; cos K = (r*r + (geocentric distance)*
      (geocentric distance) - R*R ) / 2*r*(geocentric distance) where
      R is the distance between the earth and the sun.
 
  Additionally, this data set contains the reduced value for maximum
  observed head diameter, in minutes of arc, for comets after 1953.
  Again, HEAD DIAMETER was derived by S. K. Vsekhsvyatskii.
 
  Occasionally multiple values were published in a single table row for
  one of the parameters.  In these cases, an additional record was
  created in the present data file(s) for the comet, with the additional
  value being placed in the appropriate parameter field while other
  parameter fields were left blank.
 
  The note field is used to indicate unusual situations and to preserve
  notes from the original, published tables.
 
 
  Notes
  -----
 
  Specific comet notes from Dr. Mike A&apos;Hearn, 1997 February 21 [Ian
  Jordan was employed by Dr. A&apos;Hearn and assisted in producing the PDS
  product from the spreadsheet program files which constituted the
  original submission; &apos;Marsden&apos; is Dr. Brian Marsden of the Minor
  Planet Center]:
 
  1. The comet labelled 952 in Vsekhsviatsky&apos;s table is clearly a
     typo for the comet of 962 (as indicated elsewhere in the text of
     the monograph).  This comet is in Marsden&apos;s catalog as 962 B1,
     which came to perihelion in Dec of 961.  I have merged this pair
     onto a common line in the spreadsheet.
 
  2. Comet of 1006 was incorrectly labelled as Halley in the spreadsheet.
     It is not Halley, nor is it called Halley anywhere by
     Vsekhsviatsky.  On the other hand, I do not find a comet in 1006 in
     any of Marsden&apos;s catalogs.  I will pursue this further later.
 
  3. Comet of 1625.  Labelled by Vsekhsviatsky, on the basis of a 19th
     century paper by Crommelin, as an early apparition of comet
     Crommelin. Apparently Marsden has not been able to successfully
     link this to the modern apparitions since Marsden does not list
     this comet at all. This is one that should be followed up with Don
     Yeomans since he did some work on P/Crommelin.  Ian [Jordan] has
     already parenthesized the name in the database.
 
  4. Comet of 1678.  Vsekhsviatsky associates this with comet deVico-
     Swift but this is apparently wrong.  Marsden associates it with
     6P/d&apos;Arrest and this is probably the right identification.  I have
     edited the name field in Vsekhsviatsky&apos;s file accordingly.  (Ian
     had already made the association with P/d&apos;Arrest and put the other
     names in parens).
 
  5. Comet of 1746.  Apparently the observations do not allow
     computation of a reliable orbit so it is not in the catalog of
     Marsden.  I can pursue it later.
 
  6. 1826 III.  Clearly this comet has a poorly determined orbit,
     even according to the discussion by Vsekhsviatsky.  I will try
     later to get crude numbers to put in for correlations.
 
  7. 1846 II.  This was the first apparition of 3D/Biela after it
     split into two components.  Ian has associated Vsekhsviatsky&apos;s data
     with the main component which seems to me to be the right
     thing to do.  He has done the same thing again when the comet
     reappeared as 1852 III.
 
  8. 1860 I.  Also a split comet.
 
  9. 1872 I.  Probably a Kreutz-family comet, but no good orbit.
 
 10. 1880 VI.  This one seems to have been well observed but is not
     in Marsden&apos;s catalog - I don&apos;t know why.
 
 11. 1882 II.  Another split comet.
 
 12. 1913 I.  Hardly any observations - no orbit.
 
 13. 1916 III and 1916 IV.  Few observations of either - no good orbit.
 
 14. 1928 III.  Very few observations - no good orbit.
 
 15. 1930 VII and 1930 VIII.  The comet which Vsekhsviatsky calls 1930
     VIII does appear to be 10P/Tempel 2.  It agrees in orbital elements
     and magnitude with Marsden&apos;s catalog.  However, Marsden&apos;s current
     designation is 1930 VII.  This led Ian to associate Vsekhsviatsky&apos;s
     1930 VII with Tempel 2, I think incorrectly.  I infer that
     Vsekhsviatsky&apos;s 1930 VII is a comet for which there is no good
     orbit. I have adjusted the spreadsheet accordingly.
 
 16. 1933 IV and 1933 V.  Another case of Brian&apos;s current numbering system
     being different from Vsekhsviatsky&apos;s.  I have adjusted the
     spreadsheet to reflect the &apos;real&apos; comets and changed the notation
     accordingly.  I have also deleted a blank line that Ian had
     immediately following these two comets.
 
 17. 1939 VIII.  This was formerly known as Comet Kulin.  However, it is
     likely that this was really an asteroid and Brian does not include
     it in his catalog.  The orbit is currently being worked on.
 
 18. I have deleted a bunch of blank lines immediately following P/Tempel
     2 or 1951 VIII.  This does not appear to represent a break in the
     data, unless maybe the first supplement is retroactive.
 
 19. 1965 VIII Ikeya-Seki.  Another split comet.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
  This dataset is released in the form of ASCII files which may be
  stored on disk or other magnetic medium and which may be
  distributed by ftp, email, real-time access by remote login, or by
  whatever means is most convenient.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
  As noted above, data was compiled from S. K. Vsekhsvyatskii&apos;s
  publications of comet characteristics.  Every effort was made to
  apply known errata of both the original Russian publication and,
  were available, the English translations.  The parameters files
  have been proofed against the publications.  Designation conflicts
  have been checked against standard catalogs from the Minor Planet
  Center.
 
 
  Review
  ======
  This dataset underwent external peer review in September 1998.
 
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
  As noted above, data were compiled from S. K. Vsekhsvyatskii&apos;s
  publications of comet characteristics.  Vsekhsvyatskii compiled the
  characteristics from various published observations.  The data
  include Vsekhsvyatskii&apos;s quality code for H10 values.
 
  Note that the fourth of the six source articles, containing
  observations from 1965-1969, was completely superceded by the fifth
  article, which spanned 1965-1970.  Thus, none of the records in the
  present data set came from the fourth article.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>PSSB-00140</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

