<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.vg2-u-lecp-4-rdr-sector-15min-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>VG2 URA LECP RESAMPLED RDR STEPPING SECTOR 15MIN V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.comet_sl9-jupiter_collision::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.voyager::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vg2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:lecp.vg2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.uranus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vg2-u-lecp-4-rdr-sector-15min-v1.0__browserp_vg2-u-lecp-4-rdr-sector-15min-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Krimigis, S.M., T.P. Armstrong, W.L. Axford, C.O. Bostrom, C.Y. Fan, G.
                   Gloeckler, and L.J. Lanzerotti, The Low Energy Charged Particle (LECP)
                   Experiment on the Voyager Spacecraft, Space Sci. Rev., Vol. 21, p. 329,
                   1977.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KRIMIGISETAL1977</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mauk, B.H., S.M. Krimigis, E.P. Keath, A.F. Cheng,
                   T.P. Armstrong, L.J. Lanzerotti, G. Gloeckler, and
                   D.C. Hamilton, The Hot Plasma and Radiation Environment
                   of the Uranian Magnetosphere, Journal of Geophysical
                   Research, 92, 15283, 1987.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MAUKETAL1987</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>VG2-U-LECP-4-RDR-SECTOR-15MIN-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>VG2 URA LECP RESAMPLED RDR STEPPING SECTOR 15MIN V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1993-02-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1986-01-24T00:00:00.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1986-01-30T00:00:00.000Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>BARRY H. MAUK</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            VG2 URA LECP RESAMPLED RDR STEPPING SECTOR 15MIN V1.0
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set consists of resampled data from the Low Energy
            Charged Particle (LECP) experiment on Voyager 2 while the
            spacecraft was in the vicinity of Uranus. This instrument
            measures the intensities of in-situ charged particles (&gt;26 keV
            electrons and &gt;30 keV ions) with various levels of
            discrimination based on energy, mass species, and angular arrival
            direction. A subset of almost 100 LECP channels are included with
            this data set. The LECP data are globally calibrated to the
            extent possible (see below) and they are time averaged to about
            15 minute time intervals with the exact beginning and ending
            times for those intervals matching the LECP instrumental cycle
            periods (the angular scanning periods). The LECP instrument has a
            rotating head for obtaining angular anisotropy measurements of
            the medium energy charged particles that it measures. The cycle
            time for the rotation if variable, but during encounters it is
            always faster than 15 minutes. Thus, the full angular anisotropy
            information is preserved with this data. The data is in the form
            of &apos;Rate&apos; data which has not been converted to the
            usual physical units. The reason is that such a conversion would
            depend on uncertain determinations such as the mass species of
            the particles and the level of background. Both mass species and
            background are generally determined from context during the study
            of particular regions. To convert &apos;Rate&apos; to
            &apos;Intensity&apos; for a particular channel one performs the
            following tasks: 1) Decide on the level of background
            contamination and subtract that off the given rate level.
            Background is to be determined from context and from making use
            of sector 8 rates (sector 8 has a 2 mm Al shield covering it). 2)
            Divide the background corrected rate by the channel geometric
            factor and by the energy bandpass of the channel. The geometric
            factor is found in entry &apos;CHANNEL_GEOMETRIC_FACTOR&apos; as
            associated with each channel &apos;CHANNEL_ID&apos;. To determine
            the energy bandpass, one must judge the mass species of the of
            the detected particles (for ions but not for electrons). The
            energy band passes are given in entries
            &apos;MINIMUM_INSTRUMENT_PARAMETER&apos; and
            &apos;MAXIMUM_INSTRUMENT_PARAMETER&apos; in table
            &apos;FPLECPENERGY&apos;, and are given in the form
            &apos;Energy/Nucleon&apos;. For channels that begin their names
            with the designations &apos;CH&apos; these bandpasses can be used
            on mass species that are accepted into that channel (see entries
            &apos;MINIMUM_INSTRUMENT_PARAMETER&apos; and
            &apos;MAXIMUM_INSTRUMENT_ PARAMETER&apos; in table
            &apos;FPLECPCHANZ&apos;, which give the minimum and maximum
            &apos;Z&apos; value accepted -- these entries are blank for
            electron channels). For other channels the given bandpass refers
            only to the lowest &apos;Z&apos; value accepted. The bandpasses
            for other &apos;Z&apos; values are not all known, but some are
            given in the literature (e.g. Krimigis et al., 1979). The final
            product of these instructions will be the particle intensity with
            the units: counts/(cm**2.str.sec.keV). Some channels are subject
            to serious contaminations, and many of these contaminations
            cannot be removed except with a region-by-region analysis, which
            has not been done for this data. thus, to use this data it is
            absolutely vital that the contamination types
            (&apos;CONTAMINATION_ID&apos; , &apos;CONTAMINATION_DESC&apos;)
            and the levels of contamination (&apos;DATA_QUALITY_ID&apos;
            corresponding to the definitions &apos;DATA_QUALITY_DESC&apos;)
            be carefully examined for all regions of study. A dead time
            correction procedure has been applied in an attempt to correct
            the linear effects of detector overdrive (pulse-pileup). This
            procedure does not fix severely overdriven detectors. A procedure
            is available for correcting Voyager 2 LECP electron contamination
            of low energy ion channels, but its effectiveness has been
            evaluated only for the Uranus data set. Thus, corrections have
            been applied only to the Uranus data set. Also included with this
            data are one standard deviation statistical uncertainties for the
            directional data (sectors 1 through 8) expressed as a percent.
            Unknown values are generally coded as such, however in some
            instances the value will read &apos;ZERO&apos; when its status is
            unknown.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      This data set consists of resampled data from the Low Energy
      Charged Particle (LECP) experiment on Voyager 2 while the
      spacecraft was in the vicinity of Uranus.  This instrument
      measures the intensities of in-situ charged particles (&gt;26 keV
      electrons and &gt;30 keV ions) with various levels of
      discrimination based on energy, mass species, and angular
      arrival direction.  A subset of almost 100 LECP channels are
      included with this data set.  The LECP data are globally
      calibrated to the extent possible (see below) and they are time
      averaged to about 15 minute time intervals with the exact
      beginning and ending times for those intervals matching the
      LECP instrumental cycle periods (the angular scanning periods).
      The LECP instrument has a rotating head for obtaining angular
      anisotropy measurements of the medium energy charged particles
      that it measures.  The cycle time for the rotation if variable,
      but during encounters it is always faster than 15 minutes.
      Thus, the full angular anisotropy information is preserved with
      this data.  The data is in the form of &apos;Rate&apos; data which has
      not been converted to the usual physical units.  The reason is
      that such a conversion would depend on uncertain determinations
      such as the mass species of the particles and the level of
      background.  Both mass species and background are generally
      determined from context during the study of particular regions.
      To convert &apos;Rate&apos; to &apos;Intensity&apos; for a particular channel one
      performs the following tasks: 1) Decide on the level of
      background contamination and subtract that off the given rate
      level.  Background is to be determined from context and from
      making use of sector 8 rates (sector 8 has a 2 mm Al shield
      covering it).  2) Divide the background corrected rate by the
      channel geometric factor and by the energy bandpass of the
      channel.  The geometric factor is found in entry
      &apos;CHANNEL_GEOMETRIC_FACTOR&apos; as associated with each channel
      &apos;CHANNEL_ID&apos;.  To determine the energy bandpass, one must judge
      the mass species of the of the detected particles (for ions but
      not for electrons).  The energy band passes are given in
      entries &apos;MINIMUM_INSTRUMENT_PARAMETER&apos; and
      &apos;MAXIMUM_INSTRUMENT_PARAMETER&apos; in table &apos;FPLECPENERGY&apos;, and are
      given in the form &apos;Energy/Nucleon&apos;.  For channels that begin
      their names with the designations &apos;CH&apos; these bandpasses can be
      used on mass species that are accepted into that channel (see
      entries &apos;MINIMUM_INSTRUMENT_PARAMETER&apos; and &apos;MAXIMUM_INSTRUMENT_
      PARAMETER&apos; in table &apos;FPLECPCHANZ&apos;, which give the minimum and
      maximum &apos;Z&apos; value accepted -- these entries are blank for
      electron channels).  For other channels the given bandpass
      refers only to the lowest &apos;Z&apos; value accepted.  The bandpasses
      for other &apos;Z&apos; values are not all known, but some are given in
      the literature (e.g.  Krimigis et al., 1979).  The final
      product of these instructions will be the particle intensity
      with the units: counts/(cm**2.str.sec.keV).  Some channels are
      subject to serious contaminations, and many of these
      contaminations cannot be removed except with a region-by-region
      analysis, which has not been done for this data.  thus, to use
      this data it is absolutely vital that the contamination types
      (&apos;CONTAMINATION_ID&apos; , &apos;CONTAMINATION_DESC&apos;) and the levels of
      contamination (&apos;DATA_QUALITY_ID&apos; corresponding to the
      definitions &apos;DATA_QUALITY_DESC&apos;) be carefully examined for all
      regions of study.  A dead time correction procedure has been
      applied in an attempt to correct the linear effects of detector
      overdrive (pulse-pileup).  This procedure does not fix severely
      overdriven detectors.  A procedure is available for correcting
      Voyager 2 LECP electron contamination of low energy ion
      channels, but its effectiveness has been evaluated only for the
      Uranus data set.  Thus, corrections have been applied only to
      the Uranus data set.  Also included with this data are one
      standard deviation statistical uncertainties for the
      directional data (sectors 1 through 8) expressed as a percent.
      Unknown values are generally coded as such, however in some
      instances the value will read &apos;ZERO&apos; when its status is
      unknown.
 
      Processing Level Id            : 4
      Software Flag                  : Y
      Processing Start Time          : 1987-02-01
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;ELECTRON RATE&apos;
      ----------------------------------
        A measured parameter equaling the number of electrons hitting
        a particle detector per specified accumulation interval.  The
        counted electrons may or may not be discriminated as to their
        energies (e.g.  greater than E1, or between E1 and E2).
 
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Data Set Parameter Name        : ELECTRON RATE
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 15.000000
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : 15.000000
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : COUNTS/SECOND
        Noise Level                    : 0.000000
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : MINUTE
 
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;ION RATE&apos;
      -----------------------------
        A measured parameter equaling the number of ions striking a
        particle detector per specified accumulation interval.  The
        counted ions may or may not be discriminated as to their
        energies (e.g.  energy/nucleon or energy/charge between E1
        and E2 or greater than E1) and/or as to their ion composition
        (atomic number Z or mass number greater than Z1 or M1, or
        between Z1 and z2 or M1 and M2).
 
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Data Set Parameter Name        : ION RATE
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 15.000000
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : 15.000000
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : COUNTS/SECOND
        Noise Level                    : 0.000000
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : MINUTE
 
 
    Source Instrument Parameters
    ============================
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : ELECTRON RATE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : ELECTRON RATE
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VG2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : ION RATE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : ION RATE
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      Processing History
      ------------------
        Source Data Set ID    : N/A
        Software              : UNK
        Product Data Set ID   : VG2-U-LECP-4-RDR-SECTOR-15MIN-V1.0
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      At all times during this planetary encounter there exist data
      in this data set that can be rated with the highest confidence
      level.  However, some of the channels of data are contaminated
      by various kinds and various levels of contaminations.  It is
      therefore imperative, in using this data set, that the
      contamination tables within the catalog be examined.  Also, not
      all kinds of contamination have been fully documented.  When in
      doubt the data supplier must be contacted.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XM-11A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

