<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.clem1-l-spice-6-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CLEMENTINE MOON SPICE KERNELS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_space_program_science_experiment::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.clem1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.clem1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-spice-6-v1.0__browserp_clem1-l-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-spice-6-v1.0__browser_clem1-l-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-spice-6-v1.0__browser_wgc_clem1-l-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.naif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CLEM1-L-SPICE-6-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CLEMENTINE MOON SPICE KERNELS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2007-04-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1994-01-26</start_time>
        <stop_time>1994-05-07</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>BORIS V. SEMENOV</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Semenov, B.V., and C.H. Acton, CLEMENTINE SPICE KERNELS V1.0,
            CLEM1-L-SPICE-6-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2007.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Navigation and ancillary data in the form of SPICE System kernel
            files for Clementine.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set includes the complete set of Clementine SPICE data
            files (``kernel files&apos;&apos;), which can be accessed using
            SPICE software. The SPICE data contains geometric and other
            ancillary information needed to recover the full value of science
            instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft
            and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments,
            spacecraft orientation, spacecraft sequences of events, and data
            needed for relevant time conversions.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 Data Set Overview
 =================
    This data set includes the complete set of Clementine SPICE data
    files (``kernel files&apos;&apos;), which can be accessed using SPICE
    software. The SPICE data contains geometric and other ancillary
    information needed to recover the full value of science
    instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft
    and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments,
    spacecraft orientation, spacecraft sequences of events, and data
    needed for relevant time conversions.
 
    This data set is contained on a single virtual volume, CLSP_1000,
    including data from all mission phases and covering from the day
    after launch, 1994-01-26, through the end of the mission,
    1994-05-07.
 
 
 Data Types (SPICE kernel types)
 ===============================
    SPK kernels contain ephemerides for spacecraft, planets,
    satellites, comets and asteroids as well as for moving or fixed
    spacecraft and instrument structures. They provide position and
    velocity, given in a Cartesian reference frame. SPK files are
    located under the ``data/spk&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
    PCK kernels contain certain physical, dynamical and cartographic
    constants for target bodies, such as size and shape
    specifications, and orientation of the spin axis and prime
    meridian. PCK files are located under the ``data/pck&apos;&apos; directory
    of this data set.
 
    IK kernels (Instrument description kernels) give descriptive and
    operational data peculiar to a particular scientific instrument,
    such as internal timing relative to the spacecraft clock and
    field-of-view model parameters. IK files are located under the
    ``data/ik&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
    CK kernels describe pointing, containing a transformation
    traditionally called the C-matrix which is used to determine
    time-tagged pointing (orientation) angles for a spacecraft
    structure upon which science instruments are mounted. CK files
    are located under the ``data/ck&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
    EK (Events) kernels are derived from the integrated sequence of
    events used to produce actual spacecraft commands. EK files are
    located under the ``data/ek&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
    LSK (Leapseconds) kernels contain the leapseconds and the values
    of other constants required to perform a transformation between
    Universal Time Coordinated (UTC) and Ephemeris time (ET). LSK
    files are located under the ``data/lsk&apos;&apos; directory of this data
    set.
 
    SCLK (Spacecraft Clock) kernels contain on-board clock
    calibration data required to perform a mapping between Ephemeris
    time (ET) and spacecraft on-board time (SCLK.) SCLK files are
    located under the ``data/sclk&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
    FK (Frame Definitions) kernels contain information required to
    define reference frames, sources of frame orientation data and
    inter-connections between these frames and other frames supported
    within the SPICE system. This includes mounting alignment
    information for each instrument. FK files are located under the
    ``data/fk&apos;&apos; directory of this data set.
 
 
  Kernel File Details
  ===================
    A brief overview of the different types of Clementine kernels
    included in this data set is provided in the
    CONFIDENCE_LEVEL_NOTE section of this file while details specific
    to individual files are found in the ``*info.txt&apos;&apos; files in the
    corresponding data directory. The most detailed description of
    the data in each file is provided in metadata included inside the
    file -- in the description area of text kernels or in the comment
    area of binary kernels.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The SPICE Toolkit contains software modules needed to read SPICE
    kernel files. SPICELIB software is highly documented via internal
    headers. Additional documentation is available in separate ASCII
    text files called Required Reading files. For example, the S- and
    P- Kernel (SPK) Required Reading File, named ``spk.req&apos;&apos;, describes
    use of the SPK kernel file readers and contains sample programs.
 
    The latest SPICE Toolkit for a variety of computer platforms such
    as PC, Mac, SUN, etc. is available at the NAIF Node of PDS
    electronically (via anonymous FTP and WWW servers). Refer to
    information in ``software/softinfo.txt&apos;&apos; for details regarding
    obtaining this software. Each version of the Toolkit is also
    archived at the NASA National Space Science Data Center.
 
 
  Loading Kernel Files into a SPICE-based Application
  ===================================================
    The easiest way to make data from a collection of SPICE kernels
    available to a SPICE-based application is to list these kernels
    in a meta-kernel and load it into the program using the high
    level SPICE data loader routine FURNSH. This data set provides
    such meta-kernel(s) under the ``extras/mk&apos;&apos; directory. For more
    information about the MGS meta-kernel(s), see the file
    ``extras/mk/mkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    This data set contains SPICE kernel files created during mission
    operations and after mission data reconstruction and analysis.
    Some general information about this collection follows here, but
    the prospective user is also referred to extensive descriptions
    about each file that are stored inside each kernel file. These
    metadata provide detailed information regarding the information
    source from which the data were derived, the type of processing
    applied to the source data, applicability of the data, etc.
    Metadata are located in the ``comment area&apos;&apos; for binary kernel
    types (SPK, CK, ESQ), accessible using either the COMMNT or
    SPACIT utility program found in the NAIF Toolkit. Metadata are
    located after ``\begintext&apos;&apos; markers within the text kernel types
    (PCK, IK, FK, LSK, SCLK, MK), accessible by using any available
    text file display tool such as a word processor, text editor, or
    the unix ``more&apos;&apos; or ``cat&apos;&apos; commands.
 
    Where there are questions about data accuracy or ``confidence&apos;&apos;
    not addressed herein the reader is invited to contact the NAIF
    node of the Planetary Data System for possible further
    information.
 
 
  SPK Files
  =========
    Two kinds of SPK files are provided in this archive: SPK files
    containing the spacecraft orbit and SPK files containing the Solar
    System ephemerides. Each of these kinds is briefly described
    below; more information is available in the file
    ``data/spk/spkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
    This data set includes three spacecraft orbit SPK files, each
    from a different source: the Spacecraft Operations Team based at
    Naval Research Laboratory (NRL), the Clementine Gravity Team from
    Goddard Space Flight Center (GSFC), and the Solar System Dynamic
    group of the Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL). All three files
    provide trajectory covering most of the mission, with the
    coverage of the NRL SPK starting about three weeks earlier than
    the coverage of the other two files.
 
    Of the three SPKs the NRL file is the oldest; the trajectory
    provided in it was determined during mission. The GSFC SPK file
    contains trajectory determined after the end of the mission, in
    November 1994, as a part of the Clementine gravity data
    reduction. The JPL SPK provides the most recent of the three
    solutions, done in 2002 as a part of the Lunar gravity field
    improvement effort.
 
    Based on the coverage and history of these solutions NAIF
    recommends that, unless there are special circumstances, the JPL
    and NRL SPK files are used together in such way that the
    JPL SPK providing more a recent, and likely more accurate
    solution, is loaded last (to have higher priority) and the NRL file
    providing the longest coverage is loaded first (to have lower
    priority and be used only for the periods for which the JPL SPK
    does not provide coverage).
 
    The difference of the trajectories provided by the three
    spacecraft SPK files varies greatly throughout the mission,
    ranging from a few meters for some orbits to hundreds of meters
    to kilometers for the fits near the propulsive maneuvers.
    Appendix 1 of the ``data/spk/spkinfo.txt&apos;&apos; provides a summary of
    the down-track, radial, and out-of-plane components of the
    maximum difference for each pair of SPKs for each orbit.
 
    This data set also includes the orbit number file generated using
    the NAIF&apos;s ORBNUM utility program for the JPL SPK file for the
    orbital phases of the mission. This file is not SPICE kernel; for
    this reason it is provided in the ``extras/orbnum&apos;&apos; directory.
    For more information about the Clementine orbit number file, see
    the file ``extras/orbnum/orbinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
    This data set includes the DE414 SPK file, which the latest
    version of the JPL Planetary Ephemeris available at the time when
    this archive was created.
 
 
  CK Files
  ========
    This data set includes a single CK file providing the actual
    orientation of the Clementine spacecraft bus. This orientation is
    based on the data from the SPQ files generated and delivered to
    the project on a daily basis during mission operations by the
    Spacecraft Team, NRL and converted to CK files by Applied
    Coherent Technology (ACT) Corporation using the CPQ2CK program
    provided by NAIF. Unfortunately the specifics of production of
    the SPQ files had not been documented. It was suggested that the
    SPQ files contained the ``raw&apos;&apos; orientation estimated by the
    on-board Kalman filter using data from the star trackers and
    gyros, sent down in housekeeping telemetry and stored ``as is&apos;&apos;
    in the SPQ files but it is not known for sure. It is also not
    clear whether the time tags attached to the ``raw&apos;&apos; attitude
    telemetry suffered from the same problems as the science image
    time tags and, if so, whether anything was done in the SPQ
    generation pipeline to correct them.
 
    More information about the Clementine CK files is available in
    the file ``data/ck/ckinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
  PCK Files
  =========
    Two PCK files are provided in this data set, one is a text PCK
    containing on the official IAU/IAG/COSPAR values accepted in
    2000, the other is a binary PCK containing high-accuracy
    orientation data for the lunar principal axes (PA) reference
    frame, from the JPL Solar System Dynamics Group&apos;s planetary
    ephemeris DE-403. Both files were the latest versions of the
    files of these types distributed by NAIF at the time when this
    archive was created. None of the PCK files used during mission
    operations and post-mission data analysis was included in this
    data set because they were superseded by the PCK files mentioned
    above.
 
    More information about the PCK files included in this data set is
    available in the file ``data/pck/pckinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
   FK Files
   ========
    This data set includes the Clementine mission FK file and a number
    of generic Lunar FK files. The Clementine FK file, created many
    years after the end of the mission in 2000, defines the frames
    for the Clementine spacecraft and its science instruments. The
    instrument frames defined in it incorporate mission-era mounting
    alignment data from the IK files included in this archive. The
    Lunar FK files, created in 2006-2007, define a number of lunar
    body-fixed frames associated high-accuracy lunar orientation data
    provided by the JPL Solar System Dynamics Group&apos;s planetary
    ephemerides and provide a mechanism to direct the SPICE system to
    associate either the lunar ``principal axis&apos;&apos; frame or the lunar
    ``mean Earth&apos;&apos; with the Moon.
 
    More information about the Clementine FK files is available in
    the file ``data/fk/fkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
  IK Files
  ========
    This data set includes an IK file for each of the Clementine
    instruments -- HIRES, UVVIS, NIR, LWIR, LIDAR, CPT, and Star
    Trackers A and B. While these kernels were made at the time of
    archive preparation in 2007, they incorporate the instrument
    model parameters and mounting alignments that were derived at a
    much earlier time, during mission operations and/or immediate
    post mission data analysis in 1994. Although various printouts
    and hand notes indicate that the values provided in the IKs are
    probably the latest values derived by Thomas Duxbury, JPL at the
    end of the mission, NAIF was not able to either confirm this or
    to trace these value to an officially published or archived
    document. In addition to this mission-era data each of the IKs
    includes extensive comments and a GETFOV-type FOV definition;
    these were added when the IKs were updated at the time of the
    archive preparation.
 
    More information about Clementine IK files is available in the
    file ``data/ik/ikinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
  SCLK Files
  ==========
    Only one SCLK kernel is included in this data set -- the SCLK
    kernel providing the nominal mapping of the Clementine on-board
    clock to ET. This file was created and used during mission
    operations. While this file is not adequate to support conversion
    of the actual Clementine on-board time tags it is still required
    to access data in the Clementine CK files.
 
    More information about the Clementine SCLK files is available in
    the file ``data/sclk/sclkinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
  LSK Files
  =========
    This data set includes the latest generic LSK kernel distributed
    by NAIF at the time when this archive was created. Metadata
    describing how the LSK data are obtained or computed is contained
    inside the LSK text file. The time conversion provided by SPICE
    LSK files is accurate to approximately 0.000030 seconds.
 
    More information about the LSK files is available in the file
    ``data/lsk/lskinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
  EK Files
  ========
    This data set includes a set of EK files containing the NAIF&apos;s
    Clementine image catalog. This catalog was created by NAIF in
    1994, after the end of the mission, to make the Clementine image
    attributes and derived geometry information available to the NAIF
    staff in the EK database format. It is included in this data set
    for the record and for convenience to the future users of the
    Clementine SPICE data who may desire to get the image times, file
    names, and other ``basic&apos;&apos; image attributes from a SPICE kernel
    rather than from the PDS index and/or label files. This catalog
    contains data for all 1,900,483 images archived in the
    CLEM1-L/E/Y-A/B/U/H/L/N-2-EDR-V1.0 data set.
 
    More information about the EK files is available in the file
    ``data/ek/ekinfo.txt&apos;&apos;.
 
 
  Kernel Files Not Included In This Data Set
  ===========================================
    A number of kernel files used to process science data archived in
    PDS were either not included in this data set because they were
    superseded by the files provided in this archive or were included
    into the archive under different names. These files are:
 
      Type  Old file                 --&gt;  Archived file
      ----  ----------------------  -----  ---------------------------
      SPK   SPKMERGE_940219_940504   (S)   clem_gsfc.bsp
            _CLEMV001b.bsp
      SPK   SPKMER09.BSP             (R)   clem_gsfc.bsp
      SPK   SPKMERGE_9402191254_94   (R)   clem_gsfc.bsp
            05040324_CLEM.v002.bsp
      SPK   clemdef.bsp              (R)   clem_nrl.bsp
      SPK   clem_ask020625.bsp       (R)   clem_jpl.bsp
      SPK   de245_1994.bsp           (S)   de414.bsp
 
      SCLK  dspse002.tsc             (R)   clem_nom.tsc
 
      CK    clem_2mn.bck             (S)   clem_act_ck3.bc
      CK    clem_5sc.bck             (S)   clem_act_ck3.bc
      CK    clem_act.bck             (S)   clem_act_ck3.bc
      CK    clemdef1.bck             (S)   clem_act_ck3.bc
 
      PCK   403s.bpc                 (S)   moon_pa_de403_1950_2198.bpc
      PCK   de245lib.bpc             (S)   moon_pa_de403_1950_2198.bpc
      PCK   pck00005.tpc             (S)   pck00008.tpc
      PCK   pck00006.tpc             (S)   pck00008.tpc
 
      FK    clem_v10.tf              (S)   clem_v20.tf
 
      IK    astar005.ti              (S)   clem_astar_006.ti
      IK    bstar005.ti              (S)   clem_bstar_006.ti
      IK    cpt001.ti                (S)   clem_cpt_002.ti
      IK    hires007.ti              (S)   clem_hires_008.ti
      IK    lidar004.ti              (S)   clem_lidar_005.ti
      IK    lwir007.ti               (S)   clem_lwir_008.ti
      IK    nir007.ti                (S)   clem_nir_009.ti
      IK    nir008.ti                (S)   clem_nir_009.ti
      IK    uvvis007.ti              (S)   clem_uvvis_008.ti
 
      EK    Apr15-May07.ek           (R)   clem_moon_940415_940507.bdb
      EK    Jan27-Mar12.ek           (R)   clem_moon_940127_940312.bdb
      EK    Mar12-Mar30.ek           (R)   clem_moon_940312_940330.bdb
      EK    Mar30-Apr15.ek           (R)   clem_moon_940330_940415.bdb
      EK    Sky.ek                   (R)   clem_sky_940201_940507.bdb
 
    where (R) stands for ``renamed to&apos;&apos; and (S) stands for ``superseded
    by&apos;&apos;.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>PSCM-00025</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

