<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.jno-j-uvs-3-rdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>JUNO JUPITER UVS 3 REDUCED DATA RECORD V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.juno::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.jno::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:uvs.jno::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Gladstone, G.R., S.C. Persyn, J.S. Eterno, B.C. Walther, D.C. Slater, M.W.
                   Davis, M.H. Versteeg, K.B. Persson, M.K. Young, G.J. Dirks, A.O. Sawka, J.
                   Tumlinson, H. Sykes, J. Beshears, C.L. Rhoad, J.P. Cravens, G.S. Winters, R.A.
                   Klar, W. Lockhart, B.M. Piepgrass, T.K. Greathouse, B.J. Trantham, P.M. Wilcox,
                   and M.W. Jackson, The Ultraviolet Spectrograph on NASA&apos;s Juno Mission, Space
                   Science Reviews, doi:10.1007/s11214-014-0040-z, 2014.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GLADSTONEETAL2014</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>JNO-J-UVS-3-RDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>JUNO JUPITER UVS 3 REDUCED DATA RECORD V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2016-06-21</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>BRAD TRANTHAM</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Trantham, Brad, JUNO J UVS REDUCED DATA RECORD V1.0,
            JNO-J-UVS-3-RDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2014.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Juno Ultraviolet Spectrograph (UVS) CODMAC Level 3 Reduced
            Data Record is a collection of the far ultraviolet photon
            detections obtained by the UVS instrument, corrected, calibrated,
            and located in space and time.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Juno Ultraviolet Spectrograph (UVS) CODMAC Level 3 Reduced
            Data Record is a collection of the far ultraviolet photon
            detections obtained by the UVS instrument, corrected for
            instrumental effects, radiometrically calibrated, and correlated
            with the auxiliary information needed to locate the observations
            in space and time. These data are organized, in a manner very
            similar to the RDR product files from which they are derived,
            into extensions within files formatted according to the Flexible
            Image Transport System (FITS) standard, version 2.1b. The UVS RDR
            archive enables reprocessing of the corrected and calibrated
            science data into far ultraviolet map products as map processing
            routines improve. Investigators interested in applying advanced
            mapping methods or needing to understand the properties of the
            corrected and calibrated data will find the RDR products useful.
            Many investigators, however, will be interested in using the UVS
            CODMAC Level 5 far ultraviolet map products directly.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
DATA SET OVERVIEW
=================
  The Juno Ultraviolet Spectrograph (UVS) CODMAC Level 3 Reduced Data Record
  is a collection of the far ultraviolet photon detections obtained by the UVS
  instrument, corrected for instrumental effects, radiometrically calibrated,
  and correlated with the auxiliary information needed to locate the
  observations in space and time.  These data are organized, in a manner very
 similar to the RDR product files from which they are derived, into extensions
within files formatted according to the Flexible Image Transport System (FITS)
  standard, version 2.1b.  The UVS RDR archive enables reprocessing of the
corrected and calibrated science data into far ultraviolet map products as map
  processing routines improve. Investigators interested in applying advanced
  mapping methods or needing to understand the properties of the corrected and
  calibrated data will find the RDR products useful.  Many investigators,
  however, will be interested in using the UVS CODMAC Level 5 far ultraviolet
  map products directly.
 
 
PARAMETERS
==========
  The fundamental derived parameters contained in the UVS RDR data set are
  the absolute time tag for each of the detected far ultraviolet photons, the
  weight factor applied to each to account for instrumental effects, the
  radiometric and wavelength calibrations and the geometric locations.  From
  these derived parameters in the RDR data set further processing will be able
  to compute monochromatic fluxes (photons/sec/cm^2/Angstrom) at the UVS
  location.
 
PROCESSING
==========
  UVS EDR data products will be generated at the UVS Science Operations
  Center (SOC), located at the Southwest Research Institute in San Antonio,
  Texas.  The products will be generated by an automated pipeline process.
 The UVS instrument will nominally generate one to many housekeeping telemetry
  files and science data files per orbit.  Once per day these UVS-generated
  files will be retrieved from the Juno spacecraft by the Juno Mission
  Operations Center (MOC) and then transferred by the MOC to the UVS SOC.
  The automated UVS SOC pipeline will ingest these files and invoke software
  to process them into EDR data product files.  No calibration of the science
  data will be done at this time.  Raw housekeeping telemetry values will be
  converted to engineering units, where applicable, and these converted values
 will be included in the EDR data product files. The pipeline will then invoke
  software to read these EDR data product files, apply instrumental
  corrections and calibrations (for detector deadtime, dark counts, flatfield,
  effective area, and wavelength), spatially locate the data with the aid of
  input SPICE kernels, and write the results out into the RDR data product
  files.  The FITS header of the RDR data product file will contain
  information regarding which corrections and calibrations were performed, and
  how.
 
 
DATA
====
  The UVS RDR data product file will contain the following types of data:
 
  1.  Calibrated Spectral Image:  This is a reconstructed histogram generated
      from the photon list data in the EDR data product but with instrumental
      calibrations applied.  This summary image is used as a &apos;quick-look&apos;
      check on data quality. [Extension 0 = primary FITS header and data unit
      (HDU)]
 
  2.  Acquisition List:  This dataset contains a list of the generated frame
      acquisitions as determined from the housekeeping data file.  The list
      includes, for each frame, the instrument frame sequence number, start
      and stop times, mode type, aperture door and other instrument state
      information. These data are simply copied as is from the EDR data
      product. The frame acquisition times and instrument state data
      contained in this list are used to cross-reference with the photon list
      mode data in the science files for purposes of selecting data and
      checking timing consistency. [Extension 1]
 
  3.  Ancillary Data:  This dataset contains ancillary spatial location and
      pointing information that varies smoothly and slowly over the Juno
      orbit. Also included in this extension are other slowly varying
      instrument-related quantities such as the detector locations of the
      STIM pixels, a measure of the background dark signal, and data quality
      flags.  Entries in this table are typically separated by 30s intervals
      instead of on a per-photon basis in order to reduce data volume and
      computation time. [Extension 2]
 
  4.  Calibrated Analog Count Rate:  This dataset contains a high-resolution
      sequence of UV photon count rates as read from the housekeeping data,
      with corrections for deadtime applied.  [Extension 3]
 
  5.  Calibrated Digital Count Rate:  This dataset contains a high-resolution
      sequence of UV photon count rates computed from the calibrated photon
      list data for each acquisition (nominally the whole orbit), with
      corrections for deadtime applied. [Extension 4]
 
  6.  Pulse Height Distribution (Lyman Alpha):   This is one of three
      histograms where the bins are arranged as pulse height vs. time. One
      histogram will be created per spin of the spacecraft. The spin rate may
      vary over the course of the mission.. This histogram contains photons
      whose spectra are recorded on detector columns numbered between 850
      and 930. [Extension 5]
 
  7.  Pulse Height Distribution (Stellar):   This is one of three histograms
      where the bins are arranged as pulse height vs. time. One histogram
      will be created per spin. This histogram contains photons whose spectra
      are recorded on detector columns numbered between 931 and 1770.
      [Extension 6]
 
  8.  Pulse Height Distribution (STIM):   This is one of three histograms
      where the bins are arranged as pulse height vs. time. One histogram
      will be created per spin. This histogram contains photons whose
      spectra are recorded on detector columns numbered between 0-149 and
      1950-2047. [Extension 7]
 
  9.  Housekeeping Data:  This dataset contains the complete housekeeping
      dataset, both in raw format and, where applicable, in calibrated
      engineering units.  These data are simply copied as is from the EDR
      data product. HK data are included here to assist with joint instrument
      and data quality trending analyses (foreseen and unforeseen).
      [Extension 8]
 
  10. Wavelength Lookup Image:  This dataset contains a 2048 x 256 image
      whose floating-point pixel values are the wavelengths corresponding to
      the pixel locations on the detector. This wavelength calibration image
      is provided to be used with Extension 0 for quick-look checks, but not
      for scientific analysis.  Its file-averaged wavelength solution makes
      it generally unsuitable to be used with pixel list data. [Extension 9]
 
  11. Mask Information: This dataset contains the coordinates and times of
      masks applied to the detector during observations. This data is parsed
      out of planning documents prepared by the operations team and the
      extension will be left empty if the planning document was unavailable
      at processing time. [Extension 10]
 
 
 
ANCILLARY DATA
==============
  Ancillary data used in the generation of the UVS RDR data set include those
  calibration values required to apply instrumental corrections and
  calibrations to the science data as well as trajectory and pointing
  information for the Juno spacecraft and clock conversion tables required to
  enable the geometric calibration of the science data.  The source of the
  instrumental calibration data are the UVS engineers and UVS scientists at
  the Southwest Research Institute in San Antonio, Texas [see
  GLADSTONEETAL2014 for further details], while the source of the spacecraft
  trajectory, pointing, and clock data are SPICE kernels provided to the UVS
  SOC by the Juno JSOC, having been ultimately generated by the MOC itself,
  the Flight Dynamics Facility (FDF) at GSFC, or the Navigation and Ancillary
  Information Facility (NAIF) at JPL.
 
SOFTWARE
========
  Because the UVS RDR data product files adhere to version 2.1b of the FITS
  standard, all FITS readers up to this standard should be able to
  successfully read these files.  There are many such FITS readers freely
  available in the public domain.
 
 
MEDIA/FORMAT
============
  The UVS EDR data product files are written in FITS format, and the format
  of each file is described in an accompanying detached PDS label.  The EDR
  archive itself will be electronically delivered from the Juno SOC (JSOC)
  to the PDS Imaging Node, where it will be made generally available via
  the World Wide Web.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence level information will be provided after more thorough analysis
  of the data.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>PRE_PEER_REVIEW</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

