<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.phx-m-om-3-radiometric-sci-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>PHOENIX MARS MECA OPTICAL MICROSCOPE 3 RADIOMETRIC SCI V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.phoenix::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.phx::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:om.phx::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.phx-m-om-3-radiometric-sci-v1.0__browserp_phx-m-om-3-radiometric-sci-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.phx-m-om-3-radiometric-sci-v1.0__browser_geo_phx-m-om-3-radiometric-sci-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.phx-m-om-3-radiometric-sci-v1.0__dvo_imaging_phx-m-om-3-radiometric-sci-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hecht, M.H., J. Marshall, W.T. Pike, U. Staufer, D. Blaney, D. Braendlin, S.
                   Gautsch, W. Goetz, H.-R. Hidber, H.U. Keller, W.J. Markiewicz, A. Mazer, T.P.
                   Meloy, J.M. Morookian, C. Mogensen, D. Parrat, P.H. Smith, H. Sykulska, R.J.
                   Tanner, A. Tonin, S. Vijendran, M. Weilert, P.M. Woida, Microscopy capabilities
                   of the Microscopy, Electrochemistry, and Conductivity Analyzer (MECA),
                   submitted to J. Geophys. Res., 2008.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HECHTETAL2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>PHX-M-OM-3-RADIOMETRIC-SCI-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>PHOENIX MARS MECA OPTICAL MICROSCOPE 3 RADIOMETRIC SCI V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2008-12-23</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2008-05-25T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>MICHAEL H. HECHT</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Hecht, Michael, Phoenix Mars MECA Imaging Science RDR V1.0, NASA
            Planetary Data System, PHX-M-OM-3-RADIOMETRIC-SCI-V1.0, 2008.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            PHX MECA Imaging RDR Science data includes processed data
            products from the Optical Microscope (OM), along with data from
            the MECA command electronics.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Microscopy, Electrochemistry, and Conductivity Analyzer
            (MECA) experiment on the Mars Phoenix Lander consists of four
            instrument components plus command electronics. This MECA Imaging
            Science RDR data set contains data from one of the four MECA
            components, the Optical Microscope (OM).
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set contains data to help understand the morphology, reflectance
    and texture of Martian soil and dust at the microscopic scale (typically in
    the range 10 - 100 microns). In most cases full-frame images with full pixel
    resolution will be acquired. In some cases, as e.g. for AFM context, the
    images will be subframed. Onboard downsampling is available, but will not be
    used during normal operations. Null strip (containing information on bias
    and system noise) and dark strip (information on dark current) are returned
    as a separate product if requested.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    N/A
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    This data set uses the Committee on Data Management and Computation (CODMAC)
    data level numbering system. The Phoenix EDRs are considered CODMAC Level 2
    (equivalent to NASA Level 0) or Edited Data (i.e. cleaned, time-ordered and
    quality-flagged data). The EDRs are reconstructed from Level 1 or Raw Data,
    which are the telemetry packets within the project specific Standard
    Formatted Data Unit (SFDU) record. They are assembled into complete images,
    but are not radiometrically or geometrically corrected. Phoenix EDR data
    products were generated by the Multi-mission Image Processing Lab (MIPL) at
    the Jet Propulsion Laboratory. The EDRs are raw uncalibrated data
    reconstructed from telemetry packet SFDUs and formatted according to the
    Camera EDR Software Interface Specification (SIS). Meta-data acquired from
    the telemetry data headers and a meta-data database were used to populate
    the PDS label. There will not be multiple versions of a Phoenix Camera EDR.
    Missing packets will be identified and reported for retransmission to the
    ground as partial datasets. Prior to retransmission, the missing EDR data
    will be filled with zeros. The EDR data will be reprocessed only after all
    partial datasets are retransmitted and received on the ground. In these
    cases, the original EDR version will be overwritten. The EDR data product
    will be placed into the File Exchange Interface (FEI) for distribution.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The OM data files will be decoded, decompressed camera image data in single
    frame form as an Experiment Data Record (EDR). The image data are acquired
    as 12-bit data, but stored as 16-bit signed integers. There are three data
    types:
 
    1) Full Frame EDRs
    Each Full Frame EDR contains a 512 columns * 256 rows image array. The size
    of a Full Frame EDR data product is therefore approximately 2.1 Mb (260 kB).
 
    2) Subframe EDRs
    Subframe EDRs are intended to provide context for the AFM data.
 
    3) Null &amp; Dark Strip EDRs
    Each Null &amp; Dark Strip EDR contains a 16 columns * 256 rows array. The pixel
    values are stored as 16-bit signed integers. The first and last 4 columns
    are pre-pixels (obtained by reading out &apos;virtual pixels&apos; without vertical
    shift) and contain information on the bias value and system noise. The
    central 8 columns are masked pixels that contain information on the dark
    current. Null &amp; Dark Strip EDRs are not available for each and every Full
    Frame EDR, but will only be generated and downlinked occasionally upon
    request.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    No ancillary data are needed to understand OM EDRs. Rotation and translation
    positions of the sample wheel are specified in units of motor step numbers
    in the EDR label. The Phoenix Project Software Interface Specification (SIS)
    for Camera Data Products provides the necessary information to convert
    rotation position step numbers into substrate IDs.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    N/A
 
 
  Software
  ========
    PDS-labeled images and tables can be viewed with the program NASAView,
    developed by the PDS and available for a variety of computer platforms from
    the PDS web site http://pdsproto.jpl.nasa.gov/Distribution/license.html.
    There is no charge for NASAView.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    The data set will initially be delivered and kept online. Upon Mission
    completion, the OM EDRs will be delivered to PDS on DVD as part of the
    complete Phoenix EDR data set.
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    N/A
 
 
  Review
  ======
    The data have not undergone any review process, such as PDS Peer review.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    No data gaps expected. Any data packets lost during downlink shall be
    retransmitted (cf. section on Processing).
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    None.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

