<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.uly-j-gas-5-sky-maps-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ULY JUPITER INTERSTELLAR NEUTRAL-GAS EXPERIMENT SKY MAPS</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.ulysses::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.uly::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:gas.uly::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.uly-j-gas-5-sky-maps-v1.0__browserp_uly-j-gas-5-sky-maps-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Banaszkiewicz, M., M. Witte, and H. Rosenbauer, Determination of
                   interstellar helium parameters from the ULYSSES- NEUTRALGAS experiment:
                   Method of data analysis, Astron. Astrophys. Supp. Ser., 120, 1-16, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BANASZKIEWICETAL1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Witte, M., H. Rosenbauer, E. Keppler, H. Fahr, P. Hemmerich, H. Lauche, A.
                   Loidl, and R. Zwick. The Interstellar Neutral-Gas Experiment On Ulysses,
                   Astron. Astrophys. Suppl. Ser., 333, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.WITTEETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Witte, M., H. Rosenbauer, M. Banaszkiewics, and H. Fahr, The Ulysses
                   Neutral Gas Experiment: determination of the velocity and temperature of
                   the interstellar neutral Helium, Adv. Space Res., 13, (6)121, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.WITTEETAL1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Witte, M., M. Banaszkiewicz, and H. Rosenbauer, Recent results on the
                   parameters of the interstellar helium from the ULYSSES/GAS experiment,
                   Space Sci. Rev., 78, 289-296, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.WITTEETAL1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>ULY-J-GAS-5-SKY-MAPS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ULY JUPITER INTERSTELLAR NEUTRAL-GAS EXPERIMENT SKY MAPS</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1999-03-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1991-07-22T23:17Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1992-04-10T22:42Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>MANFRED WITTE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>TBD</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Ulysses interstellar neutral gas (GAS) experiment sky maps of the
            count rates of interstellar helium particles (in the NG-mode) or
            from celestial UV-intensities (UV-mode).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>not applicable</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
      The GAS-Instrument on ULYSSES provides angular distributions
      of count rates from interstellar helium particles (in the
      NG-mode) or from celestial UV-intensities (UV-mode).
 
      Therefore the data are presented in the form of maps rather
      than as time series (as for most other ULYSSES experiments).
 
      The intensities are mapped in an ecliptic coordinate system
      centered in the spacecraft. In this system, the positions of
      the Sun and the planets vary with time and with the position
      of the spacecraft along its trajectory, however, the positions
      of stars remain fixed. The actual positions of Sun, Earth, and
      Jupiter are indicated by yellow, green and white dots,
      respectively. The area around the Sun is excluded from
      observation to avoid damaging intensities from direct
      sunlight.
 
      The intensities obtained in the UV-mode (the housekeeping
      parameter HV given in the bottom line of each map, has a
      positive value) are color coded in the range 10...1000
      counts/s, in the NG-mode (HV has a negative value) in the
      range 0.1...10 counts/s.
 
      File Name Conventions:
 
      [Note that the naming convention was modified from that
      originally provided to ISO 9660 and DOS compliant 8.3 at the
      PDS/PPI node. The description provided below reflects these
      changes.]
 
      The maps are provided in three different formats, as indicated
      in the extensions of the filenames yddd_NV.ext.
      1.)   *.ps   :   postscript format.
      2.)   *.gif  :   ready-to-view GIF-format.
      3.)   *.txt  :   ASCII-format to allow further computerized
                       processing. This format is described in
                       detail in the separate file FORMAT.TXT. These
                       files are contained in a compressed format in
                       the *.ZIP-files.
 
      The further information encoded in the filename is
      yddd         :   date of measurement(yy: year,ddd: day of the
      year). N            :   indicator of the telescope used,
                       1 =  narrow field of view (NFOV),
                       2 =  wide field of view (WFOV).
      V            :   Version indicator,
                       1,2, ... :  Running number of measurement
                                   during that day.
                       C        :  The map is composited from
                                   individual sub-images, named in
                                   the lower left corner of the map.
                       Ix       :  This map contains data from more
                                   than one scan through the covered
                                   area (to improve counting
                                   statistics).
 
      For further information see the separate files
      /CATALOG/REF.CAT and GASDATA.FMT.
 
      Interstellar Gas (NG-mode):
 
      Most of these maps are restricted to an area around the
      apparent flow direction of the interstellar helium particles.
 
      It is important to note, that the locally observed, apparent
      flow direction deviates from the flow direction at large
      distances (outside the solar system) for two reasons:
      1.) The local flow direction results from a deflection of the
          asymptotic direction due to the solar gravity (hyperbolic
          orbits).
      2.) The observed, apparent flow direction deviates from the
          local flow direction due to the aberration effect,
          resulting from a combination of the particle velocity
          vector and the spacecraft velocity vector. This effect is
          significant (of the order of 10 degrees) as the
          spacecrafts velocity is of the same order as the particle
          velocity (several 10 km/s).
 
      The systematic variation in the flow intensity which can be
      observed during over extended periodes in the ULYSSES mission
      is a result of the variation of the relative energy of the
      particles in the instrument&apos;s system. The detection efficiency
      of helium particles is strongly energy dependent with a sharp
      cut-off at energy around 30 eV (equivalent to a velocity of
      about 30 km/s for helium particles). This threshold is only
      exceeded when the spacecraft velocity (in magnitude and
      direction) adds in a favourable way to the local particle
      velocity. This is the case during extended periodes of the
      ULYSSES mission, from launch to Jupiter fly-by (Nov. 1990 to
      Feb. 1992) and in periods before and after perihelion (July
      1994 to July 96 and again in 1999 to 2001).
 
      Due to a residual sensitivity of the instrument to UV-photons,
      even in the NG-mode, also the signal from UV-stars is
      registered. This has been used to verify the pointing accuracy
      of the instrument to be of the order to a few tenths of a
      degree.
 
      Neutral particles from Jupiter:
 
      Close to Jupiter, in January to April 1992, the integral
      fluxes of low energy neutral particles can be derived from the
      observation of their angular distributions.
 
      Record Format
      -------------
      The files are written in ASCII, free format. Each file
      consists of a
       - HEADER section     (records 1 to 50)  and the
       - PIXEL-DATA section (records 51 to EOF)
 
      1.) HEADER
      records:
        1-10: HOUSEKEEPING DATA of date:
                1: date of start of measurements, source-filename
              2-6: housekeeping-data (command register contents)
                7: file generation date
                8: ecl. longitude and latitude of Sun, as seen from
                   ULS
                9: ecl. longitude and latitude of Earth, as seen
                   from ULS
               10: ecl. longitude and latitude of Jupiter, as seen
                   from ULS
 
       11-17: CELESTIAL DATA of date (ecliptic system, sun-centered)
               11: date(yy,doy,hh,mm);
                   direction of spin axis (ecl.long; ecl.lat;(deg.))
               12: position + velocity of ULS(ecl.kart.coord.(AU,
                   Km/s))
               13: position + velocity of Earth(ecl.kart.coord.(AU,
                   Km/s))
               14: position + velocity of Jupiter(ecl.kart.coord.
                   (AU, Km/s))
            15-17: transformation matrix, S/C-system -&gt; ecliptic
                   system
               18: source-files for this image
            19-20: TBD
            21-50: Model parameter (TBD)
 
      2.) PIXELDATA
      records 51-end of file(EOF):
          each record contains the data for one pixel in the fields:
                1: measured counts/s * 100
                2: total number of counts in the accumulation
                   period
                3: star flag
                       0 = O.K.;
                       1 = pixel contaminated by star light
                      -1 = not yet determined
                4:  counts/sec, as calculated along the line of
                    sight from a model (dummy value = -99.)
              5-7:  TBD         (dummy value = -99.)
            8-EOR:  5 pixel coordinates
                    (each direction is given in longitude and
                    latitude (deg.) of the ecl.system, ULS
                    centered)
                    8:  direction of the pixel center (line of
                        sight)
                    9-12:   4 directions to the corners of the
                            pixel,
                   (9-EOR): (there can be 3 or 5 or more corners, in
                            case the pixel intersects with the
                            borders of the coordinate system)
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      Confidence Level Overview
      =========================
      Some confidence level information provided in Data Set
      Overview. For more information regarding the confidence
      level of this data set please contact:
 
        Manfred Witte
        Max-Planck-Institut fur Aeronomie
        Max-Planck-Strasse 2
        37191 Katlenburg-Lindau
        GERMANY
 
        Phone:    (49) 5556 979324
        Telefax:  (49) 5556 979240
        Internet: witte@linmpi.mpg.de
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>1990-090B</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

