<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ody-m-grs-4-dhd-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 4 DHD V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.2001_mars_odyssey::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.ody::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:grs.ody::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-grs-4-dhd-v1.0__browserp_geo_ody-m-grs-4-dhd-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-grs-4-dhd-v1.0__dvo_geo_ody-m-grs-4-dhd-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-grs-4-dhd-v1.0__pds.ua.grs_web_site::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Boynton, W. V., W. C. Feldman, I. Mitrofanov, L. G. Evans, R. C. Reedy, S.
                   W. Squyres, R. Starr, I. Trombka, C. d&apos;Uston, J. R. Arnold, P. A. J.
                   Englert, A. E. Metzger, H. Wanke, J. Bruckner, D. M. Drake, C. Shinohara,
                   C. Fellows, D. K. Hamara, K. Harshman, The Mars Odyssey gamma-ray
                   spectrometer instrument suite, Space Sci. Rev., 110 (1-2): 37-83, 2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BOYNTONETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Planetary Data System Standards Reference, JPL Document D-7669, Part 2, Jet
                   Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PDSSR2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Seidelmann, P.K., V.K. Abalakin, M. Bursa, M.E. Davies, C. de Bergh, J.H.
                   Lieske, J. Oberst, J.L. Simon, E.M. Standish, P. Stooke, and P.C. Thomas,
                   Report of the IAU/IAG working group on cartographic coordinates and rotational
                   elements of the planets and satellites: 2000, Celestial Mechanics and Dynamical
                   Astronomy, 82, 83-111, 2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SEIDELMANNETAL2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>ODY-M-GRS-4-DHD-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 4 DHD V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2004-07-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2002-02-19T00:00:00.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>WILLIAM BOYNTON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Boynton, W.V., Mars 2001 Odyssey Gamma Ray Spectrometer Derived
            High Energy Neutron Detector Data V1.0, ODY-M-GRS-4-DHD-V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Mars Odyssey Gamma Ray Spectrometer (GRS) Derived High Energy
            Neutron Detector Data (DHD) archive contains background
            subtracted count values needed to calculate neutron counting
            rates derived from HEND experiment data records (EDRs).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Prism counting rates, normalizations, corrections, and thermal,
            epithermal, and fast neutron counting rates derived from neutron
            data collected by the Neutron Spectrometer of the Odyssey GRS
            instrument suite.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Mars Odyssey Gamma-Ray Spectrometer (GRS) is a suite of
      three instruments working together to collect data that will
      permit the mapping of elemental concentrations on the surface
      of Mars. The suite of three instruments, the gamma-ray sensor
      head (GS), the Los Alamos National Laboratory (LANL) neutron
      spectrometer (NS) and the Russian Academy of Science Institute
      for Space Research (IKI) high-energy neutron detector (HEND),
      are a complementary set of instruments in that the neutron
      instruments have better counting statistics and sample to a
      greater depth than the GS, but the GS determines the abundance
      of many more elements. A full description of the Mars
      Odyssey Gamma-Ray Spectrometer instrument can be found in
      [BOYNTONETAL2004].
 
      The ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 4 DHD (DHD) data set is a
      time series collection of counts and backgrounds for
      the five neutron signals obtained by HEND&apos;s four detectors.
 
      The five neutron signals of interest are the:
 
        Small Detector,  SD,  energy range 0.4 eV to 1 keV;
        Medium Detector, MD,  energy range 10 eV to 100 keV;
        Large Detector,  LD,  energy range 10 eV to 1 MeV;
        Inner Scintillator, IN_SC_LOW,
                       neutron pulse height 1 MeV to 2.5 MeV;
        Inner Scintillator, IN_SC_HIGH,
                       neutron pulse height &gt; 2.5 MeV;
 
      Each of the GRS HEND detectors collects a new spectrum (pixel
      or frame) approximately every 20 seconds, 360 times per orbit.
      Approximately 4200 spectra are expected to be received every
      day. The data (both science and engineering) are downloaded
      from the spacecraft by the Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) into
      the Telemetry Data System (TDS). The TDS sends data to a process
      that translates data packets and examines instrument health via
      messages. Data are output to a spooler that passes it to both
      the University of Arizona (UA) database ingest process and to
      IKI. The UA ingest process inputs raw data into the UA database.
      IKI maintains a separate database that is used to process the
      DHD data. HEND data are processed by IKI through a number of
      processes to yield counts and backgrounds for the five
      neutron signals obtained by HEND&apos;s four detectors. The
      derived HEND data are retrieved from IKI and inserted into the
      UA database. The DHDs are prepared for PDS from the UA database.
 
      The DHD is intended to be the first intermediate data product
      available for the HEND portion of the GRS. These data should
      be useful to those scientists who are experienced in neutron
      spectroscopy.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      The DHD data set is composed of a single data type (DHD). The
      objective of compiling the DHD is to create a series of neutron
      data processed to yield local spacecraft background subtracted
      counts for each of the five distinct neutron signals.
 
      Each DHD product data file will contain a time series of
      derived neutron counts collected over an Earth Day. The
      24-hour data files will be grouped by Earth years, i.e., 365
      data files per year.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      A full description of the HEND data processing can be found in
      the Mars Odyssey Gamma-ray Spectrometer HEND Data
      Processing document located in the document folder that
      accompanies this release. The following paragraphs are a summary
      of how the data are processed from data receipt through
      background subtraction.
 
      GRS HEND data are downloaded from the Mars Odyssey spacecraft
      by JPL into the Telemetry Data System (TDS). The TDS sends the
      data to a process called GRS_tl that translates GRS packets
      from any source to any destination and examines instrument
      health via messages. The data are checked for packet types,
      header information, messages, errors, engineering and
      channelized data values and are output to a spooler and to a
      data display IDL program called GRS Displays. Data sent to the
      spooler are passed to the UA database ingestion process, which
      inputs raw data into the UA database. Data sent to the GRS
      Displays program is recorded at IKI and held in a data
      repository.  All additional steps of HEND data processing are
      done at IKI.
 
      All data packets received by the GRS Displays program are
      processed for timing and spatial information. Once time data
      are extracted from the data packet, UTC time is calculated from
      the spacecraft event time (sc_ev_time, time at the middle of
      the collection interval in 256th seconds) by a SPICE function.
      The UTC time is then inserted into the database. The spatial
      portion of the data packet is calculated using other SPICE
      routines. The returned values are all the spatial elements of
      an observation, including latitude and longitude at the
      mid-point of the observation.
 
      The HEND instrument collects five neutron signals from four
      independent detectors, whose response functions are sensitive
      to different energy regions. Raw neutron counts are reported in
      the HEND portion of the EDR data set as a 16-channel spectrum
      for each of the four detectors (SD_SPECTRUM, MD_SPECTRUM,
      LD_SPECTRUM,NEUTRON_SPECTRUM). In the DHD data set, raw neutron
      counts are reported as the sums of channels 1-16 in the SD
      (Small Detector), MD (Medium Detector), and LD (Large Detector).
      The inner scintillator records two neutron signals, LOW (sum of
      channels 1-4 in the inner scintillator) and HIGH (sum of
      channels 5-15 in the inner scintillator). The raw neutron
      counts for the LOW and HIGH signals are reported in the DHD as
      the sum of channels 1-4 and 5-15 respectively, of the
      NEUTRON_SPECTRA field of the HEND portion of the EDR data set.
 
      The background term reported for each collection interval is
      a combination of the galactic cosmic-ray flux induced
      spacecraft background and a spacecraft orbital geometry term
      to account for the shadowing by the planet of the galactic
      cosmic-ray flux. The galactic cosmic-ray flux induced
      background was measured in each detector during the cruise
      phase of the mission when the spacecraft was far from both the
      Earth and Mars. The observed background count for the
      detector of interest is multiplied by (1-omega(t)/4pi) where
      omega(t) is the solid angle subtended by Mars for the current
      position in the spacecraft orbit. The resulting term is the
      background counts in the particular collection interval for the
      detector of interest.
 
      The background subtracted counts reported for each signal in
      the DHD data set are simply the background counts subtracted
      from the summed raw counts.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      The DHD data set is composed of a series of date stamped files
      that contain 24-hours worth (00:00:00 UTC to 23:59:59 UTC) of
      data.
 
 
      Derived HEND Data
      -------------
        Derived HEND data are composed of raw counts, a
        background component, background subtracted counts
        and the associated timing and  spatial information. The five
        raw counts fields included in the DHDs consist of the
        cumulative counts of neutrons at the detector of interest
        over one collection interval. The collection interval is
        approximately 19.7 seconds, but may vary over the course of
        mapping. The five background count fields are derived from
        spatial data and count data collected during the cruise phase
        of the mission. The five background subtracted count fields
        are the background subtracted counts at the detector of
        interest over one collection interval. Timing and spatial
        data provided with the counts include spacecraft clock values
        and spacecraft geometry data. The sc_ev_time, utc time and
        spatial fields are all recorded at the center of the
        collection interval.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      Ancillary data needed to understand the HEND data processing
      can be found in the Mars Odyssey Gamma-ray Spectrometer HEND
      Data Processing document located in the document folder that
      accompanies this release.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      The coordinate system used for all GRS data is a Mars
      areocentric system following the IAU convention
      [SEIDELMANNETAL2002], with east longitudes from 0 to 360.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      A library of source code to parse the DHD data product files
      is included in the software directory. This library allows a
      programmer to build applications that display or manipulate
      DHD data. This source is written in the Java language, and
      requires version 1.3 of the Java Runtime Environment (JRE) or
      Java Software Development Kit (SDK).
 
      Documentation for the code is located in the software directory
      in the file GRS_CODE_DOC.ZIP. The contents of this file are
      described in the label GRS_CODE_DOC.LBL.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The DHD will be delivered using DVD media. Formats will be
      based on standards for such products established by the
      Planetary Data System (PDS) [PDSSR2001].
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      The data presented in the DHD are intended to be the first
      intermediate data set released for the HEND portion of the
      GRS. Data presented here are a highly processed representation
      of the GRS HEND data as received from the spacecraft. It is
      possible that changes will be made in the data processing
      procedures if errors are found. If errors are found, the data
      will have to be regenerated from the raw unprocessed data set.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      The DHD was reviewed internally by the GRS team prior to
      release to the PDS. PDS will perform an external peer review of
      the DHD.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Data reported are the processed raw HEND data received from the
      spacecraft during the mapping mission stage. Data coverage and
      quality are addressed in the following sections.
 
 
      Primary Mapping
      ---------------
      The Mapping portion of the mission began February 19, 2002, and
      is expected to last until August, 2004. Primary mapping is
      broken into two phases: stowed mapping and deployed mapping.
 
 
      Stowed Mapping
      --------------
        The stowed mapping configuration began on February 19, 2002
        and lasted until June 1, 2002. The stowed mapping
        configuration is with the Odyssey spacecraft in a mapping
        orbit, with the GRS in data collection configuration
        without the 6-meter boom deployed. The reason for data
        collection in the stowed configuration is to measure the
        gamma-ray background signal from the spacecraft. The HEND
        instrument was always in the same spacecraft position. On
        June 1, 2002 the GRS was shutdown to prepare for boom
        deployment, which occurred on June 4, 2002. No data
        were collected during this time period.
 
        There are short periods of missing data due to missing
        telemetry that cannot be recovered.
 
 
      Deployed Mapping
      ----------------
        Deployed Mapping began on June 5, 2002 and is expected to
        continue until at least August, 2004.
 
        A number of solar particle events, and solar flare events
        have been recorded. HEND Data collected during these times,
        as indicated by the SUN_ACTIVITY field being greater than 1,
        are suspect.
 
        There are short data gaps due to missing telemetry that
        cannot be recovered.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    The major limitation of this data set is that it is derived from
    the raw minimally processed HEND data. The data are received
    from spacecraft telemetry, and ingested into a database. If gaps
    exist in the telemetry, data are lost. Timing and spatial
    components of the data set rely on the accuracy of the NAIF SPICE
    kernels. The validity of the derived HEND counts is based
    on the &apos;correctness&apos; of each step in the processing. It is
    possible that changes will be made in the processing procedures
    if errors are found. If errors are found, the data will
    have to be regenerated from the raw unprocessed data set.
 
 
  Data Compression
  ===============
    No compression is used on the DHD data set.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

