<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.di-iras-c-fpa-5-9p-phot-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DEEP IMPACT: IRAS PHOTOMETRY OF COMET 9P/TEMPEL 1</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_impact::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.infrared_astronomical_satellite::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.iras::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:fpa.iras::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.9p-tempel_1_1867_g1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.di-iras-c-fpa-5-9p-phot-v1.0__browserp_di-iras-c-fpa-5-9p-phot-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Beichman, C.A., G. Neugebauer, H.J. Habing, P.E. Clegg, and T.J. Chester,
                   1988, Infrared Astronomical Satellite Catalog and Atlases, Volume 1,
                   Explanatory Supplement, NASA RP-1190.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BEICHMANETAL1988</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lisse, C.M., M.F. A&apos;Hearn, T.L. Farnham, O. Groussin, K.J. Meech, U. Fink, and
                   D.G. Schleicher, The Coma of Comet 9P/Tempel 1, Space Science Reviews, 117,
                   161-192, 2005, doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3384-6.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LISSEETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Wheelock, S.L., T.N. Gautier III, J. Chillemi, D. Kester, H. McCallon, C.
                   Oken, J. White, D. Gregorich, F. Boulanger, J. Good, and T. Chester, 1994,
                   IRAS Sky Survey Atlas Explanatory Supplement, JPL Publication 94-11
                   (Pasadena: JPL).
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.WHEELOCKETAL1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   YOUNG, E.T., G. NEUGEBAUER, E.L. Kopan, R.D. Benson, T.P. Conrow, W.L.
                   Rice, and D.T. Gregorich, A User&apos;s Guide to IRAS Pointed Observation
                   Products, IPAC Preprint No. PRE-008N, 1985.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.YOUNGETAL1985</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DI/IRAS-C-FPA-5-9P-PHOT-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DEEP IMPACT: IRAS PHOTOMETRY OF COMET 9P/TEMPEL 1</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2003-10-30</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1983-06-18</start_time>
        <stop_time>1983-10-08</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STEPHANIE MCLAUGHLIN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Lisse, C.M. and S.A. McLaughlin, IRAS PHOTOMETRY OF 9P/TEMPEL 1
            FOR DEEP IMPACT V1.0, DI/IRAS-C-FPA-5-9P-PHOT-V1.0, NASA
            Planetary Data System, 2003.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            IRAS photometry of the coma of comet 9P/Tempel 1 in support of
            the NASA Deep Impact Mission
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains photometry of comet 9P/Tempel 1 as derived
            from reprocessed IRAS images from 1983, in support of the NASA
            Deep Impact Mission.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  This data set description was prepared by Stephanie McLaughlin and
  is based on the documentation provided by Carey Lisse and
  included in this archive.
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
 
    This data set contains 12-, 25-, 60-, and 100-micron photometry of
    the dust coma of comet 9P/Tempel 1 during its 1983 apparition.
    The photometry was derived from reconstructed observations acquired
    by the Focal Plane Array (FPA) instrument on the Infrared Astronomical
    Satellite (IRAS).  The types of observations were Sky Survey Atlas
    (ISSA) scans and Additional/Pointed Observations (AO).  A comprehensive
    discussion of these data was provided by Carey Lisse and included as
    documentation.  The reconstructed images used for this photometric
    analysis are available in the PDS data set
    DI/IRAS-C-FPA-5-9P-IMAGES-V1.0.
 
    These data support the analysis of the dust environment of Tempel 1
    for the NASA Deep Impact Mission (Lisse et al. 2005 [LISSEETAL2005]).
 
    Background
    ----------
 
      IRAS imaged comet 9P/Tempel 1 during the months before and after
      perihelion on July 9, 1983.  IRAS spent the majority of its
      observing time in the survey mode that systematically mapped
      the sky with a series of overlapping and confirming ISSA scans
      (Wheelock et al. 1994 [WHEELOCKETAL1994]).  However, IRAS also
      devoted time to making pointed observations (A0) of selected
      fields of interest (Young et al. 1985 [YOUNGETAL1985]).  IRAS
      observations were acquired by its Focal Plane Array, a
      multi-wavelength detector with spectral bands centered nominally
      at 12, 25, 60, and 100 microns (Beichman et al. 1988
      [BEICHMANETAL1988]).
 
      To support analysis of the dust coma of comet 9P/Tempel 1, Russell
      Walker selected sets of AO and ISSA images archived at the Infrared
      Processing and Analysis Center (IPAC), then corrected the images
      for the effects of extended source emissions.  Walker delivered the
      reconstructed, in-band radiance images and noise maps to the Deep
      Impact project.  These data are archived in PDS as data set
      DI/IRAS-C-FPA-5-9P-IMAGES-V1.0.
 
      Walker provided aperture photometry of Tempel 1 with his delivery
      of reconstructed IRAS images.  However, a preliminary review of
      the photometry determined that the background subtraction method
      could be improved.  Lisse developed an algorithm that better
      simulated the background then used this method to derive the
      photometry in this data set.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
 
    The following reconstructed, in-band radiance images were used
    to derive the photometry:
 
    AO
    --
      SOP  OBS   UTC Date                                Bands (micron)
      ===  ===   =====================================   ===============
      287   13   1983-06-18, 21.50 days pre-perihelion   12, 25, 60, 100
      407   12   1983-08-17, 38.50 days post-perihelion  12, 25, 60, 100
      407   43   1983-08-17, 38.75 days post-perihelion  12, 25, 60, 100
      509   40   1983-10-07, 90.00 days post-perihelion  12, 25, 60, 100
      510   22   1983-10-08, 90.25 days post-perihelion  12, 25, 60, 100
 
      where SOP = satellite operations plan and OBS = observation number
 
    ISSA
    ----
      Mean SOP   Mean UTC Date                           Bands (micron)
      ========   ======================================  ===============
        339      1983-07-14,  4.50 days post-perihelion  12, 25, 60, 100
        368      1983-07-28, 19.25 days post-perihelion  12, 25, 60, 100
        389      1983-08-08, 30.00 days post-perihelion  12, 25, 60, 100
        421      1983-08-24, 46.00 days post-perihelion  12, 25, 60, 100
        493      1983-09-28, 81.25 days post-perihelion  12, 25, 60, 100
 
        where Mean SOP is the average satellite operations plan used to
        identify a specific, reconstructed survey scan
 
    For sky background removal, Lisse applied an algorithm that employed
    a 2-dimensional quadratic surface fit to a synthetic background,
    created by taking the in-band radiance image and replacing all
    pixels within a certain pixel radius, centered at the nucleus,
    with the median value of the image.  The masked region size was
    chosen to eliminate any contamination of the background by cometary
    emission.  The background surface fit was then subtracted from
    the original in-band radiance image.
 
    For photometry, circular apertures of increasing radii were sampled
    until the summed in-band radiances reached an asymptote.  The results
    were recorded in ASCII tables, one for each in-band radiance image.
    For more information about these processes, refer the explanatory
    supplement included with this data set.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
    The aperture photometry data are ASCII tables with fixed-length
    records.  Each table contains five columns of data:  aperture radius
    in pixels, aperture radius in arcseconds, total in-band radiance for
    the circular aperture, median value for the subtracted background,
    statistical noise in the summed in-band radiance.  In-band radiance,
    background, and noise are recorded in units of Watts/cm^2/steradian.
 
    The naming convention for the AO aperture photometry tables is
    sSOP_oOBS_BANDum_phot.tab where SOP is the satellite operations
    plan number, OBS is the observation number, and BAND is the
    wavelength in microns.
 
    The naming convention for the ISSA aperture photometry tables is
    sMEANSOP_BANDum_phot.tab where MEANSOP is the average satellite
    operations plan number and BAND is the wavelength in microns.
 
 
  Data
  ====
 
    One photometry table corresponds to one reconstructed, in-band
    radiance image.  The PDS label includes the file name of the
    radiance FITS image used to derive the photometry.
 
    The first record in each photometry table is intentionally set
    to zeros because it is the true zero point for the photometry.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
 
    This data set is released as a logical data volume.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    1) To derive calibrated absolute photometry using the in-band
       radiances found in the aperture photometry tables, convert the
       in-band radiance to a flux density, apply a color correction,
       then divide by a COBE/IRAS recalibration factor.  These steps,
       along with correction and recalibration factors, are described
       in the explanatory supplement for this data set.
 
    2) This data set was used extensively by the Deep Impact science team
       to develop a model of the dust coma of Tempel 1.  These data were
       reviewed during an during an external peer review in October 2003
       and were approved for ingestion into the PDS, pending the
       resolution of liens.  Liens were resolved in August 2005.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

