<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lro-l-crat-2-edr-rawdata-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LRO MOON CRATER EDR RAWDATA VERSION 1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:crat.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-crat-2-edr-rawdata-v1.0__browserp_lro-l-crat-2-edr-rawdata-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Spence, H.E., A.W. Case, M.J. Golightly, T. Heine, B.A. Larsen, J.B. Blake, P.
                   Caranza, W.R. Crain, J. George, M. Lalic, A. Lin, M.D. Looper, J.E. Mazur, D.
                   Salvaggio, J.C. Kasper, T.J. Stubbs, M. Doucette, P.Ford, R. Foster, R. Goeke,
                   D. Gordon, B. Klatt, J. O&apos;Conner, M. Smith, T. Onsager, C. Zeitlin, L.W.
                   Townsend, Y. Charara (2010), CRaTER: The Cosmic Ray Telescope for the Effects
                   of Radiation Experiment on the Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter Mission, Space Sci.
                   Rev., 150, 243-284, DOI: 10.1007/s11214-009-9584-8.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SPENCEETAL2010</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LRO-L-CRAT-2-EDR-RAWDATA-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LRO MOON CRATER EDR RAWDATA VERSION 1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2010-03-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2009-06-29T00:00:00.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2009-12-31T23:59:59.000Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>PROF. HARLAN SPENCE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Spence, H.E., LRO MOON CRATER EDR RAWDATA VER- SION 1.0,
            LRO-L-CRAT-2-EDR-RAWDATA-V1.0, NASA PLANETARY DATA SYSTEM, 2010
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains raw data from the LRO LRO CRaTER Instrument
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set comprises the raw binary data from from the LRO
            Cosmic Ray Telescope for the Effects of Radiation (CRaTER)
            instrument. The data consists of the unconverted primary science,
            secondary science, and housekeeping CCSDS- formatted data packets
            and data headers.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
 
    The Cosmic Ray Telescope for the Effects of Radiation (CRaTER) is a
    stacked detector-absorber cosmic-ray telescope designed to answer key
    questions to enable future human exploration of the Solar System.
    CRaTER&apos;s primary measurement goal is to measure directly the average
    lineal energy transfer (LET or &apos;y&apos;) spectra caused by space radiation
    penetrating and interacting with shielding material.  Such measured LET
    spectra are frequently unavailable.  In the absence of measurements,
    numerical models are used to provide estimates of LET; the reliability of
    the models require experimental measurements to provide a ground truth.
 
    The CRaTER Level 0 dataset consists of files containing the raw primary
    science, secondary science, and housekeeping telemetry packets and packet
    headers created by the instrument.  The Level 0 data are meant to be used
    only for archival purposes in order to reconstruct the other CRaTER data
    products in the future, should that become necessary.  The Level 0 data
    are not intended to be used directly in data analyses or scientific
    investigations--the data are stored in binary data structures and have
    not been converted to appropriate engineering or science values.  Users
    seeking CRaTER data are strongly encouraged to use the Level 1 or Level 2
    datasets.
 
    See the MISSION.CAT file for more information on the LRO mission.
    See the CRAT_INST.CAT file for more information on the CRaTER instrument.
    See SPENCEETAL2010 for detailed description of LRO flight version of the
    instrument, its operations, and data processing.
 
    Science Objectives and Observation Strategy
    -------------------------------------------
    CRaTER is designed to achieve characterization of the global lunar
    radiation environment and its biological impacts and potential mitigation
    as well as investigation of shielding capabilities and validation of
    other deep space radiation mitigation strategies involving materials.
    CRaTER will fill knowledge gaps regarding radiation effects, provide
    fundamental progress in knowledge of the Moon&apos;s radiation environment,
    and provide specific path-finding benefits for future planned human
    exploration.
 
    Parameters
    ----------
    LRO CRaTER flight instrument identification:
    --instrument model = Flight Model 1 (FM1);
    --instrument serial number (S/N) = 02;
    --FPGA revision code = 3.
 
    Data
    ----
    CRaTER&apos;s principal measurement is the energy deposited in the 3-pairs of
    silicon detectors by charged particles and photons passing through the in-
    strument&apos;s &apos;telescope&apos; unit.  Whenever the coulombic charge signal re-
    sulting from the energy deposited in a detector exceeds a predefined and
    fixed threshold, the instrument&apos;s electronics performs a detailed measure-
    ment of the signals from all of the detectors.  The resulting detector
    signal amplitudes are compared to the values of the &apos;lower level discrim-
    inators&apos; (LLDs).  LLDs establish minimum amplitudes for signals to qualify
    as valid charged-particle or photon interactions.  The LLD values are
    generally set to insure that the desired charged-particle or photon mea-
    surements are not contaminated by system electronic noise.  Seperate LLD
    settings are required for the thick and thin detectors due to the dif-
    ference in their sensitivities; the thin and thick detector LLD values are
    reported in the &apos;DiscThin&apos; and &apos;DiscThick&apos; parameters as part of the
    secondary science packet.
 
    In addition to the LLD settings, measurement filtering is achieved through
    detector coincidence requirements--the combination of detectors register-
    ing valid signals to qualify as a charged-particle or photon measurement
    &apos;event&apos;.  To measure all charged particles arriving from the instrument&apos;s
    zenith or nadir directions, for example, the coincidence requirements
    would be valid signals in at least detectors 1, or 2, or 5, or 6.  Con-
    versely, a coincidence consisting of valid signals in all six detectors
    would ensure only zenith- or nadir-arriving charged particles with high
    energies are reported.  For CRaTER&apos;s six axially-coaligned detectors there
    are 64 possible coincidence combinations.  The desired set of coincidence
    combinations are stored as a coincidence mask parameter in the instru-
    ment&apos;s memory; the coincidence mask setting is reported in the &apos;Mask&apos;
    parameter as part of the secondary science packet.
 
    To qualify as an &apos;event&apos;, therefore a charged particle or photon passing
    through CRaTER&apos;s telescope must interact and deposit sufficient energy to
    generate signals with amplitudes in excess of the specified LLDs in a
    specified combination of detectors; only data for valid &apos;events&apos; are re-
    ported in the instrument&apos;s telemetry.
 
    The measured interaction event data is written as a series of primary
    science packets to the instrument&apos;s output telemetry buffer for the space-
    craft to read. At ~1 second intervals CRaTER receives a timing pulse from
    the spacecraft, at which time it flushes the primary science data from the
    output buffer and writes a secondary science packet for the spacecraft to
    read.  Every 16 seconds a housekeeping packet is also created and written
    to the output buffer.
 
    This Level 0 dataset is composed of the three types of time-sequential,
    raw CRaTER data records: (1) primary science, (2) secondary science, and
    (3) housekeeping.
 
    The primary science raw data consists of the signal pulse heights from
    each of the six detectors produced during an &apos;event&apos;.  The raw event data
    in the primary science packets are the scalar channel numbers output by
    the detector-amplifier strings&apos; analog-to-digital converters (ADCs) fol-
    lowing signal pulse height analysis.
 
    The secondary science raw data contain the majority of instrument config-
    uration settings, status flags, and event counters.  Reported configura-
    tion settings include the last command sent to CRaTER, detector LLD set-
    tings, and coincidence mask values.  Status flags available in the secon-
    dary science raw data include detector bias status, selected pulse am-
    plitude range and rate for the internal calibration pulser, and detector
    processing status.  Counters report the number of &apos;singles&apos; for each de-
    tector as well as the number of &apos;good&apos;, &apos;rejected&apos;, and total events re-
    corded by CRaTER during the monitoring period.
 
    The housekeeping raw data contains the output of internal monitors used to
    assess the operating health of the instrument, such as power supply
    voltage monitors, detector bias voltages and bias currents, pulse ampli-
    tudes from the internal calibration pulser, and temperatures at five loca-
    tions inside of the instrument&apos;s housing.  The analog output from radia-
    tion monitor is also included in the housekeeping data packets.
 
    The primary science, secondary science, and housekeeping packets are
    written to seperate files in binary format.  Each file begins with a
    64-byte header and continues with one or more CCSDS packets. Each packet
    begins with a 6-byte CCSDS header that defines the type (ApID 120,
    121, or 122) and length of the packet, followed by a 6-byte secondary
    header containing a time tag and instrument-specific flags.  Each of the
    files contains all of the data from a single UTC day.  The files&apos; binary
    structures are documented in CRaTER SPDR and Archive Volume Software
    Interface Specification (Document 32-01211), sections 5.2.6 and
    Appendix C.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    -------------------------
    No confidence level information is provided for the Level 0 data since it
    consists of only the raw instrument binary data and is not intended for
    direct use in data analyses.
 
    Confidence level information is provided with the Level 1 and Level 2
    sets.
 
    Review
    ------
    A minimal set of automated quality control steps are used by the data
    processing system to verify the integrity of the data.  During the
    creation of the Level 0 data files from the downlinked instrument data
    files, each data packet&apos;s CCSDS header is checked for format and content.
    Packets are discarded if their headers are corrupted, incorrectly
    formatted, or containing invalid values.  All packets are sorted into
    time order and checked for temporal gaps.  Duplicate packets are also
    discarded.  Metrics plus any detected anomalies are written to process
    log files for review by scientists and engineers from the instrument
    team.  Anomalies noted during the processing are investigated.  Anomalies
    due to missing input files (e.g., instrument science and housekeeping
    data files, spacecraft housekeeping data files, spacecraft ephemeris
    kernels, and ancillary files such as leap second and spacecraft clock
    kernels) are corrected by locating the missing input and reprocessing the
    data.
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    -------------------------
    Start date for the initial version of the LRO-L-CRAT-2-EDR-RAWDATA-V2.0
    archival volume is 2009-06-29T00:00:00.000.  This date/time is the begin-
    ning of the first full UTC day following completion of LRO lunar orbit
    insertion (LOI) maneuvers and transition to the nominal nadir-pointing
    observation attitude.  It is also the first day for which complete re-
    constructed ephemeris (&apos;SPK&apos;) data was available from the LRO Mission
    Operations Center.  There is only limited re-constructed ephemeris data
    currently available for the period between initial instrument power-up
    (2009-06-20) and LOI completion/transition to the nominal observing
    attitude.  CRaTER data obtained during Cruise Phase (instrument power-up
    - 2009-06-23), Lunar Orbit Acquisition (2009-06-23), and the initial
    Commissioning Period (2009-06-23 - 2009-06-28) will be included when more
    complete ephemeris data becomes available.
 
    Data gaps are identified during initial data processing. Each gap&apos;s
    beginning and end times are recorded in gap files stored in the DOCUMENT
    directory--there are seperate gap files for primary science, secondary
    science, and house-keeping data.  Each gap file contains a cumulative
    listing of the missing data up to and including the time span covered for
    the data current volume.  The minimum duration between successive data
    packets to qualify as a data gap is specified during data processing.
 
    The default gap duration specifications are:
    --primary science = 2 seconds;
    --secondary science = 2 seconds;
    --and housekeeping =20 seconds.
 
    These default gap duration values may be over ridden at the time of data
    processing.  The gap duration specifications used while processing a
    specific day&apos;s data are recorded in the corresponding process log files
    and stored in the DATA subdirectoy directory containing the data products.
 
    Limitations
    -----------
    The LRO-L-CRAT-2-EDR-RAWDATA-V1.0 data set includes all data obtained
    by the CRaTER instrument, including data from periods when the instrument
    was placed into special configurations.  Special configurations include
    the instrument start-up tests that occur whenever the instrument is power
    cycled to (e.g., initial instrument start-up, recovery following space-
    craft transition to sun-safe mode) as well routine calibrations (90-degree
    off-nadir GCR background measuerments, internal pulser sweeps, LLD zero
    crossing measurements, and LLD sweeps).
 
    As specified in CRaTER Standard Product Data Record and Archive Volume
    Software Interface Specification, Document 32-01211, the Level 0 house-
    keeping data files contain the voltage (V28BUS) and current draw (I28bus)
    measured at the instrument side of the instrument-spacecraft 28 VDC bus
    interface.  For the LRO CRaTER instrument, the voltage (V28BUS) and cur-
    rent (I28BUS) values are UNDEFINED.  Immediately prior to instrument
    delivery, the signal leads from these two monitors were removed to reduce
    excessive EMI emmission; however, the instrument software still processes
    the signals from these open leads and includes them in the housekeeping
    packets stored in the instrument housekeeping files.  Although no longer
    defined, these values have been retained in the Level 0 housekeeping files
    in order to preserve the structure defined for the instrument&apos;s house-
    keeping packets (LRO telemetry ApID = 122).  Although values can be
    retrieved for the voltage (V28BUS) and current (I28BUS) parameters from
    the Level 0 housekeeping data files, they are UNDEFINED and should be
    discarded from any analyses.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

