<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ear-c-phot-3-rdr-lowell-comet-db-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LOWELL OBSERVATORY COMETARY DATABASE</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.support_archives::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.lowell::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:phot.lowell::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.comet::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-c-phot-3-rdr-lowell-comet-db-v1.0__browserp_ear-c-phot-3-rdr-lowell-comet-db-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   A&apos;Hearn, M.F. and R.L. Millis, Abundance correlations among comets,
                   Astronomical Journal, 85, 1528-1537, 1980.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.AHEARN-MILLIS1980</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   A&apos;Hearn, M.F. and V. Vanysek, Photometry and Polarimetry Network, The
                   Comet Halley Archive - Release 1.0 CD-ROM USA_NASA_IHW_HAL_0019 through
                   _0024 (Arch: E. Grayzeck, D. Klinglesith, M. Niedner), International
                   Halley Watch, Goddard Space Flight Center, Greenbelt, MD, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.AHEARN-VANYSEK1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   A&apos;Hearn, M.F., Photometry and Polarimetry Network, The Comet Halley
                   Archive Summary Volume, Ed. Z. Sekanina (Pasadena: JPL), 193-235, 1991.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.AHEARN1991</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   A&apos;Hearn, M.F., R.L. Millis and P.V. Birch, Gas and dust in some recent
                   periodic comets, Astronomical Journal, 84, 570-579, 1979.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.AHEARNETAL1979</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   A&apos;Hearn, M.F., R.L. Millis and P.V. Birch, Comet Bradfield 1979 X - The
                   gassiest comet? Astronomical Journal, 86, 1559-1566, 1981.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.AHEARNETAL1981</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   A&apos;Hearn, M.F., D.G. Schleicher, R.L. Millis, P.D. Feldman and D.T.
                   Thompson, Comet Bowell 1980b. Astronomical Journal, 89, 579-591, 1984.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.AHEARNETAL1984</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   A&apos;Hearn, M.F., R.L. Millis, D.G. Schleicher, D.J. Osip, and P.V. Birch,
                   The Ensemble of Properties of Comets: Results from Narrowband Photometry
                   of 85 Comets, 1976-1992. Icarus, 118, 223-270, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.AHEARNETAL1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Cochran, A.L. and D.G. Schleicher, Observational constraints on the
                   lifetime of cometary H2O. Icarus, 105, No. 1, 235-253, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.COCHRAN-SCHLEIC1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Haser, L., Distribution d&apos;Intensite dans la tete d&apos;une comete, Bull. Acad.
                   R. Belgique, Classes des Sciences, Ser. 5, 43, 740, 1957.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HASER1957</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kim, S.J., M.F. A&apos;Hearn and W.D. Cochran, NH emissions in comets -
                   Flourescence vs collisions, Icarus 77, 98-108, 1989.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KIMETAL1989</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Osborn, W.H., M.F. A&apos;Hearn, U. Carsenty, R.L. Millis, D.G. Schleicher, P.V.
                   Birch, H. Moreno, and A. Gutierrez-Moreno, Standard Stars for Photometry of
                   Comets, Icarus, 88, 288, 1990.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.OSBORNETAL1990</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Osip, D.J., D.G. Schleicher, R.L. Millis, M.F. A&apos;Hearn and P.V. Birch, 15
                   years of comet photometry: A comparative analysis of 80 comets,
                   &apos;Asteroids, Comets, Meteors 1991&apos;, Lunar and Planetary Institute, 443-445,
                   1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.OSIPETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Randall, C.E., D.G. Schleicher, R.G. Ballou, and D.J. Osip, Observational
                   constraints on molecular scalelengths and lifetiems in comets, Bulletin of
                   the Astronomical Society, Vol. 24, No. 3, 1063 [abstract], 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.RANDALLETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Schleicher, D.G., and M.F. A&apos;Hearn, The Fluorescence of Cometary OH.
                   Astrophys. J., 331, 1058, 1988.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SCHLEICHER-AHEA1988</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Schleicher, D.G., The Fluorescence of Cometary OH and CN, PhD Thesis,
                   University of Maryland, 1983.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SCHLEICHER1983</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>EAR-C-PHOT-3-RDR-LOWELL-COMET-DB-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LOWELL OBSERVATORY COMETARY DATABASE</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1998-02-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1976-08-12T06:24:28.800Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1991-10-11T11:15:12.600Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID J. OSIP</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>Unknown</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Narrowband photometry of 85 comets taken by A&apos;Hearn and
            Millis primarily at Lowell Observatory
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The database presented here is comprised entirely of observations
            made utilizing conventional photoelectric photometers and
            narrowband filters isolating 5 emission species (OH, NH, CN, C3
            and C2) and continua. This work was initiated by A&apos;Hearn and
            Millis in 1976 and includes 2020 observations of 85 comets
            obtained over 429 nights through the end of 1992. The total
            number of observations, however, is not evenly distributed over
            the 85 comets. The median number of observations for a comet is
            6, with only a single observation obtained for 14 comets while
            there were 820 observations of P/Halley. The majority of
            observations were obtained at either Lowell Observatory or Perth
            Observatory, however four other observatories were used including
            an extensive campaign on comet P/Halley from the Cerro Tololo
            Interamerican Observatory (CTIO). In this archive, results for a
            subset of 68 comets are presented while the results for P/Halley
            from this study are archived in the IHW archive.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
 
      LOWELL OBSERVATORY COMETARY DATABASE
 
        [ NOTE: These files do NOT comprise the intended complete
                dataset.  Further work is being carried out on 17 of
          the 85 observed comets.  These 17 objects have been omitted
          from this initial submission.  Once that work is completed,
          an updated version of this dataset will be submitted and
          ingested. ]
 
      The database presented here is comprised entirely of observations
      made utilizing conventional photoelectric photometers and narrowband
      filters isolating 5 emission species (OH, NH, CN, C3 and C2) and
      continua.  This work was initiated by A&apos;Hearn and Millis in 1976 and
      includes 2020 observations of 85 comets obtained over 429 nights
      through the end of 1992.  The total number of observations, however,
      is not evenly distributed over the 85 comets.  The median number of
      observations for a comet is 6, with only a single observation
      obtained for 14 comets while there were 820 observations of P/Halley.
      The majority of observations were obtained at either Lowell
      Observatory or Perth Observatory, however four other observatories
      were used including an extensive campaign on comet P/Halley from the
      Cerro Tololo Interamerican Observatory (CTIO). In this archive, results
      for a subset of 68 comets are presented while the results for P/Halley
      from this study are archived in the IHW archive.
 
      One &apos;observation&apos; as defined here represents a set of measurements
      usually through at least 5 narrowband filters.  A typical measurement
      sequence consisted of sets of 3 ten second integrations in each of
      two or three filters on the comet followed by a similar integration
      set on a sky position about 30 arcminutes from the comet.  This would
      alternate from comet to sky and sky to comet until data were
      collected for all appropriate filters.  While this description
      illustrates the observational method, it is important to keep in mind
      that deviations were common.  For example, filter integration times
      of 90 seconds or longer were often employed for faint comets while
      times as short as 10 seconds were used for bright comets at high
      airmasses.  A night of observing would normally include comet
      observation(s) along with standard star measurements in all filters
      extending over a sufficient range of airmass (most often bracketing
      the comet observations) to accurately determine extinction
      coefficients.  A discussion of standard stars and the zero
      point for the magnitude system with respect to the International
      Halley Watch filter set can be found in Osborn, et al. (1990)
      [OSBORNETAL1990]. A full description of these data and the reduction
      process, along with a comparative analysis of the results of Haser
      model production rates can be found in A&apos;Hearn, et al. (1995)
      [AHEARNETAL1995].  Several tables from that paper are included in
      the PDS archives as the &apos;LOWELL OBSERVATORY COMETARY DATABASE -
      PRODUCTION RATES&apos; dataset.
 
      Parameters
      ==========
      All essential parameters including fluxes, aperture sizes, comet
      heliocentric and geocentric positions and heliocentric radial velocity
      are provided in this PDS submission. The fluorescence efficiencies used
      for the column density calculations as well as all additional Haser
      Model parameters can also be found in A&apos;Hearn, et al. (1995)
      [AHEARNETAL1995].
 
      Filters
      =======
      The program began with a set of narrowband filters isolating the
      emission species CN, C3,and C2 as well as three continuum regions at
      392, 412, and 524 nanometers (A&apos;Hearn, et al. 1979 [AHEARNETAL1979]).
      In 1979, filters isolating the emission species OH and NH were added
      along with an additional continuum filter at 367 nanometers (A&apos;Hearn,
      et al. 1981 [AHEARNETAL1981]).  By 1984, the standardized filters of
      the International Halley Watch (IHW) replaced the earlier filters at
      wavelengths greater than 365 nm.  Full details of the IHW filters can
      be found in A&apos;Hearn (1991) [AHEARN1991] and A&apos;Hearn and Vanysek (1992)
      [AHEARN&amp;VANYSEK1992].
 
      Processing
      ==========
      The processing carried out on the Lowell Observatory Cometary
      Database has been described in detail elsewhere (A&apos;Hearn &amp; Millis
      1980 [AHEARN&amp;MILLIS1980]; A&apos;Hearn 1991 [AHEARN1991]; A&apos;Hearn, et
      al. 1995 [AHEARNETAL1995]), a brief explanation follows.
 
      The initial data product consists of Universal Times and object and
      sky measurements.  For pulse-counting systems, count rates were
      measured and corrected to first order for the dead-time of the
      detector using:   n = nobs/[1.0 - nobs*t] where n and nobs are the
      actual and observed counting rates and t is the detector dead-time.
      For direct-current systems, readings from the DC amplifier were
      calibrated using standard voltages.  Actual counts were then
      converted to instrumental magnitudes. The standard stars defined for
      the IHW (Osborn et al. 1990 [OSBORNETAL1990]) were used for extinction
      and absolute calibration to reduce the instrumental magnitudes to
      the standard magnitude system outside the atmosphere. Extinction
      coefficients were evaluated for each night by least squares fitting
      of magnitude vs. airmass for individual standards.  A global least
      squares solution using all standards and simultaneously solving for
      the extinction coefficients and the zero point correction was also
      often employed.  For all but the OH filter, the atmospheric
      attenuation is linear with airmass and in these cases airmass was
      calculated via the standard  cubic polynomial:
 
              X = secZ - 0.0018167*[secZ - 1] - 0.002875*[secZ - 1]^2
                       - 0.0008083*[secZ - 1]^3
 
      where Z is the refracted zenith distance.  In the case of the OH
      filter, the monochromatic attenuation changes appreciably across
      the bandpass.  Therefore, a pseudo-airmass was modeled such that
      the attenuation would be linear in this variable.  A detailed
      description of the modeling procedure can be found in A&apos;Hearn (1991)
      [AHEARN1991] and references therein.
 
      It is straightforward to convert from the standard system magnitudes
      to fluxes per unit wavelength in the continuum by simply applying a
      scale factor depending on the specific wavelength A&apos;Hearn (1991)
      [AHEARN1991].  However, a complication arises when dealing with the
      IHW 4845 angstrom continuum filter A&apos;Hearn, et al. (1995)
      [AHEARNETAL1995].
 
      In order to derive the fluxes in the emission bands, the underlying
      continuum must first be subtracted.  Assuming there is no gross
      structure in the continuum reflectivity of the cometary grains (i.e.,
      they vary linearly with wavelength with respect to solar colors), it
      is possible to use observations of the comet in a pair of continuum
      bandpasses along with solar analog colors to evaluate the continuum
      contribution to an emission band.  In this study we have used two
      pairs of continuum filters; 3650-4845 angstroms for the IHW filter
      set and 3675-5240 angstroms for the earlier data.  After removal of
      the underlying continuum, the emission band fluxes were converted to
      real units (ergs cm-2 s-1) by multiplying by appropriate scale
      factors for each filter A&apos;Hearn, et al. (1995) [AHEARNETAL1995].
 
      Fluxes-Column Abundances of Emission Species
 
      The emission band fluxes were converted to molecular abundances in
      the observed column by means of the fluorescence efficiency (L/N),
      commonly referred to as the g-factor.  The g-factor values used for
      this analysis can be found in A&apos;Hearn, et al (1995) [AHEARNETAL1995].
 
      The fluorescence efficiencies for OH (Schleicher &amp; A&apos;Hearn 1988
      [SCHLEICHER&amp;AHEA1988]) and NH (Kim, et al. 1989 [KIMETAL1989])
      were interpolated from tables as a function of heliocentric radial
      velocity at 1 AU in order to account for the Swings effect.  They
      were then scaled by the standard heliocentric distance (rH)
      dependence of rH^-2.  For CN, a double interpolation in heliocentric
      radial velocity and heliocentric distance was used to account for
      the Swings effect as well as known deviations from the standard
      rH^-2 dependence (Schleicher 1983 [SCHLEICHER1983]).  Again the
      interpolated values were then scaled by rH^-2.  Fluorescence
      efficiencies for C2 and C3 are taken as single values scaled by
      rH^-2.  The Swings effect is not prevalent in these bands due to
      the much larger number of lines involved as even a significant
      effect for an individual line will have basically no effect on
      the band intensities.
 
      Column Abundances - Molecular Production Rates
 
      The column abundances for each species were converted to production
      rates by means of the classic Haser model.  Haser modeling consists
      of two steps.  For a detailed description of the original model the
      reader is referred to Haser (1957) [HASER1957]; the following is a
      brief explanation.
 
      First, two scale-lengths are required to infer the spatial distribution
      in the coma and allow extrapolation from the molecular abundance in a
      given field of view to the entire coma abundance.  Second, the lifetime
      of the observed species is needed in order to calculate a production
      rate.  If the parent species is known (not the case for most of our
      species) and a branching ratio for production of the daughter from the
      parent is also known, the production rate of the parent can likewise be
      determined.  This study is limited to the production rates of the
      observed species, so the branching ratio is set to one.
 
      The scale-lengths used for this reduction are all recently determined
      independently from wide-field CCD images and long-slit spectra
      (Randall, et al. 1992 [RANDALLETAL1992]; Cochran &amp; Schleicher 1993
      [COCHRAN&amp;SCHLEIC1993]).
 
      Continuum Fluxes - Dust Production
 
      As a factor to compare intrinsic dust production from comet to comet,
      we have adopted the parameter A(q)frho, as described by A&apos;Hearn, et
      al. (1984) [AHEARNETAL1984].  The formula is A(q)frho = q*rH^2*D*Fl/a
      where A(q) is the Bond albedo at the observed scattering angle, q; f
      is the filling factor of grains in the field of view; rho is the radius
      of the circular field of view; rH and D are heliocentric and
      geocentric distances (measured in AU); Fl is the mean continuum flux
      averaged over the filter bandpass (in erg cm-2 s-1 A-1); a is the
      angular diameter of the field of view (in arcsec); and q is a filter-
      dependent numerical coefficient that incorporates the solar flux
      within the filter bandpass.
 
      Provided the dust flows away from the nucleus without changing its
      velocity or breaking up and without brightening or darkening, A*f*rho
      will be proportional to the dust production rate.
 
      While the A*f*rho measure of the dust production is rather ad hoc, it
      serves as an adequate means, essentially independent of the aperture
      size, of comparing dust production between comets or for the same
      comet at different times.
 
      Error Propagation
 
      Photometric uncertainties in the raw data were initially determined
      assuming the most common filter integration time of 30 seconds and
      using the rms scatter of the individual 1 second integrations.  All
      uncertainties were expressed as percent errors.
 
      The percentage uncertainties estimated for each filter were then
      propagated through the reduction procedure described in the previous
      sections.  Additional errors in the extinction coefficients, the zero
      point of the photometric system, and the flux transformation
      coefficients were added in quadratically.  An additional source of
      uncertainty, the dominant source for the bright comets, was centering
      error due to the comet&apos;s motion and diffuse nature.  In this study,
      we have quadratically added a centering error of 3 0.000000 for
      measurements of the continuum and C3 and an error of 2 0.000000 for
      all other species.  These values are higher for the continua and C3
      since these species have the most sharply peaked spatial distributions.
 
      The percentage errors for the emission band fluxes were then calculated
      via the following equation:
 
      SigEM = SQRT[P_EM^2.0+
                   ((((W_cont2-W_em)/(W_cont2-W_cont1))^2*P_cont1^2 +
                     ((W_em-W_cont1)/(W_cont2-W_cont1))^2*P_cont2^2)
                     *Cp_em^2)/(100-Cp_em)^2)]
 
      where P_EM, P_cont1, and P_cont2 are the percentage uncertainties in
      the emission band filter and the two respective continuum bands; W_em,
      W_cont1, and W_cont2 are the wavelengths of the emission band and the
      continuum bands and Cp_em is the precentage of underlying continuum in
      the emission band.
 
      The final photometric flux errors provide an adequate representation
      of statistical uncertainties in the data.  These percentage errors in
      the fluxes are representive of the uncertainties in most other derived
      parameters (e.g., column densities and production rates).  In the case
      of gassy comets, these final errors underestimate the uncertainty in
      the C3 and NH filters since they fail to include the additional error
      from contamination of the underlying continuum as previously
      discussed.  There may be additional uncertainties introduced from the
      choice of model parameters (e.g., scale-lengths, lifetimes) that are
      not well understood at this time.  However, since they affect the
      results for all comets the same way (i.e., they will not affect a
      comparative analysis), they are not incorporated.
 
 
      Data
      ====
      Three data files constitute this submission to the PDS:
 
      locdflux.tab  includes the comet ID, the UT date and time, and
                    fluxes for each of the observed species along with
                    the percentage uncertainties in the flux measurements.
 
      locdprod.tab  includes observational circumstances and Haser Model
                    production rates for 68 of the comets included in
                    the A&apos;Hearn et al (1995) [AHEARNETAL1995] analysis.
 
      locdparm.tab  includes comets full names, comet ID, and
                    observational circumstances.
 
 
      Coverage
      ========
 
      Following is a list of the comets included in this data set.
 
                                         Principal
        Number, Type and Name           Designation
        ------------------------------  -----------
         49P/Arend-Rigaux                 1951 C2
         47P/Ashbrook-Jackson             1948 Q1
           C/Austin                       1982 M1
           C/Austin                       1984 N1
           C/Austin                       1989 X1
         85P/Boethin                      1985 T2
         19P/Borrelly                     1904 Y2
           C/Bowell                       1980 E1
           C/Bradfield                    1979 M1
           C/Bradfield                    1979 Y1
           C/Bradfield                    1980 Y1
           C/Bradfield                    1987 P1
         16P/Brooks 2                     1889 N1
         23P/Brorsen-Metcalf              1989 N1
         87P/Bus                          1981 E1
           C/Bus                          1981 H1
           C/Cernis                       1983 O1
           C/Cernis-Petrauskas            1980 O1
        101P/Chernykh                     1977 Q1
         67P/Churyumov-Gerasimenko        1969 R1
        108P/Ciffreo                      1985 V1
         27P/Crommelin                    1928 W1
          6P/d&apos;Arrest                     1851 M1
           C/Elias                        1981 G1
          2P/Encke                        1818 W1
          4P/Faye                         1843 W1
           C/Furuyama                     1987 W2
         78P/Gehrels 2                    1981 L1
         21P/Giacobini-Zinner             1900 Y1
         26P/Grigg-Skjellerup             1922 K1
         65P/Gunn                         1970 U2
          1P/Halley                       1982 U1
           D/Haneda-Campos                1978 R1
        103P/Hartley 2                    1991 N1
           C/Hartley-Good                 1985 R1
           P/Hartley-IRAS                 1983 V1
         45P/Honda-Mrkos-Pajdusakova      1948 X1
         88P/Howell                       1981 Q1
        126P/IRAS                         1983 M1
           C/IRAS                         1983 O2
           C/IRAS-Araki-Alcock            1983 H1
         59P/Kearns-Kwee                  1963 Q1
         68P/Klemola                      1965 U1
           C/Kohler                       1977 R1
         22P/Kopff                        1906 Q1
           C/Levy                         1990 K1
           C/Levy-Rudenko                 1984 V1
           C/Liller                       1988 A1
           C/Machholz                     1985 K1
           C/Meier                        1978 H1
           C/Meier                        1979 S1
           C/Meier                        1980 V1
         97P/Metcalf-Brewington           1991 A1
         28P/Neujmin 1                    1913 R2
           C/Nishikawa-Takamizawa-Tago    1987 B1
           C/Okazaki-Levy-Rudenko         1989 Q1
           C/Panther                      1980 Y2
         94P/Russell 4                    1984 E1
         31P/Schwassmann-Wachmann 2       1929 B1
        102P/Shoemaker 1                  1984 S2
           C/Shoemaker                    1983 R1
           C/Shoemaker                    1984 K1
           C/Shoemaker                    1984 U1
           C/Shoemaker                    1984 U2
           C/Shoemaker-Levy               1991 B1
           C/Shoemaker-Levy               1991 T2
           C/Skorichenko-George           1989 Y1
         74P/Smirnova-Chernykh            1975 E2
           C/Sorrells                     1986 V1
         38P/Stephan-Oterma               1980 L2
           C/Sugano-Saigusa-Fujikawa      1983 J1
        109P/Swift-Tuttle                 1992 S2
         98P/Takamizawa                   1984 O1
         69P/Taylor                       1915 W1
          9P/Tempel 1                     1867 G1
         10P/Tempel 2                     1873 N1
           C/Thiele                       1985 T1
           C/Tsuchiya-Kiuchi              1990 N1
         62P/Tsuchinshan 1                1965 A1
          8P/Tuttle                       1858 A1
         81P/Wild 2                       1978 A2
        116P/Wild 4                       1990 B1
           C/Wilson                       1986 P1
         46P/Wirtanen                     1948 A1
         43P/Wolf-Harrington              1924 Y1
           C/Kohoutek                     1973 E1
           C/West                         1975 A1-A
 
 
 
      Ancillary Data
      ==============
      See the associated Production Rates dataset for tables of the
      Production Rate and Active Areas, Production Rate r(H) Dependencies,
      Assymetry of Production Rates about Perihelion, and Observational
      and Dynamical Parameters from A&apos;Hearn et al. (1995) [AHEARNETAL1995].
 
      Media/Format
      ============
      This dataset is released in the form of ASCII files which may be
      stored on disk or other magnetic medium and which may be
      distributed by ftp, email, real-time access by remote login, or by
      whatever means is most convenient.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      Review
      ======
      The LOCD was reviewed internally by David Osip prior to release to
      the planetary community. The PDS external peer review was held in
      September 1998.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>PSSB-00142</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

