<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mer1-m-rat-2-edr-ops-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MER 1 MARS ROCK ABRASION TOOL EDR OPS VERSION 1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_exploration_rover::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mer1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rat.mer1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer1-m-rat-2-edr-ops-v1.0__browserc_mer1-m-rat-2-edr-ops-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer1-m-rat-2-edr-ops-v1.0__browser_geo_mer1-m-rat-2-edr-ops-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer1-m-rat-2-edr-ops-v1.0__dvo_geo_mer1-m-rat-2-edr-ops-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer1-m-rat-2-edr-ops-v1.0__pds.geo.mer.analysts_notebook::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Gorevan, S.P., The Rock Abrasion Tool Mars Exploration Rover Mission, Journal
                   of Geophysical Research- Planets, 2003.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GOREVANETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mars Exploration Rover Mission, Rock Abrasion Tool Experiment Data Record
                   Software Interface Specification, 2003
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.RATEDRSIS2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MER1-M-RAT-2-EDR-OPS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MER 1 MARS ROCK ABRASION TOOL EDR OPS VERSION 1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2004-08-24</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-01-29T03:39:03.695Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>Kiel Davis</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Gorevan, Stephen, MER 1 Mars Rock Abrasion Tool EDR Ops V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, MER1-M-RAT-2-EDR-OPS-V1.0, 2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains Rock Abrasion Tool (RAT) Operations
            Experiment Data Records (EDRs) acquired by Opportunity (MER 1)
            during the Mars Exploration Rover Mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This archive contains Mars Exploration Rover Operations (Ops)
            Rock Abrasion Tool (RAT) Experiment Data Record (EDR) products
            and ancillary files. The RAT Operations EDR products archived on
            this volume are the original products used during mission
            operations by the Mars Exploration Rover project.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set contains the primary data that is useful for
    investigating the mechanical properties of the varied rock types
    that the rover encountered. During all phases of RAT operations
    (i.e., calibration, seek-scan, grinding, diagnostic or brush
    station), the RAT application software stores sensor values and
    information about the RAT machine state. RAT data products will be
    comprised of time-ordered data records that include motor positions,
    motor currents, contact switch states, temperature sensor values,
    bus voltage, software/algorithm states, error bit fields, etc. Data
    records will be written to the detailed data product at a nominal
    rate of 2-Hz. Anomaly reports will include data stored at 8-Hz.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    This data set uses the Committee On Data Management And
    Computation (CODMAC) data level numbering system.  The MER camera
    Payload EDRs are considered level 2 or Edited Data (equivalent
    to NASA level 0). The data files are generated from level 1 or
    Raw Data which are the telemetry packets within the
    Project-specific Standard Formatted Data Unit (SFDU) record.
 
    RAT EDRs were generated by the MIPL (Multimission Image Processing
    Laboratory) at JPL under the Operation Products Generation Subsystem
    using the telemetry processing software mertelemproc.  The EDRs
    are raw uncalibrated data reconstructed from telemetry data products
    and formatted according to the Camera EDR/RDR Software Interface
    Specification. Meta-data acquired from the telemetry data headers
    and a meta-data database were used to propagate the PDS label.
    There will not be multiple versions of a RAT EDR. If telemetry
    packets are missing during the initial downlink, the missing data
    will be identified and reported for retransmission of the data to
    the ground. The data will be reprocessed after all data is received
    and the original version will be overwritten.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The structure of the RAT EDR consists of an attached ASCII PDS label
    and a binary data file.  It should be noted that an EDR can be
    generated with only the PDS label.  This will occur when only the
    telemetry header and no binary data is received.
 
    A RAT EDR consists of a table of time-ordered current, encoder,
    and temperature measurements for the three RAT motors during a
    single RAT deployment. A RAT EDR covers a maximum time interval of
    6 hours, and has a maximum sampling rate of 8 Hz. Both the sampling
    rate and time interval are commandable. Each RAT EDR is contained in
    a separate file. The file is binary with fixed-length records of 96
    bytes, and with a PDS label in ASCII text attached to the beginning
    of the file. The maximum file size is 7.8 Mbytes.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    RATViewer is a data analysis tool developed by the RAT Team at
    Honeybee Robotics. RATViewer will be used by the Team to generate
    quick-look data products so that RAT health and performance can be
    assessed in real time. RATViewer facilitates instrument health
    analysis by comparing downlinked RAT initialization data to
    calibration data. Both the calibration data and a collection of
    derived data taken from pre-mission experiments and mission
    operations simulations are included in the PDS archive of RAT data
    products.
 
    PDS-labeled images and tables can be viewed with the program
    NASAView, developed by the PDS and available for a variety of
    computer platforms from the PDS web site
    http://pdsproto.jpl.nasa.gov/Distribution/license.html.
    There is no charge for NASAView.
 
    RATViewer software will be included on RAT archive volumes and will
    be available for downloading from PDS web sites that distribute RAT
    data products.
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    The data set will initally be delivered and kept online. Upon
    Mission completion, the Rock Abrasion Tool EDRs will be delivered to
    PDS on DVD as part of the complete MER EDR data set.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
NULL
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

