<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mex-m-aspera3-3-rdr-els-ext2-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MARS EXPRESS ASPERA-3 CAL RDR ELECTRON SPECTROMTR EXT2 V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_express::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mex::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:aspera-3.mex::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:plasma_stream.solar_wind::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mex-m-aspera3-3-rdr-els-ext2-v1.0__browserp_mex-m-aspera3-3-rdr-els-ext2-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Barabash, S., et. al., ASPERA-3: Analyser of Space Plasmas and Energetic Ions
                   for Mars Express, ESA SP-1240, September 2004
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BARABASHETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MEX-M-ASPERA3-3-RDR-ELS-EXT2-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MARS EXPRESS ASPERA-3 CAL RDR ELECTRON SPECTROMTR EXT2 V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2008-12-22</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2007-10-01T00:23:50Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>SANDEE JEFFERS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Lundin, R., S. Barabash, D. Winningham, R. Frahm, MARS EXPRESS
            ASPERA-3 CAL RDR ELECTRON SPECTROMTR EXT2 V1.0,
            MEX-M-ASPERA3-3-RDR-ELS-EXT2-V1.0, ESA Planetary Science Archive
            (PSA), NASA Planetary Data System (PDS), 2005
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains calibrated Mars Express ASPERA-3 Electron
            Spectrometer (ELS) data for the second mission extension (October
            1, 2007 - May 31, 2009). The data are provided in units of
            Differential Number Flux (DNF): cnts/(cm**2-sr-sec-eV)
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains calibrated Mars Express ASPERA-3 Electron
            Spectrometer (ELS) data for the second mission extension (October
            1, 2007 - May 31, 2009). These data are provided in units of
            Differential Number Flux (DNF): cnts/(cm**2-sr-sec-eV)
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Overview:
    =========
 
    The Electron Spectrometer (ELS) provides in situ electron
    measurements in the energy range 0.05 eV to 20 keV to help
    satisfy the following scientific objectives:
 
       1. Determine the instantaneous global distributions of plasma
          and neutral gas near Mars by providing undisturbed solar
          wind parameters
 
       2. Define the local characteristics of the main plasma regions
 
       3. Complement the ENA images
 
    Parameters:
    ===========
 
    All ELS data products have the same format and parameters, and
    each row (data file record) in the ELS SPREADSHEET data products
    has eight (8) COLUMN objects (parameters):
       1. Start Time - Begin Date/Time in UTC of data samples
       2. Stop Time - Ending Date/Time in UTC of data samples
       3. Data Type Name - SENSOR, SCAN, or MODE. The SENSOR rows are
          the ELS science data for each sector (16 sectors). The SCAN
          rows are the deflection voltages (volts) that correspond to
          the SENSOR rows.  There is one SCAN row per 16 SENSOR rows.
          The 16 SENSOR rows are followed by one corresponding SCAN
          row.  The SCAN row indicates the deflection voltage per
          step that corresponds to the previous 16 SENSOR rows for
          each step.  To convert the deflection voltages to center
          energies (eV), use the K_FACTOR per anode in the
          calibration tables:  eV = volt * K_FACTOR. There are 16
          SENSOR rows + 1 SCAN row (17 in all) followed by 23 rows of
          MODE data for the same time period. The MODE rows contain
          informational data such as Time/Step Summations and Sector
          Enable Flags.
       4. Data Type Id - Numeric ID indicating SENSOR, SCAN, or MODE.
       5. Data Name - Short description for data on that row.  For
          example &apos;ELS Sector 0 LR&apos; for ELS sector 0 Low Range
          science data (SENSOR rows for ELSSCIL data products), &apos;ELS
          Sector 0 HR&apos; for ELS sector 0 High Range science data
          (SENSOR rows for ELSSCIH data products), &apos;Deflection
          Potential&apos; for SCAN rows, or &apos;Time Summation&apos; for
          informational data (MODE row).
       6. Data Unit - Indicates the data unit:
            &apos;cnts/(cm**2-sr-sec-eV)&apos; for SENSOR data
            &apos;volt&apos; for SCAN data
            &apos;Unitless&apos; for MODE data
       7. Values - These are the actual data values.  For this column
          there are multiple values as indicated by the ITEMS keyword
          in the label files.  This value will vary from file to
          file, but remains consistent within a data (.CSV) file.
          For the SENSOR rows, these are the science data sampled at
          the corresponding deflection volts indicated in the
          corresponding SCAN row that follows the 16 ELS sector
          (SENSOR rows) data.  The MODE data rows contain only one
          value each and remaining ITEMS are indicated &apos;missing&apos; with
          commas (value,,...,,).  Please note that the data values
          are formatted for a high level of accuracy, and that this
          does not indicate the accuracy of the ELS instrumentation.
       8. Data Quality Value - Quality indicator for the data on that
          row. The data quality value is only applicable for the
          SENSOR data. See CONFIDENCE_LEVEL_NOTE under &apos;Data
          Coverage/Quality&apos; for valid values and descriptions.
 
    Data Products:
    ==============
 
    The Standard Data Products for ELS PSA Level 2 (RDR) products
    are:
 
       1. ELSSCIL_DNF - ELectron Spectrometer SCIence Low range
          data in Differential Number Flux units.
 
       2. ELSSCIH_DNF - ELectron Spectrometer SCIence High range
          data in Differential Number Flux units.
 
       NOTE:  There is not a one-to-one correspondence between the
              ELSSCIL and ELSSCIH data products. Most of the time,
              both products are produced for the same time period.
              However, there are times when only ELSSCIL products are
              produced or only ELSSCIH products are produced, not
              both.
 
    Ancillary Data:
    ===============
 
    It is important for ASPERA-3 science studies to know where in
    space and time the Mars Express spacecraft and ASPERA-3
    instruments are located and what objects (Sun, Mars, Earth,
    Phobos, Deimos) are in the fields of views. The ASPERA-3 view
    directions for each sensor can be derived using the SPICE kernels
    and software. The ASPERA-3 Sensor Frames and Geometry Information
    document (in DOCUMENT directory) provides a code example (in C
    and FORTRAN) for determining the view directions for the ASPERA-3
    sensors.
 
    Coordinate System:
    ==================
 
    The ASPERA-3 data are always in the instrument reference frame
    since data are sampled in situ. The GEOMETRY table contains
    spacecraft related parameters expressed in the J2000 reference
    frame, and the ASPERA-3 Sensor Frames and Geometry Information
    document (in DOCUMENT directory) provides information for
    determining the ASPERA-3 sensors view directions and transforming
    to the J2000 reference frame.
 
    References:
    ===========
 
    Refer to the ASPERA-3 Experiment to Archive Interface Control
    Document (EAICD) found in the DOCUMENT directory
    (MEX_ASPERA3_PSA_ICD_V01_03) for more information and detail
    concerning data set formulation and contents.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Review:
    =======
 
    These data have been reviewed by the instrument team and are of
    the highest quality that can be generated at this time. Science
    results based on these data have been published in several
    journals (Science, Nature, EGU, etc.). After submission to the
    PDS, these data successfully completed the peer review process.
 
    Data Coverage/Quality:
    ======================
 
    The data quality indicators in the data files for each sensor are
    associated with the data returned in telemetry.  Valid values
    are:
 
       0 - Good Data: Default because assumption is that data
                      are good unless determined otherwise.
 
       1 - Questionable Data: +30V monitor value is not within
                              tolerance
 
       2 - Invalid Data: +12V, -12V, +5V, or -5V monitor value is not
                         within tolerance or high voltage is not
                         enabled
 
       3 - Bad Data: +30V monitor value and (+12V, -12V, +5V, or -5V
                     monitor value) are not within tolerance
 
       4 - Unknown State: Time related Main Unit housekeeping packet
                          is not available.
 
      -1 - Data Unavailable:  No data returned for the sensor, so a
                              fill value is used for data quality.
 
    Limitations:
    ============
 
       There are no known limitations at this time.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

