<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mgs-m-tes-3-tsdr-v2.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MGS M THERMAL EMISSION SPECTROMETER 3 TSDR V2.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_global_surveyor::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mgs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:tes.mgs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-tes-3-tsdr-v2.0__browserp_geo_mgs-m-tes-3-tsdr-v2.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-tes-3-tsdr-v2.0__dvo_geo_mgs-m-tes-3-tsdr-v2.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgs-m-tes-3-tsdr-v2.0__pds.asu.tes_web_site::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Christensen, P.R., Mars Global Surveyor Thermal Emission Spectrometer Data
                   Processing User&apos;s Guide, version 1.02, February 1999.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CHRISTENSEN1999</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MGS-M-TES-3-TSDR-V2.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MGS M THERMAL EMISSION SPECTROMETER 3 TSDR V2.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2002-01-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1998-04-02T10:04:56Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>PHILIP R. CHRISTENSEN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Christensen, P. R., MGS M THERMAL EMISSION SPECTROMETER 3 TSDR
            V2.0, MGS-M-TES-3-TSDR-V2.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2002
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The MGS-TES Time Sequential Data Record (TES-TSDR) archive (V2.0)
            contains raw and calibrated spectral radiance data, visual and
            thermal bolometric radiance measurements, and several atmospheric
            and surface properties derived from these data.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The TES-TSDR data product contains the raw and calibrated thermal
            IR radiance spectra, the visual and thermal bolometric radiance
            measurements, and several atmospheric and surface properties
            derived from this data. Also included are the parameters that
            describe each observations, some downlinked diagnostic
            information, and the pointing and positional information derived
            from the project&apos;s SPICE kernels.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The TES-TSDR data product contains the raw and calibrated
    thermal IR radiance spectra, the visual and thermal bolometric
    radiance measurements, and several atmospheric and surface
    properties derived from this data.  Also included are the
    parameters that describe each observations, some downlinked
    diagnostic information, and the pointing and positional
    information derived from the project&apos;s SPICE kernels.
 
    The TES data is divided into 10 tables (OBS, RAD, BOL, GEO,
    POS, TLM, IFG, CMP, ATM, LMB).  Each table is stored in a
    separate file as a PDS TABLE structure, using fixed-length
    binary records, with extensions to handle the variable length
    spectra.  Every record is stored with the spacecraft time, and
    related records can be retrieved from each table using time as
    a common key.  In some tables, up to 6 records can be stored
    for a given time, one for each detector.  In these cases the
    records also include a field named &apos;detector&apos;, which with the
    time field, uniquely identifies the record.
 
    The data products on this volume may be reprocessed at the end
    of the mission.
 
 
  Modification History
  ====================
    Version 1 data volumes include MGST_0001 through MGST_0226, released
    between June 1999 and October 2001.  These volumes contain TES data
    collected August 1997 through March 2001.
 
    The version 2 data set release began January 2002;  version 2
    supersedes version 1.  The version 2 release is necessitated by
    several improvements that the TES Team has made to the version 1
    data set throughout the mapping phase of the MGS mission.  The most
    significant of these improvements include:
 
       MGST_0100 (Oct 1999) - classification and quality fields added
                              to the OBS and RAD tables;
 
       MGST_0162 (Oct 2000) - thermal inertia fields added to the BOL
                              and RAD tables;
 
       MGST_0188 (Apr 2001) - ATM table replaces SRF table and is
                              filled with atmospheric products;
 
       MGST_0213 (Oct 2001) - geometry and position fields are calculated
                              using new calibration software (V003a).
 
    Since previously released volumes were not re-released with each
    improvement, incompatability problems developed between data volumes
    released at different times.  The version 2 data release incorporates
    all of the above changes and is a uniform collection of all available
    TES mapping data.
 
 
   Data
   ====
    Each table is stored in a PDS TABLE structure using
    fixed-length binary records sorted time-sequentially.  Each
    table file is prefixed with an ASCII header that describes the
    contents and format of the table, and a pointer that indicates
    where the binary table data starts.  The description identifies
    each column in the table, detailing its name, starting position
    (in bytes), size (in bytes), data type, description and scaling
    factors if applicable.  In some cases the column being
    described is a fixed-length array of related, homogeneous
    values, in which case the column description also includes the
    number of items in the array, and the size of each item.
 
    Four tables (RAD, ATM, CMP, IFG) store variable length data.
    These variable length records are stored in a file separate
    from the fixed length records, and are addressed from the
    fixed-length records with a pointer column.  Pointer columns
    contain the position of the variable length data, in bytes,
    from the start of the file it is in.
 
    Fixed-length records are stored in files with a .DAT extension.
    The variable length records that are referenced by an
    individual .DAT file are found in a file with the same name,
    but with a .VAR extension.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    Mars areocentric, west positive;  Mars body constants obtained
    from the IAU-1994 report
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The TES project has produced a software tool that not only
    reads the PDS table and variable length records, but is also
    capable of joining the related records among multiple tables.
    This piece of software is called &apos;vanilla&apos;, and is provided
    on this cd.
    &apos;Vanilla&apos; is also available via anonymous ftp from
    ftp://east.la.asu.edu/pub/software/vanilla/vanilla.tar.Z.  The
    vanilla program works on UNIX machines with integers in
    MSB_INTEGER format and on PC platforms.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
   CD-ROM
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Please refer to the MGS Thermal Emission Spectrometer Data
    Processing User&apos;s Guide (CHRISTENSEN1999), which is included
    in this data set archive.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>96-062A-02B</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

