<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-e-v-h-sw-epps-3-eps-ddr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER E/V/H/SW EPPS CALIBRATED EPS DDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:epps.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-sw-epps-3-eps-ddr-v1.0__browserp_mess-e-v-h-sw-epps-3-eps-ddr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Andrews, G.B., T.H. Zurbuchen, B.H. Mauk, H. Malcom, L.A. Fisk, G. Gloeckler,
                   G.C. Ho, J.S. Kelley, P.L. Koehn, T.W. LeFevere, S.S. Livi, R.A. Lundgren, and
                   J.M. Raines, The Energetic Particle and Plasma Spectrometer instrument on the
                   MESSENGER spacecraft, Space Science Reviews, 131, 523-556, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ANDREWSETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-E/V/H/SW-EPPS-3-EPS-DDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESSENGER E/V/H/SW EPPS CALIBRATED EPS DDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-05-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-257T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-120T15:08:14Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>GEORGE HO</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            George C. Ho
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The MESSENGER EPPS DDR observations consist of energetic particle
            and plasma data collected by the EPPS instrument during orbital
            operations of Mercury.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== This data set consists of the MESSENGER
            Energetic Particle and Plasma Spectrometer (EPPS) advanced data
            products, also known as DDR/DAPs. The system encompasses 2
            instrument subsystems - the Energetic Particle Spectrometer (EPS)
            and the Fast Imaging Plasma Spectrometer (FIPS). This data set
            contains EPS instrument data. EPS covers the energy range of 25
            to &gt; 500 keV for electrons, and 10 keV/nucleon to ~3 MeV total
            energy for ions. There is one DDR data product for EPS
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The data set consists of advanced data products, also known as
      DDR/DAPs.
 
      For all the DDR products there is a detached PDS label file that
      describes the contents of one data file. Each label file will have
      the same base name as the data file it is describing, with the
      extension .LBL to denote a label file. The label file defines the
      start time and end of the observation, product creation time, and
      the structure of the ASCII tables. Each data product is identified
      within the PDS label by a STANDARD_DATA_PRODUCT_ID value, shown in
      parentheses in the table below.
 
      The EPS portion of the data archive consists of
      two DDR data products which are tables of pitch-angle values and
      pitch-angle distribution function spectrograms provided as browse
      plots for selected energetic electron events based on the selection
      criteria outlined in Ho et al. (2012, JGR) during the Mercury Orbit
      phase.
 
      The pitch angle spectrogram browse products were a one-time delivery
      included in release 9.The pitch angle value table DDRs are included
      in both releases 9 and 11. The pitch angle value tables in release 11
      include the entire EPS data set covering the Mercury Orbit Year 2.
 
      These products are summarized in the data table below. A more
      complete description of each product may be found in the EPPS DDR SIS
      document, located in the DOCUMENT directory of the document volume.
 
 
    Instrument Overview
    ===================
      The EPS sensor consists of a 60-mm diameter, tuna-can-like
      cylinder, in which a start foil and stop foil, wrapped around
      opposite curved sides of the cylinder, constitute the TOF chamber.
      The detectors are arranged so that each detector senses the
      events within a given range of incidence angles. Each of the 6
      detector modules is composed of 4 pixels: large and small ion and
      large and small electron.
 
      See the EPPSINST.CAT file for more information and
      [ANDREWSETAL2007] for full details.
 
 
    Calibration Overview
    ====================
      This data set is normalized and background subtracted.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
   The accumulation times for each event are 120 seconds for the EPS
   Pitch Angle Spectrogram. Calibration
   parameters are described in the Calibration Implementation document.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      EPS Pitch Angle table (EPSP_A)
 
      The pitch angle values tables contain the pitch angle for each of
      the six look directions reported at the same cadence as the EPS
      LoRes Spectral rate measurements (see EPPS CDR document). Each file
      thus has a one-to-one relationship with a corresponding LoRes
      spectral file.
 
 
      EPS Pitch Angle Spectrogram (EPS_PAS)
 
      Contains the pitch angle spectrogram for the EPS odd shaped
      channels (ion=1,5,7,9). A given pitch angle spectrogram DDR data
      file contains all the observations obtained on
      one electron event.   The particle measurement is 120 seconds
      averaged.  0 denotes the same direction as the measured magnetic
      field, and 180 is opposite to the local field.  The color scale is
      normalized to the maximum flux for the time interval covered in the
      plot.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      The EPPS DDR data are the processed data set released for the
      EPPS.  Data presented here are an accurate representation of the EPPS
      data as received from the spacecraft and have been processed from
      instrument unit to physical unit.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      The EPPS DDR was reviewed internally by the EPPS team prior to
      release to the PDS. PDS also performed an external review of the
      EPPS CDR.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Data reported are the processed data received from the
      spacecraft during the sixteen mission phases: Launch,
      Earth Cruise, Earth Flyby, Venus 1 Cruise, Venus 1 Flyby,
      Venus 2 Cruise, Venus 2 Flyby, Mercury 1 Cruise, Mercury 1 Flyby,
      Mercury 2 Cruise, Mercury 2 Flyby, Mercury 3 Cruise,
      Mercury 3 Flyby, Mercury 4 Cruise, Mercury Orbit, Mercury Orbit
      Year 2, Mercury Orbit Year 3, Mercury Orbit Year 4, and Mercury
      Orbit Year 5.  These mission phases are defined as:
 
                           Start time         End time
      Phase Name           Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)
      -----------------    ----------------  ----------------
      Launch                3 Aug 2004 (216)  12 Sep 2004 (256)
      Earth Cruise         13 Sep 2004 (257)  18 Jul 2005 (199)
      Earth Flyby          19 Jul 2005 (200)  16 Aug 2005 (228)
      Venus 1 Cruise       17 Aug 2005 (229)   9 Oct 2006 (282)
      Venus 1 Flyby        10 Oct 2006 (283)   7 Nov 2006 (311)
      Venus 2 Cruise        8 Nov 2006 (312)  22 May 2007 (142)
      Venus 2 Flyby        23 May 2007 (143)  20 Jun 2007 (171)
      Mercury 1 Cruise     21 Jun 2007 (172)  30 Dec 2007 (364)
      Mercury 1 Flyby      31 Dec 2007 (365)  28 Jan 2008 (028)
      Mercury 2 Cruise     29 Jan 2008 (029)  21 Sep 2008 (265)
      Mercury 2 Flyby      22 Sep 2008 (266)  20 Oct 2008 (294)
      Mercury 3 Cruise     21 Oct 2008 (295)  15 Sep 2009 (258)
      Mercury 3 Flyby      16 Sep 2009 (259)  14 Oct 2009 (287)
      Mercury 4 Cruise     15 Oct 2009 (288)  03 Mar 2011 (062)
      Mercury Orbit        04 Mar 2011 (063)  17 Mar 2012 (077)
      Mercury Orbit Year 2 18 Mar 2012 (078)  17 Mar 2013 (076)
      Mercury Orbit Year 3 18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)
      Mercury Orbit Year 4 18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)
      Mercury Orbit Year 5 18 Mar 2015 (077)  30 Apr 2015 (120)
 
 
      The EPS pitch angle distribution data have been corrected for
      priority scheme in the instrument processor.
 
      During orbital phase, a certain sector in the EPS field-of-view has a
      direct view of the sunlit side of the planet. During these periods, the
      single event data (Fast, Scanned, etc) may be susceptible to photon
      contamination. The science event data (all rate and spectra data) have
      additional on-board software processing that should eliminate this
      photon contamination.  But the user should always consult with the
      instrument team at JHU/APL to verify the quality of specific data prior
      to publication.
 
      During spacecraft noon-midnight orbits, EPS instrument temperature can
      rise to levels that affect the low energy channels.  We have noticed
      during some of these orbits, the temperature induced noise renders
      those energy channels below 100 keV to be useless.  In addition, the
      higher than normal temperature also induced a data &apos;drop-out&apos; where the
      count in all rate drops by a factor during one integration period and
      remains so for a few minutes to hours.  The EPS team is currently
      investigating the cause of this &apos;drop-out&apos;.  Users should always
      consult the instrument team at JHU/APL to verify the quality of
      specific data prior to publication.
 
      During orbital phase, EPS routinely switches between large and small
      pixel on both the ion and electron detector.  User should check the
      pixel size flag in the data to know which pixel the detectors are
      using.
 
      EPS Shaped channel Sector 3 and 11 have malfunction detectors and do
      not produce any data product.
 
      As always, users of the EPPS data should consult with the instrument
      team at JHU/APL to verify the quality of specific data prior to
      publication.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      This data set is fully processed, science quality data.  It has been
      reviewed at high level by the EPS instrument team.  It has not been,
      however, manually validated on a point by point.  Users are
      encouraged to contact the EPS instrument team when questions about
      the data arise.  Some analysis of this data requires detailed
      knowledge of EPS pointing which can be extracted from SPICE.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

