<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mer1-mer2-m-pancam-5-atmos-opacity-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MER MARS PANCAM ATMOSPHERIC OPACITY RDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_exploration_rover::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mer1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mer2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:pancam.mer1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:pancam.mer2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer1-mer2-m-pancam-5-atmos-opacity-v1.0__dvo_geo_mer1-mer2-m-pancam-5-atmos-opacity-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer1-mer2-m-pancam-5-atmos-opacity-v1.0__pds.geo.mer.analysts_notebook::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Bell, J.F. III, The Mars Exploration Rover Athena Panoramic Camera (Pancam)
                   Investigation, Journal of Geophysical Research, June 23, 2003.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BELLETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mars Exploration Rover Mission, Panoramic Camera Atmospheric Opacity
                   Software Interface Specification, 2003
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.OPACITYSIS2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MER1/MER2-M-PANCAM-5-ATMOS-OPACITY-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MER MARS PANCAM ATMOSPHERIC OPACITY RDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2004-08-24</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-01-25T07:18:28.780Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>Mark Lemmon</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Lemmon, Mark, MER Mars Pancam Atmospheric Opacity RDR V1.0, NASA
            Planetary Data System, MER1/MER2-M-PANCAM-5-ATMOS-OPACITY-V1.0,
            2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Mars Exploration Rover Pancam Atmospheric Opacity Reduced Data
            Record
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>not applicable</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    A Mars atmospheric opacity data product consists of two files, an
    ASCII formatted detached PDS label file and an ASCII formatted data
    file. The data file contains values of the Mars atmospheric opacity
    or optical depth derived from MER Pancam images of the Sun acquired
    with the two solar filters.  The effective wavelengths of these
    filters are 440 and 880 nm. Each data file contains an ASCII table
    of the derived atmospheric opacity for a given rover and Pancam
    solar filter. Each table contains columns with the source Pancam
    image identifier, the time of image acquisition, the Mars season
    (Ls), Sun-Mars distance, airmass, observed solar flux, and opacity.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    MER Pancam Atmospheric Opacity RDRs are considered Level 5 or
    Derived Data (equivalent to NASA Level 2). The Mars atmospheric
    opacity data products are generated from analysis of MER Pancam
    images.
 
    The Mars atmospheric opacity data products are produced by the
    Atmospheres Science Theme Group (STG) of the MER Science Operations
    Working Group (SOWG) using processing procedures and software
    developed by Mark Lemmon, Texas A&amp;M University.
 
    The data product is generated after each sol in which opacity data
    is acquired. The generation is done in four steps. First, the input
    parameters are set up. A list of Pancam data products to be
    processed is read and associated values are determined for Ls, the
    distance of Mars from the Sun, the sol that the data were acquired,
    and the actual elevation angle of the Sun. It is likely that
    standard tools such as the NAIF toolkit will be used for these
    computations. For each Pancam data product, the airmass is computed
    by integration through a spherically symmetric atmosphere with a
    scale height equivalent to the gas scale height of the Martian
    atmosphere.
 
    Second, the solar flux is extracted from each calibrated Pancam
    data product. To do this, the background is determined within an
    annulus at a fixed radius from the center of the Sun in the image.
    That background is subtracted, as it would lead to a significant
    departure from Beers&apos; Law at high airmasses. After background
    subtraction, the solar flux is integrated over the image. The
    presence of a few missing pixels (e.g., a Phobos transit or a
    missing packet that only partly overlaps the Sun) can be
    accommodated by the integration algorithm. The presence of a large
    number of missing pixels or any saturated pixels will result in the
    rejection of an image (returning a flux and opacity of -1.000).
 
    Third, a relative calibration is derived. Data from the afternoon of
    all sols during which more than 1 image was acquired are considered,
    together with instrumental uncertainties. The published calibration
    is considered as a single datum with associated uncertainty. The
    instrument response is varied, and a single best-fit opacity is
    derived for each afternoon using Beers&apos; Law (I_observed = I_0 exp
    (-t h), where h = airmass). A best-fitting responsivity is
    chosen by minimizing the reduced C^2 of the fit.
 
    Fourth, the relative calibration is used to derive opacities. All
    images are considered, and Beers&apos; Law is applied to every pair of
    I_observed and airmass. The relative calibration method ensures that
    (1) substantial calibration uncertainty is not propagated into
    uncertainty in opacity once sufficient surface data are obtained,
    and (2) that the processing transfers smoothly from using the
    laboratory calibration when the first datasets are obtained to using
    the relative calibration when enough surface data exist.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    Each Mars atmospheric opacity data product is structured as two
    files; a detached PDS label file and a separate data file. Both
    components are stored as ASCII text. Data within the opacity data
    file is organized by time with the most recent measurement being
    appended to the end of the file.
 
    Each Mars atmospheric opacity data product consists of two parts.
    The first part of the data file contains header information, which
    includes parameter values used in the opacity computations and
    column names for the data rows. The second part of the file,
    starting at line 10 consists of a PDS table object. The table has
    eight columns and a variable number of rows. There is one row for
    each opacity measurement. The number of rows in a data product will
    increase as new measurements of atmospheric opacity are made. Each
    row is 88 bytes long including the carriage return and line feed
    characters. All columns are fixed-width as described in the PDS
    label and are also delimited with commas. Text columns are
    surrounded by double-quotes and are left-justified. Numeric
    columns are right-justified.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The ASCII format of the Mars atmospheric opacity data product means
    that the data can be displayed using a text editor. In addition, the
    use of the PDS table structure for this data product means the data
    can be readily imported into spreadsheet and plotting programs.
 
    PDS-labeled tables can be viewed with the program NASAView,
    developed by the PDS. NASAView is available in versions that run on
    SUN/SOLARIS, Windows, and LINUX operating systems. NASAView can be
    obtained from the PDS web site
    http://pdsproto.jpl.nasa.gov/Distribution/License.
    There is no charge for NASAView.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    The data set will initally be delivered and kept online. Upon
    Mission completion, the Pancam Atmospheric Opacity RDRs will be
    delivered to PDS on DVD.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
NULL
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

