<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mpfl-m-asimet-4-ddr-edl-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MPFL MARS ATM STRUCT INST AND MET PKG DERIVED EDL V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_pathfinder::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mpfl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:asimet.mpfl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mpfl-m-asimet-4-ddr-edl-v1.0__browserp_mpfl-m-asimet-4-ddr-edl-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mpfl-m-asimet-4-ddr-edl-v1.0__dvo_atmos_mpfl-m-asimet-4-ddr-edl-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BOUGHERETAL1990</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BRAUNETAL1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Folkner, W.M., C.F. Yoder, D.N. Yuan, E.M. Standish, and R.A. Preston, Interior
                   Structure and Seasonal Mass Redistribution of Mars from Radio Tracking of Mars
                   Pathfinder, Science, 278, 1749-1752, 1997
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FOLKNERETAL1997B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HUBBARD1984</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KALLEMEYNETAL1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Magalhaes, J.A., J.T. Schofield and A. Seiff, Results of the Mars Pathfinder
                   atmospheric structure investigation. Journal of Geophysical Research, 104,
                   8943-8956, 1999.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MAGALHAESETAL1999</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NIER-MCELROY1977</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.OWEN-BIEMANN1976</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Schofield, J.T., J.R. Barnes, D. Crisp, R.M. Haberle, J.A. Magalhaes, J.R.
                   Murphy, A. Seiff, S. Larsen, and G. Wilson, The Mars Pathfinder Atmospheric
                   Structure Investigation/Meteorology (ASI/MET) Experiment, Science, 278,
                   1752-1758, 1997.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SCHOFIELDETAL1997</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SEIFF-KIRK1977</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SEIFFETAL1973</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Seiff, A., J.E. Tillman, J.R. Murphy, J.T. Schofield, D. Crisp, J.R.
                   Barnes, C.KaBaw, C. Mahoney, J.D. Mihalov, G.R. Wilson, and R. Haberle, The
                   Atmosphere Structure and Meteorology Instrument on the Mars Pathfinder
                   Lander, J. Geophys. Res., 102, 4045-4056, 1997.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SEIFFETAL1997</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Smith, D.E., F.J. Lerch, R.S. Nerem, M.T. Zuber, G.B. Patel, S.K. Fricke, and
                   F.G. Lemoine, An Improved Gravity Model for Mars: Goddard Mars Model 1, Journal
                   of Geophysical Research, 98, 20871-20889, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SMITHETAL1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MPFL-M-ASIMET-4-DDR-EDL-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MPFL MARS ATM STRUCT INST AND MET PKG DERIVED EDL V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1998-09-04</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1997-07-04T16:51:46.440Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1997-07-04T16:54:41.378Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JULIO A. MAGALHAES</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            MPFL MARS ATM STRUCT INST AND MET PKG DERIVED EDL V1.0
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Mars Pathfinder bounced down and rolled to a stop on the surface
            of Mars on July 4, 1997. It landed in an ancient floodplain in
            the Ares Vallis region of Chryse Planitia at 19.1 degrees North
            Areocentric latitude, and 326.48 degrees East longitude.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    Mars Pathfinder bounced down and rolled to a stop on the surface
    of Mars on July 4, 1997.  It landed in an ancient floodplain in
    the Ares Vallis region of Chryse Planitia at 19.1 degrees North
    Areocentric latitude, and 326.48 degrees East longitude.
 
    As the spacecraft traveled through the atmosphere to its landing
    site, the Atmospheric Structure Investigation/Meteorology package
    (ASIMET) measured aerodynamic accelerations on the lander
    throughout the entry using onboard accelerometers.  In addition,
    sensors directly measured pressures and temperatures during the
    parachute descent phase, which began at about 8.5 km above the
    landing site.  This data set contains the profiles of atmospheric
    density, pressure, and temperature derived from the accelerations
    measured prior to parachute release.
 
    A first description of the ASIMET results can be found in
    [SCHOFIELDETAL1997].  The ASI experiment is described in the same
    reference.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    All of the data in this data set are contained in an ASCII
    tabular file, (&apos;EDL_DDR.TAB&apos;) with a detached PDS label
    (&apos;EDL_DDR.LBL&apos;).
 
    The tabular file is formatted so that it may be read directly
    into many database management systems (DBMS) or spreadsheet
    programs on various computers.  All fields in the table are
    separated by commas, and are right justified.  The &apos;start byte&apos;
    and &apos;bytes&apos; values listed in the PDS label do not include the
    commas between fields.  The records are of fixed length, and the
    last two bytes of each record contain the ASCII carriage return
    and line feed characters.  This allows the table to be treated as
    a fixed length record file on computers that support this file
    type and as a normal text file on other computers.
 
    The PDS label is object-oriented.  The object to which the label
    refers (the TABLE) is denoted by a statement of the form:
 
        ^object = location
 
    in which the carat character (&apos;^&apos;, also called a pointer in this
    context) indicates that the object starts at the given location.
    For an object located outside the label file (as in this case),
    the location denotes the name of the file containing the object.
    For example:
 
        ^TABLE = &apos;EDL_DDR.TAB&apos;
 
    indicates that the TABLE object is in the file EDL_DDR.TAB, in
    the same directory as the detached label file.
 
    The detached label file is a stream format file, with a carriage
    return (ASCII 13) and a line feed character (ASCII 10) at the end
    of each record.  This allows the file to be read by the MacOS,
    DOS, UNIX, and VMS operating systems.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The first column in the data table contains the Spacecraft Clock
    Start Count (SCLK) at the time the data sample was acquired.  The
    SCLK is formatted as decimal fractions of a second.
 
    The second column shows the elapsed time, in seconds, since the
    spacecraft passed the altitude of 3,597.2 km.  The first data
    point in the file is at time = 34.156 seconds, with a
    corresponding SCLK of 1246726312.75.  At that time, the
    equivalent UTC time was 16:51:46.440, July 4, 1997.
 
    The third column shows the altitude of the spacecraft above the
    landing site, in kilometers.  Note that the radius of Mars at the
    landing site is 3389.72 km [FOLKNERETAL1997B].
 
    Column four shows the planetocentric latitude, in degrees, of the
    spacecraft at the time the sample was acquired.
 
    The fifth column contains the east longitude, in degrees, of the
    spacecraft.
 
    The sixth column contains the calculated atmospheric density, in
    kilograms per meter cubed.
 
    The seventh column contains the calculated atmospheric pressure,
    in millibars.
 
    The eighth column contains the calculated atmospheric
    temperature, in Kelvin.
 
    Column nine contains the mean molecular weights (amu) that were
    used to evaluate the atmospheric temperatures.  These mean
    molecular weights were derived from molecular weight as a
    function of pressure measured by the Viking 1 Upper Atmosphere
    Mass Spectrometer [SEIFF&amp;KIRK1977].
 
    The tenth column shows the width of the uncertainty envelope in
    the positive direction, of the atmospheric density.  It is
    measured in kilograms per meter cubed.  The value in the sixth
    column plus the value in this column gives the upper boundary of
    the density uncertainty envelope.
 
    The eleventh column shows the width of the uncertainty envelope
    in the negative direction, of the atmospheric density.  It is
    measured in kilograms per meter cubed.  The value in the sixth
    column plus the value in this column gives the lower boundary of
    the density uncertainty envelope.
 
    The twelfth column shows the width of the uncertainty envelope in
    the positive direction, of the atmospheric pressure.  It is
    measured in millibars.  The value in the seventh column plus the
    value in this column gives the upper boundary of the pressure
    uncertainty envelope.
 
    The thirteenth column shows the width of the uncertainty envelope
    in the negative direction, of the atmospheric pressure.  It is
    measured in millibars.  The value in the seventh column plus the
    value in this column gives the lower boundary of the pressure
    uncertainty envelope.
 
    The fourteenth column shows the width of the uncertainty envelope
    in the positive direction, of the atmospheric temperature.  It is
    measured in Kelvin.  The value in the eighth column plus the
    value in this column gives the upper boundary of the temperature
    uncertainty envelope.
 
    The fifteenth column shows the width of the uncertainty envelope
    in the negative direction, of the atmospheric temperature.  It is
    measured in Kelvin.  The value in the eighth column plus the
    value in this column gives the lower boundary of the temperature
    uncertainty envelope.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    Measured accelerations from the three science accelerometers on
    the Mars Pathfinder lander have been processed to reconstruct the
    trajectory and profiles of atmospheric density, pressure, and
    temperature.  The measured accelerations used as input for the
    reconstruction can be found in the
    &apos;MPFL-M-ASIMET-2/3-EDR/RDR-EDL-V1.0&apos; data set.
 
    A full description of the data and the procedure used to generate
    the atmospheric structure profiles on this CD can be found in
    [MAGALHAESETAL1999].  The procedure for the reconstruction of
    planetary atmospheric structure from accelerometer data was first
    described by [SEIFFETAL1973], and a more detailed description of
    the procedure appeared in [SEIFF&amp;KIRK1977].  The analysis of the
    Mars Pathfinder ASI data has utilized the same basic
    deterministic approach, but the analysis algorithm and software
    were independently developed to refine and extend the atmospheric
    structure reconstruction procedure used previously.  The
    reconstruction procedure used to derive the profiles in this file
    can be divided into four general steps.  First, the trajectory of
    the lander was reconstructed using the measured accelerations, a
    model for the gravity field of the planet, the equations of
    motion of the lander, and an initial condition provided by the
    Navigation Team.  Second, the atmospheric density profile was
    derived from the measured aerodynamic decelerations and the
    aerodynamic characteristics of the Pathfinder lander.  Third, an
    atmospheric pressure profile was derived by integrating the
    equation of hydrostatic equilibrium using the density profile.
    Fourth, an atmospheric temperature profile was derived from the
    ideal gas law using the density profile, pressure profile, and a
    model for the variation of mean molecular weight with pressure.
 
    With knowledge of the external forces acting on the spacecraft,
    the velocity and position of the probe were determined by
    integrating the equations of motion starting with an initial
    condition provided by the Navigation Team.  The equations of
    motion written in a planet-centered spherical coordinate system
    rotating with the planet were used for the computations.  The
    acceleration due to gravity was not directly measured by the
    accelerometers during passage through the atmosphere.  To include
    the effects of gravity, we have used a gravity model that
    includes the first zonal harmonic coefficient J2 in the
    normalized spherical harmonic expansion of the gravity field (cf.
    [HUBBARD1984]).  For Mars J2 = 8.759 x 10**-4 [SMITHETAL1993].
    Higher order harmonics are of much smaller magnitude
    [SMITHETAL1993] and are not important over the short time
    interval of EDL.  The aerodynamic drag on the vehicle was
    directly obtained from the three-axis science accelerometer
    measurements.  Due to the small angle of attack alpha (= angle
    between the symmetry axis of the entry vehicle and the direction
    of the relative velocity vector) during the Pathfinder entry (cf.
    [BRAUNETAL1995]) and due to the close proximity of the z-axis
    accelerometer to the axis of symmetry, the measured z-axis
    accelerations during entry were very close (generally within
    0.02%) to the true deceleration along the flight path.
 
    Initial conditions for the integration were provided by the Mars
    Pathfinder Navigation Team in the form of an entry velocity and
    entry location at a prescribed time.  This so-called &apos;entry
    state&apos; is based on observations of range and rate of motion along
    the line-of-sight derived from radiometric tracking of the
    spacecraft combined with trajectory solutions based on high-order
    models of the gravitational forces on the vehicle from solar
    system bodies (cf. [KALLEMEYNETAL1996]).  The &apos;entry state&apos; for
    4-July-1997 16:51:12.28 UTC with 1-sigma uncertainties listed is
    r = 3597.2 +/- 1.7 km, theta = 23 +/- 0.04 degrees N Areocentric
    latitude, phi = 343.67 +/- 0.01 degrees East Longitude, VR =
    7444.7 +/- 0.7 m/s, gamma = 16.85 +/- 0.02 degrees, psi = 255.41
    +/- 0.02 degrees.  r is the radial distance from the center of
    mass of the planet.  VR is the entry speed, gamma is the flight
    path angle below horizontal, and psi is the flight path azimuth
    measured clockwise from North (all in a Mars-fixed, ie rotating,
    coordinate system).  This initial state was marched forward in
    time using a fourth and fifth order Runge-Kutta-Fehlberg
    integrator with automatic step-size control.
 
    Atmospheric density rho is related to the aerodynamic
    deceleration of a spacecraft through the aerodynamic drag
    equation:
 
                                 -2m      Av
                         rho =  -----   ------                 (1)
                                C_D A   V_R**2
 
    where Av is the acceleration along the flight path relative to
    the atmosphere, V_R is the probe velocity relative to the
    atmosphere, m is the probe mass, C_D is the drag coefficient of
    the probe, and A is the probe&apos;s cross-sectional area.  The drag
    coefficient C_D varies during the entry, and this variation can
    be accounted for iteratively using aerodynamic databases compiled
    from pre-flight experiments and numerical simulations, as
    discussed further below.  V_R was set equal to the velocity
    relative to the surface of the planet (V), which was derived from
    the trajectory reconstruction, since the Pathfinder lander&apos;s
    velocity was very much greater than expected wind magnitudes
    during the time interval covered by this file.  During the entry
    phase, the total mass of the Mars Pathfinder entry vehicle was m
    = 585.3 kg and it&apos;s area was A = 5.526 m**2.  During the
    parachute descent phase, the total mass was initially decreased
    by the mortar firing (0.5 kg) and later by the separation of the
    heatshield (74 kg).  The total area of the parachute was
    approximately 121 m**2.
 
    The aerodynamic drag coefficient C_D of the lander is needed in
    order to evaluate atmospheric densities from the observed
    decelerations and the reconstructed trajectory, as shown in eq.
    1.  The aerodynamic properties of the Mars Pathfinder entry
    vehicle were determined from experimental data and computational
    fluid dynamic simulations, and these data have been used to
    create an aerodynamic database [BRAUNETAL1995].  C_D varies
    during the entry and depends on the velocity of the vehicle, the
    angle of attack alpha, the Knudsen number (Kn), and Mach number
    (Mach).  Since Kn depends on the atmospheric density and Mach
    depends on the atmospheric temperature, an iterative procedure
    was required to accurately determine the atmospheric density and
    aerodynamic coefficients.  Initial density, pressure, and
    temperature profiles were evaluated by assuming a constant value
    of C_D.  From these profiles, Kn and Mach as a function of time
    were determined and used to evaluate improved values of C_D from
    the aerodynamic database.  The resulting new density, pressure,
    and temperature profiles were then used as a basis for the next
    iteration.  This procedure was continued until successive
    iterations yielded minor change in the atmospheric structure.
    Two iterations beyond the initial profiles were found to yield
    excellent convergence.
 
    Atmospheric pressure (p) was derived from the density by
    integrating the equation of hydrostatic equilibrium from an
    initial altitude z0 down to each value of altitude z.  z0 = 140
    km was used since at this altitude the density measurements are
    well above the instrument&apos;s threshold value, which is determined
    by the digital resolution.  The initial value p(z0) for the
    integration is estimated by using rho(z0) and d[rho]/dz at z0 to
    derive a density scale height and hence temperature, which can be
    used with the ideal gas law and an estimate of the mean molecular
    weight to derive a starting pressure.  The temperature profile
    was derived from the density and pressure profiles by using the
    ideal gas law and a model for the variation with pressure of the
    mean molecular weight.
 
    We have assumed that the atmosphere is well mixed below ~100 km
    altitude with a mean molecular weight of 43.49, which is based on
    Viking Lander mass spectrometer measurements [OWEN&amp;BIEMANN1976].
    At higher altitudes photodissociation and diffusive separation
    lead to a gradient with altitude of the mean molecular weight.
    We have created a model for the variation of molecular weight
    with pressure based on the Viking 1 Upper Atmosphere Mass
    Spectrometer results [NIER&amp;MCELROY1977, SEIFF&amp;KIRK1977].  The
    mean molecular weights in column 9 are derived from this model.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The MET RDR table can be displayed on UNIX, Macintosh, and PC
    platforms as a simple ASCII file, or using the PDS developed
    program, NASAView.  This software is freely available from the
    PDS Central Node and may be obtained from their web site at
    http://pds.nasa.gov/.  For more information or help in
    obtaining the software, contact the PDS operator at the following
    address:
 
    Address:     Planetary Data System, PDS Operator
                 Jet Propulsion Laboratory
                 4800 Oak Grove Drive
                 Pasadena, CA 91109
 
    Phone:       (818) 354-4321
    Email:       pds_operator@jpl.nasa.gov
    WWW URL:     http://pds.nasa.gov/
 
 
  Media / Format
  ==============
    The ASI/MET EDL derived data will be stored and distributed on
    compact disc-read only memory (CD-ROM) media.  The CD will be
    formatted according to ISO-9660 and PDS standards.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    Uncertainty envelopes based on the 3-sigma uncertainties in the
    entry velocity and the effects of digitization are included in
    columns 10-15.  The uncertainty envelopes have been
    conservatively chosen.  The effects of uncertainties in C_D can
    be estimated from the iteration procedure for the entry profiles
    (described in the &apos;Processing&apos; section).  We found the
    uncertainties in the profiles introduced by C_D are well within
    the uncertainty envelopes we have included in the file.
 
    The temperatures have been evaluated using a molecular weight
    model based on the Viking 1 Upper Atmosphere Mass Spectrometer
    results [NIER&amp;MCELROY1977, SEIFF&amp;KIRK1977], as discussed above.
    Although the season, landing site coordinates, and solar cycle
    phase were very similar for the Pathfinder and Viking 1 landings,
    the Local Solar Time of the two landings were quite different.
    The NCAR Mars Thermospheric General Circulation (MTGCM) models of
    the upper atmosphere (cf.  [BOUGHERETAL1990]) indicate that
    substantial diurnal variation in the molecular weight profile can
    occur (Bougher, personal communication).  To estimate the
    uncertainties in the temperatures due to possible diurnal
    variations in the molecular weights, we have evaluated
    temperatures using molecular weight profiles from the MTGCM
    (Bougher, personal communication) runs for local times around the
    Pathfinder landing.  To the extent that the MTGCM and Viking 1
    profiles bound the possible range of molecular weights, the
    uncertainty ranges from ~4 Kelvin near 140 km altitude down to
    zero at altitudes near and below 100 km.  Note that these
    uncertainties are much smaller than the error envelopes included
    in the file.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    The contents of this CD have been peer reviewed by the following
    people:
 
    Lyle Huber        - PDS Atmospheres Node, New Mexico State University
    Julio Magalhaes   - MPF ASI/MET Team, NASA Ames Research Center
    Jim Murphy        - MPF ASI/MET Team &amp; PDS Atmospheres Node, New
                        Mexico State University
    Tim Schofield     - MPF ASI/MET Team Lead, Jet Propulsion Laboratory
    Rob Sullivan      - MPF Participating Scientist, Cornell University
    Betty Sword       - PDS Central Node Data Engineer, Jet Propulsion
                        Laboratory
    John Wilson       - Non-MPF scientist, Geophysical Fluid Dynamics
                        Laboratory/NOAA, Princeton University
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    The calibration and quality of the accelerometer data has been
    checked in several ways.  Measurements by the accelerometers were
    acquired during the cruise phase and known accelerations were
    compared to the accelerometer readings.  At the surface of Mars,
    surface acceleration measurements of 3.716 m/s**2 agreed well
    with the value of 3.717 m/s**2 calculated for the lander location
    and height (cf. [FOLKNERETAL1997B]).  The observed deceleration
    profiles during atmospheric entry were also compared to entry
    simulations.  Finally, the landing site position computed from
    our trajectory reconstruction was compared to the accurate
    determination of landing site location based on measurement of
    the radio signal from the lander on the surface as reported in
    [FOLKNERETAL1997B].
 
    After accelerometer gain state changes, very brief transients
    were produced in the accelerometer data as expected based on
    tests of the accelerometers and associated electronics prior to
    launch.  The extent of these transients were defined by careful
    inspection of the data near the time of the gain change and by
    extrapolating data acquired immediately prior to the gain change
    to define the end of the transient.  The time constant for the
    transients was far less than one second.  Inspection of the data
    using the procedure mentioned above showed that the effects of
    the transients were generally undetectable within about 1 second
    of the gain change.  The values in the transient were then
    replaced by interpolation between the values acquired before the
    gain change and the values acquired about 1 second after the gain
    change.  Since the rise and fall of the peak deceleration pulse
    due to the atmosphere varies approximately exponentially with
    time, extrapolation and interpolation through the transients was
    performed using the logarithm of the accelerations for gain
    changes occurring during the deceleration pulse.
 
    Only two data values were missing from the accelerometer
    measurements; one z-axis measurement (at SCLK 1246726322.53) and
    one x-axis measurement (at SCLK 1246726361.41).  These two points
    were replaced by using linear interpolation across the adjacent
    points.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    Refinements for the effects of the small variations in the angle
    of attack have not yet been incorporated.  This correction should
    only affect the smallest amplitude (less than or similar to a few
    Kelvin) structures.  Improvements in the calibration of the
    spacecraft clock indicate about a 1.5 second shift in the UTC
    corresponding to the first data point of the file.  Hence, at
    time T0 (SCLK 1246725418.00000) the UTC time was
    1997-07-04T16:36:50.172Z.  This shift has not been incorporated
    in the profiles presented here and should have only a small
    effect (few degrees Kelvin).  Further work to incorporate these
    refinements is in progress.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

