<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.vo1-vo2-m-mawd-4-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>VO1/VO2 MARS ATMOSPHERIC WATER DETECTOR 4 V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.viking::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vo1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vo2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mawd.vo1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mawd.vo2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vo1-vo2-m-mawd-4-v1.0__browserp_vo1_vo2-m-mawd-4-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vo1-vo2-m-mawd-4-v1.0__dvo_atmos_vo1-vo2-m-mawd-4-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Davies, D.W., The Vertical Distribution of Mars Water
                   Vapor, Journal of Geophysical Research, 84, 2875-2879,
                   1979.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DAVIES_1979</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Farmer, C.B., D.W. Davies, P.E. Doms, A.L. Holland,
                   and D.D. Laporte, Mars: Water Vapor Observations From
                   the Viking Orbiters, Journal of Geophysical Research,
                   82, 4225-4248, 1977.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FARMER_ETAL_1977</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Jakosky, B.M., M.R. Lapointe, and R.W. Zurek,
                   The Observed Day-to-Day Variability of Mars Atmospheric
                   Water Vapor, Icarus, 73, 80-90, 1988.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JAKOSKY_ETAL_1988</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Jakosky, B.M., and C.B. Farmer, The Seasonal and
                   Global Behavior of Water Vapor in the Mars
                   Atmosphere: Complete Global Results of the Viking
                   Atmospheric Water Detector Experiment, Journal of
                   Geophysical Research, 87, 2999-3019, 1982.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JAKOSKY_FARMER_1982</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>VO1/VO2-M-MAWD-4-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>VO1/VO2 MARS ATMOSPHERIC WATER DETECTOR 4 V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1989-11-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1976-06-22</start_time>
        <stop_time>1980-07-30</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>C.B. FARMER</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            VO1/VO2 MARS ATMOSPHERIC WATER DETECTOR DATA&quot;
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set consists of the raster-averaged radiant intensities
            and associated data parameters produced from data acquired by the
            Mars Atmospheric Water Detectors (MAWD) onboard the Viking
            Orbiters. The basic observations give temporal coverage spanning
            just over two martian years and variable, but extensive, spatial
            coverage of the planet. MAWD was a five-channel grating
            spectrometer measuring solar radiation reflected from the surface
            and atmosphere of Mars in and out of water vapor bands in the 1.4
            micrometer spectral interval. The data set described here
            contains the solar reflected radiant intensities (i.e.,
            radiances) measured by MAWD, derived water vapor column
            abundances, a derived &apos;1.4-micrometer brightness&apos;, and
            ancillary data (e.g., viewing geometry, surface elevation and air
            mass). Column water vapor abundances were derived by comparing
            the reflected radiant intensities in three water vapor absorption
            bands to radiant intensities in the two interspersed continua
            observed air mass and then normalized by the air mass to obtain a
            vertical column abundance. A basic description of the instrument,
            its observational modes and its derived data products is given in
            [FARMER_ETAL_1977]. A description of the global and seasonal
            variation of water vapor on Mars, based on the complete MAWD
            observational record, is given in [JAKOSKY_FARMER_1982]. This
            data set was generated from the raster-level data base
            constructed during the Viking Mission on the original data
            processing system (IRPS: Infrared Processing System) by the MAWD
            Science Team, led by C. B. Farmer, JPL. Together with the
            instantaneous field of view (IFOV) radiances and geometry, the
            raster-level radiances, associated water column abundances and
            ancillary data have been archived at the NSSDC (NSSDC id
            75-075A-03A, 75-083A-03A). Data from the final phase of the VO-1
            mission were added, supervised by R. Zurek, JPL. Eventually, the
            data set was restructured, additional quality flags were
            introduced, and a second estimate of the water vapor column
            abundance (WFAPT, termed COLUMN_H2O_A in the data set) was added
            [by R. Zurek, JPL [JAKOSKY_ETAL_1988].]. The data base was
            restructured, while preserving key unique parameters, into a
            consistent format with the Viking Orbiter Infrared Thermal Mapper
            (IRTM) data [R. Mehlman, R. Zurek]. Both the MAWD and IRTM data
            sets were then accessible with the XXFUNC package. Further
            quality checking of the MAWD data was carried out by B. Jakosky,
            U. Colorado.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      This data set consists of the raster-averaged radiant
      intensities and associated data parameters produced from data
      acquired by the Mars Atmospheric Water Detectors (MAWD) onboard
      the Viking Orbiters.  The basic observations give temporal
      coverage spanning just over two martian years and variable, but
      extensive, spatial coverage of the planet.  MAWD was a
      five-channel grating spectrometer measuring solar radiation
      reflected from the surface and atmosphere of Mars in and out of
      water vapor bands in the 1.4 micrometer spectral interval.  The
      data set described here contains the solar reflected radiant
      intensities (i.e., radiances) measured by MAWD, derived water
      vapor column abundances, a derived &apos;1.4-micrometer brightness&apos;,
      and ancillary data (e.g., viewing geometry, surface elevation
      and air mass).  Column water vapor abundances were derived by
      comparing the reflected radiant intensities in three water
      vapor absorption bands to radiant intensities in the two
      interspersed continua; the calculation was done for the
      observed air mass and then normalized by the air mass to obtain
      a vertical column abundance.  A basic description of the
      instrument, its observational modes and its derived data
      products is given in [FARMER_ETAL_1977].  A description of the
      global and seasonal variation of water vapor on Mars, based on
      the complete MAWD observational record, is given in
      [JAKOSKY_FARMER_1982].  This data set was generated from the
      raster-level data base constructed during the Viking Mission on
      the original data processing system (IRPS: Infrared Processing
      System) by the MAWD Science Team, led by C. B.  Farmer, JPL.
      Together with the instantaneous field of view (IFOV) radiances
      and geometry, the raster-level radiances, associated water
      column abundances and ancillary data have been archived at the
      NSSDC (NSSDC id 75-075A-03A, 75-083A-03A).  Data from the final
      phase of the VO-1 mission were added, supervised by R.  Zurek,
      JPL.  Eventually, the data set was restructured, additional
      quality flags were introduced, and a second estimate of the
      water vapor column abundance (WFAPT, termed COLUMN_H2O_A in the
      data set) was added [by R.  Zurek, JPL; see
      [JAKOSKY_ETAL_1988].].  The data base was restructured, while
      preserving key unique parameters, into a consistent format with
      the Viking Orbiter Infrared Thermal Mapper (IRTM) data [R.
      Mehlman, R. Zurek].  Both the MAWD and IRTM data sets were then
      accessible with the XXFUNC package.  Further quality checking
      of the MAWD data was carried out by B.  Jakosky, U. Colorado.
 
      The data set contains the following fields (listed as the field
      name followed by a description):
 
      SC_ID
         Spacecraft id
 
      ORBIT_NO
         Orbit number
 
      SEQUENCE_NO
         Numeric order of a given sequence within an orbit
 
      SEQUENCE_ID
         Sequence identifier
 
      SEQ_TITLE
         Sequence title
 
      IRKS_IN_SEQ
         Number of irks in the sequence
 
      FDS_AT_START
         The count on the spacecraft internal (Flight Data
         System) clock at the start of the sequence
 
      IRK
         Raster number within the sequence (represents a
         4.48 second interval).
 
      SOL_DIST_PER
         Solar distance at spacecraft periapsis
 
      SOL_LON_PER
         Areocentric solar longitude at spacecraft periapsis
 
      SOL_CLAT_PER
         Areocentric solar colatitude at spacecraft periapsis
 
      LATITUDE
         Projected latitude of the center of the raster
         footprint on the planet
 
      LONGITUDE
         Projected longitude of the center of the raster
         footprint on the planet
 
      SLANT_RANGE
         Slant distance between the spacecraft and the center
         of the raster footprint on the planet
 
      INCID_ANGLE
         Incidence angle at the center of the raster footprint
         on the planet
 
      EMISS_ANGLE
         Emission angle at the center of the raster footprint
         on the planet
 
      PHASE_ANGLE
         Phase angle at the center of the raster footprint
         on the planet
 
      MARTIAN_DAY
         Martian day, referenced to 0 degrees longitude at
         midnight, with day 1 beginning at Viking Orbiter 1 orbit
         insertion.  Day is incremented by 1 when the
         observations cross local midnight.
 
      LOCAL_TIME
         Local time of day (1/24 of a martian day) at the center
         of the raster footprint on the planet
 
      RADIANCE_1
         Radiance, channel 1 (7223.13 cm**-1)
 
      RADIANCE_2
         Radiance, channel 2 (7224.50 cm**-1)
 
      RADIANCE_3
         Radiance, channel 3 (7232.20 cm**-1)
 
      RADIANCE_4
         Radiance, channel 4 (7238.50 cm**-1)
 
      RADIANCE_5
         Radiance, channel 5 (7242.74 cm**-1)
 
      BRIGHTNESS
         The 1.4 micrometer brightness, range and incidence angle
         corrected, defined as:
 
         B=0.5 * (R2 + R4) * (DSM/1.5237)**2 / COS(I),  where:
 
               B = 1.4 micrometer brightness
               R2 = channel 2 radiance
               R4 = channel 4 radiance
               DSM = Mars-Sun distance (AU)
               COS(I) = cosine of the incidence angle at the
                    center of the raster footprint
 
      SURFACE_ELEV
         Surface elevation at the center of the raster footprint
         (derived from the 1976 USGS topographic maps)
 
      COLUMN_H2O_A
         The column water abundance computed using seasonally
         and topographically varying surface pressure and a
         Curtis-Godson pressure set to 1/2 the surface pressure
 
      COLUMN_H2O_B
         The column water abundance computed using constant
         effective pressure and temperature
 
      AIR_MASS
         The air mass through which the observation was obtained
 
      MISSING_IFOV
         Count of the number of instantaneous fields of view
         missing from the raster
 
      QUALITY
         The quality of geometry and calibration.  For general
         use, constraining QUALITY &lt;= 5 is recommended.
               1 - Good data, as processed
               2 - Lat/lon corrected by interpolation;  surface
                    elevation recomputed
               3 - Surface elevation recomputed using database
                    lat/lon
               5 - Lat/lon updated with some uncertainty;  still
                    thought to be useful
               6 - Lat/lon updated, but estimates are
                    questionable
               7 - Out-of-bounds (upper or lower) water amounts,
                    set arbitrarily to 150.1 pm in original
                    processing
               9 to 13 - Various geometry problems: incorrect
                    lat, lon, emission, or incidence
               18 - Rasters with bad radiances or many data
                    defects
 
 
      Processing Level Id     : 4
      Software Flag           : Y
      Processing Start Time   : 1976
      Processing Stop Time    : 1981
      Native Start Time       : 415147628
                                (FLIGHT DATA SYSTEM CLOCK CNT)
      Native Stop Time        : 964563436
                                (FLIGHT DATA SYSTEM CLOCK CNT)
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;BRIGHTNESS TEMPERATURE&apos;
      -------------------------------------------
        The kinetic temperature of an ideal blackbody which, if
        observed with the spectral response of the instrument
        spectral channel in question would yield the observed
        radiance.
 
        Data Set Parameter Name        : BRIGHTNESS TEMPERATURE
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : KELVIN
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 1.12
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : 1.12
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : N/A
        Noise Level                    : N/A
 
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;DERIVATIVE OF MODEL WITH ALBEDO&apos;
      ----------------------------------------------------
        The differential dependence of model temperature upon the
        assumed surface bolometric bond albedo, at the nominal value
        of model thermal inertia.
 
        Data Set Parameter Name        : DERIVATIVE OF MODEL WITH
                                         ALBEDO
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : DEGREES
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : N/A
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : N/A
        Noise Level                    : N/A
 
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;DERIVATIVE OF MODEL WITH INERTIA&apos;
      -----------------------------------------------------
        The differential dependence of model temperature upon the
        assumed surface thermal inertia, at the nominal value of
        model bolometric bond albedo.
 
        Data Set Parameter Name        : DERIVATIVE OF MODEL WITH
                                         INERTIA
        Data Set Parameter Unit        :
               KELVIN / (10**(-3)*CAL*CM**(-2)*S**(-1/2)*K**(-1))
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : N/A
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : N/A
        Noise Level                    : N/A
 
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;LAMBERT ALBEDO&apos;
      -----------------------------------
        The reflectance of a grey Lambert (ideal diffuse) smooth
        surface parallel to the target body geoid which would yield
        the observed reflected radiation in the absence of any
        atmosphere.
 
        Data Set Parameter Name        : LAMBERT ALBEDO
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 1.12
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : 1.12
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : N/A
        Noise Level                    : N/A
 
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;MINNAERT ALBEDO&apos;
      ------------------------------------
        Albedo computed presuming a Minnaert behavior, with the
        Minnaert exponent k equal to 0.95.  A_m = Visual_Brightness *
        cos(incidence angle)**-k * cos(emission angle)**(1.-k).
 
        Data Set Parameter Name        : MINNAERT ALBEDO
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 1.12
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : 1.12
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : 1.12
        Noise Level                    : N/A
 
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;MODEL TEMPERATURE&apos;
      --------------------------------------
        The surface kinetic temperature calculated using a nominal
        set of parametric values for a smooth planet of uniform
        physical properties and for the latitude, time of day, and
        season of the observation.  The model used for the Viking
        IRTM is described in the appendix of [KIEFFER_ETAL_1977].
 
        Data Set Parameter Name        : MODEL TEMPERATURE
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : KELVIN
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : N/A
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : N/A
        Noise Level                    : N/A
 
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;PHASE CORRECTED ALBEDO&apos;
      -------------------------------------------
        Albedo computed using a phase dependence derived from IRTM
        observations (See [KIEFFER_ETAL_1977]).  A_g = A_l *
        (1.+0.000146*exp(0.075*phase_angle&lt;degrees&gt;) where A_l =
        Visual_brightness / cos(incidence angle)
 
        Data Set Parameter Name        : PHASE CORRECTED ALBEDO
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 1.12
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : 1.12
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : N/A
        Noise Level                    : N/A
 
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;SINGLE POINT THERMAL INERTIA&apos;
      -------------------------------------------------
        The thermal inertia which would yield the observed brightness
        temperature, based on the observed Lambert albedo, the model
        temperature and partial derivatives of model temperature with
        albedo and inertia, and an approximation of the non-linear
        dependence of model temperatures with respect to thermal
        inertia.  If the observation was at night, so that no measure
        of albedo was made, the albedo is assumed to be the same as
        in the nominal thermal model.
 
        Data Set Parameter Name        : SINGLE POINT THERMAL INERTIA
        Data Set Parameter Unit        :
                              10**(-3)*CAL*CM**(-2)*S**(-1/2)*K**(-1)
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : N/A
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : N/A
        Noise Level                    : N/A
 
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;VISUAL BRIGHTNESS&apos;
      --------------------------------------
        The radiant energy measured in the IRTM solar band (0.3-3.0
        microns), normalized to that expected for an ideal Lambert
        reflector observed under normal incidence at the current
        heliocentric range of the target body.
 
        Data Set Parameter Name        : VISUAL BRIGHTNESS
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : WATT/(METER*METER)/STERADIAN
        Sampling Parameter Name        : TIME
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : SECOND
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 1.12
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : 1.12
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : N/A
        Noise Level                    : N/A
 
 
    Source Instrument Parameters
    ============================
      Instrument Host ID              : VO1
      Data Set Parameter Name         : RADIANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 1
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : RADIANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 1
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO1
      Data Set Parameter Name         : RADIANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 2
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : RADIANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 2
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO1
      Data Set Parameter Name         : RADIANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 3
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : RADIANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 3
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO1
      Data Set Parameter Name         : RADIANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 4
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : RADIANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 4
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO1
      Data Set Parameter Name         : RADIANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 5
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : RADIANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 5
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO1
      Data Set Parameter Name         : 1.4 MICROMETER BRIGHTNESS
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 2
      Important Instrument Parameters : 2
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : 1.4 MICROMETER BRIGHTNESS
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 2
      Important Instrument Parameters : 2
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO1
      Data Set Parameter Name         : 1.4 MICROMETER BRIGHTNESS
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 4
      Important Instrument Parameters : 2
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : 1.4 MICROMETER BRIGHTNESS
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 4
      Important Instrument Parameters : 2
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO1
      Data Set Parameter Name         : COLUMN WATER ABUNDANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 1
      Important Instrument Parameters : 5
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : COLUMN WATER ABUNDANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 1
      Important Instrument Parameters : 5
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO1
      Data Set Parameter Name         : COLUMN WATER ABUNDANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 2
      Important Instrument Parameters : 5
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : COLUMN WATER ABUNDANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 2
      Important Instrument Parameters : 5
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO1
      Data Set Parameter Name         : COLUMN WATER ABUNDANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 3
      Important Instrument Parameters : 5
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : COLUMN WATER ABUNDANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 3
      Important Instrument Parameters : 5
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO1
      Data Set Parameter Name         : COLUMN WATER ABUNDANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 4
      Important Instrument Parameters : 5
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : COLUMN WATER ABUNDANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 4
      Important Instrument Parameters : 5
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO1
      Data Set Parameter Name         : COLUMN WATER ABUNDANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 5
      Important Instrument Parameters : 5
 
      Instrument Host ID              : VO2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : COLUMN WATER ABUNDANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE CHANNEL 5
      Important Instrument Parameters : 5
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      Processing History
      ------------------
        Source Data Set ID          : IFOV LEVEL MAWD DATA
        Software                    : FAPT: H2O VAPOR PROD ALGORITHM
        Product Data Set ID         : VO1/VO2-M-MAWD-4-V1.0
 
        Source Data Set ID          : IFOV LEVEL MAWD DATA
        Software                    : IRPS: INFRARED PROCESSING SYS
        Product Data Set ID         : VO1/VO2-M-MAWD-4-V1.0
 
 
      Software &apos;FAPT&apos;
      ---------------
        Source Data Set ID          : IFOV LEVEL MAWD DATA
        Software Name               : FAPT: H2O VAPOR PROD ALGORITHM
        Product Data Set ID         : VO1/VO2-M-MAWD-4-V1.0
        Software Type               : N/A
        Software Release Date       : N/A
        Node ID                     : N/A
        Cognizant Engineer          : N/A
        Software Access Description : N/A
 
 
      Software &apos;IRPS&apos;
      ---------------
        Source Data Set ID          : IFOV LEVEL MAWD DATA
        Software Name               : IRPS: INFRARED PROCESSING SYS
        Product Data Set ID         : VO1/VO2-M-MAWD-4-V1.0
        Software Name               : N/A
        Software Type               : N/A
        Software Release Date       : N/A
        Node ID                     : N/A
        Cognizant Engineer          : N/A
        Software Access Description : N/A
 
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      When taking data, MAWD acquired 15 successive instantaneous
      fields-of-view (IFOVs) every 4.48 seconds.  Because of low
      signal-to-noise for any given IFOV, the 15 IFOV-level radiances
      were averaged to produce a &apos;raster-level&apos; radiance associated
      with a roughly equi-dimensional &apos;footprint&apos;, which was the sum
      of the 15 IFOVs.  Together with the IFOV radiances and
      geometry, the raster-level radiances, associated water column
      abundances and ancillary data have been archived at the NSSDC
      (NSSDC id 75-075A-03A, 75-083A-03A).  The present data set
      differs from the NSSDC data in three ways: 1) Only the
      raster-level data, with their higher signal-to-noise values,
      are used; 2) more detailed quality flags have been assigned;
      and 3) a second calculation of the vertical column water
      abundance (WFAPT, termed COLUMN_H2O_A in the data set) has been
      added.  Unlike the original calculation (WAPT, termed
      COLUMN_H2O_B in the data set), which assumed a constant
      pressure for spectral-line formation and absorption, WFAPT uses
      the end-of-mission water vapor software production algorithm
      (FAPT) and a Curtis-Godson pressure set to 1/2 the surface
      pressure, as computed based on the observed seasonal trend of
      surface pressure at Viking Lander 1 and scaled by the surface
      elevation of the center of the raster-level footprint.  A
      standardized estimate of the formal error associated with WFAPT
      was made, and if this exceeded 100%, WFAPT was set to WFAPT=0.
      The formal error for the original (fixed pressure) water
      abundance estimate (WAPT) is stored on the data base.  The
      formal error takes into account the number of missing IFOVs
      when constructing the raster-level averages.  When dust is
      suspended in the atmosphere or clouds are in the field-of-view,
      the water column abundances derived here will underestimate the
      true water column abundance (see [DAVIES_1979]).  The effects
      of hazes can be minimized for most periods by using only those
      rasters whose air mass &lt; 5 or equivalent restrictions on the
      incidence and emission angles for the observation.  See
      [JAKOSKY_ETAL_1988] for further details.
 
      Initially in the mission, orbit updates were done daily; later
      on, they were done only once per week.  Therefore, the precise
      position of the spacecraft could not be determined accurately
      at all times.  Uncertainty in the spacecraft location in turn
      leads to uncertainty in the latitude and longitude, and hence
      derived geometry parameters, of each MAWD observation included
      in this data set.  The user should be aware of possible
      discrepancies in the position and geometry data contained in
      the data set.
 
      The data set contains the following fields related to
      confidence level (listed as the field name followed by a
      description.
 
      MISSING_IFOV
         Count of the number of instantaneous fields of view
         missing from the raster
 
      QUALITY
         The quality of geometry and calibration.  For general
         use, constraining QUALITY &lt;= 5 is recommended.
               1 - Good data, as processed
               2 - Lat/lon corrected by interpolation;  surface
                    elevation recomputed
               3 - Surface elevation recomputed using database
                    lat/lon
               5 - Lat/lon updated with some uncertainty;  still
                    thought to be useful
               6 - Lat/lon updated, but estimates are
                    questionable
               7 - Out-of-bounds (upper or lower) water amounts,
                    set arbitrarily to 150.1 pm in original
                    processing
               9 to 13 - Various geometry problems: incorrect
                    lat, lon, emission, or incidence
               18 - Rasters with bad radiances or many data
                    defects
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>MAG TAPE</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>75-075A-03C</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>MAG TAPE</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>75-083A-03B</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

