<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.pvo-v-oetp-5-loreselectrons-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>PVO VENUS ELECT TEMP PROBE DERVD ELECT DENS LOW RES VER 1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.pioneer_venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.pvo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:oetp.pvo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.pvo-v-oetp-5-loreselectrons-v1.0__browserp_pvo-v-oetp-5-loreselectrons-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Alexander, C.J., C.T. Russell, &apos;Solar Cycle Dependence of the Location of
                   the Venus Bow Shock, Geophys. Res. Lett., 12, 369, 1985.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ALEXANDERETAL1985</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Brace, L.H., W.T. Kasprzak, H.A. Taylor, Jr., R.F. Theis, C.T. Russell, A.
                   Barnes, J.D. Mihalov, and D.M. Hunten, &apos;The Ionotail of Venus: Its
                   Configuration and Evidence for Ion Escape, J. Geophys. Res., 92, 15, 1987.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BRACEETAL1987</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Brace, L.H., W.R. Hoegy, and R.F. Theis, &apos;Solar EUV Measurements at Venus
                   Based on Photoelectron Emission from the Pioneer Venus Langmuir Probe&apos;, J.
                   Geophys. Res., 93, 7282, 1988.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BRACEETAL1988</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Brace, L.H., R.F. Theis, and J.D. Mihalov, &apos;The Response of the Venus
                   Nightside Ionosphere and Ionotail to Solar EUV and Solar Wind Dynamic
                   Pressure&apos;, J. Geophys. Res., 95, 4075, 1990.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BRACEETAL1990</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Elphic, R.C., L.H. Brace, R.F. Theis, and C.T. Russell, &apos;Venus Dayside
                   Ionosphere Conditions: Effects of Magnetic Field and Solar EUV Flux&apos;,
                   Geophys. Res. Lett., 11, 124, 1984.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ELPHICETAL1984</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Krehbiel, J.P., L.H. Brace, J.R. Cutler, W.H. Pinkus, and R.B. Kaplan,
                   &apos;Pioneer Venus Orbiter Electron Temperature Probe&apos;, IEEE Transactions on
                   Geoscience and Remote Sensing, GE-18, 49, 1980.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KREHBIELETAL1980</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mahajan, K.K, W.T. Kasprzak, L.H. Brace, H.B. Niemann, and W.R. Hoegy,
                   Response of the Venus Exospheric Temperature Measured by Neutral Mass
                   Spectrometer to the Solar EUV Measured by Langmuir Probe on the Pioneer
                   Venus Orbiter, J. Geophys. Res., 95, 1091, 1990.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MAHAJANETAL1990</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Russell, C.T., E. Chou, J.G. Luhmann, P. Gazis, L.H. Brace,
                   and W.R. Hoegy, &apos;Solar and interplanetary control of the
                   location of the Venus bow shock&apos;, J. of Geophys. Res,
                   Vol. 93, No. A6, p. 5461, 1988.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.RUSSELLETAL1988</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Theis, R.F., L.H. Brace, K.H. Schatten, C.T. Russell, J.A. Slavin, J.A.
                   Wolf, &apos;The Venus Ionosphere as an Obstacle to the Solar Wind&apos;, Advances in
                   Space Research, 1, 47, 1980.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.THEISETAL1980</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Theis, R.F., L.H. Brace, R.C. Elphic, and H.G. Mayr, &apos;New Empirical Models
                   of the Electron Temperature and Density of the Venus Ionosphere, with
                   Applications to Transterminator Flow&apos;, J. Geophys. Res., 89, 1477, 1984.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.THEISETAL1984</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>PVO-V-OETP-5-LORESELECTRONS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>PVO VENUS ELECT TEMP PROBE DERVD ELECT DENS LOW RES VER 1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1993-10-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1978-12-05T15:07:34.817Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. ROBERT THEIS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            PVO VENUS ELECT TEMP PROBE DERVD ELECT DENS LOW RES VER 1.0
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This file gives the Ne, Te and Vs measurements derived by fitting
            the radial probe voltampere curves taken whenever PVO was within
            the ionosphere (ie., between the inbound and outbound ionopause
            crossings). Data from essentially every orbit in 1979 and 1980
            included ionosphere transits. After the summer of 1980, however,
            periapsis could no longer be maintained at low altitudes, and it
            rose slowly. After April 1981 periapsis was above the altitude of
            the dayside ionopause, so the spacecraft encountered the
            ionosphere only in the terminator regions and on the nightside
            where the ionosphere extends to much higher altitudes. Dayside
            measurements again became available early in 1992 when periapsis
            returned to low enough altitudes. The PVO Entry period of between
            July and October 1992 provided only nightside periapsis data.
            During the intervening period (1981-91), only nightside UADS
            measurements in the high altitude (downstream) ionosphere were
            available. Note that High Resolution Ne data from the 1981-91
            interval provide measurements in the dayside magnetosheath and in
            the solar wind, but these data have limited accuracy because of
            spacecraft photoelectron contributions. See [BRACEETAL1988] for
            further details on the interpretation of High Resolution
            measurements made outside the ionosphere.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      This file gives the Ne, Te and Vs measurements derived by
      fitting the radial probe voltampere curves taken whenever PVO
      was within the ionosphere (ie., between the inbound and
      outbound ionopause crossings).  Data from essentially every
      orbit in 1979 and 1980 included ionosphere transits.  After the
      summer of 1980, however, periapsis could no longer be
      maintained at low altitudes, and it rose slowly.  After April
      1981 periapsis was above the altitude of the dayside ionopause,
      so the spacecraft encountered the ionosphere only in the
      terminator regions and on the nightside where the ionosphere
      extends to much higher altitudes.  Dayside measurements again
      became available early in 1992 when periapsis returned to low
      enough altitudes.  The PVO Entry period of between July and
      October 1992 provided only nightside periapsis data.  During
      the intervening period (1981-91), only nightside UADS
      measurements in the high altitude (downstream) ionosphere were
      available.  Note that High Resolution Ne data from the 1981-91
      interval provide measurements in the dayside magnetosheath and
      in the solar wind, but these data have limited accuracy because
      of spacecraft photoelectron contributions.  See [BRACEETAL1988]
      for further details on the interpretation of High Resolution
      measurements made outside the ionosphere.
 
      As noted earlier, the geophysical values are listed at 12
      second intervals in the UADS.  Each OETP entry represents a
      time-weighted average of those radial probe measurements taken
      within approximately 10 seconds of the UADS-assigned times.  If
      no voltampere curves were recovered within that 20 second
      interval (this occurs at very low spacecraft telemetry rates),
      no UADS value is entered in that 12 second slot.  The
      instrument actually takes voltampere curves at a rate of
      120/minute, but telemetry rate limitations permit the recovery
      of raw voltampere curves at intervals between 4 to 32 seconds,
      depending upon the telemetry rate and spacecraft data format
      currently in use.
 
      The Ne values in the UADS file may actually be based on either
      the ion or electron current collected by the probe, depending
      upon the magnitude of the density at the time.  The radial
      probe electron currents saturate the electrometer when Ne &gt;
      4x104 cm-3, so it is necessary to switch over to Ni
      measurements at that point.  Since the ion currents are about a
      factor of 50 smaller, the Ni measurements can be made up to
      densities of about 2 x 106 cm-3, much greater than is present
      anywhere in the Venus ionosphere.  We assume that Ni = Ne
      everywhere in the ionosphere, so either may be used to
      construct the UADS file.  To minimize any discontinuity that
      may occur at the Ne/Ni switch-over point due to systematic
      measurement errors, Ne is normalized to Ni using a small
      universal correction factor.  This factor is 0.7, and is based
      on comparisons of the overlapping Ne and Ni measurements from
      many individual orbits.
 
      There are good theoretical reasons to believe that the Ni
      measurements are inherently more accurate at densities
      exceeding 3 or 4x104 cm-3, so this normalization approach
      improves the accuracy of the Ne measurements.  The Ni
      measurements become less accurate at lower densities because of
      uncertain changes in the ion composition, ion drift velocity,
      and a positive ion current component produced by photoelectrons
      (Ipe) leaving the probe.  Ipe becomes comparable to the true
      ion currents at Ni of approximately 1x104cm-3.  The pe currents
      produce a spin modulated signal that is modelled using
      measurements made in the solar wind just prior to the bow shock
      crossing where the ambient densities are too small to produce
      detectable ion currents.  This spin modulated Ipe waveform,
      whose amplitude is different from orbit to orbit because of
      solar EUV variations, is subtracted from the net positive
      current measurements made in the subsequent ionospheric
      passage.  This subtraction gives the true ion current which is
      directly convertible to Ni.  The spin maximum Ipe for each
      orbit is also used to construct the solar EUV file, as is
      described later.
 
      Because of the low spatial resolution of the UADS, and the fact
      that only ionosphere data are included, this file is not the
      best source of information about the ionopause.  Features such
      as the ionopause, and plasma clouds above the ionopause, are
      resolved better using the High Resolution Data File which is
      not restricted to measurements within the ionosphere.
 
    Unsupported Keywords
    ====================
      NATIVE_START_TIME = UNK
      NATIVE_STOP_TIME = UNK
      PROCESSING_LEVEL_ID = 4
      PRODUCER_INSTITUTION_NAME = &apos;GODDARD SPACE FLIGHT CENTER&apos;
      SOFTWARE_FLAG = Y
      PROCESSING_START_TIME = UNK
      PROCESSING_STOP_TIME = UNK
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
   Confidence Level Overview
   =========================
     The UADS data are based on operator-assisted voltampere curve fits.
     The absolute accuracy of the data depends primarily upon the accuracy
     of the Langmuir probe theory [KREHBIELETAL1980] and our success in
     avoiding the inclusion of data from curves that were obtained in
     situations in which the theory does not apply (e.g., probe in wake of
     the telemetry antenna, very low densities, pe contamination,
     spacecraft potential too negative, etc.).  Where these effects have
     been avoided, the errors in Te should not exceed 5% when Ne exceeds
     500 cm-3 in sunlight and about 30 cm-3 in darkness.  However, Te
     errors may be larger in regions of great spatial structure where the
     plasma parameters change while they are being measured, or in regions
     where the electron energy distribution is nonmaxwellian or appears to
     have two temperatures.  These conditions are often found in the
     nightside ionosphere and at the ionopause.  In these cases, the
     curve-fitting is done so as to measure the temperature of the lower
     temperature component of the plasma.  The curves would have to be
     refitted to obtain information on the higher temperature component.
 
     The accuracy of the Ne measurements is determined by the accuracy of
     the Ni measurements to which they are normalized by a fixed factor
     that was determined by comparisons at densities in the vicinity of 4
     x 104 cm-3.  Therefore the Ne accuracy is nominally 10%, but the
     error increases at low densities where pe background and/or
     spacecraft charging effects can be important, as described earlier.
     Ne is given in the UADS file for densities down to 2 cm-3 and Te for
     densities down to 10 cm-3, which are observed only in the nightside
     ionosphere and ionotail.  The Ne error is expected to grow as the
     density approaches these limits, but the Te measurements are less
     subject to error at low densities because knowledge of Vs is not
     needed to obtain the temperature.  In spite of the reduced accuracy,
     Ne measurements below 30 cm-3 are retained in the UADS file because
     they do reflect real variations that may be of interest even when
     their absolute accuracy may be uncertain by a factor of 2 or more.
     Examples include the detection of weak ionospheric tail rays and
     plasma clouds [BRACEETAL1987].
 
     The error in Ni is not expected to exceed 10% at densities above 4
     x104 cm-3.  Ne is used for densities below 4 x104 cm-3.  As noted
     earlier, Ne is normalized to Ni at their overlap point to gain the
     greater inherent accuracy of the ion measurements.  The normalization
     factor is based on the overlapping Ne and Ni measurements from many
     orbits, and the factor does not change throughout the mission.
     Therefore, small discontinuities in the density measurement may
     sometimes be seen at the crossover point if ionospheric conditions
     lead to unusual spacecraft potentials, ion compositions, or other
     factors that are assumed constant when adopting a fixed relationship
     between the ion and electron currents.  We assume that the
     normalization factor remains constant over the full range of Ne, and
     this may not be correct.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>78-051A-01F</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

