<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lp-l-mag-4-lunar-field-ts-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LP MOON MAG LEVEL 4 LUNAR MAGNETIC FIELD TIME SERIES V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_prospector::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mag.lp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lp-l-mag-4-lunar-field-ts-v1.0__browserc_lp-l-mag-4-lunar-field-ts-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lp-l-mag-4-lunar-field-ts-v1.0__browserp_lp-l-mag-4-lunar-field-ts-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LP-L-MAG-4-LUNAR-FIELD-TS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LP MOON MAG LEVEL 4 LUNAR MAGNETIC FIELD TIME SERIES V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2003-10-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1998-01-16</start_time>
        <stop_time>1999-07-29</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>LON L. HOOD</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>not applicable</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Lunar Prospector magnetometer (MAG) Level 2 Data (CODMAC Level
            4). Approximate measurements of the lunar crustal magnetic field
            with external (solar wind and magnetospheric) fields removed or
            minimized.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>not applicable</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    Lunar Prospector magnetometer (MAG) Level 2 Data (CODMAC Level 4).
    Selected and filtered time series data at 5 second intervals from
    the Lunar Prospector (LP) polar orbital mission to the Moon
    (January 1998 to July 1999).  These data represent approximate
    measurements of the lunar crustal magnetic field with external
    (solar wind and magnetospheric) fields removed or minimized.
    Latitude / longitude coverage is limited to specific regions
    overpassed by thespacecraft during the selected intervals.  Vector
    magnetic field components are given in two coordinate systems:
    Selenographic (SG) coordinates and east, north, and radial (ENR)
    coordinates.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The measured parameters consist of the three vector components
    of the lunar crustal magnetic field in SG and ENR coordinates
    sampled at 5-second intervals.  The units of the field measurements
    are nanoTeslas (nT). 1 nT = 0.00001 Gauss.  SG coordinates is a
    system centered in the Moon with X directed toward 0 N, 0 E, Z
    directed toward the north selenographic pole, and Y directed toward
    0 N, 90 E.  ENR coordinates are centered at the instantaneous
    spacecraft location with X directed eastward, Y directed northward,
    and Z directed radial to the Moon.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    Data were first selected from magnetically quiet periods when the
    Moon was in a lobe of the Earth&apos;s magnetotail or when the Moon was in
    the solar wind but the spacecraft was in the lunar wake.
    Hand-editing was applied to eliminate intervals of obvious
    transient external fields.  Finally, long-wavelength (&gt; 500 km)
    non-lunar fields were minimized (detrended) using a suitable filter.
 
 
  File Names and Format
  =====================
    Each file (in ascii format) is named as yy_ddd_nnx.TAB, where yy is
    year number (98 or 99), ddd is day of year, nn is orbit number on the
    selected day, x is an optional letter (A, B, etc.) to distinguish
    multiple files in one day, and &apos;TAB&apos; indicates an ASCII table file.
    Each file contains the Universal time hour of day of the
    measurement, the magnetic field components (BX, BY, BZ) in SG
    coordinates, the magnetic field components (BE, BN, BR) in ENR
    coordinates, the latitude, longitude, and approximate altitude
    (in kilometers) above the lunar surface at which the measurement
    was obtained. The altitude is estimated by subtracting the mean
    lunar radius (1738 km) from the radial distance of the spacecraft
    to the lunar center of figure.
 
    List of columns in the files:
 
      Column 1: Hour of day in Universal time (to 4 decimal places)
      Column 2: BX in nanoTeslas; X component of the magnetic field
                in SG Coordinates.  See Data Set Description for
                definition of SG Coordinates.
      Column 3: BY in nanoTeslas; Y component of the magnetic field
                in SG Coordinates.
      Column 4: BZ in nanoTeslas; Z component of the magnetic field
                in SG Coordinates.
      Column 5: BE in nanoTeslas; East comp. of the magnetic field
                in ENR coordinates.  See Data Set Description for
                definition of ENR coordinates.
      Column 6: BN in nanoTeslas; North comp. of the magnetic field
                in ENR coordinates.
      Column 7: BR in nanoTeslas; Radial comp. of the magnetic field
                in ENR coordinates.
      Column 8: Lunar Latitude in degrees; north is positive.
      Column 9: Lunar east longitude in degrees.
      Column 10: Approximate altitude of spacecraft in kilometers.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Review
  ======
    These data have been examined by the data producer, and as of
    2003-10-01 are being prepared for peer review by the PDS.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    The quality of the measurements is a strong function
    of the spacecraft altitude, which varies from a minimum of about 80
    km during the first year of the mission to about 15 km during the
    final six months of the mission.  The best crustal field measurements
    were therefore obtained during the final &apos;&apos;extended mission&apos;&apos; phase
    when the orbit periapsis was lowest.  The surface resolution of the
    measurements is normally of the same order as the spacecraft
    altitude.  However, at the lowest altitudes (about 15 km), the
    resolution is limited also by the orbit track separation, which is
    approximately 30 km at the lunar equator.  The accuracy to which the
    crustal field is measured at a single point along the spacecraft
    trajectory is limited by residual external field variations and is
    approximately 0.1 nT.
 
 
  Data Coverage
  =============
    The coverage of the measurements over the lunar surface is limited to
    those areas on the near and far side when the Moon and the LP
    spacecraft were favorably located to allow direct measurements of the
    crustal magnetic field.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

