<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ear-a-compil-5-neowisediam-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>NEOWISE DIAMETERS AND ALBEDOS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.support_archives::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.publit::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:compil.publit::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.asteroid::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.satellite::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-a-compil-5-neowisediam-v1.0__browserp_ear-a-compil-5-neowisediam-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Bauer, J. M., A.K. Mainzer, T. Grav, R.G. Walker, J.R. Masiero, and 20 others,
                   WISE/NEOWISE Observations of Active Bodies in the Main Belt, Astroph. J. 747,
                   49, doi:10.1088/0004-637X/747/1/49, 2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BAUERETAL2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Bauer, J.M., T. Grav, E. Blauvelt, A.K. Mainzer, J.R. Masiero, and 20 others,
                   Centaurs and Scattered Disk Objects in the Thermal Infrared: Analysis of
                   WISE/NEOWISE Observations, Astroph. J. 773, 22, doi:10.1088/0004-637X/773/1/22,
                   2013.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BAUERETAL2013</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Bowell, E., B. Hapke, D. Domingue, K. Lumme, J. Peltoniemi, and A.W. Harris,
                   Application of photometric models to asteroids, in Asteroids II, edited by R.P.
                   Binzel, T. Gehrels, and M.S. Matthews, pp. 524-556, Univ. of Arizona Press,
                   Tucson, 1989.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BOWELLETAL1989</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Cutri, R. M., E.L. Wright, T. Conrow, J. Bauer, D. Benford,and 37 others,
                   Explanatory Supplement to the WISE All-Sky Data Release Products, 2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CUTRIETAL2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Cutri, R.M., A. Mainzer, T. Conrow, F. Masci, J. Bauer, and 23 others,
                   Explanatory Supplement to the NEOWISE Data Release Products, 2015.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CUTRIETAL2015</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   T. Grav, A.K. Mainzer, J. Bauer, J. Masiero, T. Spahr, and 12 others,
                   WISE/NEOWISE Observations of the Jovian Trojans: Preliminary Results, Astroph.
                   J. 742, 40, doi:10.1088/0004-637X/742/1/40, 2011.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GRAVETAL2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Grav, T., A.K. Mainzer, J. Bauer, J. Masiero, T. Spahr, and 12 others,
                   WISE/NEOWISE Observations of the Hilda Population: Preliminary Results,
                   Astroph. J. 744, 197, doi:10.1088/0004-637X/744/2/197, 2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GRAVETAL2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Grav, T., A.K. Mainzer, J.M. Bauer, J.R. Masiero, C.R. Nugent, WISE/NEOWISE
                   Observations of the Jovian Trojan Population: Taxonomy, Astroph. J. 759, 49,
                   doi:10.1088/0004-637X/759/1/49, 2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GRAVETAL2012B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Grav, T., J.M. Bauer, A.K. Mainzer, J.R. Masiero, C.R. Nugent, and 3 others,
                   NEOWISE: Observations of the Irregular Satellites of Jupiter and Saturn,
                   Astroph. J. 809, 3, doi:10.1088/0004-637X/809/1/3, 2015.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GRAVETAL2015</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Harris, A.W., A thermal model for near-Earth asteroids, Icarus 131, 291-301,
                   1998.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HARRIS1998</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lebofsky, L.A. and J.R. Spencer, Radiometry and thermal modeling of asteroids,
                   In &apos;Asteroids II&apos;, Binzel, R.P., T. Gehrels, and M.S. Matthews, Eds.,
                   University of Arizona Press, Tucson, pp. 128-147, 1989.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEBOFSKY-SPENCER1989</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mainzer, A., T. Grav, J. Bauer, J. Masiero, R.S. McMillan, and 32 others,
                   NEOWISE Observations of Near-Earth Objects: Preliminary Results, Astroph. J.
                   743, 156, doi:10.1088/0004-637X/743/2/156, 2011.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MAINZERETAL2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mainzer, A., T. Grav, J. Masiero, J. Bauer, E. Wright, and 5 others, Thermal
                   Model Calibration for Minor Planets Observed with Wide-field Infrared Survey
                   Explorer/NEOWISE, Astroph. J. 736, 100, 10.1088/0004-637X/736/2/100, 2011
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MAINZERETAL2011B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mainzer, A., T. Grav, J. Masiero, J. Bauer, E. Wright, and 3 others, Thermal
                   Model Calibration for Minor Planets Observed with WISE/NEOWISE: Comparison with
                   Infrared Astronomical Satellite, Astroph. J. Lett. 737, L9,
                   doi:10.1088/2041-8205/737/1/L9, 2011
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MAINZERETAL2011C</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mainzer, A., T. Grav, J. Masiero, E. Hand, J. Bauer, and 8 others, NEOWISE
                   Studies of Spectrophotometrically Classified Asteroids: Preliminary Results,
                   Astroph. J. 741, 90, doi: 10.1088/0004-637X/741/2/90, 2011
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MAINZERETAL2011D</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mainzer, A., T. Grav, J. Masiero, J. Bauer, R.M. Cutri, and 5 others, Physical
                   Parameters of Asteroids Estimated from the WISE 3-Band Data and NEOWISE
                   Post-Cryogenic Survey, Astroph. J. 760, L12, doi:10.1088/2041-8205/760/1/L12,
                   2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MAINZERETAL2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mainzer, A., Masiero, J., T. Grav, J. Bauer, D.J. Tholen, and 9 others, NEOWISE
                   Studies of Asteroids with Sloan Photometry: Preliminary Results, Astroph. J.
                   745, 7, doi:10.1088/0004-637X/745/1/7, 2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MAINZERETAL2012B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mainzer, A., J. Bauer, T. Grav, J. Masiero, R.M. Cutri, and 6 others, The
                   Population of Tiny Near-Earth Objects Observed by NEOWISE, Astroph. J. 784,
                   110, doi:10.1088/0004-637X/784/2/110, 2014.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MAINZERETAL2014</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Masci, F., ICORE: Image Co-addition with Optional Resolution Enhancement,
                   arXiv:1301.2718, 2013
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MASCI2013</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Masiero, J.R., A.K. Mainzer, T. Grav, J.M. Bauer, R.M. Cutri, and 13 others,
                   Main Belt Asteroids with WISE/NEOWISE. I. Preliminary Albedos and Diameters,
                   Astroph. J. 741, 68, doi:10.1088/0004-637X/741/2/68, 2011.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MASIEROETAL2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Masiero, J.R., A.K. Mainzer, T. Grav, J.M. Bauer, R.M. Cutri, and 2 others,
                   Preliminary Analysis of WISE/NEOWISE 3-Band Cryogenic and Post-cryogenic
                   Observations of Main Belt Asteroids, Astroph. J. 759, L8,
                   doi:10.1088/2041-8205/759/1/L8, 2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MASIEROETAL2012</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Masiero, J., A.K. Mainzer, T. Grav, J.M. Bauer, E.L. Wright and 3 others, A
                   Revised Asteroid Polarization-Albedo Relationship Using WISE/NEOWISE Data,
                   Astroph J. 749, 104, doi:10.1088/0004-637X/749/2/104, 2012.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MASIEROETAL2012B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Masiero, J.R., T. Grav, A.K. Mainzer, C.R. Nugent, J.M. Bauer, and 2 others,
                   Main-belt Asteroids with WISE/NEOWISE: Near-infrared Albedos, Astroph. J. 791,
                   121, doi:10.1088/0004-637X/791/2/121, 2014.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MASIEROETAL2014</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Nugent, C.R., A. Mainzer, J. Masiero, J. Bauer, R.M. Cutri, and 5 others,
                   NEOWISE Reactivation Mission Year One: Preliminary Asteroid Diameters and
                   Albedos, Astroph. J. 814, 117, doi:10.1088/0004-637X/814/2/117, 2015.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NUGENTETAL2015</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>EAR-A-COMPIL-5-NEOWISEDIAM-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>NEOWISE DIAMETERS AND ALBEDOS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-06-02</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2016-06-02</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JOSEPH MASIERO</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Mainzer, A.K., Bauer, J.M., Cutri, R.M., Grav, T., Kramer, E.A.,
            Masiero, J.R., Nugent, C.R., Sonnett, S.M., Stevenson, R.A., and
            Wright, E.L., NEOWISE Diameters and Albedos V1.0.
            EAR-A-COMPIL-5-NEOWISEDIAM-V1.0. NASA Planetary Data System, 2016.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Compilation of NEOWISE diameters and albedos as of March 2016
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This PDS data set represents a compilation of published
            diameters, optical albedos, near-infrared albedos, and beaming
            parameters for minor planets detected by NEOWISE during the fully
            cryogenic, 3-band cryo, post-cryo and NEOWISE-Reactivation Year 1
            operations. It contains data covering near-Earth asteroids, Main
            Belt asteroids, active Main Belt objects, Hildas, Jupiter
            Trojans, Centaurs, and Jovian and Saturnian irregular satellites.
            Methodology for physical property determination is described in
            the referenced articles.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  --------------
 
  This data set is a compilation of the published physical properties
  for minor planets observed by the NEOWISE survey.  Data are separated
  by orbital classification, with a separate file for objects with Main
  Belt orbits that have shown comet-like activity.  Note that some
  objects in the Centaur list are also designated as comets (e.g. (2060)
  95P/Chiron).
 
  Each line of the data set provides effective spherical diameter at the
  given observing geometry (in km), visible geometric albedo (V band),
  near-infrared geometric albedo (at a wavelength of 3.4 microns) and
  thermal model beaming parameter.  Thermal model fits were performed
  primarily using the Near-Earth Asteroid Thermal Model (NEATM; Harris
  1998); in a few instances the Fast Rotating Model was used which
  required the beaming parameter to be equal to pi (Lebofsky &amp; Spencer,
  1989).
 
  Each line has a code identifying which parameters were allowed to vary
  during the least-squares fit.  The number of parameters fit depended
  on the number of WISE bands available, whether each band was dominated
  by thermal emission or reflected sunlight, and the availability of a
  measured absolute magnitude (H).  When measurements in all four WISE
  bands and an H magnitude were available, they were used as
  observations input to the thermal model which performed a
  least-squares minimization using diameter, albedo, infrared albedo and
  beaming parameter as free parameters to be fit.  When fewer
  measurements were available, fewer parameters were fit.  Parameters
  that could not be fit were set to an assumed value as described in the
  associated reference publications.  Assumed values varied by
  population based on the typical value for that parameter for that
  population, as determined for objects where more bands were available.
  The majority of fits are based on single frame detections.  For the
  remainder, a flag indicates that the fit is based on a stack of the
  predicted positions of the object in the NEOWISE data.  Positions were
  computed using the IPAC Moving Object Search Tool (MOST;
  http://irsa.ipac.caltech.edu/applications/MOST/), and the resulting
  thumbnails were stacked using the Image Co-addition with Optional
  Resolution Enhancement routine (ICORE; Masci 2013).  Extraction of
  photometry for each stack is described in the publication associated
  with the fit.
 
  The formal designation of each object (asteroid number, comet number,
  or satellite number) is also provided in each line of the tables.  The
  tables include the provisional designation for an object where
  available, MPC packed format names (for comparison with the tables
  published in the referenced articles), absolute magnitude (H) and
  phase parameter (G) from the H-G photometric system (Bowell, et al.,
  1989), mean Julian Date of the observations used for the fit, number
  of detections in each band used for fitting, and a reference code that
  is described in the &apos;references&apos; table.  The listed H and G are the
  measured values at the time of the original publication that were used
  as input to the thermal model.
 
  Objects that were detected at different epochs (and therefore
  different viewing geometries) will have multiple entries in a
  table. Fits for each epoch were computed independently; the individual
  publications describe the criteria for splitting observations into
  separate epochs.  Fits from multiple epochs are included to give users
  an indication of whether an object is more of less likely to be round.
 
  All images obtained by the NEOWISE survey were processed using the
  standard WISE Scan-Frame Pipeline that includes photometric
  calibration and source extraction based on PSF-fitting.  The pipeline
  is described in the Explanatory Supplement to each WISE and NEOWISE
  data release (Cutri, et al., 2012; 2015) that is hosted with the data
  at the NASA/IPAC Infrared Science Archive.
 
  First-look analysis of fitted physical properties was conducted by the
  NEOWISE team to describe and validate the data set.  In addition to
  the analyses conducted in the papers presenting the fits, other
  analyses comparing the NEOWISE physical properties to external
  datasets include:
 
  -Discussion of the thermal modeling routine and comparison with radar
   and occultation data (Mainzer et al. 2011a)
 
  -Comparison of NEOWISE physical property fits to those from IRAS
   (Mainzer et al. 2011b)
 
  -Comparison of NEOWISE physical properties to spectral taxonomic
   classifications, including albedo distributions of each taxonomic
   class (Mainzer et al. 2011c)
 
  -Comparison of NEOWISE physical properties to taxonomic
   classifications based on Sloan Digital Sky Survey colors (Mainzer et
   al. 2012)
 
  -Comparison of NEOWISE-derived albedos with asteroid polarimetric
   properties (Masiero et al. 2012)
 
 
  References
  --------------
 
  Bowell, E., Hapke, B., Domingue, D., et al., 1989, &apos;Application of
  photometric models to asteroids&apos;, Asteroids II, University of Arizona
  Press, 524.
 
  Cutri, R.M., Wright, E., Conrow, T., et al., &apos;Explanatory Supplement
  to the WISE All-Sky Data Release Products&apos;, 2012.
 
  Cutri, R.M., Mainzer, A., Conrow, T., et al., &apos;Explanatory Supplement
  to the NEOWISE Data Release Products&apos;, 2015.
 
  Harris, A.W., 1998, &apos;A Thermal Model for Near-Earth Asteroids&apos;, Icarus
  131, 291.
 
  Lebofsky, L.A. &amp; Spencer, J.R., 1989, &apos;Radiometry and a thermal
  modeling of asteroids&apos;, Asteroids II, University of Arizona Press, 128.
 
  Mainzer, A., Grav, T., Masiero, J., et al., 2011a, &apos;Thermal Model
  Calibration for Minor Planets Observed with Wide-field Infrared Survey
  Explorer/NEOWISE&apos;, ApJ, 736, 100.
 
  Mainzer, A., Grav, T., Masiero, J., et al., 2011b, &apos;Thermal Model
  Calibration for Minor Planets Observed with WISE/NEOWISE: Comparison
  with Infrared Astronomical Satellite&apos;, ApJL, 737, 9.
 
  Mainzer, A., Grav, T., Masiero, J., et al., 2011c, &apos;NEOWISE Studies of
  Spectrophotometrically Classified Asteroids: Preliminary Results&apos;,
  ApJ, 741, 90.
 
  Mainzer, A., Masiero, J., Grav, T., et al., 2012, &apos;NEOWISE Studies of
  Asteroids with Sloan Photometry: Preliminary Results&apos;, ApJ, 745, 7.
 
  Masci, F., 2013, &apos;ICORE: Image Co-addition with Optional Resolution
  Enhancement&apos;, arXiv:1301.2718.
 
  Masiero, J., Mainzer, A., Grav, T., et al., 2012 &apos;A Revised Asteroid
  Polarization-Albedo Relationship Using WISE/NEOWISE Data&apos;, ApJ, 749,
  104.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The quality of underlying photometric data is described in the WISE
    Explanatory Supplement documentation (Cutri et al., 2012; 2015).  The
    quoted error bars for fitted physical properties represent statistical
    uncertainties propagated from the measured data and the assumed error
    bars on the absolute magnitudes (denoted H) drawn from the Minor
    Planet Center.  There are additional systematic uncertainties inherent
    to the thermal model used for fitting that represent an additional
    ~10% relative uncertainty in diameter for objects with fitted beaming
    parameters and ~15% for objects with assumed beaming parameters
    (Mainzer, et al, 2011).  This uncertainty propagates to a ~20% and
    ~40% relative uncertainty in the albedos, respectively.  Most objects
    have ~10 detections spaced roughly evenly over 36 hours, averaging
    over the rotational periods of many objects and providing a robust
    measurement of the effective spherical diameter.  However, the
    diameters could be less accurately constrained for objects with fewer
    detections, with spin axes near the line of sight, or with rotation
    periods related by a low integer ratio to the WISE satellite&apos;s orbital
    period (resulting in non-random, aliased samples of the light curve).
    Objects indicated with the &apos;S&apos; stacked flag are based on fluxes
    derived from image co-adds that are co-moving with the object&apos;s
    predicted position and may have larger systematic uncertainties
    (e.g. Bauer et al., 2013).
 
 
    References:
 
    Bauer, J.M., Grav, T., Blauvelt, E., et al., 2013, &apos;Centaurs and
    Scattered Disk Objects in the Thermal Infrared: Analysis of
    WISE/NEOWISE Observations&apos;, ApJ, 773, 22.
 
    Cutri, R.M., Wright, E., Conrow, T., et al., &apos;Explanatory Supplement
    to the WISE All-Sky Data Release Products&apos;, 2012.
 
    Cutri, R.M., Mainzer, A., Conrow, T., et al., &apos;Explanatory Supplement
    to the NEOWISE Data Release Products&apos;, 2015.
 
    Mainzer, A., Grav, T., Masiero, J., et al., 2011, &apos;Thermal Model
    Calibration for Minor Planets Observed with Wide-field Infrared Survey
    Explorer/NEOWISE&apos;, ApJ, 736, 100.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

