<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dif-e-mri-3-4-epoxi-earth-v2.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>EPOXI EARTH OBS - MRI CALIBRATED IMAGES V2.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.epoxi::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mri.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dif-e-mri-3-4-epoxi-earth-v2.0__browserp_dif-e-mri-3-4-epoxi-earth-v2.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Belton, M.J.S., K.J, Meech, S. Chesley, Y. Pittichova, B. Carcich, M. Drahus,
                   A. Harris, S. Gillam, J. Veverka, N. Mastrodemos, W. Owen, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, S.
                   Bagnulo, J. Bai, L. Barrera, F. Bastien, J.M. Bauer, J. Bedient, B.C. Bhatt, H.
                   Boehnhardt, N. Brosch, M. Buie, P. Candia, W.-P. Chen, P. Chiang, Y.-J. Choi,
                   A. Cochran, C.J. Crockett, S. Duddy, T. Farnham, Y.R. Fernandez, P. Gutierrez,
                   O.R. Hainaut, D. Hampton, K.A. Herrmann, H. Hsieh, M.A. Kadooka, H. Kaluna, J.
                   Keane, M.-J.Kim, K. Klaasen, J. Kleyna, K. Krisciunas, L.M. Lara, T.R. Lauer,
                   J.-Y. Li, J. Licandro, C.M. Lisse, S.C. Lowry, L. McFadden, N. Moskovitz, B.
                   Mueller, D. Polishook, N.S. Raja, T. Riesen, D.K. Sahu, N. Samarasinha, G.
                   Sarid, T. Sekiguchi, S. Sonnett, N.B. Suntzeff, B.W. Taylor, P. Thomas, G.P.
                   Tozzi, R. Vasundhara, J.-B. Vincent, L.H. Wasserman, B. Webster-Schultz, B.
                   Yang, T. Zenn, and H. Zhao, Stardust-NExT, Deep Impact, and the accelerating
                   spin of 9P/Tempel 1, Icarus, Volume 213, Issue 1, p. 345-368, 2011,
                   doi:10.1016/j.icarus.2011.01.006.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BELTONETAL2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Cowan, N.B., E. Agol, V.S. Meadows, T.A. Livengood, D. Deming, C.M. Lisse, M.F.
                   A&apos;Hearn, D.D. Wellnitz, S. Seager, and D. Charbonneau, Alien Maps of an
                   Ocean-Bearing World, ApJ, 700, 915-923, 2009, doi:10.1088/0004-637X/700/2/915.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.COWANETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Crow, C.A., L.A. McFadden, T. Robinson, V.S. Meadows, T.A Livengood, T.
                   Hewagama, R.K. Barry, L.D. Deming, C.M. Lisse, and D. Wellnitz, Views from
                   EPOXI: Colors in Our Solar System as an Analog for Extrasolar Planets, ApJ,
                   729(2), 130-139, 2011, doi:10.1088/0004-637X/729/2/130.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CROWETAL2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hampton, D.L., J.W. Baer, M.A. Huisjen, C.C. Varner, A. Delamere, D.D.
                   Wellnitz, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, and K.P. Klaasen, An Overview of the Instrument Suite
                   for the Deep Impact Mission, Space Science Reviews, 117, 43-93, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3390-8.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAMPTONETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., M.F. A&apos;Hearn, M. Baca, A. Delamere, M. Desnoyer, T. Farnham, O.
                   Groussin, D. Hampton, S. Ipatov, J. Li, C. Lisse, N. Mastrodemos, S.
                   McLaughlin, J. Sunshine, P. Thomas, and D. Wellnitz, Deep Impact Instrument
                   Calibration, Rev. Sci. Instrum., 79, 091301, 2008, doi:10.1063/1.2972112.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., M. A&apos;Hearn, S. Besse, D. Bodewits, B. Carcich, T. Farnham, L.
                   Feaga, O. Groussin, D. Hampton, M. Huisjen, M.S. Kelley, S. McLaughlin, F.
                   Merlin, S. Protopapa, J. Sunshine, P. Thomas, and D. Wellnitz, EPOXI Instrument
                   Calibration, Icarus, 225(1), 643-680, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.icarus.2013.03.024.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Livengood, T.A., L.D. Deming, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, D. Charbonneau, T. Hewagama, C.M.
                   Lisse, L.A. McFadden, V.S. Meadows, T.D. Robinson, S. Seager, and D.D Wellnitz,
                   Properties of an Earth-Like Planet Orbiting a Sun-Like Star: Earth Observed by
                   the EPOXI Mission Astrobiology, 11(9), 907-930, 2011, doi:10.1089/ast.2011.0614.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LIVENGOODETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DIF-E-MRI-3/4-EPOXI-EARTH-V2.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>EPOXI EARTH OBS - MRI CALIBRATED IMAGES V2.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2012-12-31</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2008-03-18T18:21:24.742Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2009-10-05T09:54:25.693Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STEPHANIE MCLAUGHLIN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            McLaughlin, S.A., B. Carcich, D. Deming, T. Livengood, T.
            Hewagama, K.P. Klaasen, and D.D. Wellnitz, EPOXI EARTH OBS - MRI
            CALIBRATED IMAGES V2.0, DIF-E-MRI-3/4-EPOXI-EARTH-V2.0, NASA
            Planetary Data System, 2012.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Calibrated 750-nm filter images of Earth acquired by the Deep
            Impact Medium Resolution Visible CCD during three 24-hour-long
            observing periods on 18-19 Mar 2008 and on 27-28 Mar, 27-28 Sep
            and 4-5 Oct 2009 for the EPOXI mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset contains calibrated, 750-nm filter images of Earth
            acquired by the Deep Impact Medium Resolution Visible CCD (MRI)
            during the EPOCh and Cruise 2 phases of the EPOXI mission. The
            MRI instrument was only used during the first Earth observing
            period on 18-19 March 2008 and the last two on 27-28 March and
            04-05 October 2009. Each observing period lasted approximately 24
            hours, and one MRI image was taken simultaneously with the first
            north/south scan of the HRI IR spectrometer at half-hour
            intervals to serve as context spectra. On 27-28 September 2009
            during the first attempt at Earth south polar observations, a
            full set of MRI context images was acquired although the HRII and
            HRIV instruments were turned off by fault protection shortly
            after the sequence started. Version 2.0 includes the application
            of a horizontal destriping process, new absolute calibration
            constants for filters, and revised electronic crosstalk
            calibration files.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This dataset contains calibrated, 750-nm filter images of Earth
    acquired by the Deep Impact Medium Resolution Visible CCD (MRI)
    during the EPOCh and Cruise 2 phases of the EPOXI mission.  The MRI
    instrument was only used during the first Earth observing period on
    18-19 March 2008 and the last two on 27-28 March and 04-05 October
    2009.  Each observing period lasted approximately 24 hours, and one
    MRI image was taken simultaneously with the first north/south scan
    of the HRI IR spectrometer at half-hour intervals to serve as
    context spectra.  On 27-28 September 2009 during the first attempt
    at Earth south polar observations, a full set of MRI context
    images was acquired although the HRII and HRIV instruments
    were turned off by fault protection shortly after the sequence
    started.  Version 2.0 includes the application of a horizontal
    destriping process, revised electronic crosstalk calibration files,
    and a corrected spacecraft clock algorithm to remove a known
    systematic error at the subsecond level in the conversion of the
    spacecraft times to UTCs.
 
 
    Required Reading
    ---------------
      The documents detailed below are essential for the understanding and
      interpretation of this data set.  Although a copy of each document is
      provided in the DOCUMENT/ directory of this data set, the most recent
      version is archived in the Deep Impact and EPOXI documentation set,
      DI-C-HRII/HRIV/MRI/ITS-6-DOC-SET-V4.0, available online at
      http://pds.nasa.gov.
 
      EPOXI_SIS.PDF
        - The Archive Volume and Data Product Software Interface
          Specifications document (SIS) describes the the data set, the
          science data products, and defines keywords in the PDS labels.
 
      EPOXI_CAL_PIPELINE_SUMM.PDF
        - The EPOXI Calibration Pipeline Summary provides an overview
          of the final version of the calibration pipeline that generated
          the data products in this dataset.  For a thorough discussion
          of the pipeline, see &apos;EPOXI Instrument Calibration&apos; by Klaasen,
          et. al. (2013) [KLAASENETAL2011].
 
      INSTRUMENTS_HAMPTON.PDF
        - The Deep Impact instruments paper by Hampton, et al. (2005)
          [HAMPTONETAL2005] provides very detailed descriptions of the
          instruments.
 
      EPOCH_EARTH_OBS.PDF
        - This document describes of the EPOCh Earth observations
          although most of the information is captured in this data set
          catalog file you are reading.
 
      EPOCH_EARTH_SEQ_2008.PDF
      EPOCH_EARTH_SEQ_2009.PDF
       - These documents provide pointing and sequencing information
         for the EPOCh Earth observations in 2008 and 2009, including
         descriptions of the HRII scans of Earth (scan direction,
         rate, etc.).
 
      EPOCH_OVERVIEW.PDF
        - This presentation provides an overview of the EPOCh phase of
          the EPOXI mission.
 
      MRI_3_4_EPOXI_EARTH.TAB
        - This ASCII table provides image parameters such as the mid-obs
          Julian date, exposure time, filter, mission activity type, and
          description or purpose for each observation (i.e., data product)
          in this data set.  This file is very useful for determining which
          data files to work with.
 
      Publications of the scientific results from the Earth observations
      in this data set include Cowan, et al. (2009) [COWANETAL2009],
      Livengood, et al. (2009) [LIVENGOODETAL2009], and Crow, et al. (2011)
      [CROWETAL2011].
 
 
    Related Data Sets
    -----------------
      The following PDS data sets are related to this one and may be useful
      for research:
 
      DIF-E-MRI-2-EPOXI-EARTH-V1.0
        - Raw MRI Earth observations (context images)
 
      DIF-E-HRII-2-EPOXI-EARTH-V1.0
      DIF-E-HRII-3/4-EPOXI-EARTH-V2.0
        - Raw and calibrated 1.05- to 4.8-micron HRI IR spectra of Earth,
          covering the same observing periods as this data set (no IR
          spectra were acquired when the HRII and HRIV instruments were
          prematurely turned off at the beginning of the first attempt
          of an Earth south polar observation on 27 Sep 2009)
 
      DIF-E-HRIV-2-EPOXI-EARTH-V1.0
      DIF-E-HRIV-3/4-EPOXI-EARTH-V2.0
        - Raw and calibrated HRIV visible CCD Earth observations at
          350, 450, 550, 650, 750, 850, and 950 nm, covering the same
          observing periods as this data set except 27-28 Sep 2009
          (only seven HRIV frames were acquired before that instrument
          was prematurely turned off at the beginning of the first
          attempt of an Earth south polar observation on 27 Sep 2009)
 
      DIF-C/E/X-SPICE-6-V1.0
        - EPOXI SPICE kernels
 
      DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV/MRI-6-EPOXI-TEMPS-V1.0
        - HRII, HRIV, and MRI instrument thermal telemetry data for EPOXI
          which may be useful for determining how temperature fluctuations
          affect the science instruments, in particular the IR spectrometer
 
      DI-C-HRII/HRIV/MRI/ITS-6-DOC-SET-V4.0
        - Deep Impact and EPOXI documentation set including a draft of the
          Deep Impact instrument calibration paper by Klaasen, et al. (2008)
          [KLAASENETAL2006]
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The calibrated two-dimensional FITS CCD images and PDS labels in this
    dataset were generated by the Deep Impact/EPOXI data pipeline,
    maintained by the project&apos;s Science Data Center (SDC) at Cornell
    University.  The final version of the pipeline, dated December
    2012, was used.  Known limitations and deficiencies of the pipeline
    are discussed in the EPOXI Calibration Pipeline Summary document
    in this dataset or by Klaasen, et al. (2013) [KLAASENETAL2011].
 
    For each CCD image, the pipeline generates two types of calibrated
    products:
 
      - Uncleaned radiance data provided in units of
        Watts/(meter**2 steradian micron) and identified by the
        mnemonic &apos;RADREV&apos;.  The RADREV data are considered to be
        reversible because the calibration steps can be backed out to
        return to the original, raw data numbers.  A RADREV image can
        be converted to unitless I-over-F by multiplying by the value
        assigned to the DATA_TO_IOVERF_MULTIPLIER keyword in the PDS
        label.  Alternatively, a RADREV image can be converted from
        radiance units to calibrated data numbers by multiplying by the
        value assigned to the DATA_TO_DN_MULTIPLIER in the PDS label.
 
      - Irreversibly cleaned radiance data provided in units of
        Watts/(meter**2 steradian micron) and identified by the
        mnemonic &apos;RAD&apos;.  The RAD data are considered to be
        irreversible because the calibration steps, such as smoothing
        over bad pixels, cannot easily be backed out to return to the
        original, raw data numbers.  A RAD image can be converted
        to unitless I-over-F by multiplying by the value assigned to
        the DATA_TO_IOVERF_MULTIPLIER keyword in the PDS label.
        Alternatively, a RAD image can be converted from radiance units to
        calibrated data numbers by multiplying by the value assigned to
        the DATA_TO_DN_MULTIPLIER in the PDS label (though interpolated
        pixels will not be real data).  Please note that values in the
        overclock rows and columns bordering the active CCD area are
        set to 0 in the RAD product.
 
    The calibration pipeline performed the following processes, in the
    order listed, on the raw FITS data to produce the RADREV and RAD
    products found in this data set (the process uses the image mode
    and filter to select the appropriate set of calibration files):
 
      - Decompression of compressed images (reversible)
      - Correction for bias (reversible)
      - Subtraction of a dark frame (reversible)
      - Removal of horizontal, instrumental striping (reversible)
      - Removal of electronic cross-talk (reversible)
      - Application of a normalized flat field (reversible)
      - Removal of CCD transfer smear (reversible)
      - Conversion of data numbers to units of radiance for an absolute,
        radiometric calibration that is reversible (RADREV)
      - Interpolation over bad and missing pixels identified in the
        RADREV data to make a partially cleaned, irreversible, radiometric
        calibration with units of radiance (RAD);  Steps for despiking
        (i.e., cosmic ray removal) and denoising the data which are part
        of the RAD stream were not performed because the existing routines
        are not robust
      - Calculation of multiplicative factors to convert a RADREV or RAD
        image to I-over-F
 
    As part of the calibration process, the pipeline updated the
    pixel-by-pixel image quality map, the first FITS extension, to identify:
 
      - Pixels where the raw value was saturated,
      - Pixels where the analog-to-digital converter was saturated,
      - Pixels that were ultra-compressed and thus contain very little
        information, and
      - Pixels considered to be anomalous as indicated by bad pixel
        maps (missing pixels were identified when the raw FITS files
        were created).
 
    The pipeline also created a FITS image extension to capture the
    signal-to-noise ratio map and another extension to capture the values
    used to remove horizontal striping.  The calibration steps and files
    applied to each raw image are listed in the PROCESSING_HISTORY_TEXT
    keyword in the PDS data label.
 
 
  Data
  ====
 
    FITS Images and PDS Labels
    --------------------------
      Each calibrated image is stored as FITS.  The primary data unit
      contains the two-dimensional CCD image which is followed by two
      image extensions that are two-dimensional pixel-by-pixel maps
      providing additional information about the CCD image:
 
        - The first extension uses one byte of eight, bit flags to
          describe the quality of each pixel in the primary image.
          The PDS data label defines the purpose of each bit.
 
        - The second extension provides a signal-to-noise ratio for
          each pixel in the primary image.
 
        - The third extension contains the two columns of DN values that
          were subtracted from every non-overclock column in the left
          and right halves of the primary image array by the stripe
          removal process; since destriping may remove scattered light
          from very bright sources, the EPOXI SIS document describes
          how to &apos;restripe&apos; an image if needed.
 
      Each FITS file is accompanied by a detached PDS data label.  The
      EPOXI SIS document provides definitions for the keywords found in
      a data label and provides more information about the FITS primary
      image and the extensions.  Many values in a data label were
      extracted from FITS image header keywords which are defined in the
      document EPOXI_FITS_KEYWORD_DESC.ASC found in the Deep Impact and
      EPOXI documentation dataset, DI-C-HRII/HRIV/MRI/ITS-6-DOC-SET-V4.0.
 
 
    File Naming Convention
    ----------------------
      The naming convention for the raw data labels and FITS files is
      MVyymmddhh_eeeeeee_nnn_rr.LBL or FIT where &apos;MV&apos; identifies the MRI
      instrument, yymmddhh provides the UTC year, month, day, and hour at
      the mid-point of the observation, eeeeeee is the exposure ID
      (OBSERVATION_ID in data labels), nnn provides the image number
      (IMAGE_NUMBER in the data labels) within the exposure ID, and
      rr identifies the type of reduction:
 
        RR for RADREV data (reversibly calibrated, radiance units)
        R  for RAD data (partially cleaned RADREV data, radiance units)
 
      Up to 999 individual images or frames can be commanded for one
      exposure ID.  Therefore, nnn in the file name provides the
      sequentially increasing frame number within an exposure ID and
      corresponds to IMAGE_NUMBER in the data labels.  For example, if 32
      frames were commanded for a scan with an exposure ID of 1000000, the
      first FITS file name would be MV08031818_1000000_001_RR.FIT and the
      last would be MV08031818_1000000_032_RR.FIT.
 
 
    Image Compression
    -----------------
      All calibrated data products are uncompressed.  If an associated raw
      data product was compressed on-board the flyby spacecraft (and thus
      received on the ground and archived as compressed) then the
      calibration pipeline used one of four 8-bit lookup tables to
      decompress the raw image.  See the EPOXI SIS and EPOXI Hartley 2
      Calibration Pipeline Summary documents as well as Klaasen, et al.
      (2008) [KLAASENETAL2006] for more information.
 
 
    Image Orientation
    -----------------
      A true-sky &apos;as seen by the observer&apos; view is achieved by displaying
      the image using the standard FITS convention:  the fastest-varying
      axis (samples) increasing to the right in the display window and the
      slowest-varying axis (lines) increasing to the top.  This convention
      is identified in the data labels:  the SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION
      keyword is set to RIGHT and LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION to UP.
 
      The direction to celestial north, ecliptic north, and the Sun is
      provided in data labels by CELESTIAL_NORTH_CLOCK_ANGLE,
      ECLIPTIC_NORTH_CLOCK_ANGLE, and SUN_DIRECTION_CLOCK_ANGLE keywords
      and are measured clockwise from the top of the image when it is
      displayed in the correct orientation as defined by
      SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION and LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION.  Please note
      the aspect of the North celestial pole in an image can be computed
      by adding 90 degrees to the boresight declination given by
      DECLINATION in the data labels.
 
      For a comparison of the orientation of FITS image data from the three
      science instruments, see the quadrant nomenclature section of the
      the EPOXI SIS document.
 
 
    Instrument Alignment
    --------------------
      For a comparison of the field of view and the relative boresight
      alignment of MRI to the High Resolution Instrument Visible CCD
      (HRIV) and the slit of the High Resolution IR Imaging Spectrometer
      (HRII), see the instrument alignment section of the EPOXI SIS
      document or section 5.1 of Klaasen, et al. (2013) [KLAASENETAL2011].
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
    Data Units
    ----------
      The calibrated RADREV and RAD image data have units of radiance,
      W/(m**2 steradian micron).
 
 
    Imaging Modes
    -------------
      One image mode was used for all MRI Earth observations:
 
                     X-Size  Y-Size
        Mode Name    (pix)   (pix)   Comments
        ---- ------  ------  ------  ---------------------------------------
          2  SF1       512    512    Sub-frame, shuttered
 
      All modes are unbinned.  Most image modes have a set of bias
      overclock rows and columns, located around the edges of the image
      array.  All overclock pixels were excluded from the calculation of
      the values for MINIMUM, MAXIMUM, MEDIAN, and STANDARD_DEVIATION in
      the data labels.  These overclock areas described in the Deep
      Impact instruments document and the Deep Impact instrument
      calibration document included with this dataset.
 
 
    Filters
    -------
      A summary of the MRI filters used for the Earth observations is
      provided below.  For more information about the filters, see the
      Deep Impact instruments document.  For the effective center
      wavelengths and the corresponding full-width-half-max values see
      Klaasen, et al. (2013) [KLAASENETAL2011].
 
        Filter         Center Width
        #  Name        (nm)   (nm)   Comments
        -  ----------  -----  -----  -------------------------------
        4  RED          750    100   For context
 
 
    Time- and Geometry-Related Keywords
    -----------------------------------
      All time-related keywords in the data labels, except
      EARTH_OBSERVER_MID_TIME, are based on the clock on board the flyby
      spacecraft.  EARTH_OBSERVER_MID_TIME provides the UTC when an
      Earth-based observer should have been able to see an event recorded
      by the instrument.
 
      For Earth observations, sub-spacecraft and sub-solar longitude and
      latitude coordinates (planetocentric, body-fixed rotating) are
      provided, when available, in the data labels by
      SUB_SPACECRAFT_LONGITUDE, SUB_SPACECRAFT_LATITUDE,
      SUB_SOLAR_LONGITUDE, and SUB_SOLAR_LATITUDE.
 
      The SDC pipeline was not able to automatically determine the proper
      geometric information for the target of choice in some cases.  When
      these parameters could not be computed, the corresponding keywords
      in the data labels are set to a value of unknown, &apos;UNK&apos;.  Also if
      GEOMETRY_QUALITY_FLAG is set to &apos;BAD&apos; or GEOMETRY_TYPE is set to
      &apos;PREDICTED&apos; in the PDS labels, then this indicates the geometry
      values may not be accurate and should be used with caution.  The
      value &apos;N/A&apos; is used for some geometry-related keywords in the data
      labels because these parameters are not applicable for certain
      calibration targets.
 
      Observational geometry parameters provided in the data labels were
      computed at the epoch specified by the mid-obs UTC, IMAGE_MID_TIME,
      in the data labels.  The exceptions are the target-to-sun values
      evaluated at the time light left the target that reached the
      spacecraft at mid-obs time and the earth-observer-to-target values
      evaluated at the time the light that left the target, which reached
      the spacecraft at mid-obs time, reached Earth.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    The geometric parameters included in the data labels and FITS headers
    were computed using the best available SPICE kernels at the time the
    data products were generated.  Most kernels are available in the EPOXI
    SPICE dataset, DIF-C/E/X-SPICE-6-V1.0; others that had not yet been
    archived in the PDS when this dataset was produced are available online
    at the Operational Flight Project Kernels website maintained by the
    NASA Navigation and Ancillary Information Facility (NAIF),
    http://naif.jpl.nasa.gov/naif/data_operational.html.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    Earth Mean Equator and Vernal Equinox of J2000 (EME J2000) is the
    inertial reference system used to specify observational geometry
    parameters in the data labels, unless specified otherwise (e.g,
    SUB_SPACECRAFT_LONGITUDE).
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The observations in this data set are in standard FITS format with PDS
    labels, and can be viewed by a number of PDS-provided and commercial
    programs.  For this reason no special software is provided with this
    data set.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The data files in this data set were reviewed internally by the EPOXI
    project.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    This dataset was peer reviewed and certified for scientific use on
    05 March 2013.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    There are no unexpected gaps in this data set.  All Earth observations
    received on the ground were processed and included in this data set.
 
    Horizontal striping through some images indicates missing data.  The
    image quality map extension identifies where pixels are missing.  If
    the second most-significant bit of a pixel in the image quality map is
    turned on, then data for the corresponding image pixel is missing.  For
    more information, refer to EPOXI SIS document.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
 
    Timing
    ------
      An improved operations spacecraft clock SPICE kernel,
      DIF_SCLKSCET.00119.TSC, was used to convert to UTC and to calculate
      geometry-related parameters for this dataset.  Therefore observation
      times for these calibrated images are improved and differ at the
      sub-second level when compared to the archived raw images.
 
      The EPOXI project plans to generate a complete and highly accurate
      set of UTC correlations since launch.  This will ultimately result
      in a future version of a SCLK kernel that will retroactively change
      correlation for **all** Deep Impact and EPOXI data.  When this
      kernel is available, it will be added to the SPICE data sets for
      the two missions and posted on the NAIF/SPICE web site at
      http://naif.jpl.nasa.gov/naif/.   If time and funding permit, the
      EPOXI project will provide more precise times for archived data.
 
 
    Predicted Observational Geometry
    --------------------------------
      Some data products for the Earth observation in October 2009 have
      geometry values based on predicted (estimated) pointing C-kernels
      found in the EPOXI SPICE archive.  Memory limitations on board the
      spacecraft caused some attitude information to be overwritten, and
      thus reconstructed (final and accurate) pointing information for
      part of this observing period was not generated nor available to the
      data pipeline.  However the EPOCh team provided a file of the
      observational geometry parameters they computed and used for their
      analysis.  See EPOCH_EARTH_GEOM_2009OCT.ASC located in the DOCUMENT/
      directory of this data set.
 
 
    CCD Horizontal Gap
    ------------------
      The two central rows of the CCD are physically 1/6-pixel narrower and
      collect only 5/6 of the charge of a normal row (Klaasen, et al., 2008
      [KLAASENETAL2006] and Klaasen, et al., 2013 [KLAASENETAL2011]).
      However, the data pipeline reconstructs images with uniform row
      spacing, which introduces a 1/3-pixel extension at the center of the
      raw and calibrated image arrays.  Thus for two features on either side
      of the midpoint line outside of the two central rows, the vertical
      component of the true angular separation between those features is
      one-third of a pixel less than their measured separation in the
      reconstructed image.  As for all geometric distortions, correction of
      this 1/3-pixel extension will require resampling of the image and an
      attendant loss in spatial resolution. The data pipeline process does
      not perform this correction in order to preserve the best spatial
      resolution.  However, it does correct for the 1/6 decrease of signal
      in the two central rows by the flat-field division so that the pixels
      in those two rows have the correct scene radiance in the calibrated
      images.  Thus, the surface brightness measurement is preserved
      anywhere in the geometrically distorted but calibrated images.  Point
      source or disk-integrated photometric measurements using aperture
      photometry that includes these central rows will be slightly distorted
      unless special adjustments are made, such as subtracting 1/6-pixel
      worth of signal to the two central rows and adjusting for the
      geometric distortion in the calibrated images, as described in
      Appendix A of Belton, et al. (2011) [BELTONETAL2011].
 
 
    Displaying Images
    -----------------
      Flight software writes an image header over the first 100 bytes of
      quadrant A.  These image header pixels are included in the calibrated
      FITS images.  Since the values in these pixels vary dramatically,
      it is recommended that the values of the MINIMUM and MAXIMUM
      keywords in the data label (or the MINPVAL and MAXPVAL in the FITS
      header) be used to scale an image for display because these values
      exclude the header bytes as well as the overclock rows and columns
      located around the edge of the CCD image.  For more information,
      see the quadrant nomenclature section of the EPOXI SIS document.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

