<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dif-cal-hrii-hriv-mri-6-epoxi-temps-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>EPOXI HRII/HRIV/MRI INSTRUMENT TEMPERATURES V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.epoxi::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:hrii.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dif-cal-hrii-hriv-mri-6-epoxi-temps-v1.0__browserp_dif-cal-hrii-hriv-mri-6-epoxi-temps-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hampton, D.L., J.W. Baer, M.A. Huisjen, C.C. Varner, A. Delamere, D.D.
                   Wellnitz, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, and K.P. Klaasen, An Overview of the Instrument Suite
                   for the Deep Impact Mission, Space Science Reviews, 117, 43-93, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3390-8.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAMPTONETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., M.F. A&apos;Hearn, M. Baca, A. Delamere, M. Desnoyer, T. Farnham, O.
                   Groussin, D. Hampton, S. Ipatov, J. Li, C. Lisse, N. Mastrodemos, S.
                   McLaughlin, J. Sunshine, P. Thomas, and D. Wellnitz, Deep Impact Instrument
                   Calibration, Rev. Sci. Instrum., 79, 091301, 2008, doi:10.1063/1.2972112.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV/MRI-6-EPOXI-TEMPS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>EPOXI HRII/HRIV/MRI INSTRUMENT TEMPERATURES V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2009-09-30</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2007-12-17T17:29:57.142Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2008-12-31T23:55:36.441Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STEPHANIE MCLAUGHLIN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Carcich, B., and D. Hampton, EPOXI HRII/HRIV/MRI INSTRUMENT
            TEMPERATURES V1.0, DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV/MRI-6-EPOXI-TEMPS-V1.0, NASA
            Planetary Data System, 2009.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw temperature measurements for EPOXI from 17 Dec 2007 to 31 Dec
            2008 from multiple sensors located in the HRII, HRIV, and MRI
            instruments and on the HRI and MRI telescopes, instrument
            platform, and solar wings of the Deep Impact flyby spacecraft
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Raw temperature measurements from telemetry for the EPOXI mission
            from 27 sensors located in the HRII, HRIV, and MRI instruments
            and on the HRI and MRI telescopes, instrument platform, and solar
            wings of the Deep Impact flyby spacecraft. The data were
            collected from 17 December 2007 through 31 December 2008, during
            the first cruise and EPOCh phases of the mission as well as the
            early part of the second cruise phase. Future versions of this
            data set will include thermal data from the remaining part of the
            second cruise phase and the 103P/Hartley 2 encounter phase (DIXI)
            of the mission.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set contains raw temperature measurements from telemetry
    for the EPOXI mission from 27 sensors located in the HRII, HRIV,
    and MRI instruments and on the HRI and MRI telescopes, instrument
    platform, and solar wings of the Deep Impact flyby spacecraft.
    The data for this version were collected from 17 December 2007
    through 31 December 2008, during the first cruise and EPOCh phases
    of the mission as well as the early part of the second cruise
    phase.  Future versions of this data set will include thermal data
    from the remaining part of the second cruise phase and the
    103P/Hartley 2 encounter phase (DIXI) of the mission.
 
    Most of the sensors are part of the spacecraft thermal subsystem which
    continuously control the thermal environment via the spacecraft
    telemetry stream.  Temperatures are recorded in the telemetry at
    various rates throughout the mission from several times every hour to
    as frequently as once every minute depending whether the instruments
    are turned on or off.  It is important to note that 1) these thermal
    sensors are independent of those used to record the measurements that
    are embedded in the science data image headers by the software
    on-board the spacecraft and 2) the IR Spectral Imaging Module (SIM)
    bench temperatures recorded in the telemetry are known to be one to
    two degrees different, but more realistic, than the measurements
    captured in the image headers.  See the Deep Impact instrument
    calibration paper by Klaasen, et al. (2008) [KLAASENETAL2006] for
    more information.
 
    These data are used by the EPOXI science team to monitor and
    understand the thermal environment and to calibrate the HRII
    instrument which is very sensitive to temperature fluctuations.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    Thermal measurements received in the original telemetry stream from
    the flyby spacecraft were extracted and formatted into two fixed-width
    ASCII tables with detached PDS labels; There is one table and label
    for each thermal sensor.  No corrections or conversions were applied
    to the raw temperatures.  The tools used to extract the measurements
    from the engineering telemetry have been run in a mode called `report
    on change only&apos;, i.e. for each sensor the tools excluded subsequent
    contiguous measurements that are the same as the previous measurement.
    Please note the HRI IR Spectral Imaging Module (SIM) bench
    temperatures recorded in the telemetry are known to be one to two
    degrees Celsius different than the measurements collected by the
    instruments and recorded in the science data image headers.
 
    HRI Temperatures Tables
    -----------------------
      Raw measurements from each of the 14 different temperature sensors
      located at various points on the HRI telescope, the HRI IR
      spectrometer (HRII) which includes the SIM, and the HRI visible CCD
      (HRIV) are provided as separate fixed-width ASCII tables, by AMMOS
      number, with detached PDS labels.  Additionally raw measurements
      from a sensor in the panel underneath the instrument platform and
      four sensors located on the back side of the two solar wings on the
      flyby spacecraft are also provided as separate fixed-width ASCII
      tables, by AMMOS number, with detached PDS labels.
 
         S/C
      Sensor# : AMMOS# : Sensor Description
        TS104 : T-0276 : HRI tele. barrel at center (first sensor, TIB side A)
        TS102 : T-0287 : HRI SIM bench at prisms (first sensor, TIB side A)
        TS103 : T-0296 : HRI CCD plate assembly (first sensor, TIB side A)
        TS118 : T-0298 : HRI beam splitter
        TS131 : T-0302 : HRI primary mirror
        TS107 : T-0303 : HRI pre-amp box
        TS134 : T-0305 : HRI IR detector cooler (secondary radiator)
        TS114 : T-0306 : HRI IR focal plane array (primary radiator)
        TS116 : T-0327 : HRI electronics box
        TS110 : T-1777 : HRI tele. barrel at center (second sensor,TIB side B)
        TS108 : T-1792 : HRI SIM bench at prisms (second sensor, TIB side B)
        TS109 : T-1793 : HRI CCD plate assembly (second sensor, TIB side B)
        TS115 : T-1804 : HRI SIM bench at rear flexure
        TS135 : T-1806 : Baffle extension on the HRI telescope barrel
        n/a   : T-0339 : Panel underneath the instrument platform
        TS1   : T-0275 : Back side of solar array wing 1, -Z direction
        TS3   : T-0280 : Back side of solar array wing 1, +Z direction
        TS2   : T-1776 : Back side of solar array wing 2, -Z direction
        TS4   : T-1781 : Back side of solar array wing 2, +Z direction
 
    MRI Temperatures Tables
    ----------------------
      Raw measurements from each of the eight different temperature sensors
      located at various points on the MRI telescope and the MRI visible
      CCD are provided as separate fixed-width ASCII tables, by AMMOS
      number, with detached PDS labels.
 
         S/C
      Sensor# : AMMOS# : Sensor Description
        TS132 : T-0277 : MRI optical bench at primary mirror (TIB side A)
        TS106 : T-0284 : MRI CCD plate assembly (first sensor, TIB side A)
        TS105 : T-0299 : MRI telescope box at center bottom
        TS133 : T-1778 : MRI telescope box extension
        TS112 : T-1797 : MRI CCD plate assembly (second sensor, TIB side B)
        TS111 : T-1800 : MRI primary mirror (TIB side B)
        TS113 : T-1805 : MRI pre-amp box
        TS117 : T-1819 : MRI electronics box
 
    The spacecraft sensor numbers (TSnnn) and AMMOS numbers (T-nnnn),
    Advanced Multi-Mission Operations System) are provided to help
    researchers locate the thermal sensors illustrated in the Pictorial
    Atlas of Deep Impact (&amp; EPOXI) Instrument Thermal Telemetry document
    which included in this data set.  Again, it is important to note these
    temperature sensors are independent of those used to record
    measurements that were embedded in the science data image headers
    by the software on-board the spacecraft.
 
 
  Temperature Sensors
  ===================
    Thermal sensors are placed on active operating components and in
    critical locations on the HRI and MRI telescopes and in the HRII
    infrared spectrometer, the HRIV CCD, and the MRI CCD, as well as on
    the instrument platform and the two solar wings of the flyby
    spacecraft. A ll of these sensors, except those on the instrument
    platform and solar wings, are connected to side A or B of the flyby
    spacecraft&apos;s Thermal Interface Board (TIB).  The sensors are used to
    monitor the thermal environment and, with the instrument heaters,
    provided a closed-loop temperature control via the telemetry stream.
    Measurements are recorded in the telemetry at various rates throughout
    the mission, from about once every minute to several times every hour
    whether the instruments were turned on or off.
 
    To see where the thermal telemetry points are located, please refer
    to the Pictorial Atlas of Deep Impact (&amp; EPOXI) Instrument Thermal
    Telemetry document included in this data set.  For a discussion of
    the thermal design of the instruments, see Hampton, et al. (2005)
    [HAMPTONETAL2005].  The Deep Impact instrument calibration paper
    by Klaasen, et al. (2008) [KLAASENETAL2006] describes how various
    temperatures affect the calibration of the HRII, HRIV, and MRI
    instruments.  Drafts of these two documents are included in this
    data set.
 
 
  Media Format
  ============
    This data set is released in electronic format.
 
 
  This data set overview was prepared by Stephanie McLaughlin with input
  from Brian Carcich, the data supplier, and Donald Hampton, the
  instrument engineer.  Plots in the document directory were provided
  by Lori Feaga.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Review
  ======
    This date set successfully passed a peer review held by the PDS Small
    Bodies Node on 23 July 2009.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SUPERSEDED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

