<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dawn-m-grand-3-rdr-mars-counts-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DAWN GRAND CALIBRATED MARS FLYBY COUNTS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.dawn_mission_to_vesta_and_ceres::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:grand.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dawn-m-grand-3-rdr-mars-counts-v1.0__browserp_dawn-m-grand-3-rdr-mars-counts-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Prettyman, T.H., W.C. Feldman, F.P. Ameduri, B.L. Barraclough, E.W. Cascio,
                   K.R. Fuller, H.O. Funsten, D.J. Lawrence, G.W. McKinney, C.T. Russell, S.A.
                   Soldner, S.A. Storms, C. Szeles, and R.L. Tokar, Gamma-ray and neutron
                   spectrometer for the Dawn mission to 1 Ceres and 4 Vesta, IEEE Trans. Nucl.
                   Sci., Volume 50, Issue 4, pp. 1190-1197, August 2003, DOI
                   10.1109/TNS.2003.815156
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PRETTYMANETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DAWN-M-GRAND-3-RDR-MARS-COUNTS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DAWN GRAND CALIBRATED MARS FLYBY COUNTS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2009-02-17T22:33:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2009-02-18T00:45:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>THOMAS H. PRETTYMAN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Prettyman, T.H., DAWN GRAND CALIBRATED MARS FLYBY COUNTS V1.0.
            DAWN-M-GRAND-2-RDR-MARS-COUNTS-V1.0. NASA Planetary Data System,
            2009.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The GRaND Reduced Data Records (RDR) are a time-ordered
            collection of corrected gamma ray and neutron counting data and
            calibrated pulse height spectra.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The GRaND RDR are a time-ordered collection of corrected gamma
            ray and neutron counting data and calibrated pulse height spectra
            acquired by GRaND during all phases of the Dawn mission. This
            data set is specific to Mars Gravity Assist (MGA), and includes
            data acquired during Mars approach and flyby. The RDR is a
            calibrated data set derived from the Experiment Data Records
            (EDR), consisting of time-series counting rates from which
            elemental abundances can be determined. Ancillary ephemeris and
            pointing data needed for analysis and mapping of the time series
            data are included in the data set.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Overview
  ========
 
The Dawn Mission&apos;s Gamma Ray and Neutron Detector
(GRaND) is a nuclear spectrometer that will collect data needed to map
the elemental composition of the surfaces of 4-Vesta and 1-Ceres
[PRETTYMANETAL2003].  GRaND measures the spectrum of planetary gamma
rays and neutrons, which originate from cosmic ray interactions and
radioactive decay within the surface, while the spacecraft (S/C) is in
orbit around each body. The instrument, which is mounted on the +Z deck
of the S/C, consists of 21 sensors designed to separately measure
radiation originating from the surface of each asteroid and background
sources, including the space energetic particle environment and cosmic
ray interactions with the spacecraft.  The nuclear spectroscopy data
provided by GRaND will be analyzed to determine the abundance of major
rock forming elements, such as O, Fe, Ti, Si, Al, Mg, Ca, Cl and
radioactive elements, including K and Th, as well as light-elements such
as H, C, and N, which are constituents of ices and the products of
aqueous alteration of silicate minerals and ices.
 
 
The GRaND Reduced Data Records (RDR) are a time-ordered
collection of corrected gamma ray and neutron counting data and
calibrated pulse height spectra acquired by GRaND during Mars Gravity
Assist (MGA).  Similar products will be developed for science mapping at
4-Vesta and 1-Ceres and for data acquired during cruise.  The RDR is a
calibrated data product (Level 1B) that is derived from Experiment
Data Records (EDR, Level 1A).  The objective of the RDR is to provide
counting rates and ancillary pointing and ephemeris data needed for
mapping.  The ancillary data includes the subsatellite point, the
distance and direction to body center, and the spacecraft velocity
vector relative to Mars, which is needed to account for the motion of
low energy (thermal and epithermal) neutrons relative to the spacecraft.
In the current version of the data set, counting rates and fluxes
corrected for altitude and spacecraft motion, which require knowledge of
the instrument response, are not provided; however, future versions of
the RDR, especially for Vesta and Ceres mapping will include counting
rates corrected for solid angle and pointing as well as incident gamma
 ray and neutron fluxes.
 
Processing steps for the RDR data set include:
- Determination of the mid-point time of each science accumulation
  interval and the livetime, accounting for roll-over of the dead time
  counter; - Construction of pulse height spectra from the gamma ray and
  neutron event data;
- Correction of pulse height spectra for ADC differential nonlinearity;
- Calibration and gain/offset correction of pulse height spectra to
  provide a consistent energy scale for peak analysis;
- Analysis of spectra to determine the net areas (counting rates) of
  selected spectral features, including:
        -- the 10B(n,alpha) peak area from the Category 1 (CAT1)
           spectrum, for the +Z phoswich, which is sensitive to
           epithermal neutrons from the target body;
        -- the 6Li(n,t) peak area from the +Z CAT1 phoswich, which is
           sensitive to thermal and epithermal neutrons from the target
           body; -- the net areas of the 478 keV gamma ray full energy
           peaks for each of the four CAT2 BGO pulse height spectra,
           resulting from coincidences between 93 keV deposited in the
           four boron-loaded-plastic (BLP) scintillators by the
           10B(n,alpha)7Li* reaction and the associated gamma ray
           (7Li*-&gt;7Li+478keV):
                --- Because the +Z and -Z BLP scintillators are shielded
                    by Gd and lithiated glass, their CAT2 counting rates
                    are sensitive to epithermal neutrons;
                --- Because the side +Y and -Y scintillators are not
                    shielded, their counting rates are sensitive to both
                    thermal and epithermal neutrons.
        -- the fast neutron counting rates for each of the boron-loaded
           plastic scintillators;
        -- net counting rates for selected gamma rays.
 
 
The data set consists of ASCII tables, divided by
functionality into four categories: ephemeris and pointing data EPX
(where X denotes the target: X=&apos;X&apos; for cruise, X=&apos;M&apos; for Mars, X=&apos;V&apos; for
Vesta, and X=&apos;C&apos; for Ceres); neutron counting rates (NCR); gamma ray
counting rates (GCR), and the BGO pulse height spectrum (BGO). The fast
neutron flux spectrum (with units of neutrons/cm2/s/MeV), which can be
unfolded from the fast neutron pulse height spectrum given the response
function, and CZT composite spectrum will be included in future
releases.
 
The Level1b data are represented as a time series in which counting
rates and spectra are averaged over a time-window, consisting of an odd
number of science accumulation intervals (TELREADOUT) selected by the
evaluator.  Note that ephemeris and pointing data are not averaged.
Rather, their instantaneous values at the mid-point of each time window
is reported. Two types of time series are possible: a central moving
average (CMA), in which the averaging window is centered on each point
in the original time series, and a result is reported for each science
accumulation interval; and a decimated time series (DTS), in which the
averaging window is shifted forward in time by its width, resulting a
 data set that has fewer points than the original time series.
 
The CMA is intended for mapping, for example, in cases where full
sampling of rapidly changing counting rates and solid angles is needed.
The DTS is useful for averaging over long periods of time, for example,
during cruise, when counting rates are not changing rapidly.  By
averaging over long time intervals, the DTS can be used to produce high
precision gamma ray spectra needed for accurate peak identification,
analysis, and calibration.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
The RDR data are derived from the EDR files, which cover
arbitrary and irregular time periods, generally determined by the
pattern of downlinks from the spacecraft.  The RDR are evaluated for a
single instrument state found in the EDR files, generally corresponding
to the instrument fully configured for science data acquisition.
Consequently, the value of TELREADOUT is the same for all records
extracted from a particular EDR file.  The EDR science records need not
be contiguous; however, time-windows containing gaps are not included in
the RDR.  Generally, science data records with elevated counting rates
associated with solar energetic particle (SEP) events will be excluded
from the RDR; however, throughout MGA, solar activity was minimal and no
records were lost.
 
The RDR files are contained in a single directory.  The name of the
directory includes the type of time series (CMA or DTS):
 
     GRD-L1B-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-CMA  (directory name for a central
                                        moving average), or
     GRD-L1B-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-DTS  (directory name for a decimated
                                        time series).
 
The top level directory name contains the SCET UTC dates for the first
and last science data records (Y1M1D1 and Y2M2D2, respectively), and the
creation date (YCMCDC) for the archive.  For example, for
GRD-L1B-090217-090218_090517, the first science data record was acquired
on 17-Feb-2009.  The last science data record was acquired on
18-Feb-2009.  The archive was created by the processing code on
 17-May-2009.
 
The data files and formats are the same for both types of time series.
All counting rates are reported as counts per second.  Histograms have
units of counts/second/channel. The processing parameters, including the
window width and the value of TELREADOUT are given in the label files.
The following files are included (note that &apos;TSI&apos; is either &apos;CMA&apos; or
&apos;DTS&apos;, depending on the type of time series):
 
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-TSI-EPM.TAB - Contains a
     time series of ephemeris and pointing data, including the total
     livetime, the distance and direction to body center, the velocity
     of the spacecraft rotated into the reference frame of the
     instrument, the subsatellite position and altitude, and the
     fractional solid angle subtended by the body at the spacecraft.  In
     addition, the average counting rate for the &apos;coincidence of three
     or more sensors&apos; scaler (SCALER_SCI[15]) is provided as an
     indicator of the interaction rate of galactic cosmic rays.
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-TSI-NCR.TAB - Contains a time series
     of neutron counting rates determined from CAT1, CAT2, and CAT4
     pulse height spectra.  Counting rates sensitive to neutrons in the
     thermal, epithermal, and fast energy ranges are provided.
     Propagated uncertainties (1-sigma) are provided.
 
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-TSI-GCR.TAB - Contains a
     time series of net areas for selected full energy interaction peaks
     from the pulse height spectrum acquired by the BGO sensor.
     Propagated uncertainties (1-sigma) are provided.
 
 
     GRD-L1A-Y1M1D1-Y2M2D2_YCMCDC-TSI-BGO.TAB - Contains a
     time series of BGO 1024-channel pulse height spectra that have been
     adjusted so that the offset is 0 keV with a slope of 8.9
     keV/channel.  Note that the method for determining the uncertainty
     in the counting rates for each channel is provided in the format
     file.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
 
The RDR data from each EDR data file are processed in several steps:
1. Specification of processing parameters, including the target
   instrument state, the time series type and window width, and
   parameters for spectrum processing and analysis;
2. Extracting science data records from the EDR for the selected state;
3. Generation of the time series structure;
4. Construction of pulse height spectra from event data;
5. Correction of pulse height spectra in preparation for peak analysis
   (including livetime, ADC differential nonlinearity and gain and offset
   corrections).
6. Determining peak areas and uncertainties from time-averaged neutron
   and gamma ray spectra;
7. Writing the data and labels.
 
Details of the processing are described in Prettyman, T.H. and W.C.
Feldman (2009), PDS data processing for the Dawn gamma ray and neutron
detector, GRD_L1B_Processing_V2.0.pdf, available in the document
directory of this volume.  A summary of the processing algorithms and
parameters is provided here.
 
The RDR time series is constructed by averaging corrected counting rates
over a window using one of two methods: Central Moving Average (CMA) or
Decimated Time Series (DTS).  The CMA method provides a result for each
science data record by averaging over records on either side of the
current point as illustrated here:
 
 
                    Science records
       XXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXX ... |
        1 | | 2 |
         | 3 |
          | 4 |
           | 5 |
             ....
where each of the time-ordered science records is indicated by an X and
the window boundaries are indicated by the vertical bars.  The middle of
each time series is labeled with an index (1, 2, ...).
 
 
The DTS method marches the window through the science data
records, resulting in a decimated time series as follows:
 
 
      Science records
      XXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXXX ...| 1 || 2 || 3 || 4 || 5 |...
 
The number of science data records averaged for each point in the time
series is given by WINDOW_WIDTH, which is an odd integer.  For both
methods, all time, ephemeris, and pointing information is determined at
the midpoint of the window.
 
 
A variety of spectrum analysis methods are used to extract
peak areas recorded in the neutron and gamma ray files.  These are
described in detail in the data processing document.  For Mars flyby,
time-averaged background data were determined during a period of time
for which the instrument was far from Mars and sensitive only to
neutrons produced on board the spacecraft by galactic cosmic ray
interactions.  In some cases (e.g., analysis of the CAT1 spectrum),
background continuum functions were determined using a coarse time
window (CMA), under the assumption that the background shape does not
change as rapidly as the peak.  The window width for Mars flyby
background subtraction was 11 science accumulation intervals.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
 
The Level 1B data include ancillary data in the form of
SCET UTC strings reported in each row of the time series tables.  The
UTC strings are determined from the spacecraft clock ticks recorded in
each state-of-health packet and for the first packet in each science
data record using NAIF SPICE (leap seconds kernel).  This information is
used in Level 1B processing to accurately determine the mid-point of
each science accumulation interval, which is used for mapping.  In
addition, pointing and ephemeris data are provided in the Level 1B file
at the center of each time interval:
     - the distance and direction of body center in the instrument
       coordinate system;
     - the velocity of the spacecraft rotated into the reference frame
       of the instrument
     - the subsatellite longitude, latitude, and altitude;
     - the fractional solid angle subtended by Mars at the spacecraft.
The target was &apos;IAU_MARS&apos;.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
 
The instrument coordinate system (Fig. 1) determines the
naming convention of the sensors and orientation of the instrument
relative to the spacecraft. The use of MZ indicates a sensor on the -Z
(zenith-facing during mapping) side of GRaND;  PZ indicates the sensor
is on the +Z (spacecraft) side; MY indicates the sensor is on the -Y
side (inboard) side of the instrument; and PY indicates the sensor is on
the +Y side (outboard, towards the +Y solar panel) side of the
instrument.  The phototube assembly, marked &apos;P&apos; on the diagram in Fig. 1
 points along the +X axis (towards the high gain antenna).
 
   .................
   . ooooooooooooo .
   . o           o .
   . o           o .
   . o    +Z     o .
   . o   (PZ)    o .
   . o           o .---&gt; +Y (PY)
   . ooo       ooo .
   .   P       P   .
   .   P       P   .
   .   PPPPPPPPP   .
   .               .
   .................
           |
           v
        +X (PX)
 
 
Figure 1. The coordinate system for GRaND is the same as
that of the S/C. For the diagram above, the observer is looking in the
-Z (MZ) direction and can see the outline of the phoswich assembly (o)
on the +Z side of GRaND. The phototubes are on the +X side and the
scintillators are on the -X side. During mapping at Vesta and Ceres, the
planetary surface is in the +Z direction.
 
 
  Software
  ========
 
The RDR were generated using an IDL-based processing
code compatible with IDL Version 7.0, distributed by ITT Visual
Information Solutions, Boulder, CO (2008).  Program name:
GRD_L1B_Pipeline.pro. Version: 1.0. Ancillary data were generated using
 the NAIF/ICY IDL toolkit.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
 
The RDR label and data files are delivered by electronic
transmission to the PDS.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Review
  ======
 
The RDR will be reviewed internally by the Dawn Science
Team prior to submission to the PDS.  The PDS will also conduct an
external peer review of the RDR prior to releasing the data to the
general public.
 
 
  Data Coverage/Quality
  =====================
 
The RDR does not include all of the science data
records, only those corresponding to instrument state selected by the
evaluator.  Science data records acquired during instrument ramp up or
power on are typically excluded from the RDR.
 
While Dawn successfully completed it&apos;s gravity assist at Mars, the
spacecraft entered safe-mode shortly following closest approach. At that
time, all of the instruments were shut down. All planned activities which
had not been executed did not occur. Any data from activities which had
taken place, but which had not yet been dumped out of instrument memory
and into the spacecraft virtual recorder were lost. GRaND returned data
through shortly after closest approach. FC2 returned 6 lit images of
Mars. VIR returned no data for the Mars flyby.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
 
The RDR is an intermediate data product.  While it is a time series,
sufficient information is provided to make maps of counting rates
corrected for altitude and pointing, suitable for scientific data
analysis.  Determination of spatially-resolved elemental abundances
requires knowledge of the instrument response function, which will be
provided as a higher order data product, along with models of the
radiation background and radiation output from the target body.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

