<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-v-h-rss-1-edr-rawdata-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER V/H RADIO SCIENCE SUBSYSTEM 1 EDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-v-h-rss-1-edr-rawdata-v1.0__browserp_mess-v-h-rss-1-edr-rawdata-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-v-h-rss-1-edr-rawdata-v1.0__browser_geo_mercury_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-v-h-rss-1-edr-rawdata-v1.0__dvo_geo_mess-v-h-rss-1-edr-rawdata-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Srinivasan, D.K., M.E. Perry, K.B. Fielhauer, D.E. Smith, and M.T. Zuber, The
                   radio frequency subsystem and radio science on the MESSENGER mission, Space
                   Science Reviews, 131, 557-571, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SRINIVASANETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-V/H-RSS-1-EDR-RAWDATA-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESSENGER V/H RADIO SCIENCE SUBSYSTEM 1 EDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2015-03-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2006-10-18</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>MARK E. PERRY</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Perry, M.E., Solomon, S.C., Lemoine, F.G., Smith, D.E., Zuber,
            M.T., MESSENGER Radio Science Raw Data
            (MESS-V/H-RSS-1-EDR-RAWDATA-V1.0), NASA Planetary Data System,
            2010.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw radio science data and ancillary files from the MESSENGER
            mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains archival raw, partially processed, and
            ancillary/supporting radio science data acquired during the
            MESSENGER mission. The radio observations were carried out using
            the MESSENGER spacecraft and Earth-based receiving stations of
            the NASA Deep Space Network (DSN). The observations were designed
            to be part of a data set that is of sufficient quality and
            quantity to generate high-resolution gravity field models of
            Mercury. Of most interest are likely to be the Orbit Data Files
            in the ODF directory. The data range from 2006 to 2014; there are
            gaps in the data.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The MESSENGER Radio Science (RS) Raw Data Archive (RDA) is a
      time-ordered collection of raw and partially processed data
      collected during the MESSENGER mission to Mercury.
 
      This data set was collected during the cruise and orbital phases
      of the MESSENGER mission; the earliest data are from 2006.
      This period includes the three Mercury flybys and the orbit-phase
      data from Mercury orbit insertion (MOI) on 11 March 2011 to
      17 March 2014.
 
      This data set includes four primary data types.
      Tracking and Navigation Files (TNFs) are the raw
      product of the closed-loop tracking system.  Orbit Data
      Files (ODFs) are edited versions of TNFs, specifically
      targeted to spacecraft navigators and scientists interested in
      gravity fields.  Radio Science Receiver (RSR) data are the raw
      product of the open-loop receiver.  Delta-Differential One-way
      Ranging (DDOR) use two DSN stations and a quasar to provide
      additional position information normal to the line of sight.
      The data set also includes ancillary data or
      supporting data to be used in analyzing the primary data.
 
      Please see documentation in the DOCUMENT directory for
      additional information on the data files and their format.
      First-time users of the data set should begin with the
      MESSENGER_EDR_SIS, which is found in the DOCUMENT directory.
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      See individual SIS documents, which are located in the
      DOCUMENT directory, for detailed descriptions of each file
      contained in this data archive.
 
    Processing
    ==========
      Typical TNFs contain data from a 24-hour period and combine data from
      several antennas if there were multiple passes during the 24-hour
      period. ODFs are abstracted from subsets of TNF data.  A full PDS label
      accompanies each ODF file and gives a bit-level description of the
      content and format. RSR data were modified during Ground Data System
      handling so that MISSION_ID in the Primary Header CHDO was set to 5.
 
    Data
    ====
      Users should consult listings in the INDEX.TAB file to
      ascertain full coverage of each data type.
 
      The DATA directory contains ODF and TNF data for each DSN pass.
      During the cruise phase of the mission, there were
      usually three DSN contacts per week. During
      flybys, and the weeks preceding and following, there are more DSN
      contacts, and usually continuous for the four days centered on
      close approach. There are TNF and ODF data for each contact. DDOR
      data are infrequent, and concentrated near flybys. There are no
      DDOR data after MOI. RSR data were archived for a
      6-month period starting late in 2006. These data span a long
      superior conjunction and were collected for potential use for
      studying the solar corona. RSR data are also collected at each
      occultation event during the cruise phase of the mission.
 
      During the Mercury orbital phase of the mission, there were one
      or two DSN contacts per 24 hours. MESSENGER orbited Mercury every 12
      hours for the first 12 months of orbit operations. Each 24 hours, one
      contact included data obtained using MESSENGER&apos;s high-gain antennas
      (HGAs) and low-gain  antennas (LGAs). The LGA data usually included the
      periapsis portion of the orbit and 75 minutes on either side of the
      periapsis. The HGA data were farther from Mercury and usually 6-9 hours
      in duration. If there was a second contact in a 24-hour span, it was
      usually LGA data that covered the second periapsis portion of the
      orbit. If there was an Earth occultation during the orbit, it was
      usually observed using the LGAs and there were usually RSR data
      collected for several minutes during both ingress and egress. During
      the first two weeks after MOI, DSN contact was nearly continuous.
 
      Starting in April 2012, thirteen months after MOI, MESSENGER began
      orbiting Mercury with an eight-hour period. The timing and frequency
      of contacts changed as described in the DATA COVERAGE AND QUALITY
      section, below.
 
      ODFs are stored in the ODF directory on archival volumes. File
      names are described in MESSENGER_EDR_SIS.html. The typical ODF
      contains under 2 Mbytes of data.
 
      ODFs during cruise are primarily 10-sec Doppler X-band data, but
      there are some ODFs with 1-second integration periods (during flybys)
      and some with 60-second integration periods. During the orbital phase
      of the mission most ODFs have 5-second integration periods.
 
      Every file in the directory has a PDS label. Except for files
      in the root directory and in the CATALOG directories, the
      label is a separate file in the same directory with the same
      name but a LBL extension. The TNF labels are embedded, not detached.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      An extensive set of ancillary files is provided for detailed
      analysis and interpretation of the primary (tracking) data. Users
      should refer to the INDEX.TAB listing to locate ancillary files
      and to the MESSENGER RS Raw-Data SIS for a description of the ancillary
      data files, their data formats, and their naming conventions.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      The NAIF reader routines enable the raw data and ancillary data to be
      converted into a wide range of reference frames. Most of the data are
      linked to time and are independent of reference frame. The user chooses
      their reference frame.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      Software for parsing, reducing, and analyzing data such as
      these must usually operate at the bit-level and is
      written for a narrow range of platforms.  It is not suitable
      for general distribution.  No software is included with this
      archival data set.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this data set include the three flybys of Mercury, Mercury
      Orbit Insertion (MOI) and the first forty-two months of MESSENGER&apos;s
      orbital phase.
 
      The ODF data have been processed by the navigation team and by the
      gravity science team during the course of their analyses.
      This processing shows the data to be of good quality, sufficient for
      analysis of Mercury&apos;s gravitational field.
      Most of the cruise data were obtained using the spacecraft&apos;s high-gain
      antennas. There are periods within a few days of the closest approach
      to Mercury where the low-gain antennas were used. The gain of the
      low-gain antennas is typically 20-25 dB lower than the high-gain
      antennas, so the data encompass a wide range of RF power levels, and
      the signal-to-noise ratio therefore has a wide range. Variations in
      the proximity of the RF path to the Sun also contribute to a
      wide variation in the signal-to-noise ratio. Due to occultations and
      the availability of DSN stations, the tracking data are not
      continuous and may have several gaps during a single MESSENGER orbit.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was reviewed by the MESSENGER RS
      Team prior to submission to the Planetary Data System (PDS).
 
      Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data
      set, key elements of the archive were distributed for
      preliminary review.  These included electronic versions of
      example PDS labels, CATALOG files, and Software Interface
      Specifications.  These materials were distributed to PDS
      personnel, the experiment investigator, and others,
      as appropriate.
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Data reported are the minimally processed data received from
      the spacecraft during the the following mission phases:
      Launch, Earth Cruise, Earth Flyby, Venus 1 Cruise,
      Venus 1 Flyby, Venus 2 Cruise, Venus 2 Flyby, Mercury 1 Cruise
      Mercury 1 Flyby, Mercury 2 Cruise, Mercury 2 Flyby,
      Mercury 3 Cruise, Mercury 3 Flyby, Mercury 4 Cruise,
      Mercury Orbit, Mercury Orbit Year 2, Mercury Orbit Year 3 and Mercury
      Orbit Year 4. These mission phases are defined as:
 
                            Start time          End time
      Phase Name            Date (DOY)          Date (DOY)
      -------------------   -----------------  -----------------
      Launch                03 Aug 2004 (216)  12 Sep 2004 (256)
      Earth Cruise          13 Sep 2004 (257)  18 Jul 2005 (199)
      Earth Flyby           19 Jul 2005 (200)  16 Aug 2005 (228)
      Venus 1 Cruise        17 Aug 2005 (229)  09 Oct 2006 (282)
      Venus 1 Flyby         10 Oct 2006 (283)  07 Nov 2006 (311)
      Venus 2 Cruise        08 Nov 2006 (312)  22 May 2007 (142)
      Venus 2 Flyby         23 May 2007 (143)  20 Jun 2007 (171)
      Mercury 1 Cruise      21 Jun 2007 (172)  30 Dec 2007 (364)
      Mercury 1 Flyby       31 Dec 2007 (365)  28 Jan 2008 (028)
      Mercury 2 Cruise      29 Jan 2008 (029)  21 Sep 2008 (265)
      Mercury 2 Flyby       22 Sep 2008 (266)  20 Oct 2008 (294)
      Mercury 3 Cruise      21 Oct 2008 (295)  15 Sep 2009 (258)
      Mercury 3 Flyby       16 Sep 2009 (259)  14 Oct 2009 (287)
      Mercury 4 Cruise      15 Oct 2009 (288)  03 Mar 2011 (062)
      Mercury Orbit         04 Mar 2011 (063)  17 Mar 2012 (077)
      Mercury Orbit Year 2  18 Mar 2012 (078)  17 Mar 2013 (076)
      Mercury Orbit Year 3  18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)
      Mercury Orbit Year 4  18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)
 
      There are RSR files for 6 months starting in late 2006 to cover the
      long solar conjunction for potential use for solar-corona studies.
 
      There are data for the second flyby of Venus, after which there are no
      data until late in 2007, after which the data are archived for all DSN
      contacts.
 
      There are three differences in the data for the flybys: 1) DSN coverage
      increases for the four weeks centered on each flyby, including
      nearly-constant coverage for +/-24 hours; 2) for most of the period
      within three days of close approach, the RF power is at least 20 dB
      below nominal because the low-gain antennas are used; 3) if there is an
      Earth occultation (M1 and M3), there are RSR data. RSR data are
      collected only for occultations and for a solar-conjunction
      investigation in 2006/2007. During flyby occultations, RSR data are
      recorded on multiple antennas, channels, and subchannels in multiple
      sample rates, bit rates, and frequency ranges; the data from each of
      these recordings is in a separate file which is identified by the
      channel and subchannel.
 
      ODF and TNF data are collected during each DSN
      contact. There are both 10-s and 1-s ODF data during portions of
      each flyby. DDOR data are collected irregularly, usually before and
      after critical events such as flybys or propulsive maneuvers. There
      are no DDOR data after MOI. Except for the safe mode that occurred near
      close approach during the third flyby of Mercury, periods of
      off-nominal operations are not documented, here.
 
      During the first twelve months of the
      orbital phase of the mission, there is usually one
      contact using a high-gain antenna (HGA) every other orbit. Each
      MESSENGER orbit lasts 12 hours. Each HGA contact lasts 6-8 hours and
      is during the portions of the orbit where MESSENGER is farther from
      Mercury. There is a low-gain antenna (LGA) contact either before or
      after the HGA contact, and the LGA contact includes the periapsis
      portion of the orbit. The LGA contact also includes any Earth
      occultations that may occur during the orbit. The LGA contact
      varies from 2 to 4 hours. Occasionally, an occultation will occur
      during HGA transmissions. For periods that total approximately 50%
      of the orbital mission, there was a second LGA contact during
      the second orbit that occurred during a 24-hour timespan.
      These second LGA contacts occur during weeks and months
      when the geometry is particularly favorable for
      high-quality Doppler or when there are occultations in Mercury&apos;s
      southern hemisphere, which is not reachable by the laser altimeter.
      Spacecraft activities such as orbit-correction maneuvers or
      momentum-dumping maneuvers may cause modifications to this
      nominal plan.
 
      After switching to an eight-hour orbit period, contacts are less
      frequent, and the HGA data are usually six hours per day or less.
      Most 24-hour periods contain at least one contact that includes
      LGA data for one of the three periapsis passes each 24 hours.
      There are periods when MESSENGER uses the HGA during the periapsis
      pass; these occur when the Earth-Mercury-Sun angle is near
      90 degrees, which is a geometry that has particularly poor
      signal on the LGAs.
 
      RSR data for occultation measurements are captured
      predominantly when the viewing geometry produces good
      signal-to-noise observations,
      when the range to Earth is less than 1 AU.
 
      YY/DDD       Comments
      ------       ----------------
      06/291       Start of RSR solar-conjunction campaign
      07/139       End of RSR solar-conjunction campaign
      07/156       Second flyby of Venus
      07/347       Beginning of complete data archive
      08/014       First flyby of Mercury (M1) Includes an occultation
      08/280       Second flyby of Mercury(no occultation)
      09/272       Third flyby of Mercury (M3) Includes an occultation.
                   RF interrupted by safe mode at 21:57:21 UTC
      11/077       Mercury orbital insertion (MOI).
      12/111       Orbital period reduced to 8 hours.
      13/260       Last data to be included in the delivery 11 data set.
      14/076       Last data to be included in the delivery 12 data set.
      14/260       Last data to be included in the delivery 13 data set.
 
 
      The start and stop days of the periods when Mercury occults
      RF transmissions to Earth are
      YY/DDD to YY/DDD
      11/077 to 11/129
      11/190 to 11/293
      12/045 to 12/120
      12/241 to 12/278
      13/030 to 13/121
      13/231 to 13/264
      14/015 to 14/120
      14/223 to 14/253
      14/361 to 15/086
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The limitations in this data set follow from the quality of
      the execution, which is described above under Data Coverage
      and Quality.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

