<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.go-j-pls-4-summ-avg-counts-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GALILEO JUPITER AVERAGED PLASMA COUNTS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.galileo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:pls.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.callisto::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.europa::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.ganymede::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.io::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-j-pls-4-summ-avg-counts-v1.0__browserp_go-j-pls-4-summ-avg-counts-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Frank, L. A., K. L. Ackerson, J. A. Lee, M. R. English, and G. L. Pickett, The
                   Plasma Instrumentation for the Galileo Mission, Sp. Sci. Rev., 60, 283-307,
                   1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FRANKETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GO-J-PLS-4-SUMM-AVG-COUNTS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GALILEO JUPITER AVERAGED PLASMA COUNTS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2003-11-21</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1995-12-07T15:30Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2003-09-21T18:45Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>XIANZHE JIA</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Frank, L.A., Paterson, W.R., Ackerson, K.L., GALILEO JUPITER
            AVERAGED PLASMA COUNTS V1.0, GO-J-PLS-4-SUMM-AVG-COUNTS-V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 2008.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains averaged raw data from the Plasma Science
            instrument(PLS) on the Galileo spacecraft for all Jupiter orbits.
            These data have been averaged and reformatted into ASCII tables
            to facilitate data display and analysis.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains averaged raw data from the Plasma Science
            instrument(PLS) on the Galileo spacecraft for all Jupiter orbits.
            These data have been averaged and reformatted into ASCII tables
            to facilitate data display and analysis.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Overview:
    =========
 
    This data set contains raw data from the Plasma Science instrument
    (PLS) onboard the Galileo spacecraft during the Jupiter orbital
    operations phase (December 1995 to end of mission). These data have
    been edited, averaged, and reformatted from the raw telemetry packets into
    a simple ASCII tabular structure to display and analysis.
 
 
    Parameters:
    ===========
 
    This data set includes high time resolution (LPW) data recorded
    during targeted encounters Galileo moon encounters and selected
    magnetospheric survey itenrvals when telemetry was available.
 
    The basic data set parameters are the detector count rates in units
    of counts per second. Data are provided at the full instrument
    sampling rate in all sampling parameters (time, detector, E/Q, M/Q).
    The instrument has twenty (20) detectors (seven ion, seven electron,
    six mass spectrometer) and can sample E/Q or M/Q (mass spectrometer
    detectors only) in sixty-four (64) steps for each detector.
 
 
    Processing:
    ===========
 
    These data have been averaged from the PLS uncalibrated full-
    resolution data set (DATA_SET_ID = GO-J-PLS-3-RDR-FULLRES-V1.0).
    Please refer to the data set catalog file for a full description of
    the processing performed on that data set. The following is a
    description of the averaging performed on this data set.
 
    The uncalibrated counts have been averaged over all detectors
    available at each time step.  The time is located at the center of the
    interval. In order to remove data gaps between the detectors, each
    energy channel has been fitted and with a cubic spline.  To smooth the
    data over timesteps, a simple two point running average was used over
    all 64 energy channels in time.  Finally, to smooth the data, an
    average was performed over a square consisting of nine unweighted
    points with the original data point being at the center of the square.
    For simplicity, and due to the similar values across the detectors in
    the E_STEP tables, only the values used in E_STEP_2.TAB were used in
    the plotting and ascii tables.
 
 
    Ancillary Data:
    ===============
 
    Spacecraft Events:
 
    xxx_SEF.TXT   A time ordered file extracted from the As-Run
    Spacecraft Events Files (ARSEF) that provides the timing of events
    that are significant to the plasma experiment. These  events include
    whether or not the instrument is &apos;on&apos;, which type of data are being
    acquired (RTS or  LPW), the time of thruster firings, etc. The &apos;xxx&apos;
    in the file name is the orbit name (i.e. G01 for orbit Ganymede 1).
 
 
    Coordinate System:
    ==================
 
    Data are provided in PLS instrument coordinates. Please refer to the
    instrument description paper [FRANKETAL1992] for a description of the
    instrument mounting, detector fields of view, and spin phase
    sectoring. See also the SECTOR.TAB file in the ancillary data files.
 
 
    Software:
    =========
 
    There is no software provided with this archive.
 
 
    Media/Format:
    =============
 
 
    These data are archived on either CDROM or DVDROM media. The data
    files are stored in a simple ASCII table form that is described by a
    detached PDS label (Table Object). Each table has the following
    structure:
 
    Col#    Name  Format   Description
    ---------------------------------------------------------------------
    1       UTC     A21    Spacecraft event time (UTC) at the average
                           center
    2-65    Counts  e10.2  Average count rates at 64 energy steps
    66-129  Energy  e10.2  Energy for count rate channel of same array
                           index
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Data Coverage/Quality:
    ======================
 
    The data are not continuous in time.  High resolution data were available
    for only short intervals of about an hour each orbit.
 
    The PLS instrument has two analyzers: A and B.  Each analyzer has its own
    sensors, high voltage supplies, analyzer plates, and data paths.  The two
    analyzers normally start a spin-mode at the same time.  And they normally
    end a spin-mode at the same time.  Both data streams are buffered
    internally by the PLS data system and sent out to the spacecraft in a
    packetized telemetry scheme.  Generally, the two streams are interleaved
    on a minor-frame-by-minor-frame basis, but if one analyzer does not have
    data ready and the other does then the telemetry that is ready is sent.
    (Note that the two analyzers have different numbers of sensors and create
    different quantities of data.)
 
    On the ground, the PLS telemetry stream is decommutated and separated into
    A and B data-sets for each spin-mode.  The time tag attached to each
    A-data-set and each B-data-set is the time of the first telemetry packet
    containing some of that data.  As soon as a complete data set has been
    decommutated on the ground it is written to the output file.  And this is
    the key to understanding what is happening.  Sometimes the first data-set
    to appear in the telemetry stream is also the first one to be completed.
    And sometimes the first data-set to appear in the telemetry is the last to
    be completed.  It is essentially a random thing.
 
    It is crucial to note that PLS takes all of its data in a spin-
    synchronized fashion, not in a SCLK-synchronized fashion.  We went to
    great pains to ensure that the data were obtained in well-defined spin
    sectors and in repeatable directions.  Differences of a couple of
    minor-frames are not significant.  The spin-phase angles are the
    quantities of importance.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

