<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mgn-v-rss-4-bsr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MAGELLAN BISTATIC RADAR CALIBRATED DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.magellan::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mgn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.mgn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgn-v-rss-4-bsr-v1.0__browserp_mgn-v-rss-4-bsr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgn-v-rss-4-bsr-v1.0__dvo_geo_mgn-v-rss-4-bsr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.rs::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Pettengill, G.H., P.G. Ford, and R.A. Simpson, Electrical properties of the
                   Venus surface from bistatic radar observations, Science, 272, 1628-1631, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PETTENGILLETAL1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Simpson, R.A., G.L. Tyler, B. Haeusler, M. Paetzold, and R. Mattei, Venus
                   Express bistatic radar: high elevation anomalous reflectivity, Journal of
                   Geophysical Research, submitted, April 2008.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SIMPSONETAL2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MGN-V-RSS-4-BSR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MAGELLAN BISTATIC RADAR CALIBRATED DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2008-10-31</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1994-06-05</start_time>
        <stop_time>1994-06-05</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>RICHARD A. SIMPSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Simpson, R.A., Magellan Bistatic Radar Calibrated Data V1.0,
            MGN-V-RSS-4-BSR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2008.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Calibrated data from three orbits of S-Band (13 cm wavelength)
            Magellan bistatic radar data collected with NASA antenna DSS 63
            on 5 June 1994 when the specular point crossed Maxwell Montes.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Calibrated data from three orbits of S-Band (13 cm wavelength)
            Magellan bistatic radar data collected with NASA antenna DSS 63
            on 5 June 1994 when the specular point crossed Maxwell Montes.
            Similarly processed data were used by Pettengill et al. (SCIENCE,
            272, 1628-1631, 1996) to infer existence of a semiconductor layer
            covering anomalously reflecting regions at high altitude on
            Venus. This new data set includes calibrated time samples of
            receiver output as well as calibrated power spectra and voltage
            cross spectra (between the two received polarizations). The data
            set was written to three DVD+R volumes for delivery to the NASA
            Planetary Data System (PDS).
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      This archive contains calibrated data from Magellan (MGN) Bistatic Radar
      (BSR) experiments conducted on 5 June 1994 at S-Band (13 cm wavelength)
      using the NASA Deep Space Network (DSN) 70-m antenna near Madrid, Spain
      (DSS 63).
 
      During these experiments the specular point crossed Maxwell Montes.  The
      results indicated that the surface material in the Maxwell area behaved
      as a semi-conductor (13 mhos/m) [PETTENGILLETAL1996].
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      Raw data from the MGN BSR experiments were archived in the PDS
      (DATA_SET_ID = MGN-V-RSS-1-BSR-V1.0), but no &apos;higher level&apos; products
      followed during the Magellan era.  In conjunction with analysis of new
      BSR data collected using the Venus Express spacecraft [SIMPSONETAL2008],
      the old MGN S-Band data from Maxwell were reprocessed.  This new data
      set contains time samples which have been calibrated in amplitude (PRR
      directory).  A second set of files (PRT directory) has the major sources
      of Doppler shift and other frequency effects removed, so that the echo
      centroid appears near 12500 Hz in the 25000 Hz bandwidth.  The PRR and
      PRT data are complex double precision time samples in binary files; the
      right-circularly polarized (RCP) and left-circularly polarized (LCP)
      files are coherent.
 
      The SPC directory contains 10-second averages of power spectra and
      voltage cross-spectra derived from the samples in the PRT directory.
      The cross-spectra are between the two received polarizations (RCP and
      LCP).  The SPC files are in ASCII format. There are three SPC files --
      one for each MGN orbit.  The rows in an SPC file are ordered by
      increasing time; within each time step, the rows are ordered by
      increasing frequency.  All of the spectra have 1024 frequency bins
      with 24.4 Hz resolution.
 
      The archive also includes ancillary data: power spectra used to
      &apos;equalize&apos; (flatten) the receiver spectral response (SRF directory),
      polynomial coefficients to calibrate the amplitude (GNC directory) and
      frequency (SC1 and SC2 directories) of the samples, and files useful
      in understanding the Magellan BSR experimental geometry (BSP and SRG
      directories).
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The data flow in creating the calibrated files is illustrated in the
      diagram below.  The text, which follows, describes the steps.
 
 
                                     ODR
                                      |
                                      | 8-bit real samples
                                      |
                                      V
                          RCP      --------      LCP
                        ----------| PREPMO |----------
                       |           --------           |
        16-bit samples |                              | 16-bit samples
                       |                              |
                   ---------                      ---------
                  | PREPFND |                    | PREPFND |
                   ---------                      ---------
                       |                              |
                       | PRP file                     | PRP file
                       | 64I/64Q                      | 64I/64Q
                       |                              |
                   ---------                      ---------
          SRF ---&gt;|   FND   |                    |   FND   | &lt;--- SRF
                   ---------                      ---------
                       |                              |
                       | PRQ file                     | PRQ file
                       | 64I/64Q                      | 64I/64Q
                       |                              |
                   ---------                      ---------
          GNC ---&gt;|   GAIN  |                    |   GAIN  | &lt;--- GNC
                   ---------                      ---------
                       |                              |
  to &lt;------- PRR file |                              | PRR file -------&gt; to
  ARCHIVE      64I/64Q |                              | 64I/64Q      ARCHIVE
                       V                              V
                   ---------                      ---------
                  |  STEER  | &lt;------ SC1 ------&gt;|  STEER  |
                   ---------                      ---------
                       |                              |
              PRS file |                              | PRS file
               64I/64Q |                              | 64I/64Q
                       V                              V
                   ---------                      ---------
                  |  STEER  | &lt;------ SC2 ------&gt;|  STEER  |
                   ---------                      ---------
                       |                              |
  to &lt;------- PRT file |                              | PRT file -------&gt; to
  ARCHIVE      64I/64Q |                              | 64I/64Q      ARCHIVE
                       |          ----------          |
                       |--------&gt;| FNDXLOOK |&lt;--------|
                       |          ----------          |
                       |             |                |
                       V             | Average        V
                   ---------         | Cross      ---------
                  | FNDLOOK |        | Spectrum  | FNDLOOK |
                   ---------         |            ---------
                       |             |                |
               Average |             V                |  Average
              RCP Power|         ------------         | LCP Power
              Spectrum  -------&gt;| BSRMAT2TAB |&lt;-------  Spectrum
                                 ------------
                                       |
                                       | SPC file
                                       V
                                  to ARCHIVE
 
 
      The ODR (Original Data Record) files are from the raw data archive
      (MGN-V-RSS-1-BSR-V1.0).  Program PREPMO unpacks the 8-bit real samples
      and stores them in 16-bit words with separate files for RCP and LCP.
 
      Program PREPFND was designed to reduce the bandwidth of 16-bit sample
      streams by powers of 2 using a bandpass set at an arbitrary location
      within the original bandwidth.  Here we are not interested in reducing
      bandwidth; but the program does allow us to convert from 16-bit real
      samples to double precision complex samples (64I/64Q) in a format which
      can be used as input to other software.  The &apos;preprocessed&apos; files from
      PREPFND have the file name extension PRP.
 
      The FND program does roughly the same thing as PREPFND except that (1)
      it expects complex double precision input and (2) it allows the user to
      &apos;equalize&apos; the spectrum. The input time samples are Fourier transformed,
      the spectrum is divided by the square root of a noise power spectrum
      (SRF file), and the inverse transform is taken to create new time
      samples.  To reduce instabilities in the inversion, there is 50 percent
      overlap in the transforms and only the central 50 percent of the time
      samples from each operation are retained.  Since there is no overlap at
      the beginning of the first block and at the end of the last block, a few
      samples at the beginning and end of the file must be thrown away.
      Output files from FND have a flat frequency response over the central 80
      percent of the window if the reference noise power spectrum (SRF) is
      representative of the receiver filtering.  Names of files coming from
      FND have extension PRQ.
 
      The GAIN program uses polynomial coefficients from a GNC file to compute
      an amplitude scale factor for the time samples in a PRQ file.  The
      coefficients account for changes in attenuator settings in the receiver
      system and also include a scale factor so that an output power spectrum
      is absolutely calibrated in units of zeptowatts (10^-21 W).  Output
      files from GAIN have file name extension PRR.
 
        Note to Users: To ensure that scaling between Stanford and other
        processing software is the same, compare your output with the
        following calculations of average noise power density.  The first 10
        seconds of the file was Fourier transformed (1024-point spectra), the
        244 power spectra were computed and averaged, and then the frequency
        bins indicated were averaged.  Bins from both the lower and upper
        halves of the spectrum were included and care was taken to avoid
        spacecraft, echo, and interference signals.  Units of power density
        are zeptowatts per hertz (where 1 zW = 10^-21 W).
 
             PRR File          Noise Bins       Average Noise Power Density
           ------------   -------------------   ---------------------------
           4156130B.PRR   121-173 and 743-892     0.30199+/-0.00136 zW/Hz
           4156161D.PRR   321-460 and 777-916     0.27723+/-0.00106 zW/Hz
           4156191B.PRR   121-260 and 777-916     0.33472+/-0.00128 zW/Hz
 
      The STEER program uses polynomial coefficients to synthesize a digital
      signal which is &apos;mixed&apos; with the bistatic radar samples.  In the first
      STEER operation, the coefficients are computed to predict the frequency
      of the directly propagating carrier from the spacecraft to the DSN
      antenna in the 25000 Hz bandwidth.  Within the STEER program, it is the
      predicted phase which is actually computed at each sample time.  When
      the predicted phase is subtracted from the sample phase, the frequency
      of the entire spectrum is shifted.  If the prediction is perfect, the
      directly propagating carrier will be shifted to exactly 12500 Hz, the
      center of the frequency window.  All other signals in the spectrum will
      be shifted an equal amount, effectively &apos;rotating&apos; the spectrum so that
      signals shifted out of the high end of the window reappear at the low
      end.  The first STEER operation uses coefficients from the SC1
      directory; output files from this processing have file name extensions
      PRS.
 
      In the second stage of STEER processing, the frequency differential
      between the carrier and the surface echo is computed from polynominal
      coefficients in the SC2 directory.  In the output the centroid of the
      surface echo is moved to the center of the frequency window.  Output
      files from this step have files names with extensions PRT.
 
      The FNDLOOK program computes average power spectra from time samples
      in the PRT file. If the amplitude scaling has been carried out correctly
      in the GAIN step, the spectra will accurately reflect the power reaching
      the receiver in each frequency bin of the spectrum.
 
      The FNDXLOOK program computes the average cross spectrum between the RCP
      and LCP receiver channels.  If R(f) is a single voltage spectrum from
      the RCP receiver and  conj{L(f)} is the complex conjugate of the
      corresponding voltage spectrum from the LCP receiver, then the cross
      spectrum is
 
                                 R(f)*conj{L(f)}
 
      and a time average of the cross spectrum can be denoted as
 
                                &lt;R(f)*conj{L(f)}&gt;
 
      Because the cross spectrum is a complex number, its average is computed
      by averaging the real part of the individual spectra, averaging the
      imaginary part of the individual spectra, and constructing a new complex
      value from the averages of the two parts.
 
        Note: Because the processing steps are identical for the RCP and LCP
              signals (and the SC1 and SC2 coefficents are applied in the same
              way), the PRT files for RCP and LCP remain coherent.  There may
              be small errors in the frequencies of the surface echoes, but
              both RCP and LCP have the same errors and a cross-correlation
              of the PRT files from each channel will show the same phase
              relationship as was true at the receiving antenna.
 
      BSRMAT2TAB takes the RCP power spectra, the LCP power spectra, and the
      cross spectra and constructs an ASCII file in which they are organized
      first according to time and secondly by frequency.  Each row in the
      output (SPC) file contains an RCP power, an LCP power, a magnitude of
      the cross spectrum, and a phase of the cross spectrum for a single
      time and frequency.  The design of the SPC file allows for inclusion of
      both X-Band and S-Band values; since no X-Band data were included in
      this reprocessing effort, the X-Band columns have been set to zero.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      PRR Data: Amplitude-corrected time samples are a primary data type for
      this archive; these are found in the PRR directory.  A power spectrum
      computed from a PRR file should be absolutely calibrated in units of
      zeptowatts (10^-21 W).  PRR files have a single header record followed
      by many data records containing double-precision complex time samples.
      Each file is defined as a pair of PDS TABLE objects with the first
      TABLE corresponding to the header record and the remaining (data)
      records making up the second TABLE.  A typical PRR file contains
      16 minutes of data with a complex I/Q pair of samples every 40
      microseconds (25000 samples per second).  A single (binary) complex
      sample requires 16 bytes for storage; the volume of a 16-minute file
      is 383975424 bytes.  File names have the form  ydddhhMC.PRR  where  y
      is the one-digit year (4),  ddd  is the three-digit day of year (156),
      hh  is  the two-digit hour,  and  M  is the tens of minutes when the
      file started.  C  is a letter denoting frequency band and polarization
      of the data in the file; valid choices are  B  for S-Band RCP and  D
      for S-Band LCP.  Each PRR file is accompanied by a detached ASCII PDS
      label which describes both the content and format of the file and has
      file name  ydddhhMC.LBL.
 
      PRT Data: Amplitude-corrected time samples which have also been
      corrected for the major sources of Doppler shift and other frequency
      effects are the second primary data type; these are found in the PRT
      directory.  The corrections for Doppler and other frequency effects
      should place the surface echo centroid in the range 10000-15000 Hz,
      where the total bandwidth is 25000 Hz.  The structure and naming of
      PRT files is identical to that for PRR files except for the file name
      extension (PRT).  Each PRT file is accompanied by a detached PDS
      label which describes both the content and format of the file and
      has file name  ydddhhMC.LBL.
 
      SPC Data:  The third type of primary data is the SPC file.  These are
      ASCII files containing power spectra, cross-spectrum magnitudes, and
      cross-spectrum phases. There are three SPC files -- one for each MGN
      orbit.  The first 8 or 12 rows in an SPC file contain a header (a PDS
      TABLE object) listing source files (receiver channel, PRP file name,
      SRF file name, and GNC file name).  The remaining rows contain the
      power and voltage cross-spectra measurements (a second PDS TABLE).
      The rows are ordered by time; within each time step, the rows are
      ordered by frequency.  Columns in the data part of an SPC file give:
 
         spectrum number
         center time for the average spectrum (seconds)
         frequency bin number
         frequency corresponding to the bin number (Hz)
         average X-Band RCP power (set to zero in this archive)
         average X-Band LCP power (set to zero in this archive)
         average S-Band RCP power (zeptowatts)
         average S-Band LCP power (zeptowatts)
         average X-Band cross-spectrum magnitude (set to zero)
         average X-Band cross-spectrum phase (set to zero)
         average S-Band cross-spectrum magnitude (zeptowatts)
         average S-Band cross-spectrum phase (radians)
 
      All of the spectra have 1024 frequency bins with 24.4 Hz resolution.
      For the first BSR orbit there are 192 time steps of 10 seconds each; for
      the second and third orbits, there are 288 time steps of 10 seconds
      each.
 
      SPC files have names of the form ydddhhMB.SPC where &apos;y&apos;, &apos;ddd&apos;, and &apos;M&apos;
      are the same as for PRR files and &apos;B&apos; indicates that these are the
      second versions created of each file.  The &apos;A&apos; versions were preliminary
      and have not been included in the archive.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      Ancillary files were used directly in the calibration process (GNC, SC1,
      SC2, and SRF directories) or could be used during interpretation (BSP
      and SRG directories).  They are described briefly below in the order in
      which they might be encountered during calibration.
 
      The SRF directory contains power spectra for the RCP (4156134B.SRF) and
      LCP (4156134D.SRF) channels which were used to &apos;equalize&apos; (flatten) the
      spectral response of the filters in the receiving system.  Each file is
      a 1024-point power spectrum computed from 227 seconds of noise data.
      Since the filtering is entirely digital, there is no reason to believe
      that the RCP and LCP noise power spectra would differ; but separate SRF
      files have been derived for the two channels.  Standard deviation of
      individual frequency bins is about 1.3 percent of the mean.  Each file
      includes an attached PDS label.
 
      The GNC directory contains ASCII files of coefficients for polynomials
      used to adjust the amplitude of the samples from a single receiver
      channel.  The gain calibration accounts for changes in receiver
      attenuator settings and the system temperature of the channel.  File
      4156130B.GNC contains gain coefficients for all S-RCP observations on
      5 June 1994; file 4156130D.GNC contains coefficients for all S-LCP
      observations.  Each GNC file is accompanied by a detached PDS label
      having the same file name except for the extension (LBL).
 
      The SC1 directory contains ASCII files of coefficients for polynomials
      used to adjust the frequency of the directly propagating carrier signal
      so that it is approximately centered in the 25000 Hz output bandwidth.
      Each SC1 file covers approximately 16 minutes in (nominally) one
      second steps and is valid for both RCP and LCP.  The SC1 files were
      created in the 1990&apos;s and were reformatted for archive in 2008.  File
      names have the form  ydddhhmm.SC1  where &apos;y&apos; and &apos;ddd&apos; are the same as
      for PRR files and &apos;hh&apos; and &apos;mm&apos; give the start hour and minute,
      respectively, for the data in each file.  Each SC1 file is accompanied
      by a PDS detached label having the same name except for the extension
      (LBL).
 
      The SC2 directory contains ASCII files of coefficients for polynomials
      used to adjust the frequency of the surface echo so that it is
      approximately centered in the 25000 Hz output bandwidth.  It is assumed
      that the directly propagating carrier was centered in the previous
      processing step, so this is a differential frequency correction.
      Each SC2 file covers a single MGN orbit in (nominally) 10 second
      steps and is valid for both RCP and LCP.  The SC2 files were created
      in the 1990&apos;s and were reformatted for archive in 2008.  File names
      have the form  ydddhhmm.SC2,  where the components have the same
      meaning as for SC1 files.  Each file is accompanied by a PDS detached
      label having the same name except for the extension (LBL).
 
      The BSP directory contains the spacecraft and planetary ephemerides
      for 5 June 1994 (4156156A.BSP).  The spacecraft ephemerides were
      derived from a Magellan &apos;SPK&apos; file (CYCLE6.BSP), obtained from the
      Navigation and Ancillary Information Facility (NAIF) at the NASA
      Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL).  The spacecraft ephemerides were
      then merged with the JPL DE-421 solar system ephemeris (DE421.BSP),
      also obtained from NAIF.  The BSP file is accompanied by a PDS
      minimal label which points to additional information on NAIF, its
      products and tools, and documentation on this &apos;SPK&apos; file.
 
      The SRG directory contains a single file (4156156A.SRG) summarizing
      the MGN BSR experiment geometry at one minute time increments over
      eight hours starting at 1994-06-05T13:00:00.  This is an ASCII file
      containing a single header row followed by 480 data rows.  The SRG
      file is accompanied by a PDS label (4156156A.LBL) which describes the
      content and format of the data file.
 
      The SRG header row gives:
 
        01) DSN antenna number (63)
        02) input BSP file name (4156156A.BSP)
        03) assumed spherical radius of Venus (6051800 m)
        04) assumed speed of light in vacuum (299792458 m/s)
        05) latitude of a specific target (arbitrarily set to +70 deg))
        06) longitude of a specific target (arbitrarily set to 0 deg)
        07) time spacing between rows in the data table (60 seconds)
 
      The SRG data rows contain the following.  &apos;Specific target&apos; is the
      surface point with latitude and longitude given in positions 5-6 of
      the header row.  &apos;Backscatter point&apos; is where a line drawn from
      the DSN antenna through the spacecraft (and beyond) would intercept
      the surface.  The raypath closest approach (RCA) point is where such
      a line would be closest to Venus if there were no intercept and if
      Venus were between the DSN and spacecraft.  The specular point is
      where spacecraft-to-surface-to-DSN mirror-like reflection would occur.
      If the spacecraft is in occultation, these points are not meaningful;
      existence of the backscatter point precludes existence of the RCA
      point.  Vectors are in J2000 coordinates, distances are in meters,
      velocities are in m/s, and angles are in degrees.
 
        01) Earth received time (ERT, seconds from midnight UTC)
        02) corresponding transmit time at Venus (seconds from midnight)
        03) Venus north pole vector (x,y,z components)
        04) Venus fixed-body x-axis (x,y,z components)
        05) Venus fixed-body y-axis (x,y,z components)
        06) Venus center to DSN antenna vector
        07) Venus center to MGN spacecraft vector
        08) MGN spacecraft to DSN antenna vector
        09) Venus center to specific target vector
        10) Specific target to DSN antenna vector
        11) Specific target to MGN spacecraft vector
        12) Incidence angle at the specific target
        13) Scattering angle at the specific target
        14) Spacecraft-target-DSN angle
        15) Venus center to backscatter point vector
        16) Latitude of the backscatter point
        17) Longitude of the backscatter point
        18) Venus center to RCA point
        19) Latitude of the RCA point
        20) Longitude of the RCA point
        21) Venus center to specular point vector
        22) Incidence angle at the specular point
        23) Reflection angle at the specular point
        24) Latitude of the specular point
        25) Longitude of the specular point
        26) Partial derivative of (12) with respect to Venus radius
        27) Partial derivative of (13) with respect to Venus radius
        28) Partial derivative of (14) with respect to Venus radius
        29) Partial derivative of (16) with respect to Venus radius
        30) Partial derivative of (17) with respect to Venus radius
        31) Partial derivative of (22) with respect to Venus radius
        32) Partial derivative of (23) with respect to Venus radius
        33) Partial derivative of (24) with respect to Venus radius
        34) Partial derivative of (25) with respect to Venus radius
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      In general the J2000 inertial reference frame is used.  But the radio
      data are not dependent on frames, and the NAIF software allows easy
      translation among coordinate systems.  The only file for which a
      coordinate system matters is the SRG file.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      No software is included with this archival data set.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      This archival data set was transferred to TDK and Taiyo Yuden DVD+R
      media using a Dell computer with a Plextor PX712A writer.  The software
      was Padus Disc Juggler running under the Windows XP2 operating system.
      Discs have been produced in the UDF-Bridge format with ISO 9660 Level 1
      compatibility.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      This data set is the result of reprocessing the Magellan S-Band bistatic
      radar data collected at DSS 63 on 5 June 1994.  These observations were
      the most useful for assessing the behavior of the anomalously reflecting
      materials at high elevation on Venus [PETTENGILLETAL1996].
 
      Data collected at X-Band on 5 June 1994 were not processed because there
      was little evidence that an echo had been captured (high absorption by
      the neutral atmosphere at 3.6 cm wavelength).  No data collected on the
      same date at DSS 14 were processed -- pointing errors at that ground
      station reduced signals by as much as 10 dB.  Data from other dates were
      not processed because the targets or viewing geometry appeared to be
      less promising.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was reviewed by a peer review panel prior
      to its acceptance by the Planetary Data System (PDS).  The peer
      review was conducted by the PDS Geosciences Node in accordance with PDS
      procedures.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Eight quasi-specular tracks were observed using two 70-m DSN antennas
      on 5-6 June 1994.  Each track extended from south of the Venus equator
      to beyond Maxwell Montes in the north.  The objective was to observe
      changes in reflected signal amplitude and dispersion as the specular
      point moved over different surface units.  Of particular interest was
      Maxwell Montes, targeted five days earlier in a spotlight bistatic
      experiment.  Real-time observation of echoes at S-band and possible
      detection (with intense non-real-time processing) of X-band echoes
      were predicted for 5 June 1994.
 
      Data were collected during six orbits using DSS 63 near Madrid; data
      from four orbits were collected using DSS 14 near Goldstone.  Madrid
      began by receiving S-RCP and S-LCP on the first orbit, switched to
      X-RCP and X-LCP on the second, and continued to alternate on
      successive orbits thereafter.  Previous experience had shown that
      attempting to record both S-Band and X-Band signals at 25000 samples
      per second at a single antenna led to errors.  On the fifth orbit,
      DSS 14 began with X-RCP and X-LCP (while DSS 63 collected S-RCP and
      S-LCP), and alternated thereafter.
 
      Tuning predictions for the open-loop receivers were calculated
      at Stanford; owing to a sign error, the predictions failed to
      achieve the desired result, but real-time corrections to the tuning
      (manual frequency offsets) were sufficient to keep the S-band signal
      within the passband for all but parts of the first DSS 63 orbit.
      S-band echoes were observed in real time from DSS 63; no X-band
      echoes were seen.
 
      At DSS 14 an error in ground antenna pointing reduced signal levels
      considerably; those data have very little value when compared with
      with the data from DSS 63.
 
      Some of the tapes received from DSS 63 had truncated records; these
      errors only affected the X-Band recordings. About half of the tapes
      received from DSS 14 were unreadable.
 
      The tables below summarize the data which were reprocessed and have
      been included in the calibrated data archive.  All were from 5 June
      1994, collected at DSS 63 using S-Band (13 cm wavelength).  The
      notation  4156130{B,D}.PRR  means that the S-RCP file name is
      4156130B.PRR and the S-LCP file name is 4156130D.PRR.  The &apos;missing&apos;
      PRT files included only times when there was no surface echo.
 
      =====================================================================
        Start       Stop     Calibrated Complex   Calibrated Complex Time
         Time       Time        Time Samples     Samples with Echo Centered
        (ERT)      (ERT)      (PRR Directory)            in Spectrum
                                                       (PRT Directory)
      ---------- ---------- -------------------  --------------------------
       13:09:31   13:25:30    4156130{B,D}.PRR        4156130{B,D}.PRT
       13:25:31   13:41:30    4156132{B,D}.PRR        4156132{B,D}.PRT
       13:41:31   13:48:39    4156134{B,D}.PRR
       15:58:12   16:14:11    4156155{B,D}.PRR        4156155{B,D}.PRT
       16:14:12   16:30:11    4156161{B,D}.PRR        4156161{B,D}.PRT
       16:30:12   16:46:11    4156163{B,D}.PRR        4156163{B,D}.PRT
       16:46:12   16:54:17    4156164{B,D}.PRR
       19:10:25   19:26:24    4156191{B,D}.PRR        4156191{B,D}.PRT
       19:26:25   19:42:24    4156192{B,D}.PRR        4156192{B,D}.PRT
       19:42:25   19:58:24    4156194{B,D}.PRR        4156194{B,D}.PRT
       19:58:25   20:00:23    4156195{B,D}.PRR
      =====================================================================
 
      =====================================================================
             Start       Stop    Calibrated Power  Number    Number  of
              Time       Time       and Voltage      of    Frequency Bins
             (ERT)      (ERT)     Cross-Spectra     Time         per
                                 (SPC Directory)    Steps    Time  Step
           ---------- ---------- ----------------  ------  --------------
            13:09:31   13:41:31    4156130B.SPC      192        1024
            15:58:12   16:46:12    4156155B.SPC      288        1024
            19:10:25   19:58:25    4156191B.SPC      288        1024
      =====================================================================
 
      For the three orbits which were reprocessed, the data are reasonably
      good.  But several points are worth noting:
 
        (1) Interfering signals originating on Earth passed through the
            frequency range occupied by the surface echo; but the geometry
            was slightly different on each orbit.  At most, only the data
            from the first BSR orbit were seriously compromised when the
            interfering signal passed through the surface echo at the same
            time (13:31) as the specular point was moving across Maxwell
            Montes.
 
        (2) The masers on both S-Band channels were unstable on time scales
            of seconds to minutes.  The S-RCP gain variation was relatively
            unimportant, but variations in the S-LCP gain of as much as 1 dB
            made the attempt at absolute calibration only marginally
            successful and produced false polarization signatures for noise
            which should have been random.  Forcing the background noise to
            be the same on both channels might be a better procedure in a
            future analysis even though it would lead to small errors in the
            inferred polarization of the surface echoes.
 
        (3) The GNC coefficients were chosen to give a 15 dB correction to
            sample values when S-RCP attenuation was increased or decreased
            by 15 dB, the nominal value.  The result is perfectly accurate
            in the sense that no discontinuity can be seen in the output
            S-RCP sample values after correction.  On S-LCP a 15 dB GNC
            correction proved too much, so 14.5 dB was used instead.  In
            retrospect, this was too little; a GNC correction of 14.75 dB
            appears to have been the best choice.  Since the S-LCP channel
            was already known to be unstable at the 1 dB level, no attempt
            was made to recalibrate the amplitudes to remove the 0.25 dB
            discontinuities and they can be seen in the PRR and PRT data.
 
        (4) The frequency calibration, following procedures which have easily
            located Voyager and other signals to 1 Hz, put Magellan BSR echoes
            into the desired 10000-15000 Hz window but without much additional
            precision. The most likely source of frequency error is drift of
            Magellan&apos;s on-board frequency reference, perhaps affected by
            temperature as the spacecraft maneuvered to maintain equal
            illumination in the horizontal and vertical polarization planes.
            The apparent frequency of the echo peak and its drift (as it
            appears in the SPC files) is listed below.  Note that drift of
            the echo does not invalidate the cross-spectrum values because
            the same phase corrections were applied to both polarizations;
            however, the bin location of any given cross-spectrum value will
            be offset, just as the bins of the S-RCP and S-LCP power spectra
            will be offset.
 
                 =======================================================
                 Experiment  Start    Start     End      End     Average
                              Time  Frequency   Time  Frequency   Drift
                              (s)      (Hz)     (s)      (Hz)     (Hz/s)
                 ----------  -----  ---------  -----  ---------  -------
                      1      47580    14150    48980    12500      -1.18
                      2      58700    13250    60100    12000      -0.89
                      3      69900    13000    71200    12100      -0.69
                 =======================================================
 
        (5) [PETTENGILLETAL1996] reported 1-second averaging to obtain echo
            properties.  Partly because of software limitations, the
            integration used here was 10 seconds.
 
        (6) In spite of the issues listed above, the calibrated data do show
            an excess of RCP echo power when the specular point was over
            Maxwell Montes, and especially when it was near Cleopatra Patera.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The limitations in this data set follow from the quality of
      the execution, which is described above under Data Coverage
      and Quality.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

