<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mro-m-rss-1-magr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MRO MARS RAW RADIO SCIENCE 1 V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.mro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-rss-1-magr-v1.0__browserp_mro-m-rss-1-magr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-rss-1-magr-v1.0__browser_geo_mars_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-rss-1-magr-v1.0__dvo_mro-m-rss-1-magr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Deep Space Mission System (DSMS) External Interface Specification (820-013, JPL
                   D-16765), Radio Science Receiver Standard Formatted Data Unit (SFDU), Jet
                   Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JPLD-16765</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kahan, D.S., Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter, MRO Radio Science Receiver Software
                   Interface Description, An Ad Hoc Revision of 820-013 Deep Space Network (DSN)
                   External Interface Specification (JPL D-16765), Radio Science Receiver Standard
                   Formatted Data Unit (SFDU), Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, 2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KAHAN2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MRO-M-RSS-1-MAGR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MRO MARS RAW RADIO SCIENCE 1 V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2009-06-08</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2006-08-30</start_time>
        <stop_time>2008-11-08</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DANIEL S. KAHAN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            KAHAN, D.S., Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter Gravity Science Raw Data
            Set V1.0, MRO-M-RSS-1-MAGR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2009.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Raw radio science data and ancillary files from the Mars
            Reconnaissance Orbiter mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains archival raw, partially processed, and
            ancillary/supporting radio science data acquired during the Mars
            Reconnaissance Orbiter (MRO) mission. The radio observations were
            carried out using the MRO spacecraft and Earth-based receiving
            stations of the NASA Deep Space Network (DSN). The data set was
            designed primarily to support generation of high-resolution
            gravity field models for Mars and secondarily for estimating
            density and structure of the Mars atmosphere. Of most interest
            are likely to be the Orbit Data Files and Radio Science Receiver
            files in the ODF and RSR directories, respectively, which
            provided the raw input to gravity and atmospheric investigations,
            as well as the ionospheric and tropospheric media calibration
            files in the ION and TRO directories, respectively.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter (MRO) Gravity Science (GR) Raw
      Data Archive (RDA) is the set of raw and partially processed
      radio science data collected during the MRO mission to Mars.
 
      The earliest data in this data set were collected
      on 2006-08-30.
 
      Two types of measurements were conducted, known as closed- and
      open-loop recordings. The closed-loop system used a
      phase-lock loop in the ground receiver to track the downlink
      signal, reporting both amplitude and frequency at rates
      typically of 1-10 times per second. In the open-loop system,
      the signal was simply converted to a baseband frequency range;
      the entire passband was sampled and recorded for later
      processing. Typical open-loop sampling rates for MRO were 1000
      samples per second. Closed-loop data are efficient for
      characterizing slowly changing signals and are the input to
      operational navigation and orbit-determination processes.
      Open-loop data (because of their much higher rate and volume)
      are collected only when the signal is expected to be very
      dynamic -- such as during a spacecraft maneuver or an
      occultation.
 
      The data set includes three primary data types. Tracking and
      Navigation Service Data Files (TNFs) are the most primitive (and
      most voluminous) product of the closed-loop system.  Orbit Data
      Files (ODFs) are compressed versions of TNFs, specifically
      targeted to spacecraft navigators and scientists interested in
      gravity fields.  Radio Science Receiver records (RSRs) are the
      primary data type from the open-loop system.
 
      Typical users of these data might analyze range and Doppler
      measurements in ODFs to reconstruct the spacecraft trajectory.
      Relevant questions would include the measurement uncertainties
      in range and Doppler at different DSN antennas; the uncertainties
      could set constraints on any model of Mars&apos; gravity field developed
      later, for example.
 
      The TNF data are generally reserved for use in more sophisticated
      investigations or where information beyond what is available in
      the ODF may be required.  For example, the TNF may be used to
      extract the station uplink frequency ramps, which give the
      tuning of the uplink transmitted signal in cases when a constant
      frequency is inadequate.
 
      RSR data were collected when the signal transmitted by the
      spacecraft was expected to be particularly dynamic, such as
      during a radio occultation by the atmosphere.  When an
      occultation was observed using an RSR, the spacecraft was
      usually configured to be in a carrier-only mode (no telemetry
      modulation) and the ground equipment was operated by the Radio
      Science Systems Group at JPL.   Two variations of the RSR were
      used during MRO; see the &apos;Data&apos; section below for details.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      The TNF is the primary output from the MRO closed-loop system.
      In the TNF about 20 record types are defined, each designed
      for a particular audience, although it was frequently the case
      that users needed more than one record type. The emphasis of
      the data is on phase of the transmitted and received signals.
      Each TNF is accompanied by a PDS minimal label which points
      to a software specification document (TNF_SIS.TXT) in the
      DOCUMENT directory of the archive for detailed descriptions
      of the records and fields.
 
      The ODF is a compressed version of the TNF. It contains the most
      important information (range, Doppler and frequency ramps)
      needed by spacecraft investigators, and investigators interested
      in determining gravity fields. Each ODF is accompanied by a full
      PDS label which describes both the content and format of the
      associated file. ODF data fields include:
 
           Narrowband spacecraft VLBI, Doppler mode (cycles)
           Narrowband spacecraft VLBI, phase mode (cycles)
           Narrowband quasar VLBI, Doppler mode (cycles)
           Narrowband quasar VLBI, phase mode (cycles)
           Wideband spacecraft VLBI (nanoseconds)
           Wideband quasar VLBI (nanoseconds)
           One-way Doppler (Hertz)
           Two-way Doppler (Hertz)
           Three-way Doppler (Hertz)
           One-way total count phase (cycles)
           Two-way total count phase (cycles)
           Three-way total count phase (cycles)
           PRA planetary operational discrete spectrum range (range
                units)
           SRA planetary operational discrete spectrum range (range
                units)
           RE(GSTDN) range (nanoseconds)
           Azimuth angle (degrees)
           Elevation angle (degrees)
           Hour angle (degrees)
           Declination angle (degrees)
 
      Radio Science Receiver (RSR) records contain samples of open
      loop receiver output; the samples are complex and can have
      1-16 bits in both the in-phase (I) and quadrature (Q)
      components, depending on sampling rate and precision
      requested.  Sampling rates between 1 ksps and 16 Msps may
      be requested. Each RSR file is accompanied by a full PDS
      label which describes both the format and the content
      at the bit level.  RSR data collected early in the MRO mission
      are described by original documentation [JPLD-16765].
      Beginning on January 16, 2008, externally generated frequency
      predictions for tuning the RSR were provided in a companion
      downlink frequency (DLF) file, which must be used in conjunction
      with the RSR records [KAHAN2009].
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      Typical TNFs contained data from a 24-hour period, combining
      data from several antennas if there were multiple passes in
      one day. The files archived for MRO were not screened for
      &apos;bad&apos; points.
 
      ODFs are abstracted from subsets of TNF data.  A full PDS label
      accompanies each ODF file and gives a bit level description of
      the content and format.
 
      RSR data were modified during Ground Data System handling so that
      MISSION_ID in the Primary Header CHDO was set to 5.  Data which were
      recorded on the VLBI Science Receiver (VSR), then converted to RSR
      format, were assigned the following values in the header(s):
        MINOR_DATA_CLASS = 5   (normally  4) Primary Header CHDO
        ORIGINATOR_ID    = 123 (normally 48) Secondary Header CHDO
        LAST_MODIFIER_ID = 123 (normally 48) Secondary Header CHDO
      A VSR was used for MRO when all of the available RSRs had been
      assigned to other missions.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      The data set contains primary data and secondary data.  Primary
      data are those files which would normally be used to derive science
      products and investigation results.  Secondary data are needed
      for the processing or interpretation of primary data but are
      not usually considered to have science value of their own.
      There are three types of primary data.  Listings of primary and
      secondary files can be found in INDEX/INDEX.TAB for the data set
      (as of the most recent delivery).
 
      TNFs contain the most primitive (and most voluminous) output
      from the closed-loop radio science system; they are stored in
      the TNF directory.  They have file names of the form
      MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_hhmmXuuwVn.TNF  where &apos;MROMAGR&apos; identifies the
      mission and the data set; &apos;yyyy&apos; is the four-digit year, &apos;ddd&apos;
      is the three-digit day-of-year, &apos;hh&apos; is the two-digit hour,
      and &apos;mm&apos; is the two-digit minute at the beginning of the file;
      &apos;X&apos; indicates an X-Band uplink (&apos;N&apos; denotes no uplink);
      &apos;uu&apos; indicates the uplink station (set to &apos;NN&apos; for no uplink or
      &apos;MM&apos; for two or more uplinking stations during the time interval
      covered), &apos;w&apos; indicates the downlink mode (&apos;1&apos;, &apos;2&apos;, &apos;3&apos;, or &apos;M&apos;
      for 1-way, 2-way, 3-way, or &apos;multiple&apos;, respectively), and &apos;Vn&apos;
      indicates the version number of the file. A detached PDS minimal
      label accompanies each TNF; label files have names of the form
      MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_hhmmXuuwVn.LBL.  TNFs in this data set were
      usually generated at a 1-second sampling rate.
 
      ODFs are stored in the ODF directory. ODFs are edited and/or
      compressed derivatives of TNFs.  File names are of the form
      MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_hhmmXuuwVn.ODF where the field interpretations
      are the same as for the TNF.  The ODF label has file name
      MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_hhmmXuuwVn.LBL. The typical ODF contains about
      3 Mbytes. ODFs in this data set were usually generated at a
      1-second sampling rate.
 
      RSR files are stored in the RSR directory; they are the primary
      output of the open-loop radio science system.  RSR files have
      names of the form  074MAOZyyyyddd_hhmmXuuYvvQS.abc  where
      &apos;074&apos; is the spacecraft number; &apos;MAO&apos; denotes Mars occultation;
      &apos;Z&apos; is either &apos;E&apos; for egress or &apos;I&apos; for ingress; &apos;yyyy&apos; is the
      four-digit year, &apos;ddd&apos; is the day of year, &apos;hh&apos; is the two-digit
      hour, and &apos;mm&apos; is the two-digit minute when data began; &apos;X&apos; is
      the uplink band (set to &apos;N&apos; if there was no uplink);
      &apos;uu&apos; is the uplink station
      (or &apos;NN&apos; for none or &apos;MM&apos; for multiple); &apos;Y&apos; is the downlink band;
      &apos;vv&apos; is the receiving station; &apos;Q&apos; is the receiving polarization
      (&apos;R&apos; for right-circular or &apos;L&apos; for left-circular); &apos;S&apos; indicates
      the data source (&apos;D&apos; for standard data originating on the RSR
      [JPLD-16765], &apos;M&apos; for non-standard RSR data [KAHAN2009], &apos;V&apos;
      for VSR data converted to RSR format, and &apos;W&apos; for wide-band VSR
      data converted to RSR format); and &apos;abc&apos; identifies the RSR, the
      RSR channel, and the RSR sub-channel of the recording. Each RSR
      file is accompanied by a full PDS label which describes both the
      format and the content of the data file; the label file name has
      the form  074MAOZyyyyddd_hhmmXuuYvvQS.LBL.
 
      NB: RSR data were collected using four versions of data acquisition
      software, identified by &apos;S&apos; in the file name (see above). &apos;D&apos; files
      are standard, have standard labels, and are documented in
      [JPLD-16765].  Although &apos;V&apos; and &apos;W&apos; files were collected using
      different systems, the data files have been converted to the
      [JPLD-16765] format.  A few of the fields in the &apos;V&apos; and &apos;W&apos;
      headers may have values that would not be expected in the &apos;D&apos;
      format.  &apos;M&apos; files are non-standard, have different labels, and
      require different processing, as documented in [KAHAN2009].
      &apos;D&apos; files were collected early in the MRO mission; after
      2008-01-16, all MRO RSR files were &apos;M&apos; files.  Processing of the
      &apos;M&apos; files requires use of Downlink Frequency (DLF) Files.  The
      documents [JPLD-16765] and [KAHAN2009] can be found in the
      DOCUMENT directory of this archive.
 
 
    Secondary Data
    ==============
      An extensive set of ancillary files is needed for proper analysis
      and interpretation of the data.   In the paragraphs below
      &apos;yyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd&apos; gives the start and end dates of the data in
      the file.  All ASCII files have records delimited by an ASCII
      carriage-return (ASCII 13) line-feed (ASCII 10) pair.  In some cases
      (especially for NAIF files) the &lt;CR&gt;&lt;LF&gt; may need to be converted to
      either &lt;CR&gt; or &lt;LF&gt; before the file is used on the local machine.
 
      Antenna Gimbal and Solar Array Kernel Files (AGK and SAK Directories)
      -------------------------------------------
        Antenna Gimbal Kernel files and Solar Array Kernel Files were
        produced by the JPL Navigation and Ancillary Information Facility
        (NAIF). Each AGK file contains information on the state of the
        HGA azimuth and elevation gimbals as a function of time.  Each SAK
        file contains information on the solar array gimbals.  These are
        ASCII files in NAIF transfer format.  File names have the form
        MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.AGK  or  MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.SAK.
        Each AGK or SAK file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with
        file name MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.LBL. Typical file sizes are
        1 MByte.
 
      Downlink Frequency Files (DLF Directory)
      ----------------------------------------
        Downlink Frequency files are ASCII files produced by the DSN for
        tuning an open-loop receiver (RSR) during some radio science
        activities.  They list the best pre-experiment estimates of the
        spacecraft sky frequency at specific times and a set of Everett
        polynomial coefficients for interpolation. File names have the
        form MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_hhmmXvvwVn.DLF, where &apos;X indicates that
        X-Band is used for downlink, &apos;vv&apos; is the downlink station number,
        &apos;w&apos; is the downlink mode (&apos;1&apos; for one-way, &apos;2&apos; for two-way, &apos;3&apos;
        for three-way, or &apos;M&apos; for multiple), and &apos;Vn&apos; is the version
        number.  Each file is accompanied by a PDS detached label having
        file name MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_hhmmXvvwVn.LBL.  Typical file size is
        250 KB.
 
      Earth Orientation Parameter Files (EOP Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Earth Orientation Parameter files are ASCII files produced by the
        Kalman Earth Orientation Filter (KEOF) Group at JPL. File names have
        the form MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.EOP. Each EOP file is accompanied
        by a PDS minimal label with file name MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.LBL.
        Typical file size is 24 KB.
 
      Ionosphere Calibration Files (ION Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Ionosphere Calibration files are ASCII files produced by the Tracking
        System Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL. They provide
        historical and predicted Earth ionospheric conditions. File
        names have the form MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.ION. Each ION
        file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.LBL. Typical file size is 23 KB.
 
      Light Time Files (LTF Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Light Time files were produced by the MRO Navigation Team
        (NAV). They give radio propagation time from the spacecraft
        to Earth vs time. These are ASCII files of fixed length
        records. File names have the form MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.LTF.
        Each LTF file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file
        name MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.LBL. Typical file sizes are less
        than 1 MB.
 
      Maneuver Performance Data Files (MPD Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Maneuver Performance Data files were produced by the MRO
        Spacecraft Team (SCT). They contain estimates of spacecraft
        mass and center of mass; moments of inertia; thruster
        locations, directions, and magnitudes; and propellant flow
        rate. These are ASCII files of variable length records.
        File names have the form MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.MPD. Each MPD
        file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        sssttaayyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.LBL. Typical file sizes are 4 kB.
 
      Small Forces File (SFF Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Small Forces Files were created from the MRO spacecraft
        engineering telemetry stream. These are ASCII files of
        variable length records.  File names have the form
        MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.MPD.  Each SFF file is accompanied by a
        PDS minimal label with file name MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.LBL.
        Typical file sizes are less than 0.1 MB. File content and
        structure is defined by SFF_MM_SIS_031217.htm in the DOCUMENT
        directory.
 
      Spacecraft/Planetary/Satellite Ephemeris (SPK) Files
      (SPK Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Spacecraft/Planetary/Satellite Ephemeris Files (also known as
        SP kernels or SPK files) are produced by the MRO Navigation
        Team (NAV). One file includes spacecraft, planetary, and
        satellite ephemerides.  File names have the form
        MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.SPK. This SPK file is accompanied by a
        PDS minimal label with file name having the form
        MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.LBL.
 
      Spacecraft Attitude (CK) Files
      (ACK, CCK, SCK, ACP, CCP, and SCP Directories)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        C-Kernel Files are produced by the MRO Attitude and Articulation
        Control Subsystem team (AACS) and are in NAIF transfer format.  File
        names have the form MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.FFF where FFF is a
        three-character file name extension. The ACK, CCK, and SCK
        extensions denote the reconstructed high-gain antenna, spacecraft,
        and solar array C-Kernels, respectively. The ACP, CCP, and SCP
        extensions denote the predicted high-gain antenna, spacecraft, and
        solar array C-kernels, respectively.  Each C-Kernel file is
        accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.LBL. Typical file size is 18 MB.
 
      Troposphere Calibration Files (TRO Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        Troposphere Calibration files are ASCII files produced by the Tracking
        System Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL. They provide
        historical and predicted Earth tropospheric conditions. File
        names have the form MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.TRO. Each TRO
        file is accompanied by a PDS minimal label with file name
        MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.LBL. Typical file size is 120 KB.
 
      DSN Weather Files (WEA Directory)
      ---------------------------------------------------
        DSN Weather files were produced by the Tracking System
        Analytic Calibration (TSAC) Group at JPL. Files give weather
        calibration information for DSN complexes. These are ASCII
        files of variable length records.  File names have the form
        MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.WEA. WEA files were typically
        released weekly and contain all weather data for the complex
        since 1 January. Each WEA file is accompanied by a PDS
        minimal label with file name MROMAGRyyyy_ddd_yyyy_ddd.LBL.
        The files grow at the rate of approximately 90 kB per month.
 
      Files in the CALIB Directory
      ----------------------------
        Files in the CALIB directory are those likely to have wide
        applicability in working with the raw data. They help unpack
        and allow use of the raw data, rather than being &apos;instrument&apos;
        calibration data per se. They include clock conversion files,
        tracking station locations and covariance files, a Structures
        kernel, and leapsecond files. Each file is accompanied by
        a PDS minimal label.  In the paragraphs below &apos;yy&apos;  is the
        two-digit year, &apos;mm&apos; is the two-digit month, and &apos;dd&apos;  is
        the two-digit day on which the file was created.
 
        Spacecraft Clock Conversion files allow time measured by the
        spacecraft clock to be converted to other time systems (e.g.,
        ephemeris time or UTC). These are ASCII files with names of the
        form:  TSC_yymmdd.CLK.  Each file TSC_yymmdd.CLK is accompanied
        by a PDS detached minimal label with name TSC_yymmdd.LBL.
 
        The Topocentric Reference Definition kernel defines topocentric
        reference frames associated with each of the DSN stations. They
        were produced by the JPL/PDS Navigation Ancillary Information
        Facility (NAIF) for use with NAIF-developed and MRO-provided
        software.  These are ASCII files with names of the form
        EARTH_TOPO_yymmdd.TF; each is accompanied by a detached label
        EARTH_TOPO_yymmdd.LBL.
 
        The NAIF Structures kernel contains the relative locations of
        the MRO solar array and HGA structures.  This is an ASCII file
        in NAIF transfer format.  The file name has form MRO_yymmdd.STK.
        The file is accompanied by a detached minimal label with name
        MRO_yymmdd.LBL.
 
        Leapsecond kernels contain a record of leap seconds (past and
        predicted) that allows proper conversion between ephemeris time
        and UTC.  These are ASCII files with names of the form
        LSK_yymmdd.TLS.  Each file LSK_yymmdd.TLS is accompanied by a
        PDS detached minimal label with name LSK_yymmdd.LBL.
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      SPK and CK files can be converted to a wide range of
      coordinate frames by the NAIF reader routines.
 
      Other data types are not dependent on definition of a
      coordinate system.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      Software for parsing, reducing, and analyzing data such as
      these has been developed at several institutions.
      Because such software must usually operate at the bit-level and
      is written for a narrow range of platforms, it is not suitable
      for general distribution.  No software is included with this
      archival data set.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      These data have been delivered to the PDS Geosciences Node
      electronically.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this archival data set have been collected to support
      radio science investigations, including derivation of the
      gravity field of Mars.  These are similar to data collected
      using other spacecraft and are believed to be generally of
      good quality.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This data set was designed with oversight from the Planetary
      Data System.  It was initially reviewed in May 2009 when the
      RSR and DLF data types were added.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      The ODFs in this archive contain data from all nominal MRO
      passes. They are primarily for the gravity investigation.
 
      Initially, the MRO Radio Science investigation was limited
      to gravity science. S. Asmar saw an opportunity to acquire
      atmospheric occultation data and inquired with key members
      in the science community (in this specific field) who
      supported the idea. The MRO project then accepted a proposal
      to provide modest funding for this purpose.
 
      All RSRs in this archive cover occultation
      activities when the spacecraft signal was carrier-only for
      Radio Science atmospheric investigations. Initial RSR files
      follow the format described by [JPLD-16765]. Open-loop
      (RSR) recordings for atmospheric science began March 4, 2007.
      Approximately one orbit per day was allocated to the
      Radio Science (Carrier Only) configuration for atmospheric
      occultations. As such, data cover a complete range
      of latitudes and longitudes on the Martian surface. The solar
      zenith angle, as of this writing, varies between 70 and 120
      degrees. Ingress recordings were done with a two-way
      coherent signal from the spacecraft while egress recordings
      used the USO and were one-way. Beginning on
      January 16, 2008, RSRs conform to [KAHAN2009]. DLFs are provided
      starting January 16, 2008, so the user can reconstruct the
      receiver tuning. TNFs are provided for all RSRs so the user
      has the station uplink ramps, a necessary component in deriving
      the predicted sky frequency.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The limitations in this data set follow from the quality of
      the execution, which is described above under Data Coverage
      and Quality.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

