<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mer2-m-mi-3-rdr-sci-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MER 2 MI RADIOMETRICALLY CALIBRATED RDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_exploration_rover::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mer2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mi.mer2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer2-m-mi-3-rdr-sci-v1.0__browserc_mer2-m-mi-3-rdr-sci-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer2-m-mi-3-rdr-sci-v1.0__browser_geo_mer2-m-mi-3-rdr-sci-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer2-m-mi-3-rdr-sci-v1.0__dvo_geo_mer2-m-mi-3-rdr-sci-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mer2-m-mi-3-rdr-sci-v1.0__pds.geo.mer.analysts_notebook::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mars Exploration Rover Mission, Camera Software Interface Specification, 2003
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CAMSIS2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Herkenhoff, K.E., et al., The Athena Microscopic Imager Investigation, Journal
                   of Geophysical Research, July 2, 2003.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HERKENHOFFETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MER2-M-MI-3-RDR-SCI-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MER 2 MI RADIOMETRICALLY CALIBRATED RDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2004-08-03</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-01-05T05:37:43.593Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>Ken Herkenhoff</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Herkenhoff, Ken,MER 2 MI Radiometrically Calibrated RDR V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, MER2-M-MI-3-RDR-SCI-V1.0,2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Mars Exploration Rover 2 Microscopic Imager Radiometrically
            Calibrated Reduced Data Record
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This archive volume is one of a set of volumes containing raw and
            derived data from the Mars Exploration Rover mission. This volume
            contains &quot;science&quot; data products, which were generated
            by the instrument team for archiving, as distinguished from
            &quot;operations&quot; data products, which were generated by the
            Multi-Mission Image Processing Facility (MIPL) at JPL for using
            during mission operations.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set contains data to help understand the fine-scale
    morphology, reflectance, and texture of rock surfaces and soil as
    well as the accumulation of dust on the capture and filter
    magnets. Several types of imaging data products can be created
    onboard the rover. Image data volume can be reduced by summing rows
    or columns, subframing (or windowing), or downsampling. Because the
    goal of MI observations is to resolve small features on Mars, row or
    column summing is not likely to be performed on MI images. However,
    subframing (selecting a part of the image for downlink) and/or
    downsampling (calculating a mean or median of pixels in specified
    blocks) can be used to reduce MI data volume for downlink. Subframe
    products are defined by starting row and column and by number of
    rows and columns. Downsampling can be used to create a thumbnail
    version of an image for rapid downlink and assessment on the ground.
    If the thumbnail indicates that the image is of scientific interest,
    the full-resolution image can be later returned to Earth. A
    histogram of the image data can also be generated and returned to
    Earth as a separate product. Reference pixels are returned as a
    separate product if requested.
 
    Note: MI Science RDR products generated during the first 30 sols of
    the MER mission were incorrectly labeled with the wrong data set ID,
    MERn-M-MI-2-RDR-SCI-V1.0 instead of MERn-M-MI-3-RDR-SCI-V1.0. The
    latter is the correct data set ID, as the products have level 3
    processing.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    MER Camera Payload RDRs are considered Level 3 (Calibrated Data
    equivalent to NASA Level 1-A), Level 4 (Resampled Data
    equivalent to NASA Level 1-B), or Level 5 (Derived Data
    equivalent to NASA Level 1-C, 2 or 3). The RDRs are to be
    reconstructed from Level 2 edited data, and are to be assembled
    into complete images that may include radiometric and/or geometric
    correction.
 
    MER Camera Payload EDRs and RDRs will be generated by JPL&apos;s
    Multimission Image Processing Laboratory (MIPL) under the OPGS
    subsystem of the MER GDS. RDRs will also be generated by the Athena
    Pancam Science and Microscopic Imager Science Teams under the SOAS
    subsystem of the GDS.
 
    RDR data products will be generated by, but not limited to, MIPL
    using the Mars Suite of VICAR image processing software at JPL, the
    Athena Pancam Science Team using IDL software at Cornell University
    and JPL, and the Microscopic Imager Science Team using ISIS software
    at USGS (Flagstaff) and JPL. The RDRs produced will be processed
    data. The input will be one or more Camera EDR or RDR data products
    and the output will be formatted according to this SIS. Additional
    meta-data may be added by the software to the PDS label.
 
    There may be multiple versions of a MER Camera RDRs.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    RDR products generated by MIPL will have a VICAR label wrapped by a
    PDS label, and their structure can include the optional EOL label
    after the binary data. RDR products not generated by MIPL may
    contain only a PDS label. Or, RDR products conforming to a standard
    other than PDS, such as JPEG compressed or certain Terrain products,
    are acceptable without a PDS header during mission operations, but
    may not be archivable.
 
    The RDR data product is comprised of radiometrically decalibrated
    and/or camera model corrected and/or geometrically altered versions
    of the raw camera data, in both single and multi-frame (mosaic)
    form. Most RDR data products will have PDS labels, or if generated
    by MIPL (OPGS), dual PDS/VICAR labels. Non-labeled RDRs include JPEG
    compressed products and the Terrain products. The RDR data products
    that serve operational needs are explained below.
 
    1) Radiometrically Corrected RDR
       The MIPLRAD method is a radiometric correction performed by MIPL
       (OPGS) at JPL. It can apply to any of the camera instruments, but
       only the RAD (and RAL) type is generated. MIPLRAD first backs
       out any onboard flat field that was performed. It then applies
       the following corrections: flat field, exposure time,
       temperature-compensated responsivity. The result is calibrated to
       physical units for MER of W/m^2/nm/sr. MIPLRAD is a first-order
       correction only and should be considered approximate.
 
    2) XYZ RDR
       An XYZ file contains 3 bands of 32-bit floating point numbers in
       the Band Sequential order. Alternatively, X, Y and Z may be
       stored in separate single-band files.
 
    The pixels in an XYZ image are coordinates in 3-D space of the
    corresponding pixel in the reference image. This reference image is
    traditionally the left image of a stereo pair, but could be the
    right image for special products. The geometry of the XYZ image is
    the same as the geometry of the reference image. This means that for
    any pixel in the reference image the 3-D position of the viewed
    point can be obtained from the same pixel location in the XYZ image.
    The 3-D points can be referenced to any of the MER coordinate
    systems (specified by DERIVED_IMAGE_PARAMS Group in the PDS label).
    Most XYZ images will contain &apos;holes&apos;, or pixels for which no XYZ
    value exists. These are caused by many factors such as differences
    in overlap and correlation failures. Holes are indicated by X, Y,
    and Z all having the same specific value. This value is defined by
    the MISSING_CONSTANT keyword in the IMAGE object. For the XYZ RDR,
    this value is (0.0,0.0,0.0).
 
 
  Software
  ========
    MER Camera Payload downlink processing software is focused on rapid
    reduction, calibration, and visualization of images in order to make
    discoveries, to accurately and expeditiously characterize the
    geologic environment around the rover, and to provide timely input
    for operational decisions concerning rover navigation and Instrument
    Deployment Device (IDD) target selection. Key software tools have
    been developed at Cornell University, at JPL by the MIPL, SSV, and
    APSS groups, at NASA Ames, and at the USGS/Flagstaff. These tools
    can also be used to process MI images (see below), as well as Navcam
    and Hazcam images, which have substantial scientific potential in
    addition to their operational importance
 
    PDS-labeled images and tables can be viewed with the program
    NASAView, developed by the PDS and available for a variety of
    computer platforms from the PDS web site
    http://pdsproto.jpl.nasa.gov/Distribution/license.html.
    There is no charge for NASAView.
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    The data set will initally be delivered and kept online. Upon
    Mission completion, the Microscopic Imager RDRs will be delivered to
    PDS on DVD.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
NULL
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

