<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-e-v-h-grns-2-grs-rawdata-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER E/V/H GRNS 2 GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER RAW DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:grs.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-grns-2-grs-rawdata-v1.0__browserp_mess-e-v-h-grns-2-grs-rawdata-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-grns-2-grs-rawdata-v1.0__browser_geo_mercury_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-grns-2-grs-rawdata-v1.0__dvo_geo_mess-e-v-h-grns-2-grs-rawdata-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Goldsten, J.O., E.A. Rhodes,, W.V. Boynton, W.C. Feldman, D.J. Lawrence, J.I.
                   Trombka, D.M. Smith, L.G. Evans, J. White, N.W. Madden, P.C. Berg, G.A. Murphy,
                   R.S. Gurnee, K. Strohbehn, B.D. Williams, E.D. Schaefer, C.A. Monaco, C.P.
                   Cork, J.D. Eckels, W.O. Miller, M.T. Burks, L.B. Hagler, S.J. Deteresa, and
                   M.C. Witte, The MESSENGER Gamma-Ray and Neutron Spectrometer, Space Science
                   Reviews, 131, 339-391, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GOLDSTENETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-E/V/H-GRNS-2-GRS-RAWDATA-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESSENGER E/V/H GRNS 2 GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER RAW DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2015-03-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-09-13</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>PATRICK PEPLOWSKI</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            P. N. Peplowski (APL), MESSENGER GRS raw data
            (MESS-E/V/H-GRNS-2-GRS-RAWDATA-V1.0), NASA Planetary Data System,
            2008.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The MESSENGER GRS uncalibrated observations consist of science
            and instrument data collected by the GRS sensor.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== This data set consists of the MESSENGER GRS
            uncalibrated observations, also known as EDRs. The GRS experiment
            is a gamma ray spectrometer designed to observe spectrum of gamma
            rays emitted from Mercury&apos;s surface in the energy range from
            0.1 to 10 MeV. There are ten GRS EDR data products: the raw
            spectra data, the spectra data from the shield (2 versions),
            shield count rate data, the anti-coincident spectra data, the
            microphonics data, the software rate counter data, the status
            parameters, the state of the instrument, and a GRS instrument
            command list.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
   Data Set Overview
   =================
     This data set consists of the MESSENGER GRS uncalibrated
     observations, also known as EDRs. There are ten standard data
     products associated with the GRS sensor. A single EDR data file
     will contain the observations with a time tag corresponding to
     a given Earth day. One EDR contains a set of raw spectra
     data collected by the Ge detector and a second and third EDR
     (2 versions) contain raw spectra data collected from the shield
     detector. A fourth data product contains 10-ms cadence
     measurements of the total shield count rate. A fifth EDR
     contains the spectra accumulated due to anti-coincidence events
     in the Ge detector and the shield. A sixth EDR contains
     microphonics data associated with the cryocooler. The other
     four EDRs consist of information related to software rate
     counter telemetry, status telemetry, and diagnostic instrument
     status and command data.
 
 
   Instrument Overview
   ===================
     The GRS detector is a high-resolution coaxial germanium crystal
     50 mm in diameter and 50 mm in length, chosen for its radiation
     damage resistance and annealing capabilities. The detector is
     rigidly clamped in a hermetically sealed Al capsule pressurized
     with clean, dry nitrogen. The capsule is cooled to an operating
     temperature in the 80-95 K range by a mechanical cryocooler. A
     plastic scintillator anti-coincidence shield surrounds the
     germanium detector in its sides and back, for rejection of
     cosmic-ray background. Galactic cosmic rays continuously
     bombard the surface of Mercury, and through interactions with
     the surface, gamma-rays of discrete energies that are
     characteristic of specific elements are created. A fraction of
     these gamma-rays, as well as those from the decay of radiogenic
     elements escape from the surface, where they can be detected by
     the orbiting GRS. Gamma-ray fluxes are measurable at altitudes
     up to 1000 km and for gamma-rays up to about 10 MeV that
     emanate from depths of up to tens of centimeter beneath the
     surface. Detected fluxes are generally low and require numerous
     orbital passes over a specific region to obtain a statistically
     well-defined energy spectrum. The measurements of elements such
     as Fe, Si, Mg, Na, Al, Ca, Ti, K and Th by GRS will provide
     insight into distinguishing between different formation models
     for Mercury as well as other planetary evolution issues.
 
     See the GRNS_INST.CAT file for more information and
     [GOLDSTENETAL2007] for full details.
 
 
   Calibration Overview
   ====================
     This data set is NOT calibrated; it only provides the
     uncalibrated sensor measurements.
 
 
   Parameters
   ==========
     The principal parameters when observing with the GRS are as
     follows:
 
     * Accumulation Time: The accumulation time, in seconds, of the
     Ge detector.
 
 
   Data
   ====
     There are ten standard data products associated with the GRS
     sensor. A single EDR data file will contain the observations
     with a time tag corresponding to a given Earth day. One EDR
     contains a set of raw spectra data collected from the high
     purity Ge detector during a specified amount of time. These
     data are contained in 16,384 (2^14) channels, which can be used
     to create a histogram that shows the distribution of events
     (number of strikes) as a function of energy (channel number).
     Because of the low count rates usually encountered,
     accumulation times of minutes to hours are normal.
 
     Two EDRs contain raw spectra data collected from the shield
     detector. The shield scintillator has a much lower energy
     resolution than the Ge detector, so events detected from the
     shield are binned in only 1024 channels. If events are found to
     occur in both detectors within some short time interval (of
     order microseconds), a coincidence condition is flagged; such
     events are usually caused by cosmic rays. A separate EDR
     contains the spectra accumulated due to anticoincidence events,
     to remove coincidence event background from cosmic rays.
 
     Another EDR measures the total count rate at high time cadence
     (10 ms) in order to provide new insights into the charged
     particle environment around Mercury, particularly the energetic
     electron events.
 
     The microphonics data are contained in an EDR and consist of a
     binned time series of fluctuations generated electronically
     that are associated with cryocooler vibrations. The microphonics
     data are used to help determine if the cooler is developing
     vibration issues. Data from the software event counters and
     associated data are stored in a separate EDR. Similarly, a
     separate EDR provides status data, which contains many
     engineering parameters, such as voltages, currents,
     temperatures, and modes. Another EDR contains information about
     the state of the instrument, with many parameters associates
     with the Analog-to-Digital converter event processing in the
     associated field-programmable gate array. A final EDR contains
     the time-tagged list of commands executed by the GRS instrument.
     It also records the success level of each command.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
   Confidence Level Overview
   =========================
     The GRS EDR data are the least processed data set released for
     the GRS.  Data presented here are an accurate representation of
     the GRS &apos;raw&apos; data as received from the spacecraft, with
     minimal timing processing, no data calibration, no unit
     conversion, and no spatial processing.
 
 
   Review
   ======
     The GRS EDR was reviewed internally by the GRS team prior to
     release to the PDS. PDS also performed an external review of
     the GRS EDR. Before the initial release, all functional modes
     were tested and reviewed, including bit-by-bit comparison with
     telemetry results from another tested program, GSEOS. In more
     recent releases, Ge detector science spectra are analyzed.
 
 
   Data Coverage and Quality
   =========================
     Data reported are the minimally processed data received from
     the spacecraft during the the following mission phases:
     Launch, Earth Cruise, Earth Flyby, Venus 1 Cruise,
     Venus 1 Flyby, Venus 2 Cruise, Venus 2 Flyby, Mercury 1 Cruise
     Mercury 1 Flyby, Mercury 2 Cruise, Mercury 2 Flyby,
     Mercury 3 Cruise, Mercury 3 Flyby, Mercury 4 Cruise,
     Mercury Orbit, Mercury Orbit Year 2, Mercury Orbit Year 3, and
     Mercury Orbit Year 4. These mission phases are defined as:
 
                           Start time          End time
     Phase Name            Date (DOY)          Date (DOY)
     -------------------   -----------------  -----------------
     Launch                03 Aug 2004 (216)  12 Sep 2004 (256)
     Earth Cruise          13 Sep 2004 (257)  18 Jul 2005 (199)
     Earth Flyby           19 Jul 2005 (200)  16 Aug 2005 (228)
     Venus 1 Cruise        17 Aug 2005 (229)  09 Oct 2006 (282)
     Venus 1 Flyby         10 Oct 2006 (283)  07 Nov 2006 (311)
     Venus 2 Cruise        08 Nov 2006 (312)  22 May 2007 (142)
     Venus 2 Flyby         23 May 2007 (143)  20 Jun 2007 (171)
     Mercury 1 Cruise      21 Jun 2007 (172)  30 Dec 2007 (364)
     Mercury 1 Flyby       31 Dec 2007 (365)  28 Jan 2008 (028)
     Mercury 2 Cruise      29 Jan 2008 (029)  21 Sep 2008 (265)
     Mercury 2 Flyby       22 Sep 2008 (266)  20 Oct 2008 (294)
     Mercury 3 Cruise      21 Oct 2008 (295)  15 Sep 2009 (258)
     Mercury 3 Flyby       16 Sep 2009 (259)  14 Oct 2009 (287)
     Mercury 4 Cruise      15 Oct 2009 (288)  03 Mar 2011 (062)
     Mercury Orbit         04 Mar 2011 (063)  17 Mar 2012 (077)
     Mercury Orbit Year 2  18 Mar 2012 (078)  17 Mar 2013 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 3  18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 4  18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)
 
     These specific operational periods in relation to the mission
     phases were:
 
                           Start time         End time
     Phase Name            Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)         Sensor
     --------------------  -----------------  -----------------  ------
     Launch                12 Aug 2004 (225)  13 Aug 2004 (226)
     Earth Cruise          10 Nov 2004 (315)  16 Nov 2004 (321)   Ge
     Earth Flyby           No Data
     Venus 1 Cruise        No Data
     Venus 1 Flyby         No Data
     Venus 2 Cruise        27 Mar 2007 (088)  30 Mar 2007 (089)   shield
     Venus 2 Flyby         04 Jun 2007 (155)  08 Jun 2007 (159)   shield
     Mercury 1 Cruise      26 Sep 2007 (269)  29 Sep 2007 (272)   shield
     Mercury 1 Flyby       05 Jan 2008 (005)  15 Jan 2008 (015)   shield
     Mercury 1 Flyby       13 Jan 2008 (013)  15 Jan 2008 (015)   Ge
     Mercury 2 Cruise      No Data
     Mercury 2 Flyby       03 Oct 2008 (277)  06 Oct 2008 (280)   shield
     Mercury 2 Flyby       04 Oct 2008 (278)  06 Oct 2008 (280)   Ge
     Mercury 3 Cruise      24 Sep 2009 (267)  27 Sep 2009 (270)   shield
     Mercury 3 Flyby       28 Sep 2009 (271)  06 Oct 2009 (279)   Ge
     Mercury 4 Cruise      02 Apr 2010 (092)  12 Apr 2010 (102)   shield
     Mercury 4 Cruise      13 Apr 2010 (103)  15 Apr 2010 (105)   Ge
     Mercury 4 Cruise      17 Sep 2010 (260)  24 Sep 2010 (267)   shield
     Mercury Orbit         23 Mar 2011 (082)  03 Jun 2011 (154)   Ge
     Mercury Orbit         11 Jun 2011 (162)  14 Jun 2011 (165)   Ge
     Mercury Orbit         16 Jun 2011 (167)  05 Jul 2011 (186)   Ge
     Mercury Orbit         20 Jul 2011 (201)  25 Jul 2011 (206)   Ge
     Mercury Orbit         28 Jul 2011 (209)  06 Sep 2011 (249)   Ge
     Mercury Orbit         08 Sep 2011 (251)  17 Sep 2011 (260)   Ge
     Mercury Orbit Year 2  18 Mar 2012 (078)  15 Jun 2012 (167)   shield
     Mercury Orbit Year 3  18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)   shield
     Mercury Orbit Year 4  18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)   shield
 
     In this list, &apos;shield&apos; means shield only and &apos;Ge&apos; means Ge and
     shield. The GRS operational mode during most of the flyby time
     periods was a &apos;sleep mode&apos; during which an operational heater
     maintained the cryocooler temperature at a constant value (to
     avoid temperature cycling of the cryocooler He seals) and the
     remainder of the instrument was shut down. Status data are
     continuously collected in this mode. Cryocooler exercises were
     conducted approximately every 6 months, but this is of
     engineering interest only.
 
     Data from the cryocooled GRS high-resolution Ge detector were
     collected only during the full functional test in November 2004
     and during the Mercury flybys in January and October 2008 and
     September-October 2009. This limitation preserves the lifetime of
     the limited-life cryocooler.
 
     Data from the borated plastic shield were collected as part of a
     periodic cryocooler exercise; for the Venus-2 flyby (as another
     neutron detector to aid the NS); during the Mercury 1 Cruise in
     September 2007; for the Mercury 1, 2, and 3 Flybys.
 
     A nonscience &apos;aliveness&apos; test was conducted in August 2004.
 
     The Ge detector energy resolution was somewhat degraded during
     Mercury Flyby 1 due to crystal displacement damage by cosmic
     rays, despite a 3-day anneal at 84C prior to the Flyby. To
     improve energy resolution for Flyby 2, the detector was kept at
     room temperature in July through mid-September in &apos;hot zombie&apos;
     mode (no communication with the DPU to reduce memory usage and
     avoid upset events from cosmic rays). Then a 14-day anneal at 84C
     was conducted. After this, energy resolution was improved to
     nearly that found in the first cruise test shortly after launch.
 
     During Mercury Flyby 3, the GRS data were collected only up to
     approximately 6 minutes before closest approach, at approximately
     661 km altitude, due to a S/C safing that occurred. The GRS was
     restarted once the S/C was promoted to operation, but the S/C was
     far from the planet by this time. It is estimated that only
     approximately 18 percent of the signal counts from the planet
     were obtained below 2500 km altitude, compared to previous
     flybys. After the Ge detector recooled to operational
     temperature, engineering tests were run involving Ge temperature
     and high-voltage changes.
 
     The shield was operated during May 2009 for some engineering
     tests. Otherwise the GRS operational mode during the Mercury 3
     Cruise was &apos;warm zombie&apos; mode, which performs a relatively low
     temperature Ge anneal to reduce radiation damage. Also the
     operational heater maintains the cryocooler temperature, to avoid
     cycling of the cryocooler He seals. On September 2 2009, the GRS
     was brought out of warm zombie mode and a 3-day Ge anneal at 84C
     was then performed. After this anneal the Ge energy resolution
     appeared to be close to that obtained for Mercury Flyby 2.
 
     During Mercury 4 Cruise, the GRS remained in warm zombie mode,
     except the shield was on for some spectral tests on shield-only
     data and the Ge detector and shield were on for some spectra
     tests on coincidence spectra between the shield and and the Ge
     detector.
 
     Just before orbit insertion, the GRS was brought out of warm
     zombie mode, and the Ge crystal was annealed for 7 days at 84C.
     After a few days of orbital operations the Ge energy resolution
     was measured to be close to the same value obtained for the M3
     flyby. S/C temperatures were somewhat higher than expected during
     orbital operations, but the GRS cryocooler was able to cool the
     Ge detector easily.
 
     During orbital operation, the GRS remained on continuously,
     except for periods when the high voltage was down, for various
     reasons, including an X-class SPE (Solar Particle Event) that
     safed the detector, OCMs (Orbital Correction Maneuvers), and
     cryocooler temperature setpoint changes. Periods having
     conditions that lead to broad energy resolution, such as
     radiation damage revealed by a Ge temperature increase or large
     very low-energy noise, have also been removed. Not shown in the
     table of operational periods are periods of SPEs that did not
     safe the detector: SPE2 08-02-2011, SPE3 08-04/05-2011,
     SPE4 08-09-2011, and SPE5 09-08/09-2011. These time periods
     should probably be eliminated from analysis, due to count-rate
     saturation and strong activation of gamma-ray peaks.
 
     Beginning on 11 October, 2011, the HPGe detector began
     registering anomalous counts in the low-energy (&lt; 300 keV)
     portion of the spectrum. While these events are lower in energy
     than the gamma-ray photopeaks of interest, the resulting count
     rate during these periods is sufficiently high to degrade the
     energy resolution for the detection of all gamma rays, regardless
     of energy. The magnitude of the anomalous counts and
     corresponding degradation of the energy resolution varies, and
     all data acquired after 11 October, 2011 should be carefully
     evaluated for its energy resolution prior to analysis. Particular
     care should be taken prior to summing individual gamma-ray
     spectra with differing energy resolution to produce summed
     spectra for analysis.
 
     The GRS operated in anomalous count rate mode for the remainder
     of its life. The high voltage (HV) was maintained at its nominal
     value of 3200 V until 18 November, 2011, when it was lowered to
     2700 V. It returned to 3200 V on 21 November, 2011, which was
     followed by a change to 2400 V. These changes were implemented in
     an attempt to maintain the highest possible energy resolution in
     the presence of the increased leakage current.
 
     A short detector annealing activity took place from 15 December,
     2011 to 21 December, 2011. This was followed by the arrival of an
     energetic solar particle event on 26 December, 2011 to
     27 December, 2011.
 
     A detector annealing activity took place from 19 March, 2012 to
     29 March, 2012. Following this activity the detector leakage
     current was observed to have increased significantly with a
     corresponding degradation in the leakage current.
 
     From 30 March, 2012 to 11 April, 2012, the detector high voltage
     value was varied between 1500 to 2400 V to characterize the
     energy resolution of the system as a function of high voltage.
 
     A detector annealing activity took place from 11 April, 2012 to
     28 April, 2012. Following this activity, the detector was
     operated at 2400 V.
 
     In an attempt to preserve the limited lifetime of the GRS
     cryocooler, the detector was kept warm from 5 May 2012 to
     1 June 2012. This time period corresponded to a time of elevated
     spacecraft temperatures. On 8 June, 2012 a weeklong detector
     annealing activity began.
 
     On 15 June, 2012, the GRS cryocooler failed after approximately
     9,500 hours of operation. This compares favorably to the 8,000
     hour mean lifetime for these coolers. The failure occurred during
     a routine detector cool down following the 8 June 2012 annealing
     activity. Several unsuccessful attempts to revive the cooler have
     been made. Without the ability to maintain the HPGe detector at
     cryogenic temperature, gamma-ray measurements are not possible.
     No Germanium data collected after June 15, 2012 will be supplied
     to PDS for archiving.
 
     On 25 February, 2013, new flight software was uploaded to the GRS.
     The purpose was to optimize the capability of the instrument to
     characterize neutron emission from Mercury&apos;s surface by changing
     the gain of the shield spectrum. Additionally, a new data product
     was added (SCR), which produces 10-ms cadence measurements of the
     total shield count rate. Because the shield responds to charged
     particles, these measurements represent the highest time cadence
     samples of the energetic charged particle environment around
     Mercury. The first several weeks were devoted to parameter
     optimization, with official data collection beginning on
     18 March, 2013.
 
     Beginning on 9 September, 2014, a new data operations mode was
     implemented in which the SHI data is acquired at a higher time
     cadence when MESSENGER is within 500 km altitude of Mercury.
     During these periods, SCR data collection is temporarily
     suspended.
 
     Periods of elevated count rates resulting from
     spacecraft-incident SPE events includes data collected on:
 
     3-4 June, 2011;
     1 August, 2011;
     3-4 August, 2011;
     8 August, 2011;
     7-8 September, 2011;
     21-23 September, 2011;
     3-5 October, 2011;
     14-15 October, 2011;
     3-5 November, 2011;
     17-18 November, 2011
     22-23 December, 2011;
     2 January, 2012;
     23-31 January, 2012;
     28-29 January, 2012;
 
     Post-January 2012 flares are difficult to isolate in the
     count-rate anomaly compromised dataset. Care should be used when
     utilizing these data as they may also contain gamma-ray
     detections resulting from prompt and/or long-lived activation
     products. The count rate anomaly issue does not apply to data
     collected following the 25 February, 2013 flight software upload.
 
     For measurements taken following the 25 February, 2013 software
     upload, the following times were compromised by SPEs:
 
     15-16 March, 2013;
     11-12 April, 2013;
     21-22 April, 2013;
     24-25 April, 2013;
     12-15 May, 2013;
     31 May - 1 June, 2013;
     21-25 June, 2013;
     19-23 August, 2013;
     5 October, 2013;
     11-14 October, 2013;
     22-23 October, 2013;
     25-30 October, 2013;
     6-8 November, 2013;
     19 November, 2013;
     29 November - 1 December, 2013;
     13-15 December, 2013;
     25-28 December, 2013;
     6 January, 2014;
     8-10 January, 2014;
     22-23 January, 2014;
     26 January, 2014;
     28-31 January, 2014;
     11-12 February, 2014;
     14-15 February, 2014;
     18-20 February, 2014;
     25 February - 2 March, 2014;
     4 March, 2014;
     12-14 March, 2014;
     29 April, 2014;
     1 May, 2014;
     5 May, 2014;
     4-5 June, 2014;
     10-12 June, 2014;
     17 June, 2014;
     8-9 August, 2014;
     1-5 September, 2014;
     10-12 September, 2014;
     25-27 September, 2014;
     14 October, 2014.
 
     The degree to which science data can be derived from these
     SPE-comprised periods varies on an event-by-event basis.
 
     Periods with no science data, corresponding to instrument safing
     or operations activities include:
 
     4-16 June, 2011; (Safed)
     6-16 July, 2011; (GRS Annealing)
     26 July, 2011; (Short safing event)
     7 September, 2011; (Short safing event)
     24-25 October, 2011; (Short safing event)
     8-10 November, 2011; (Safing)
     4-6 December, 2011; (Instrument Safing)
     15-20 December, 2011; (Detector Annealing)
     2-12 March, 2012;
     24-25 April, 2013; (HV shutdown during OCM)
     21-24 June, 2013; (Instrument Safing due to SPE)
     20-22 August, 2013; (Instrument Safing due to SPE)
     25-30 October, 2013; (Instrument Safing due to SPE)
     26-28 December, 2013; (Instrument Safing due to SPE)
     17 June, 2014; (HV shutdown during OCM)
     1-5 September, 2014; (Instrument Safing due to SPE)
     10-12 September, 2014; (Instrument Safing due to SPE)
 
     Restrictions on data generation resulting from limited space on
     the spacecraft data record resulted in SCR products being
     suspended during the following periods:
 
     14 December 2013 - 2 January, 2014;
     16 January 2014 - 1 February, 2014;
 
     SCR data acquired between 2 January and 16 January are subject to
     a time offset that will be fixed in a future delivery.
 
 
   Limitations
   ===========
     This data set is minimally processed data. The data are received
     from the spacecraft telemetry and ingested into the MESSENGER
     Science Operations Center (SOC). No data gaps or corrupted data
     have been identified for any of the GRS operational periods.
     Although there may be some data not identified as missing or
     corrupted, such data should be minimal and a very small fraction
     of the available data.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

