<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.vg2-nsa-rss-5-rocc-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>VOYAGER 2 TRITON RADIO OCCULTATION REDUCED DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.comet_sl9-jupiter_collision::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.voyager::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.vg2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.vg2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.triton::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.vg2-nsa-rss-5-rocc-v1.0__browserp_vg2-nsa-rss-5-rocc-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Gurrola, E.M., Interpretation of radar data from the icy Galilean
                   satellites and Triton, Ph.D. dissertation, Stanford University, Palo Alto,
                   CA, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GURROLA1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tyler, G.L., Radio Propagation Experiments in the Outer Solar System with
                   Voyager, Proceedings of the IEEE, 75, 1404-1431, 1987.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TYLER1987</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tyler, G.L., D.N. Sweetnam, J.D. Anderson, S.E. Borutzki, J.K. Campbell, V.R.
                   Eshleman, D.L. Gresh, E.M. Gurrola, D.P. Hinson, N. Kawashima, E.R. Kursinski,
                   G.S. Levy, G.F. Lindal, J.R. Lyons, E.A. Marouf, P.A. Rosen, R.A. Simpson, and
                   G.E. Wood, Voyager Radio Science Observations of Neptune and Triton, Science,
                   246, 1466-1473, 1989.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TYLERETAL1989</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>VG2-NSA-RSS-5-ROCC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>VOYAGER 2 TRITON RADIO OCCULTATION REDUCED DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1997-12-31</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1989-08-25</start_time>
        <stop_time>1989-08-25</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>RICHARD A. SIMPSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Simpson, R.A., VOYAGER 2 TRITON RADIO OCCULTATION REDUCED DATA
            V1.0, VG2-NSA-RSS-5-ROCC-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 1997
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            VOYAGER 2 TRITON RADIO OCCULTATION REDUCED DATA
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set consists of several tables and supporting
            documentation from final analysis of the Voyager 2 radio
            occultation by Triton. The data set is based on a Ph.D.
            dissertation by Eric M. Gurrola of Stanford University
            [GURROLA1995]. The tabulated data were derived from raw radio
            science observations, which are being archived separately.
            General principles for conducting these types of experiments have
            been described by [TYLER1987] results of the Triton analysis were
            published by [TYLERETAL1989].
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      This data set consists of several tables and supporting
      documentation from final analysis of the Voyager 2 radio
      occultation by Triton.  The data set is based on a Ph.D.
      dissertation by Eric M. Gurrola of Stanford University
      [GURROLA1995].  The tabulated data were derived from raw
      radio science observations, which are being archived
      separately.  General principles for conducting these types
      of experiments have been described by [TYLER1987]; early
      results of the Triton analysis were published by
      [TYLERETAL1989].
 
      During the Triton occultation, the Voyager 2 spacecraft
      provided a coherent, dual-frequency microwave radio signal
      source.  The signal frequency was derived from a precision,
      onboard Ultra-Stable Oscillator (USO).  The spacecraft
      high-gain antenna (HGA) beamed that signal through the
      atmosphere of Triton.  As the spacecraft moved on its
      trajectory, the radio signal probed different levels in the
      atmosphere.  Four hours later the signals were received at
      stations of the NASA Deep Space Network (DSN) on Earth.
 
      Because Triton&apos;s atmosphere is so tenuous, changes in the
      signal resulting from its passage through the atmosphere were
      very subtle.  Nevertheless, a phase change of about 2 radians
      at X-band was observed and can be attributed to retardation
      by a neutral atmosphere.
 
      Because oscillator instabilities on the spacecraft were
      comparable to the atmospheric effects being measured, more
      than one physically plausible model atmosphere is consistent
      with the data.  [GURROLA1995] used several techniques to model
      the oscillator instability, define a phase &apos;baseline,&apos; and
      extract an atmospheric profile.  The data archived here are in
      the form of six tables giving measured radio phase, residual
      phase, and results of the atmospheric modeling.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      Six tables are included in the data set.  In all cases, tables
      are constructed with altitude above the surface as the free
      parameter -- in steps of 0.5 km.  In four tables phase,
      relative phase, or residual phase (in radians) is the dependent
      parameter.  In one table temperature (in Kelvins) is the
      dependent parameter.  The sixth table is an autocorrelation,
      so the dependent variable is the dimensionless autocorrelation
      value, with a potential range of +/-1.0.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The spacecraft transmitted coherent signals with right circular
      polarization along the boresight of the high-gain antenna at
      both S-band (13 cm, or 2298 MHz) and X-band (3.5 cm, or 8415
      MHz) wavelengths.  Signals were received coherently at both
      wavelengths in right-circular polarization using the 70-meter
      DSN antenna near Canberra, Australia.  The microwave frequencies
      were converted to baseband (0-25 kHz) using fixed and tunable
      local oscillators; the output analog signals corresponding to
      both S- and X-band inputs were converted to digital
      representations (8-bit samples) and stored for later processing.
 
      At Stanford, the sampled signal was filtered digitally and all
      deterministic corrections for frequency/phase shifts were
      applied.  A residual phase shift in the S- and X-band signals
      was observed during both the ingress and egress occultation
      periods.  Standard methods were used to determine the
      contribution from plasma effects.  The remaining phase shift
      was attributed to Triton&apos;s neutral atmosphere; it is the
      subject of Gurrola&apos;s dissertation and the focus of this data
      set.
 
      Analysis of radio occultation data does not require knowledge
      of target body radius.  Rather, the occultation time is taken
      to be the time when the signal voltage has decreased to half
      of its free space value.  The time may then be translated to a
      radius value for a specific spacecraft trajectory.  Trajectory
      uncertainties were large enough during this analysis that no
      attempt was made to derive a new radius.  Heights are defined
      relative to the occultation point; they are not sensitive to
      small differences in trajectory.  Structure of the atmosphere
      (over hundreds of vertical kilometers) is somewhat sensitive
      to radius through assumptions of hydrostatic equilibrium.
 
    Data
    ====
      The six tables included here are, in the order they appear in
      the dissertation:
 
      VGRPHASE.TAB:  The 3.6-cm residual radio phase for Triton
                     ingress and egress, corrected for free space
                     propagation and ionospheric effects; this table
                     contains the basic observational data.
 
      BASELINE.TAB:  A comparison of the best fit model to Triton
                     3.6-cm egress data with several different
                     estimates of USO drift (baselines).
 
      ATM_MODL.TAB:  Four theoretical temperature profiles for
                     Triton; each is consistent with the data, but
                     each involves different assumptions.
 
      USO_FLUC.TAB:  The residual USO phase fluctuations after the
                     measured values in VGRPHASE.TAB have been
                     adjusted by an estimate of the slowly-varying
                     long-term USO drift.
 
      AUTOCORR.TAB:  The autocorrelation of phase noise for lags up
                     to 65 km.
 
      PH_RESID.TAB:  Residual phase from 3.6-cm egress data for the
                     best fit isothermal model atmosphere and for a
                     thermal inversion model.
 
      Each table is accompanied by a full PDS detached label with
      the same name except for suffix *.LBL.  The PDS label completely
      describes the format and contents of the table.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      The current Voyager 2 ephemeris for the Neptune encounter was
      obtained from the JPL/PDS Navigation Ancillary Information
      Facility (NAIF) and is included in the GEOMETRY directory.
      This is not the file used by Gurrola for his analysis, but it
      may allow users to reconstruct the observing configuration in
      a way that facilitates understanding of the results.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      Tables are given in terms of height above Triton&apos;s surface,
      which is taken to be approximately 1350 km from its center of
      mass.  The assumed radius is not important for this data set;
      the occultation data themselves define the &apos;zero&apos; height level,
      which is the point where the received signal power is one-fourth
      (voltage is one-half) of its free space value.  When used in
      conjunction with a specific spacecraft trajectory, the zero-
      height level can be used to derive a radius for Triton.   When
      a specific number was required, Gurrola himself used 1352.5 km.
      The published value of radius from the radio occultation is
      1355+/-7 km [TYLERETAL1989].
 
 
    Software
    ========
      There is no software in this data set.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The archival data set is written on CD-WO media using the
      Young Minds CD Studio authoring system.  The CD-WO volumes
      conform to ISO 9660 standards.
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      Derivation of an atmospheric profile for Triton depends on the
      accuracy with which USO drift on short time scales can be
      determined.  For these observations, the effects of drift and
      the effects of Triton&apos;s atmosphere are comparable.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was examined by a peer review panel
      prior to its acceptance by the Planetary Data System (PDS).
      The peer review was conducted in accordance with PDS procedures.
 
      Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data set,
      key elements of the archive were distributed for preliminary
      review.  These included electronic versions of example PDS
      labels, CATALOG files, and Software Interface Specifications.
      These materials were distributed to PDS personnel, the
      experiment investigator, and others, as appropriate.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      This data set covers both the ingress and egress Voyager 2 radio
      occultations at Triton.  X-band plots illustrate the effects;
      S-band results would have been identical, except for scaling
      by the 3/11 ratio of the two frequencies.  Egress data were
      somewhat more amenable to the types of modeling developed by
      Gurrola and are emphasized in the results; but both ingress
      and egress phase measurements are included in the data set.
      Estimates of occultation radius are not included in this data
      set; instead, an empirical determination of the &apos;zero&apos; height
      level was made from the data for both ingress and egress (see
      also, Processing, above).
 
      The uncertainties in the observations are comparable to the
      effects being measured.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      The limitations in this data set follow from the quality of
      the execution, which is described above under Data Coverage
      and Quality.
 
      Gurrola assumed a radius of 1352.5 km when he needed a
      specific value; he believes the height parameter uncertainty
      is on the order of 100 m.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>77-076A-02K</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

