<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.buglab-e-bug-4-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MARS ANALOG SOIL BUG OBSERVATIONS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.buglab::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:bug.buglab::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.buglab-e-bug-4-v1.0__browserp_geo_buglab-e-bug-4-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.buglab-e-bug-4-v1.0__dvo_geo_buglab-e-bug-4-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Allen, C.C., R.V. Morris, D.J. Lindstrom, M.M. Lindstrom, and J.P. Lockwood,
                   JSC MARS-1: Martian Regolith Simulant, LPSC XXVIII, Houston, TX, Abstract No.
                   1797, 1997.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ALLENETAL1997</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Bell, J.F. III, The Mars Exploration Rover Athena Panoramic Camera (Pancam)
                   Investigation, Journal of Geophysical Research, June 23, 2003.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BELLETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hapke, B.W., M.K. Shepard, R.M. Nelson, W.D. Smythe, and K. Mannett, Comparison
                   of the bidirectional reflectance of a well-characterized powder with
                   predictions of models based on the equation of radiative transfer, LPSC
                   XXXVIII, Houston, TX, Abstract No. 1321, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAPKEETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Morris, R.V., D.C. Golden, J.F. Bell III, T.D. Shelfer, A.C. Scheinost, N.W.
                   Hinman, G. Furniss, S.A. Mertzman, J.L. Bishop, D.W. Ming, C.C. Allen, and D.T.
                   Britt, Mineralogy, composition, and alteration of Mars Pathfinder rocks and
                   soils: Evidence from multispectral, elemental, and magnetic data on terrestrial
                   analogue, SNC meteorite, and Pathfinder samples, J. Geophys. Res., Vol. 105,
                   No. E1, pp. 1757-1817, 2000.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MORRISETAL2000</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Morris, R.V., D.C. Golden, D.W. Ming, T.D. Shelfer, L.C. Jorgensen, J.F. Bell
                   III, T.G. Graff, and S.A. Mertzman, Phyllosilicate-poor palagonitic dust from
                   Mauna Kea Volcano (Hawaii): A mineralogical analogue for magnetic Martian
                   dust?, J. Geophys. Res., Vol. 106, No. E3, pp. 5057-5083, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MORRISETAL2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>BUGLAB-E-BUG-4-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MARS ANALOG SOIL BUG OBSERVATIONS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2006-03-16</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2006-01-01</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>MICHAEL K. SHEPARD</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Shepard, M.K., and J. Ward, Mars Soil Analog BUG Observations,
            BUGLAB-E-BUG-4-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2006.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Bidirectional reflectance distribution function (BRDF)
            measurements of Mars soil analogs using the Bloomsburg University
            Goniometer (BUG).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Bloomsburg University Goniometer (BUG) was used to make
            bidirectional reflectance distribution function (BRDF)
            measurements of Mars soil analogs at Mars Exploration Rover (MER)
            Panoramic Camera (Pancam) wavelengths.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Information
  ====================
 
  OVERVIEW:
  --------
  The Bloomsburg University Goniometer (BUG) was used to make bidirectional
  reflectance distribution function (BRDF) measurements of 5 Mars soil analogs
  (AREF_235, AREF_236, AREF_237, AREF_238, and JSC_Mars1). The measurements
  were made at Mars Exploration Rover (MER) Panoramic Camera (Pancam)
  wavelengths (450-990 nm) using the Pancam flight spare filters. More
  information on the center wavelength and passband for each filter can be found
  in Table 4 and Fig. 6 of BELLETAL2003 (see CATALOG/REF.CAT).
 
  The wavelengths used in the file names are rounded and may not precisely
  agree with those in Table 4 of BELLETAL2003. Additionally, the flight spares
  may not have the precise characteristics of those flown on the rovers. The
  following table shows the correspondance between the file-name wavelength and
  that listed in Table 4 of BELLETAL2003.
 
  File name suffix     Filter Name    Table 4 wavelength (nm)
   _450                  L7/R1             432/436
   _480                  L6                482
   _530                  L5                535
   _600                  L4                601
 
   _670                  L3                673
   _750                  L2/R2             753/754
   _800                  R3                803
   _860                  R4                864
 
   _900                  R5                904
   _930                  R6                934
   _990                  R7               1009
 
 
  The archive consists of 60 tabular data files, each with an accompanying
  detached PDS label.  Within the DATA directory, the data are organized within
  5 folders, corresponding to the 5 soil samples analyzed. Within each of the
  5 folders are tabular data files containing the BRDF results for each of the
  MER Pancam wavelengths. Columns are incidence angle, emission angle, azimuth
  angle, phase angle (all in degrees, i and e are measured from nadir), and
  corrected radiance factor. Also contained in each of the 5 folders is a file
  containing the reflectance spectrum for the particular soil sample.
 
  Additional data for each sample can be found in the EXTRAS directory,
  including an image of each sample in its dish and a close-up image with a
  1-cm field-of-view. Also in this directory is a graph showing a
  comparison of measurements made of a powder from the BUG and the long arm
  goniometer at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory [HAPKEETAL2007 in
  CATALOG/REF.CAT]. Please see EXTRINFO.TXT for more information about the
  files in the EXTRAS directory.
 
 
  SAMPLE INFORMATION:
  ------------------
  Dr. Richard V. Morris (NASA Johnson Space Center) provided the AREF (Athena
  Reference) samples. Dr. Edward Guinness (Washington University in St. Louis)
  provided the JSC-Mars-1 sample [ALLENETAL1997 in CATALOG/REF.CAT].
 
  According to Dr. Morris, the AREF samples are also known with another
  designation system (Hawaii, Mauna Kea, HWMK):
 
  AREF_235 is HWMK101 (&lt; 1mm size fraction)
  AREF_236 is HWMK904 (&lt; 1mm size fraction)
  AREF_237 is HWMK940 (&lt; 1mm size fraction)
  AREF_238 is HWMK600 (&lt; 1mm size fraction)
 
  More information on these samples can be found in MORRISETAL2000 and
  MORRISETAL2001 (see CATALOG/REF.CAT).
 
  There are two other samples that are proxies for AREF_235: HMWK919 and
  HMWK606, both of which were collected at the same site as HWMK101 but in
  different years. According to Dr. Morris, variability in these spectra is
  often encountered because the spectra are very dependent upon particle
  diameter, and different particle size fractions are often presented on a
  given surface poured at different times.
 
 
  DATA SET ACQUISITION:
  --------------------
  To make the measurements, the detector reports a voltage based on the
  intensity of the light detected in a given wavelength. For reference, we
  first measure the voltage from a sample of Spectralon(R) viewed at incidence
  angle, i = 0, emission angle, e = 5 degrees. All sample voltages are divided
  by this reference to give a raw measure of reflectance. Subsequently, this
  reflectance is multiplied by cos(i)/cos(e) for each measurement to give
  radiance factor. We multiply by cos(i) because, as the incidence angle
  increases, the sample is illuminated by an increasing ellipsoid spot of
  light. The detector &apos;sees&apos; the entire spot, so there is no fall-off in
  incident intensity as incidence angle increases. Multiplying by cos(i)
  accounts for this. Dividing by cos(e) accounts for the decreasing apparent
  area of the sample as seen by the detector.
 
  Because of the architecture of the goniometer, there are low-level secondary
  reflections from the sample off of the arm or platform that are also observed
  by the detector. These reflections have an azimuthal dependence because
  various parts of the sample platform or arms are within the detector
  field-of-view as the stage rotates to different azimuths. All surfaces have
  been flocked with black felt to minimize this, but we apply a correction
  factor before reporting the radiance factor. The correction factor is
  determined by holding emission angle at e = 0, fixing i at 15, 30, 45, and 60
  deg in steps, and rotating in azimuth for each incidence angle. Because
  e = 0, there should be no change in the reflected light as the stage rotates
  in azimuth. Deviations from the minimum reflection observed represent
  additions due to scattered light. A low order polynomial is fit to the change
  in reflectance as azimuth varies, and this polynomial is used to correct all
  sample measurements at a given incidence angle. The corrections typically
  increase as incidence angle increases but are usually on order of 5% or less.
 
  A full set of measurements (cycle) at a given wavelength takes approximately
  one hour. We use a stabilized power supply with active optical feedback to
  maintain the intensity within 1% during the measurement cycle. We check the
  fidelity of our data by duplicating twenty-seven measurements at the same or
  mirror positions throughout each cycle and comparing results. We find our
  root-mean-square repeatability to typically be within 2%.
 
  Please see the GEOMETRY directory for information regarding the observation
  geometry for the data in the archive.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
This data set underwent external peer
  review from July 2 through September 28, 2007.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

