<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.go-j-mag-3-rdr-magspheric-survey-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GO JUPITER MAG MAGNETOSPHERIC SURVEY V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.galileo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mag.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:plasma_cloud.io_plasma_torus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.amalthea::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.callisto::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.europa::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.ganymede::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.io::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-j-mag-3-rdr-magspheric-survey-v1.0__browserp_go-j-mag-3-rdr-magspheric-survey-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   DESSLER, A.J. ED., PHYSICS OF JOVIAN MAGNETOSPHERE, CAMBRIDGE UNIVERSITY PRESS,
                   LONDON, APPENDIX B - COORDINATE SYSTEMS, DESSLER, A.J., 1983.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DESSLER1983</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Erickson, J.K., Z.N. Cox, B.G. Paczkowski, R.W. Sible, E.E. Theilig, Project
                   Galileo: Completing Europa, Preparing for Io, paper IAF-99-Q.2.02, presented at
                   the 50th Congress of the International Astronautical Federation, Amsterdam,
                   Netherlands, 1999.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ERICKSONETAL1999</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Erickson, J.K., D.L. Bindschadler, E.E. Theilig, N. Vandermey, Project Galileo:
                   Surviving Io, Meeting Cassini, paper IAF-00-Q.2.01, presented at the 51st
                   Congress of the International Astronautical Federation, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil,
                   2000.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ERICKSONETAL2000</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Huddleston, D.E., R.J. Strangeway, J. Warnecke, C.T. Russell, and M.G.
                   Kivelson, Ion cyclotron waves in the Io torus: Wave dispersion, free energy
                   analysis, and SO2+ source rate estimates. J. Geophys. Res, 103, P. 19887, 1998.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HUDDLESTONETAL1998A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kivelson, M.G., K.K. Khurana, J.D. Means, C.T. Russell, and R.C. Snare, The
                   Galileo Magnetic Field Investigation, Space Science Reviews, 60, 1-4, 357, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KIVELSONETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kivelson M.G., K.K. Khurana, R.J. Walker, C.T. Russell, J.A. Linker, D.J.
                   Southwood, and C. Polanskey, A Magnetic Signature at Io: Initial Report from
                   the Galileo Magnetometer, Science, 273, P. 337, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KIVELSONETAL1996A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kivelson M.G., K.K. Khurana, R.J. Walker, J. Warnecke, C.T. Russell, J.A.
                   Linker, D.J. Southwood, and C. Polanskey, Io&apos;s interaction with the Plasma
                   Torus, Science, 274, P. 396, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KIVELSONETAL1996B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kivelson M.G., K.K. Khurana, C.T. Russell, R.J. Walker, P.J. Coleman, F.V.
                   Coroniti, J. Green, S. Joy, R.L. McPherron, C. Polanskey, D.J. Southwood, L.
                   Bennett, J. Warnecke, and D.E. Huddleston, Galileo at Jupiter: Changing states
                   of the Magnetosphere and first looks at Io and Ganymede, Adv. Space Res., 20,
                   No 2, P. 193, 1997.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KIVELSONETAL1997A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mitchell, R.T., Z.N. Cox, J.K. Erickson, B.G. Paczkowski, E.E. Theilig, Project
                   Galileo: The Europa mission, paper IAF-98-Q.2.01, presented at the 49th
                   Congress of the International Astronautical Federation, Melbourne, Australia,
                   1998.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MITCHELLETAL1998</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GO-J-MAG-3-RDR-MAGSPHERIC-SURVEY-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GO JUPITER MAG MAGNETOSPHERIC SURVEY V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1997-07-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1995-11-06T00:21Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2003-09-21T18:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. MARGARET G. KIVELSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Kivelson, M.G., Khurana, K.K., Russell, C.T., Walker, R.J., Joy,
            S.P., Mafi, J.N., GO JUPITER MAG MAGNETOSPHERIC SURVEY V1.0,
            GO-J-MAG-3-RDR-MAGSPHERIC-SURVEY-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 1997
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Galileo Magnetometer data and browse plots from the Jovian
            magnetospheric survey for all orbits and satellite flybys (Io,
            Europa, Ganymede, Callisto, and Amalthea).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains magnetic field vectors acquired by the
            Galileo Orbiter magnetometer during the magnetospheric survey
            portion of the mission. These data were acquired in the optimal
            averager (opt/avg) and real-time survey (RTS) modes beginning
            during the Jupiter approach and continuing throughout Jupiter
            orbital operations. The data set covers the time period from
            1995-11-06T00:21:30 UT (Jupiter approach) until the end of
            mission (September 2003). Sampling rates are variable and
            depended upon the downlink capabilities. With few exceptions, the
            data are provided at the full downlink resolution. The data are
            provided in five coordinate systems (IRC, System III [1965], JSE,
            JSO, and JSM).
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set contains magnetic field vectors acquired by the
    Galileo Orbiter magnetometer during the magnetospheric survey
    portion of the mission. These data were acquired in the optimal
    averager (opt/avg) and real-time survey (RTS) modes beginning during
    the Jupiter approach and continuing throughout Jupiter orbital
    operations. The data set covers the time period from
    1995-11-06T00:21:30 UT (Jupiter approach) until the end of mission
    (September 2003). Sampling rates are variable and depended upon the
    downlink capabilities. With few exceptions, the data are provided at
    the full downlink resolution. The data are provided in five
    coordinate systems (IRC, System III [1965], JSE, JSO, and JSM).
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
    Data Sampling
    -------------
      Data acquisition strategies varied throughout the mission. During
      the Jupiter approach period, most particles and fields (MWG)
      instruments were off while the magnetometer acquired low
      resolution opt/avg data. During the bulk of the prime mission,
      the MWG instruments were allowed to acquire continuous RTS data
      whenever the spacecraft was inside 50 Jovian radii (Rj). When the
      MWG was not returning RTS data, MAG used its opt/avg capability to
      acquire low time resolution averages of the field. In general,
      these are ~32 minute averages, although some higher rate data (1-8
      minute) were used to fill small gaps in RTS data coverage. Early
      in the prime mission, MAG was required to &apos;pay&apos; for the bits its
      used to return the opt/avg data by not acquiring as much high
      resolution data. MAG did not return data from the MWG transauroral
      crossing recorded interval in the C3 orbit so that it could have
      continuous coverage during that orbit. After the fourth orbit, the
      MAG opt/avg data was return in the spacecraft engineering data
      stream at no cost to the team. The MWG acquired RTS data beyond
      50 Rj in selected bit rich orbits (G2, G7, G8, C9, C10) during the
      prime mission.
 
      RTS, opt/avg, and snapshot data were all stored in the MAG
      internal memory buffer. RTS data were continuously averaged at MAG
      memory address 4800 and transmitted to Earth in real-time. When an
      opt/avg ON command was given data were stored in the MAG memory
      buffer beginning at address 4800 and continuing to higher
      addresses until Opt/Avg OFF was commanded, another Opt/Avg ON was
      commanded and the MAG buffer began filling at 4800 again, or the
      MAG memory buffer filled. Opt/avg data was returned to Earth via
      Memory Read-Out (MRO) as telemetry permitted. Since RTS and
      opt/avg data used the MAG memory buffer in different ways, they
      could not be collected simultaneously. Snapshot data, which
      completely filled the MAG memory buffer, could likewise not be
      collected simultaneously with opt/avg, and caused periodic spikes
      in RTS data. Snapshot corruption of RTS data is discussed in more
      detail in the &apos;Data Quality and Coverage&apos; section of this
      document. For a more detailed discussion how MAG RTS, opt/avg, and
      snapshot data are collected, please refer to [KIVELSONETAL1992].
 
      When high-resolution data were available, but the RTS data were
      either lost or corrupted, simulated RTS (sRTS) data have been
      generated from the high-resolution data. sRTS data were averaged
      down to the RTS rate, then interpolated to be continuous with the
      existing RTS data.
 
      During the prime mission, the RTS data rate varied, depending the
      downlink capability. MAG has several different possible
      RTS data rates depending on the telemetry format:
 
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------
      Table 1. MAG RTS Rates
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------
       Format     MAG bit rate    Time between samples    Corner Freq.
                    (bps)         (seconds)    (mf)         (Hz)
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------
         A-D         2               24         36          1/34
         E           4               12         18          1/34
         F           6                8         12          1/17
         G           8                6          9          1/17
         H          12                4          6          1/17
         I          18               8/3         4          1/17
 
      Similarly, the opt/avg data can be acquired at different rates.
      The relatively high data rates fill the MAG internal memory buffer
      more quickly and are only used to cover short data disruptions.
 
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------
      Table 2.          Optimal Averager Data Rates
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------
      Time between samples     Buffer fill time     Corner Freq.
       (RIM)   (hh:mm:ss.ss)     (day/hh:mm)            (Hz)
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------
          1     00:01:00.67         03:22             1/67
          2     00:02:01.33         06:44             1/134
          4     00:04:02.67         13:29             1/268
          8     00:08:05.33       1/02:58             1/536
         16     00:16:10.67       2/05:56             1/1072
         32     00:32:21.33       4/11:51             1/2144
         64     01:04:42.67       8/23:42             1/4289
 
      The instrument has the ability to acquire longer time averages
      but these modes were not used at Jupiter.
 
      After the prime mission ended (December 1997), RTS data
      acquisition was limited to only a few days near perijove except
      for a few orbits. RTS data are typically in the 2 bps (24
      sec/sample) telemetry formats. Opt/avg data after end of the
      prime mission, are primarily provided in 32 RIM (~32 min/sample)
      averages.
 
      Both the opt/avg and the RTS data processor compute field averages
      by applying a recursive filter and decimate algorithm to the data.
      The instrument applies a calibration, decimates vectors down to
      minor frame (mf) samples (2/3 second) and despins the data using
      the spin angle value broadcast on the spacecraft bus. The corner
      frequencies of the recursive filter are provided in tables 1 and 2
      for the various sample durations. The effect of this process is
      that the spacecraft time tags both RTS and opt/avg data at the
      time of decimation (end of average), rather than at the effective
      &apos;center&apos; of the average. As a result there is a time shift or
      phase delay between RTS or opt/avg data and data (e.g. LPW) which
      have not undergone the same filtering process. The magnitude of
      the phase delay is dependent upon the averaging interval (or
      rate) and frequency content of the data. Analysis of the filter
      response to a wave at the spin period (dominant frequency) has
      determined that the phase delay may be eliminated with the
      correction:
 
        [Corrected time] = [Sample time] - (Rate * (1/3))
 
      Where the &apos;Sample time&apos; is the time assigned by the spacecraft,
      and the &apos;Rate&apos; is the sampling rate in seconds. Both &apos;Sample Time&apos;
      and &apos;Corrected Time&apos; are provided in the data files. The IRC data
      file (which does not include a &apos;Corrected Time&apos; column) contains
      a &apos;Spacecraft Clock&apos; column which corresponds to the &apos;Sample Time&apos;
      (and not the &apos;Corrected Time&apos;). The RTS and opt/avg data overlay
      high time resolution data acquired at the same time best when the
      &apos;Corrected Time&apos; is used.
 
      MAG uses fixed gains to acquire data [KIVELSONETAL1992]. Gain
      states must be manually changed by sending a gain change
      command to the instrument. There are 3 ranges of field strengths
      that the instrument can measure:
 
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------
      Table 3.    Magnetometer Ranges
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------
      Field Range (nT)     Magnetometer, range
        min      max
      ---------------------------------------------------------------------
        1/64  -    32      Outboard low field
         1/4  -   512      Outboard high field, Inboard low field
           8  - 16384      Inboard high field
 
      While the outboard magnetometer&apos;s position on the boom does make
      it less susceptible to spacecraft fields, its zero levels were
      less stable than those of the inboard magnetometer. As a result,
      the outboard magnetometer was generally not used except when the
      magnetic field strength was very low. The outboard magnetometer
      was typically only used outside of 60 Rj (in the low field
      range). From 9-60 Rj the inboard magnetometer, low field range
      was generally used. Inside of ~9 Rj the inboard magnetometer,
      high field range was used.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    Browse data are primarily processed onboard the spacecraft by using
    estimates of the instrument calibration and zero levels. The
    calibration estimates cannot be improved in post processing due to
    the onboard averaging. Any errors in the sensor zero levels in the
    spin plane sensors will appear as harmonics of the spin period,
    possibly modified by frequency folding effects associated with the
    averaging windows. These effects can be removed in the RTS data in
    post processing. The long average intervals of the opt/avg data
    effectively removes these problems without need for post processing.
    Improvements are made to the zero level correction of the spin
    aligned sensor data for both RTS and opt/avg data in post
    processing.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    These data are stored in multiple data files in order to facilitate
    use and electronic distribution. In general, data from a single
    orbit is included in a data file. For some of the more data rich
    orbits, further subdivision was provided. Data from the five
    coordinate systems are stored in four separate files. The file
    format for a particular coordinate system is independent of the data
    acquisition interval. All data files from a given coordinate system
    are identical in structure. All data files are ASCII, fixed field,
    white space delimited tables. The following tables (4a-d) describe
    the record structure of the various type of data files.
 
    --------------------------------------------------------------------
    Table 4a. IRC Coordinates (Inertial Rotor coordinates)
    --------------------------------------------------------------------
    Column    Type   Description &lt;units&gt;
    --------------------------------------------------------------------
    samp time char   spacecraft event time sample was acquired from
                     MAG memory, PDS time format
    sclk      char   spacecraft clock (rim:mf:mod10:mod8)
    Bx_sc     float  magnetic-field spacecraft (IRC) x-component &lt;nT&gt;
    By_sc     float  magnetic-field spacecraft (IRC) y-component &lt;nT&gt;
    Bz_sc     float  magnetic-field spacecraft (IRC) z-component &lt;nT&gt;
    |B|       float  magnetic-field magnitude &lt;nT&gt;
    rotattr   float  rotor right ascension &lt;degrees&gt;
    rotattd   float  rotor declination &lt;degrees&gt;
    rotattt   float  rotor spin phase (twist) angle &lt;degrees&gt;
    spinangl  float  rotor spin phase angle &lt;degrees&gt;
    RATE      float  data sample rate &lt;seconds&gt;
 
    --------------------------------------------------------------------
    Table 4b. System III [1965] Coordinates
    --------------------------------------------------------------------
    Column    Type   Description &lt;units&gt;
    --------------------------------------------------------------------
    corr time char   spacecraft event time of sample corrected for
                     MAG filter response, PDS time format
    samp time char   spacecraft event time sample was acquired from
                     MAG memory, PDS time format
    Br        float  magnetic-field R (radial) component &lt;nT&gt;
    Btheta    float  magnetic-field theta (southward) component &lt;nT&gt;
    Bphi      float  magnetic-field phi (eastward) component &lt;nT&gt;
    |B|       float  magnetic-field magnitude &lt;nT&gt;
    R         float  s/c position - Radial distance from Jupiter
                     center-of-mass &lt;Rj = 71492 km&gt;
    LAT       float  s/c position - latitude &lt;degrees&gt;
    ELON      float  s/c position - East longitude &lt;degrees&gt;
    WLON      float  s/c position - West longitude &lt;degrees&gt;
 
    --------------------------------------------------------------------
    Table 4c. Jupiter Solar Equatorial (JSE) Coordinates
    --------------------------------------------------------------------
    Column    Type   Description &lt;units&gt;
    --------------------------------------------------------------------
    corr time char   spacecraft event time of sample corrected for
                     MAG filter response, PDS time format
    samp time char   spacecraft event time sample was acquired from
                     MAG memory, PDS time format
    Bx        float  magnetic-field x (sunward) component &lt;nT&gt;
    By        float  magnetic-field y (duskward) component &lt;nT&gt;
    Bz        float  magnetic-field z (Jovian spin axis aligned)
                     component &lt;nT&gt;
    |B|       float  magnetic-field magnitude &lt;nT&gt;
    X         float  s/c position - x (sunward) component &lt;Rj&gt;
    Y         float  s/c position - y (duskward) component &lt;Rj&gt;
    Z         float  s/c position - z (northward) component &lt;Rj&gt;
    LOCHOUR   float  s/c local hour &lt;hours&gt;
 
    --------------------------------------------------------------------
    Table 4d. Jupiter Solar Orbital (JSO) and Jupiter Solar Magnetic
              (JSM) Coordinates
    --------------------------------------------------------------------
    Column    Type   Description &lt;units&gt;
    --------------------------------------------------------------------
    corr time char   spacecraft event time of sample corrected for
                     MAG filter response, PDS time format
    samp time char   spacecraft event time sample was acquired from
                     MAG memory, PDS time format
    Bx        float  JSO/JSM magnetic-field x-component &lt;nT&gt;
    By_jso    float  JSO magnetic-field y-component &lt;nT&gt;
    Bz_jso    float  JSO magnetic-field z-component &lt;nT&gt;
    By_jsm    float  JSM magnetic-field y-component &lt;nT&gt;
    Bz_jsm    float  JSM magnetic-field z-component &lt;nT&gt;
    |B|       float  magnetic-field magnitude &lt;nT&gt;
    X         float  s/c position - JSO/JSM x-component &lt;Rj&gt;
    Y_JSO     float  s/c position - JSO y-component &lt;Rj&gt;
    Z_JSO     float  s/c position - JSO z-component &lt;Rj&gt;
    Y_JSM     float  s/c position - JSM y-component &lt;Rj&gt;
    Z_JSM     float  s/c position - JSM z-component &lt;Rj&gt;
    MLOCHOUR  float  S/C magnetic local hour &lt;hours&gt;
 
    These data were processed using SPICE kernels produced by the
    Galileo NAV team during the mission. All of the SPICE kernels
    used to produce this data set are contained on the MWG archive
    volume DVD in the EXTRAS/SPICE/KERNELS directory.
 
    The kernels (PDS PRODUCT_ID) used to create this were:
      S980326B.TSP - Prime Mission Reconstruction (JA-E12)
      S000131A.TSP - GEM reconstruction (E12-E26)
      S030916A.TSP - GMM (I27-J35) reconstruction
      PCK00007.TPC - Planetary constants kernel (2000-04-24)
      MK00062B.TSC - Galileo spacecraft clock kernel
 
 
  Coordinate Systems
  ==================
    The data are provided in five coordinate systems. Data are provided
    in the spacecraft coordinate system in order to aid in the
    interpretation of particle instrument data. The other coordinate
    systems are provided for use in Jovian magnetospheric studies. The
    Jupiter spin axis is defined to have a right ascension of 268.05
    degrees and a declination of +64.49 degrees in the J2000 coordinate
    system used by SPICE.
 
    Inertial Rotor Coordinates (IRC)
    --------------------------------
      The IRC coordinate system takes the basic rotor coordinate system
      (Y along the boom, Z opposite the high gain antenna) which is
      spinning, and despins it using the rotor spin angle. For this
      reason IRC coordinates are sometimes referred to as &apos;despun
      spacecraft coordinates.&apos; In this system, Z still points along the
      spin axis opposite the HGA (or roughly anti-Earthward), X is
      approximately parallel to the downward ecliptic normal, and Y
      completes the right handed set (pointing roughly towards dawn).
 
    System III [1965] Coordinates (SYS3)
    ------------------------------------
      SYS3 magnetic field vector components form the standard right
      handed spherical triad (R, Theta, Phi) for a Jupiter centered
      system. Namely, R is radial (along the line from the center of
      Jupiter to the center of the spacecraft), and positive away from
      Jupiter. Phi, the azimuthal component, is parallel to the
      Jovigraphic equator (Omega x R) and positive in the direction of
      corotation. Theta, the &apos;southward&apos; component, completes the right
      handed set.
 
      For SYS3 trajectory both east and west longitudes are provided.
      West longitudes are related to east longitudes by to the
      algorithm:
 
        west longitude = 360. - east longitude &lt;degrees&gt;
 
      West longitude is defined such that it appears to increase with
      time for a stationary observer [DESSLER1983]. Note, however, that
      R, latitude, and west longitude constitute a left handed set. The
      SYS3 1965 prime meridian is the sub-Earth longitude of
      1965-01-01 00:00 UT. The spin rate (which was determined from the
      rotation rate of the magnetic field) is 9 hrs 55 min 29.719 sec.
      (See [DESSLER1983] for a discussion on Jovian longitude). R is the
      radial (Jupiter&apos;s center to spacecraft center) distance. Latitude
      is planetocentric.
 
    Jupiter Solar Equatorial Coordinates (JSE)
    ------------------------------------------
      JSE is a Jupiter centered cartesian coordinates system defined to
      have it&apos;s Z-axis along the Jovian spin axis, positive in the
      direction of angular momentum (northward). The X-Z plane is
      contains the Sun so that the X-axis is the projection of the Sun
      direction into Jupiter&apos;s equatorial plane (positive towards the
      Sun). Y completes the right handed set and points duskward. This
      coordinate system is sometimes called Jupiter centered, Sun
      longitude fixed coordinates.
 
    Jupiter Solar Orbital Coordinates (JSO)
    ---------------------------------------
      JSO is another Jupiter centered cartesian coordinate system. JSO
      is the equivalent at Jupiter of GSE coordinates system at Earth.
      In JSO coordinates, the X-axis points from Jupiter to the Sun. Z
      is parallel to the upward normal to Jupiter&apos;s orbital plane. Y
      completes the right handed set.
 
    Jupiter Solar Magnetic Coordinates (JSM)
    ----------------------------------------
      Another Jupiter centered cartesian coordinate system, JSM is the
      equivalent at Jupiter of GSM coordinates system at Earth. In this
      coordinate system, the X-axis points from Jupiter to the Sun. The
      secondary vector defining this coordinate system is the centered
      magnetic dipole axis (M) which is defined to be tilted 9.6 degrees
      from the Jovian spin axis towards 202 degrees SYS3 west longitude.
      The X-Z plane is contains M. Y completes the right handed set. The
      Y-Z plane rocks at the Jovian spin period about the Sun-Jupiter
      line.
 
    Local Hour
    ----------
      Local hour angle is the angle (HA) between the observer&apos;s
      (Galileo) sub-Jupiter meridian and the anti-sunward meridian,
      measured in the Jovian equatorial plane in the direction of
      planetary rotation. Local hour is the conversion of the local
      hour angle into units of decimal hours using the conversion
      factor of one hour to fifteen degrees of longitude. The following
      diagram is a graphic representation of local hour.
 
                               Sun
                                ^
                                |
                               noon          Planetocentric
                              12:00       Equatorial Projection
                                |
                                |
                                |
                                | Jupiter
                              * * */
                             *  |  *
     (dusk) 18:00 -----------*--|--*------------- 06:00 (dawn)
                             *  |\ *
                              * * *
                                |  \
                                |   \
                                |    \
                                |-HA--\
                              00:00    + Spacecraft
                             midnight
 
 
    Magnetic Local Hour
    -------------------
      Magnetic local hour angle is the angle (MHA) between the
      observer&apos;s dipole meridian and the anti-sunward meridian,
      measured in the magnetic equatorial plane in the direction of
      planetary rotation. Magnetic local hour is the conversion of the
      magnetic local hour angle into units of decimal hours by using
      the conversion factor that equates one hour to fifteen degrees of
      longitude. The following diagram is a graphic representation of
      magnetic local hour.
 
 
                               Sun
                                ^
                                |
                               noon            Dipole
                              12:00       Equatorial Projection
                                |
                                |
                                |
                                | Jupiter
                              * * */
                             *  |  *
     (dusk) 18:00 -----------*--|--*------------- 06:00 (dawn)
                             *  |\ *
                              * * *
                                |  \
                                |   \
                                |    \
                                |-MHA-\
                              00:00    + Spacecraft
                             midnight
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    There are several files that are provided in addition to the data
    files themselves that may be of value to the user. These include a
    detailed data gap listing (including reason for gap), a table of
    important spacecraft and instrument events, a discussion of
    instrument anomalies and resolutions, and a set of quick-look or
    &apos;browse&apos; plots of the data.
 
 
  References
  ==========
    [DESSLER1983] Appendix B Coordinate Systems, in Physics of the
       Jovian Magnetosphere, ed. Dessler, Cambridge Univ. Press,
       New York, 1983.
    [KIVELSONETAL1992] The Galileo Magnetic Field Investigation,
       Space Science Rev.  60, 357, 1992.
    [KIVELSONETAL1996A] A Magnetic Signature at Io: Initial Report from
       the Galileo Magnetometer, Science, 273, 337, 1996
    [KIVELSONETAL1996B] Io&apos;s interaction with the Plasma Torus, Science,
       274, 396, 1996.
    [KIVELSONETAL1997A] Galileo at Jupiter: Changing states of the
       Magnetosphere and first looks at Io and Ganymede, Adv. Space
       Res., 20, No 2, 193, 1997.
    [HUDDLESTONETAL1998A] Location and Shape of the Jovian Magnetopause
       and Bowshock, J. Geophys.  Res, 103, no. E9, 20075, 1998.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Review
  ======
    These data have been reviewed by the instrument team and are of
    the highest quality that can be generated at this time. Science
    results based on these data have been published in several
    journals (Science, Nature, JGR, etc.). After submission to the
    PDS, these data successfully completed the peer review process.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
 
    Gaps
    ----
      The magnetometer browse data set contains all of the survey data
      that were returned from the instrument. However, there are
      numerous gaps in coverage. Gaps can be caused by telemetry
      outages, insufficient downlink or uplink, conjunctions, instrument
      anomalies, spacecraft anomalies, commanding errors, etc. A
      detailed gap listing including a description of the reason for the
      gap is provided in a separate file with these data. Here is a list
      of some of the larger or more common gaps.
 
        JA:  Gaps in coverage due to limited telemetry
        J0:  Large gaps during probe relay and Io playback
        G1:  MAG flip/commanding anomaly (3.5 weeks); spacecraft safing
             1 week)
        J5:  Conjunction, limited telemetry (5 weeks)
        E6:  Instrument anomaly, radiation hit (1.5 weeks)
        G7:  MAG flip anomaly (1 week)
        E12: AACS anomaly (7 weeks)
        J13: solar conjunction (6 weeks)
        E14: spacecraft safing (5 days)
        E15: ground station reallocated to SOHO for spacecraft anomaly
             recovery effort (3 days)
        E16: spacecraft safing (4 days)
        E17: ground station reallocated to Voyager 2 for spacecraft
             anomaly recovery effort (4 days)
        E18: spacecraft safing (2 days); ground station reallocated to
             NEAR for spacecraft anomaly recovery effort (2 days)
        E19: spacecraft safing (1.5 weeks); solar conjunction (3 weeks)
        I24: loss of telemetry during MRO (4 days)
        I25: opt/avg corrupted by shapshots (2 days)
        I27: spacecraft safing (2 days); solar conjunction (2.5 weeks)
        G28: loss of telemetry during MRO (4 days)
        G29: loss of telemetry during MRO (3 days)
        C30: SSI anomaly recovery/loss of telemetry (2 days); solar
             conjunction (2.5 weeks)
        I33: spacecraft safing (1 week); loss of telemetry for MRO (2.5,
             and 3 days); solar conjunction (3 weeks); loss of telemetry
             during MRO (4 days); spacecraft safing (4.5 days)
        A34: spacecraft safing (5 days); telemetry outage (4.5 days);
             end of spacecraft operations before impact (36 weeks)
 
      Other common causes of data gaps that are not related to
      telemetry outages and anomaly gaps are listed below. Gaps may
      have occurred throughout Jupiter Orbital Operations - whenever
      the conditions which caused them existed.
 
        Gaps between consecutive opt/avg segments: Gaps of at least two
        data vectors occurred between consecutive opt/avg data segments.
        The first and last vector in every opt/avg segment are
        underfiltered and have therefore been discarded. For the most
        common data opt/avg rate, this results in a gap of ~1 hour.
        These gaps may be larger than two vectors if there is any delay
        between the MRO of the data in the buffer and the subsequent
        opt/avg ON command.
 
        Snapshot corruption of RTS data: When snapshots (see
        [KIVELSONETAL1992] for more information) were taken the
        addresses in which RTS data were averaged were overwritten with
        snapshot data. Since snapshots were written to MAG memory in
        reversed byte order, the result was a spike which persisted over
        the course of few records due to the application of the filter.
        Whenever possible RTS data corrupted by snapshots have been
        replaced with sRTS data which were unaffected by snapshots. When
        high-resolution data are not available, however, snapshots
        result in a series of short (3-6 vector), regularly spaced gaps
        in the RTS.
 
      The MAG data quality (size of error bars) varies with instrument
      mode (digitization step size), sample rate, etc. The errors can
      be broken down into three basic types: zero levels, gains, and
      geometry.
 
    Simulated RTS Data
    ------------------
      While sRTS data have been matched to the existing RTS data rates
      they have not been generated using the same process. sRTS data
      have not gone through the same recursive filter that was applied
      to the regular RTS data. sRTS has been generated for the following
      intervals:
 
        ----------------------------------------------------
        Table 5. Simulated RTS (sRTS) intervals
        ----------------------------------------------------
               High-Res.
        Orbit  Obs. ID    Start Time        Stop Time
        ----------------------------------------------------
        G1     G01-GAN    1996-06-27 06:07  1996-06-27 06:52
        G1     G01-PSX    1996-06-30 02:01  1996-06-30 02:46
        G2     G02-GAN    1996-09-06 18:33  1996-09-06 19:28
        G2     G02-PSX    1996-09-11 02:38  1996-09-11 03:18
        C3     C03-CALL   1996-11-04 13:15  1996-11-04 14:00
        E4     E04-EUR    1996-12-19 06:35  1996-12-19 07:22
        G8     G08-QRS    1997-05-06 13:00  1997-05-06 15:09
        C9     C09-CALL   1997-06-25 13:25  1997-06-25 14:11
        C9     C09-DAWN   1997-08-23 14:07  1997-08-23 16:09
        C9     C09-TAR    1997-06-28 13:50  1997-06-28 14:51
        C9     C09-DSK1   1997-07-04 14:09  1997-07-04 16:07
        C9     C09-DSK2   1997-07-14 10:03  1997-07-14 10:48
        C9     C09-DSK3   1997-07-23 13:11  1997-07-23 13:57
        C9     C09-APJ    1997-08-07 11:06  1997-08-07 12:47
        C10    C10-CALL   1997-09-16 23:49  1997-09-17 00:49
        C10    C10-EQX    1997-09-18 22:35  1997-09-18 23:21
        E11    E11-EUR    1997-11-06 20:09  1997-11-06 22:51
        E12    E12-EUR    1997-12-16 11:43  1997-12-16 12:28
        E14    E14-EUR    1998-03-29 13:05  1998-03-29 14:00
        E15    E15-EUR    1998-05-31 20:42  1998-05-31 21:43
        E15    E15-EUR    1998-05-31 20:42  1998-05-31 21:43
        E18    E18-PSX    1998-12-10 19:36  1998-12-11 00:23
        E19    E19-EUR    1999-02-01 01:49  1999-02-01 02:38
        C20    C20-PJOV   1999-05-03 16:00  1999-05-03 18:00
        C21    C21-PJOV   1999-07-01 23:52  1999-07-02 01:47
        C22    C22-PJOV   1999-08-12 08:18  1999-08-12 13:06
        C23    C23-PJOV   1999-09-14 14:36  1999-09-14 21:28
        I24    I24-IO     1999-10-11 03:42  1999-10-11 06:41
        I25    I25-TOR    1999-11-25 21:06  1999-11-26 05:54
        E26    E26-EUR    2000-01-03 17:29  2000-01-03 18:30
        I27    I27-TOR    2000-02-22 10:22  2000-02-22 12:15
        I27    I27-IO     2000-02-22 13:05  2000-02-22 14:25
        I31    I31-IO     2001-08-06 04:31  2001-08-06 05:28
        I32    I32-RAMP   2001-10-15 15:31  2001-10-15 17:26
        I32    I32-TOR    2001-10-15 21:53  2001-10-15 23:23
        A34    A34-PSX7   2002-11-05 01:05  2002-11-05 05:45
 
    Zero Levels
    -----------
      In general, the zero levels of the spin plane sensors have been
      corrected to approximately 1/4 of the digitization step size
      (i.e. if the step size is 8 nT, the zero level is good to 2 nT)
      or 0.01 nT, which ever is larger. Spin plane sensor zero levels
      are continuously adjusted by removing spin period averages in
      the spinning reference frame. The spin aligned sensor zero levels
      are monitored and adjusted at least once per orbit. The spin
      aligned sensor zero levels are assumed to drift slowly and
      linearly. The exception to this statement occurs at times
      identified as &apos;offset anomalies&apos; (see Table 7) where all three
      sensors in a triad show large (2-3 nT) jumps in the zero levels.
      These anomalies have been corrected in the processed data. In
      general, the spin aligned sensor zero level is reliable to 0.1 nT.
      Errors in zero level corrections appear as harmonics of the
      spacecraft spin period as modified by the averaging window. The
      nominal spacecraft spin period is 19 seconds and the most common
      sample rates are 24 and 12 seconds.
 
    Outboard Sensor Zero Levels
    ---------------------------
      Zero levels in the outboard sensor have proven to be strongly
      temperature dependent. Offsets changed linearly with temperature
      during the Earth-Jupiter Cruise mission phase where temperatures
      went from 280-220 K. At Jupiter, where temperatures have been
      lower than the instrument qualification ranges, offsets at
      Jupiter have experienced occasional episodes of instability.
      Offset changes may occur instantaneously or rapidly (over a
      period of minutes). In some cases the offset has drifted back to
      previous values over a period of days or months. In other cases
      the offset has returned to it&apos;s original value sharply. In all
      cases an attempt has been made to correct for these offset
      in the processing so that the data appear continuous. Table 7
      contains a listing of major offset anomalies.
 
    Gains
    -----
      The sensor gains were determined in ground calibration and
      verified in-flight. In-flight verification included comparison
      of Earth flyby data with model fields and monitoring for
      sensor gain changes using the MAG internal calibration coils.
      In general, the gains have remained stable throughout the
      mission. There has been a slight change (linear) in the
      absolute gain levels associated with the sensor temperature.
      Gains are believed to be known to substantially better than one
      percent.
 
    Geometry
    --------
      Geometry corrections for sensor mounting and non-orthogonality
      are applied through the sensor coupling matrix. Although the
      sensor triads are rigid and are not believed to have changed
      geometry through time, the triad itself is flipped periodically
      to rotate the spin aligned sensor into the spin plane. Small
      variations (&lt;0.1 degree) in the triad mounting with respect to
      the spacecraft coordinate system must be corrected after each
      sensor flip. This is done by computing a new coupling matrix.
 
      The data are despun by using the &apos;rotor spin angle&apos; that is
      broadcast on the spacecraft bus by the spacecraft attitude and
      articulation control system (AACS). Despinning must be corrected
      in ground processing to account for delays in the MAG instrument
      electronics and filters. This task is accomplished by respinning
      the data using the raw AACS data and then despinning using a
      corrected spin angle. The total correction can be as large as
      two degrees. After ground processing, the MAG data are
      geometrically correct to better than one degree, and probably
      better than 0.1 degree.
 
    Optimal Averager AACS
    ---------------------
      Two of the rotor attitude angles supplied in the IRC data files,
      Rotor Twist and Rotor Spin, are always flagged when the opt/avg
      was being used to capture the data. The opt/avg produces
      extremely low sampling rates (typically &gt;32 min/sample).In
      addition in the engineering stream the various rotor attitude
      angles are sampled asynchronously both from each other and from
      the MAG data. As a result any rotor attitude information provided
      at the MAG sampling times must be interpolated. While the other
      two angles vary only slowly, the twist and spin angles vary over
      0-2 pi at the spacecraft spin period (~20 sec). Since the MAG
      data produced by the opt/avg represent averages over many spin
      periods it is not meaningful to assign specific twist or spin
      angles to the data. It is also not possible to &apos;re-spin&apos; the
      data, which is the purpose of providing Rotor Twist and Spin in
      the first place.
 
    Slew Tests
    ----------
      Due to the continuing gyro electronics problems that were first
      observed in E12, a series of &apos;slew tests&apos; were implemented in
      order to access gyro functioning. During these tests, because of
      the potential for anomalous behavior by the gyros, the spacecraft
      attitude is not known with any certainty. This poses problems for
      both the B-field components and AACS. Opt/avg data, because of the
      relatively short duration of the tests and the long averages of
      the data, show no real effects from the corruption. The RTS data,
      however, can show the effects very clearly. As a result the
      B-field components have been flagged when a slew test was
      performed with the instrument in RTS mode, and the components were
      preserved when the instrument is in opt/avg mode. The components
      were flagged in the RTS data even when no corruption was readily
      apparent. The flagged data are available in the Galileo Jupiter
      MAG raw data set.
 
      The following table gives the timing of the slew tests. The times
      indicated correspond to the start and end of the group of commands
      that constituted a slew test. The interval in which the B-field
      components actually become corrupted was shorter than this. This
      corrupted interval started approximately with the &apos;SLEW TEST&apos;
      and ended with the &apos;ENABLE SEQID,RESD HVEC&apos; (see MAG EVENT TABLE).
      Mode indicates whether the instrument was in RTS or OPT/AVG mode.
      A value of &apos;N/A&apos; indicates that the slew test occurs in a data
      gap.
 
        -----------------------------------------------------
        Table 6. Slew tests
        -----------------------------------------------------
        Orbit   Start Time         Stop Time          Mode
        -----------------------------------------------------
        E14     1998-05-13 12:40   1998-05-13 14:23   OPT/AVG
        E17     1998-11-07 17:00   1998-11-07 20:38   OPT/AVG
        E19     1999-04-27 21:32   1999-04-27 21:40   OPT/AVG
        I24     1999-10-13 16:42   1999-10-13 18:23   OPT/AVG
        I24     1999-10-27 12:00   1999-10-27 14:15   RTS
        I25     1999-11-28 07:27   1999-11-28 09:08   N/A
        I25     1999-12-09 01:00   1999-12-09 03:15   OPT/AVG
        E26     2000-01-05 19:12   2000-01-05 20:53   OPT/AVG
        E26     2000-02-07 15:00   2000-02-07 17:15   OPT/AVG
        I27     2000-02-23 17:52   2000-02-23 19:33   N/A
        I27     2000-03-27 16:00   2000-03-27 18:15   OPT/AVG
        G28     2000-05-22 00:12   2000-05-22 01:53   RTS
        G28     2000-06-23 19:30   2000-06-23 21:45   OPT/AVG
        G28     2000-08-31 07:42   2000-08-31 09:23   OPT/AVG
        G28     2000-10-18 22:12   2000-10-18 23:53   OPT/AVG
        G28     2000-12-07 21:42   2000-12-07 23:23   RTS
        G29     2000-12-30 01:32   2000-12-30 03:13   RTS
        G29     2001-03-07 17:00   2001-03-07 19:15   OPT/AVG
        G29     2001-05-14 16:00   2001-05-14 18:15   OPT/AVG
        C30     2001-05-26 01:00   2001-05-26 02:41   N/A
        C30     2001-07-05 23:00   2001-07-06 01:15   OPT/AVG
        I31     2001-08-07 20:00   2001-08-07 21:41   N/A
        I31     2001-08-23 23:00   2001-08-24 01:15   OPT/AVG
        I32     2001-10-17 03:40   2001-10-17 05:21   RTS
        I32     2001-11-19 16:00   2001-11-19 18:15   OPT/AVG
        I33     2002-01-18 18:00   2002-01-18 19:41   RTS
        I33     2002-04-03 16:00   2002-04-03 18:15   OPT/AVG
        I33     2002-06-05 16:00   2002-06-05 19:15   OPT/AVG
        I33     2002-10-07 17:20   2002-10-07 20:35   OPT/AVG
        I33     2002-10-24 17:30   2002-10-24 20:45   RTS
        A34     2002-11-13 23:30   2002-11-14 02:11   N/A
        A34     2003-01-07 22:00   2003-01-08 01:15   OPT/AVG
 
 
    Anomalies
    ---------
      Sector Data Loss Due to Thruster Flushes:
 
      Thruster flushes (RPM PROPEL LINES VENT) cause the loss of sector
      (rotor twist) data onboard the spacecraft. This loss results in
      the corruption of RTS and opt/avg data which depend upon sector
      data for their onboard despinning. As a result RTS and opt/avg
      data taken during thruster flushes should not be trusted.
      Where they have been identified intervals of data affected by
      this problem have been removed from this data set.
 
      Offset Anomalies:
 
      Table 7 lists the offset anomalies that occurred over the course
      of the mission. These anomalies typically consisted in an
      instantaneous jump in the zero-level over all three sensors,
      though in some cases there was a slower drift. The anomaly times
      represent the times at which this jump was evident in the data.
      In some instances, these events occcurred when the affected
      magnetometer was not in use. In these cases the offsets had one
      set of values when turned off, and a different set when turned on
      some time later. The time given for these cases is the time at
      which the magnetometer was turned back and the anomaly is
      indicated as having happend &apos;before&apos; that time.
 
      While zero-levels for the inboard magnetometer did change over
      time, as evidenced by the below table the outboard magnetometer
      proved much more unstable than the inboard (URLR was the mode
      most commonly used in the outboard magnetometer). Because of its
      instability, the outboard instrument it was not used between C10
      and G29. Had it been used additional anomalies may well have been
      observed in this time period.
 
        ----------------------------------
        Table 7. Offset Anomalies
        ----------------------------------
        Orbit   Mode   Time
        ----------------------------------
        E4      URLR   before 96-12-29 21:10
        E6      URLR   before 97-03-03 19:10
        G7      URLR   before 97-04-12 07:00
        G7      URLR   97-04-16 15:19
        C9      IRLR   97-06-22 16:05
        C9      URLR   before 97-07-02 10:00
        C10     URLR   before 97-09-25 19:38
        C10     URLR   97-10-05 14:53
        G29     URLR   01-02-07 06:11
        C30     URLR   before 01-05-29 14:00
        I31     URLR   before 01-08-12 02:30
        I31     URLR   01-09-12 08:00
        I32     URLR   before 01-10-21 15:30
 
      Jupiter Orbital Insertion (JOI):
 
      Prior to the JOI burn the spacecraft spin rate was increased in
      order to make it more stable for the firing of the main engine.
      In addition there was no high-resolution AACS through this
      interval. As a result of the variable spin rate and lack of
      high-resolution AACS it was not possible despin the MAG data. As
      a result only the magnetic-field magnitude is provided.
 
      Callisto 3 Orbit:
 
      The data from the inboard sensor, low field, flip right mode
      acquired during the third orbit was irrecoverably corrupted.
      Data from this orbit should be used with caution, particularly
      in applications where the field orientation needs to be known
      to better than a few degrees. At the beginning of the orbit,
      the inboard sensor was commanded to flip right. We believe that
      when this flip occurred, the sensor triad failed to lock into
      place properly. As a result, the sensor triad appears to
      &apos;jiggle&apos; resulting in an unstable geometry. The extent of this
      jiggle is unknown but is believed to be on the order of a degree
      or so. One of the impacts of the unstable sensor geometry is that
      the sensor offsets, which are a combination of spacecraft fields
      and sensor zero levels, vary on short time scales. In order to
      reduce the spin harmonics attributable to offsets in this orbit,
      the RTS data have been averaged using a 120 second window on
      24 second centers.
 
      Callisto 9 and 10 Orbit Opt/Avg:
 
      In orbits C9 and C10 the magnetometer was commanded into opt/avg
      mode without deselecting the instrument from RTS. As a result the
      Command and Data Subsystem (CDS) overwrote the opt/avg rate
      filter constant stored in MAG memory with a RTS rate filter
      constant. This resulted in the data being under filtered relative
      to the data sample rate. This under filtering shows up as
      spin-tone in the spinning sensors in spacecraft coordinates. In
      order to eliminate the spin-tone the raw data has been averaged
      (two point averages on one point centers). Averaging has been
      performed on the following intervals:
 
        ----------------------------------------
        Table 8. Averaged intervals for
                 underfiltered opt/avg data
        ----------------------------------------
        Orb  Start Time         Stop Time
        ----------------------------------------
        C9   1997-07-10T18:15   1997-07-11T10:58
        C9   1997-08-01T14:50   1997-08-02T17:07
        C9   1997-09-11T17:04   1997-09-11T21:01
        C10  1997-09-29T11:36   1997-09-30T11:52
 
      Europa 17 MAG and AACS instability:
 
      Between 1998-09-26T15:46:24 and 1998-09-26T16:42:01 the AACS data
      are unstable. Apparently, some form of AACS calibration was
      occurring. During this period, the magnetometer spin plane
      components appear to slowly rotate and then jump back to a
      correct orientation. This problem occurred on the spacecraft and
      has not been corrected in the ground system processing.
 
      Europa 19 AACS Data Gap:
 
      Due to a spacecraft anomaly AACS data from 1999-01-31 16:02:06 -
      1999-02-01 01:49:37 (which were being stored in the Multi User
      Buffer) were never returned. The MAG data from this interval,
      however, were written to tape and returned later. Recovering the
      lost AACS - specifically the rotor right-ascension (RA), and
      declination (DEC) - was complicated by two Science Instrument
      Turns (SITURN&apos;s) which occurred in the missing interval. In
      between the SITURN&apos;s, RA and DEC were interpolated by the
      following means:
 
        1/31 16:02:06 to 18:01:28     - set to last known value
        1/31 18:01:28 to 18:26        - linearly interpolated
        1/31 18:26    to 19:31:27     - assumed constant between
          SITURN&apos;s and determined by examination
        1/31 19:31:27 to 19:49        - linearly interpolated
        1/31 19:49    to 2/1 01:49:37 - set to next known value (taken
          from high-res. data, the E19-EUR recording)
 
      AACS instability Callisto 21 - Callisto 23:
 
      The AACS data for the Callisto 21, Callisto 22, and Callisto 23
      perijove recordings (C21-PJOV, C22-PJOV, and C23-PJOV) were
      seriously corrupted. While similar problems are not evident in
      the RTS and opt/avg data, care should be taken in the use of
      these lower rate data as well. For Orbit 23 it was necessary to
      interpolate the rotor twist and spin angles of the intervals:
      1999-09-17 05:26:41 to 06:08:30 and 1999-09-27 16:06:58 to
      16:28:53.
 
      Io 25 Data Gaps Due to Corruption by Snapshots:
 
      Following recovery from spacecraft safing, MAG was inadvertently
      left in snapshot mode. As a result there are numerous short gaps
      where the RTS data were corrupted by snapshots, and a large gap
      where the OPT/AVG data were overwritten. This problem affects
      the interval 1999-11-26 04:32 to 1999-11-29 00:54.
 
      Europa 26 Data Rate Anomaly:
 
      The packet headers for the data from the time interval
      2000-01-01 23:30:00.000 to 2000-01-03 14:08:39.742 indicated that
      the data were sampled at 18 minor frames (mf) or 12 seconds
      sampling resolution. This data rate matched the MAG RTS format
      reported in the sequence (format E). In the original 12 second
      data there were a series of systematic gaps. The end of each gap
      occurred where the packet of MAG data included a time tag. This
      would be the case if an incorrect sampling rate were applied to
      the data in packets where no time tag is given, then the data
      were to jump forward to the correct time when a time tag was
      given. Accordingly the data in this interval were re-time tagged
      at 36 mf (24 second) samples. This done the data became
      continuous across what were previously gaps -- both in time (the
      data are evenly sampled), and data value (the data contain no
      steps). The reason for this discrepancy was unknown.
 
      Io 33 Offset Instability:
 
      The spin-plane offsets in the outboard sensor (URLR mode) were
      highly unstable for the RTS data. This includes the following
      intervals:
 
        2002-01-22 20:30 - 2002-01-31 13:00
        2002-10-22 00:00 - 2002-10-31 12:30
 
      While an attempt was made to correct the offsets, some problems
      may still exist (see &apos;Zero Levels&apos;). Additionally, the zero level
      instability may indicate that the sensor was about to fail. For
      both of these reasons, the data from these two intervals should
      be treated with some suspicion.
 
      Io 33 opt/avg data timing:
 
      The timing of the opt/avg data in the interval 2002-Sep-28 13:00
      to 2002-Oct-02 23:15 are somewhat questionable and the data should
      be treated with some caution. According to the planned sequence,
      the data collected after the opt/avg on command given at
      2002-09-28 12:05, were due to be read out with the MRO scheduled
      for 2002-10-02 18:00. However, due to the spacecraft safing that
      occurred 2002-10-02 03:38 the MRO was not executed. Since the
      spacecraft was still safed, the subsequent opt/avg on command
      (2002-10-02 19:05) was also not executed and the data were not
      overwritten. Thus when the MRO commanded at 2002-10-07 10:00 was
      executed the data returned appear to have been from the opt/avg at
      2002-09-28 12:05 -- and not from the opt/avg at 2002-10-02 19:05
      as originally planned. The data in this interval have been timed
      according to this assumed sequence of events.
 
      Amalthea 34 data coverage:
 
      Spacecraft operations ended on 2003-01-15. As a result there is a
      large gap in coverage from about that time until 2003-09-21 when
      operations resumed briefly to record the spacecraft&apos;s plunge into
      the Jovian atmosphere. Between these two times an occasional
      single (8 hour) pass of data was provided as a monitor of
      instrument health. However, these monitoring data are not included
      as part of this data set. The reasons for omitting these data are
      that their sporatic nature limits their usefulness, and a lack of
      AACS data prevents them from being fully processed. These
      monitoring data are included in the Galileo at Jupiter MAG raw
      data set.
 
      Jupter 35 AACS:
 
      The AACS returned in J35 had Earth Receive Times (ERTs) on
      2003-09-21, but Spacecraft Event Times (SCETs) on 2003-01-22. In
      processing the J35 data it was assumed that the ERTs were correct
      and that the SCETs were incorrect, meaning that the values of RA
      and DEC were approximately correct. Due to the difficulty of
      precisely determining the correct timing of the AACS data, the
      RA, DEC, and rotor spin delta were set to the most common values
      for the interval, and the rotor spin angle, and rotor twist angle
      were calculated from them.
 
 
  Product Versions
  ================
    The following table describes the various versions of the data
    files.
 
    --------------------------------------------------------------------
    Table 9. Data product versions
    --------------------------------------------------------------------
    Product
    Version
    ID       Description
    --------------------------------------------------------------------
     1       original release
     2       opt/avg data timing was corrected: a previous error in
             the time tagging of the opt/avg data resulted in that
             data being shifted earlier in time by one averager step.
     3       JSO coordinates were added (and included with JSM
             coordinates); a &apos;CORRECTED TIME&apos; column, which has a
             filter response time applied to the &apos;SAMPLE TIME&apos; was
             added to the SYS3, JSE, and JSO/JSM coordinate data
             files; SYS3 coordinate file was modified to include both
             east and west longitude columns; a variety of changes
             were made to record formats
 
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    There are no particular limitations or warnings regarding the
    use of these data, in general, that are not described above.
    Users should review the PDS label files associated with
    individual data files for file (orbit) specific warnings.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

