<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dii-c-its-3-4-9p-encounter-v2.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DEEP IMPACT 9P/TEMPEL ENCOUNTER - REDUCED ITS IMAGES V2.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_impact::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dii::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:its.dii::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.9p-tempel_1_1867_g1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dii-c-its-3-4-9p-encounter-v2.0__browserp_dii-c-its-3-4-9p-encounter-v2.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   A&apos;Hearn, M.F., M.J.S. Belton, W.A. Delamere, J. Kissel, K.P. Klaasen, L.A.
                   McFadden, K.J. Meech, H.J. Melosh, P.H. Schultz, J.M. Sunshine, P.C. Thomas, J.
                   Veverka, D.K. Yeomans, M.W. Baca, I. Busko, C.J. Crockett, S.M. Collins, M.
                   Desnoyer, C.A. Eberhardy, C.M. Ernst, T.L. Farnham, L. Feaga, O. Groussin, D.
                   Hampton, S.I. Ipatov, J.-Y. Li, D. Lindler, C.M. Lisse, N. Mastrodemos, W.M.
                   Owen, J.E. Richardson, D.D. Wellnitz, and R.L. White, Deep Impact: Excavating
                   Comet Tempel 1, Science, 310, 258-264, 2005, doi:10.1126/science.1118923.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.AHEARNETAL2005A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   A&apos;Hearn, M.F., M.J.S. Belton, A. Delamere, and W.H. Blume, Deep Impact: A
                   Large-Scale Active Experiment on a Cometary Nucleus, Space Science Reviews,
                   117, 1-21, 2005, doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3387-3.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.AHEARNETAL2005B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hampton, D.L., J.W. Baer, M.A. Huisjen, C.C. Varner, A. Delamere, D.D.
                   Wellnitz, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, and K.P. Klaasen, An Overview of the Instrument Suite
                   for the Deep Impact Mission, Space Science Reviews, 117, 43-93, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3390-8.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAMPTONETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., B. Carcich, G. Carcich, E.J. Grayzeck, and S. McLaughlin, Deep
                   Impact: The Anticipated Flight Data, Space Science Reviews, 117, 335-372, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3385-5.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., M.F. A&apos;Hearn, M. Baca, A. Delamere, M. Desnoyer, T. Farnham, O.
                   Groussin, D. Hampton, S. Ipatov, J. Li, C. Lisse, N. Mastrodemos, S.
                   McLaughlin, J. Sunshine, P. Thomas, and D. Wellnitz, Deep Impact Instrument
                   Calibration, Rev. Sci. Instrum., 79, 091301, 2008, doi:10.1063/1.2972112.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DII-C-ITS-3/4-9P-ENCOUNTER-V2.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DEEP IMPACT 9P/TEMPEL ENCOUNTER - REDUCED ITS IMAGES V2.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2006-12-22</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2005-07-03T07:44:28.368Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2005-07-04T05:44:29.555Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STEPHANIE MCLAUGHLIN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            McLaughlin, S. A., B. Carcich, T. McCarthy, M. Desnoyer, and K.P.
            Klaasen, DEEP IMPACT 9P/TEMPEL ENCOUNTER - REDUCED ITS IMAGES
            V2.0, DII-C-ITS-3/4-9P-ENCOUNTER-V2.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2006.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Calibrated images (version 2.0) of comet 9P/Tempel 1 acquired by
            the Deep Impact Impactor Target Sensor Visible CCD after the
            impactor was released from the flyby spacecraft on 3 July 2005
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains version 2.0 of calibrated images of comet
            9P/Tempel 1 acquired by the Deep Impact Impactor Target Sensor
            Visible CCD after the impactor was released from the flyby
            spacecraft on 3 July 2005. Version 2.0 includes uncleaned
            radiance, cleaned radiance, and I-over-F data with improved
            geometry and revised image start and stop times. The data were
            collected on 3-4 July 2005.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set contains version 2.0 of calibrated images of comet
    9P/Tempel 1 acquired by the Deep Impact Impactor Target Sensor Visible
    CCD (ITS) after the impactor was released from the flyby spacecraft
    on 3 July 2005.  Version 2.0 includes uncleaned radiance, cleaned
    radiance, and I-over-F data with improved geometry and revised image
    start and stop times.  The data were collected on 3-4 July 2005.
 
    A summary of the comet observations in this data set is provided here:
 
        Mid-Obs          Exposure IDs
         Date     DOY  Minimum  Maximum  Mission Activity
      ----------  ---  -------  -------  ---------------------------------
      2005-07-03  184  9000026  9000043  Release, Continuous Comet Imaging
      2005-07-03  184  9000060  9000128  Continuous Comet Imaging
      2005-07-04  185  9000130  9000710  Continuous Comet Imaging, Impact
 
    The 9P/Tempel 1 data are described in &apos;Deep Impact:  The Anticipated
    Flight Data&apos; by Klaasen, et al. (2005) [KLAASENTAL2005].  For more
    details about the images taken around impact, refer to the ITS
    encounter data summary document which provides a log of the exposures
    beginning about 22 hours before impact.  Both of these documents are
    included on the Deep Impact Documentation volume.
 
 
    Essential Reading
    -----------------
      The following documents, located on the Deep Impact Documentation
      volume, DIDOC_0001, are essential for the understanding and
      interpretation of this data set:
 
      ANTICIPATED_FLIGHT_DATA.*      : Anticipated flight data by Klaasen,
                                       et al. (2005) [KLAASENTAL2005]
      ITS_REDUCED_ENC_INDEX.*        : Science-related index table for
                                       this data set
      ITS_ENCOUNTER_DATA_SUMMARY.*   : Image log beginning about 22 hours
                                       before impact
      INFLIGHT_CALIBRATION_SUMMARY.* : Summary of in-flight calibrations
      CALIBRATION_DOC.*              : Instrument calibration by Klaasen,
                                       et al. (2006) [KLAASENETAL2006]
      INSTRUMENTS_HAMPTON.*          : Instrument paper by Hampton, et al.
                                       (2005) [HAMPTONETAL2005]
      MISSION_OVERVIEW_AHEARN.*      : Mission overview by A&apos;Hearn, et al.
                                       (2005) [AHEARNETAL2005B]
      SCLK_CORRELATION.*             : Discussion of the discrepancy
                                       between the spacecraft clocks and
                                       UTC
      AICD_FLIGHT_HRIV_MRI_ITS.*     : Description of the data set and
                                       definitions of label keywords
 
      Initial results from the encounter and impact were presented in
      &apos;Deep Impact: Excavating Comet Tempel 1&apos; by by A&apos;Hearn, et al.
      (2005) [AHEARNETAL2005A].
 
 
    Related Data Sets
    -----------------
      The following PDS data sets are related to this one:
 
      DII-CAL-ITS-2-9P-CRUISE-V1.0  : Raw ITS cruise calibrations
      DII-C-ITS-2-9P-ENCOUNTER-V1.0 : Raw ITS encounter data
      DII-CAL-ITS-2-GROUND-TV3-V1.0 : ITS pre-flight calib data
      DI-C-SPICE-6-V1.0             : SPICE kernels
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The calibrated two-dimensional FITS images in this data set were
    generated by the Deep Impact calibration pipeline, maintained by the
    project&apos;s Science Data Center (SDC) at Cornell University.  For
    these data (version 2.0), geometric parameters were computed using
    the final kernels found in the PDS SPICE archive for Deep Impact.
 
    The pipeline performed the following reduction steps to produce the
    images in this data set:
 
      - Decompression of compressed images
      - Subtraction of a dark frame
      - Removal of electronic cross-talk
      - Application of a normalized flat field
      - Removal of CCD transfer smear
      - Conversion of data numbers to units of radiance for an absolute,
        radiometric calibration (&apos;RADREV&apos;)
      - Interpolation over bad and missing pixels for partially cleaned,
        radiometric calibration (&apos;RAD&apos;)
      - Conversion of cleaned radiance images (&apos;RAD&apos;) to I-over-F
        images (&apos;IF&apos;)
 
    The uncleaned radiance data, designated by the mnemonic &apos;RADREV&apos;,
    were provided in units of radiance as Watts/(meter**2 steradian
    micron).  These data were considered reversible because the
    calibration steps could be removed to get back to the original, raw
    data numbers.  Only the RADREV data were included in version 1.0 of
    this data set.
 
    The irreversibly cleaned radiance data, designated by the mnemonic
    &apos;RAD&apos;, were provided in units of radiance, Watts/(meter**2 steradian
    micron).  Cosmic rays were not removed because the existing
    calibration routine was not robust.
 
    Finally, each cleaned radiance (RAD) image was divided by the solar
    spectrum at the target body&apos;s distance from the sun then multiplied
    by pi to produce a unitless I/F (I-over-F) image.  These data were
    designated by the mnemonic &apos;IF&apos;.  Cosmic rays were not removed
    from these data.
 
    During the calibration process, the pipeline updated the
    pixel-by-pixel image quality map, the first FITS extension,
    to identify the following types of pixels:
 
      - Pixels where the raw value was saturated
      - Pixels where the analog-to-digital converter was saturated
      - Pixels that were ultra-compressed and thus contain very little
        information
      - Pixels considered bad as indicated by bad pixel maps (missing
        pixels were identified when the raw FITS files were created)
 
    The pipeline also created a FITS image extension for a signal-to-noise
    ratio map.  The calibration steps and files used to reduce each raw
    image are listed in the PROCESSING_HISTORY_TEXT keyword in the PDS
    data label for that image.  For a detailed discussion of the
    calibration pipeline and the resulting data, see the instrument
    calibration document by Klaasen, et al. (2006) [KLAASENETAL2006]
    included on the Deep Impact Documentation volume.
 
    Applied Coherent Technology Corporation in Herndon, VA, produced the
    PDS data labels by extracting parameters from the FITS headers.
 
 
  Data
  ====
 
 
    File Naming Convention
    ----------------------
      The naming convention for the image labels and FITS files is
      IVcccccccccc_eeeeeee_nnn_rr.LBL or FIT where cccccccccc is the
      spacecraft clock count at the mid-point of the observation, eeeeeee
      is the exposure ID (OBSERVATION_ID in data labels).  Up to 999
      individual images could be commanded for one exposure ID.
      Therefore, nnn in the file name provides the sequentially increasing
      image number within an exposure ID and corresponds to IMAGE_NUMBER
      in the data labels.  For example, if two images were commanded for
      exposure ID 9009001, the two FITS files names would be
      IVcccccccccc_9009001_001_RR.FIT and IVcccccccccc_9009001_002_RR.FIT.
      Finally, rr identifies the type of reduction:
 
        RR for RADREV data (radiance units, reversible)
        R  for RAD data (radiance units, partially cleaned)
        I  for IF data (unitless I-over-F, partially cleaned)
 
 
    CCD Images
    ----------
      The two-dimensional, CCD images in this data set are in FITS format.
      The primary data array contains the image, followed by two image
      extensions that are pixel-by-pixel maps which provide additional
      information about the primary image:
 
        - The first extension uses one byte of eight, bit flags to
          describe the quality of each pixel in the primary image.
          The PDS data label defines the purpose of each bit.
 
        - The second extension provides a signal-to-noise ratio for
          each pixel in the primary image.
 
      Each image FITS file is accompanied by a detached PDS label.  For
      more information about the FITS primary image and extensions, refer
      to the instrument calibration document included on the Deep Impact
      Documentation volume.
 
 
    Imaging Modes
    -------------
      A summary of the imaging modes is provided below.  All image modes
      are unbinned.  For a thorough description of the modes, please see
      the Deep Impact instrument paper by Hampton, et al. (2005)
      [HAMPTONETAL2005] included on the Deep Impact Documentation
      volume.
 
                     X-Size  Y-Size
        Mode Name    (pix)   (pix)   Comments
        ---- ------  ------  ------  ---------------------------------------
          1  FF       1024   1024    Full frame, shuttered
          2  SF1       512    512    Sub-frame, shuttered
          3  SF2S      256    256    Sub-frame, shuttered
          4  SF2NS     256    256    Sub-frame, not shuttered
          5  SF3S      128    128    Sub-frame, shuttered
          6  SF3NS     128    128    Sub-frame, not shuttered
          7  SF4O       64     64    Sub-frame, not shuttered
          8  SF4NO      64     64    Sub-frame, not shuttered, no overclocks
 
      Most image modes had a set of bias overclock rows and columns,
      located around the edges of the image array.  All overclock pixels
      were excluded from the calculation of the values for MINIMUM,
      MAXIMUM, MEDIAN, and STANDARD_DEVIATION in the data labels.
 
 
    Compression
    -----------
      All data files in this data set were uncompressed.  If the
      associated raw data file was compressed on board the flyby
      spacecraft (and thus received on the ground and archived as
      compressed) then the calibration pipeline used one of four lossy
      lookup tables to decompress raw image.  For information about data
      compression, see the Deep Impact instruments document by Hampton,
      et al. (2005) [HAMPTONETAL2005] or the instrument calibration
      paper by Klaasen, et al. (2006) [KLAASENETAL2006] included on the
      Deep Impact Documentation volume.
 
 
    True-Sky ``As Seen By Observer&apos; Display
    ----------------------------------------
      A true-sky view is achieved by displaying the image using the
      standard FITS convention:  the fastest-varying axis (samples)
      increasing to the right in the display window and the slowest-
      varying axis increasing to the top.  This convention is also
      defined in the data labels:
 
        SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION = &apos;RIGHT&apos;
        LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION   = &apos;UP&apos;
 
      The direction to Celestial North and Ecliptic North, measured
      clockwise from the top of the displayed image, is provided in PDS
      labels by CELESTIAL_NORTH_CLOCK_ANGLE and
      SOLAR_NORTH_POLE_CLOCK_ANGLE, both of which assume the correct
      display defined by SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION and
      LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION.
 
      Using this convention for Tempel 1 approach images, ecliptic East is
      toward the left, ecliptic North is up, and the Sun is to the right.
      This was also the convention used when displaying ITS images of
      Tempel 1 in published papers.
 
      For a comparison of the orientation of ITS flight images with those
      from ground-based calibrations as well as those from the High and
      Medium Resolution Instrument CCDs (HRIV and MRI, respectively), see
      the quadrant nomenclature section of the &apos;Deep Impact Instrument
      Calibration&apos; document.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
    Data Units
    ----------
      Reduced RADREV and RAD data are in units of radiance,
      W/(m**2 steradian micron).  I/F data are unitless.
 
 
    Time-Related Keywords
    ---------------------
      All time-related keywords in the data labels, except
      EARTH_RECEIVED_TIME, are based on the clock on board the impactor
      spacecraft.  EARTH_RECEIVED_TIME provides the UTC when an
      Earth-based observer should have been able to see an event recorded
      by the instrument.
 
      The TIME_FROM_IMPACT_VALUE keyword in the data labels was based
      on the best estimate of the time of impact based on the clock
      onboard the impactor was UTC 05:44:34.200 on 4 Jul 2005.
      The analysis that lead to this estimate is discussed in the
      spacecraft clock correlation document included on the Deep Impact
      documentation volume.
 
 
    Geometry-Related Keywords
    -------------------------
      The SOLAR_NORTH_POLE_CLOCK_ANGLE in the data labels specified the
      the direction of ecliptic north as projected onto the image plane.
      It is measured from the &apos;upward&apos; direction, clockwise to the
      direction toward ecliptic north when the image is displayed as
      defined by the SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION and LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION
      keywords.
 
      The SDC pipeline was not able to automatically determine the
      proper geometric information for the target of choice in many
      cases.  When these parameters could not be computed, the
      corresponding keywords in the PDS data labels were set to a
      value of unknown (UNK).  Geometry-related keywords for most
      calibration targets were set to UNK.
 
      Geometric parameters provided in the data labels were computed at
      the epoch specified by MID_IMAGE_TIME, except for the target-to-sun
      and earth-observer-to-target parameters.  Target-to-sun values were
      calculated for the time when the light left the sun while
      earth-observer-to-target were calculated for the time when the light
      left the target.
 
      Geometry-related parameters in the PDS data labels are uncertain at
      a level of a few seconds because of a known 2-second discrepancy
      between the clocks on board the flyby and impactor spacecraft and
      between in-situ data and ground-based observations.  After a
      detailed analysis of the timing problem in early 2006, improved
      self-consistent SPICE kernels were generated by the Deep Impact
      project to correlate the spacecraft clocks; there is still a
      1-2 second uncertainty between the in-situ data and the ground-
      based observations and an uncertainty of about one half of a
      second between the clocks on the flyby and impactor spacecraft.
      These improved kernels were included in the DI SPICE data set
      and were used to calculate the geometric parameters in the PDS
      data labels.  For more information about this discrepancy, please
      see the spacecraft clock correlation report provided on the DI
      documentation volume, DIDOC_0001.
 
      The SPICE kernels used to calculated the geometric parameters are
      provided by the SPICE_FILE_NAME keyword in the PDS data labels.  The
      kernels were listed in the order they were loaded into memory for
      processing.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    Geometric parameters included in the data labels were computed using
    the final version of the kernel files archived in the Deep Impact
    SPICE data set.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    Earth Mean Equator and Vernal Equinox of J2000 (EME J2000) was the
    inertial reference system used to specify observational geometry
    parameters in the data labels.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    There are no gaps in this data set.  All raw images of Tempel 1 that
    were received on the ground were successfully reduced and included
    in this data set.
 
    As noted above, the geometry-related parameters in the PDS data
    labels are uncertain at a level of a few seconds because of a known
    2-second discrepancy between the clocks on board the flyby and
    impactor spacecraft and between in-situ data and ground-based
    observations.  For more information about this discrepancy, please
    see the spacecraft clock correlation report included on the Deep
    Impact Documentation volume.
 
    The FITS files in this data set were reviewed internally by the Deep
    Impact project and were used extensively by the science team.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    This data set was peer-reviewed in April 2007 and was accepted
    for the PDS archive pending resolution of liens (completed in July
    2007).
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  ========================
    There are no gaps in this data set.  All raw, Tempel 1 images were
    successfully reduced and included in this data set.
 
    Horizontal striping through some images indicates missing data.  The
    image quality map extension identifies where pixels are missing.  If
    the second most-significant bit of a pixel in the image quality map is
    turned on, then data for the corresponding image pixel is missing.
    For more information, refer to the notes about image quality map in
    the PDS data label or to the instrument calibration document.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
 
    CCD Horizontal Gap
    ------------------
      There is a 1/3-pixel, horizontal gap for a clocking phase between
      the upper and lower halves of the CCD.  It was inserted by the
      manufacturer to facilitate the simultaneous upward and downward
      reading of the upper and lower quadrants.  The gap causes a
      10 percent reduction in the sensitivity of the two central rows
      (i.e., one row immediately above the gap and one below it).
 
 
    Displaying Images
    -----------------
      Flight software overwrote the first 50 uncompressed (or 100
      compressed) pixels of first quadrant read out from the instrument
      with an image header.  These header pixels were included in the
      reduced FITS images.  Since the values in these pixels vary
      dramatically, it is recommended that the values of the MINIMUM and
      MAXIMUM keywords in the PDS data label (or the MINPVAL and MAXPVAL
      in the FITS header) be used to scale an image for display because
      these values exclude the overclock rows and columns located around
      the edge of the image.  The location of the header bytes in a FITS
      image depends on the readout order of the instrument, as discussed
      in the quadrant nomenclature section of the instrument calibration
      paper included on the Deep Impact Documentation volume.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SUPERSEDED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

