<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.co-s-j-e-v-spice-6-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CASSINI SPICE KERNELS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.saturn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.co-s-j-e-v-spice-6-v1.0__browserp_co-s-j-e-v-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.co-s-j-e-v-spice-6-v1.0__browser_co-s-j-e-v-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.co-s-j-e-v-spice-6-v1.0__browser_wgc_co-s-j-e-v-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.naif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CO-S/J/E/V-SPICE-6-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CASSINI SPICE KERNELS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2002-11-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1997-10-15T09:26:08Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-09-30T23:59:59Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>LEE ELSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Elson, L.S., C.H. Acton, D.L. Conner and B.V. Semenov, Cassini
            SPICE Kernels V1.0, CO-S/J/E/V-SPICE-6-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2005.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains navigation and ancillary data in the form
            of SPICE kernel files for the Cassini spacecraft.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set includes the complete set of Cassini SPICE data
            files (``kernel files&apos;), which can be accessed using SPICE
            software. The SPICE data contains geometric and other ancillary
            information needed to recover the full value of science
            instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft
            and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments,
            spacecraft orientation, spacecraft sequences of events, and data
            needed for relevant time conversions.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
 
      This data set includes the complete set of SPICE data for Cassini
      in the form of SPICE kernels, which can be accessed using SPICE
      software available to read these files.
 
      The SPICE data contains geometric and other ancillary information
      needed to recover the full value of science instrument data.
      In particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft and planetary
      ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments, spacecraft orientation
      and spacecraft sequences of events. Data needed for relevant time
      conversions is also included.
 
      This data set is contained on a single virtual volume, cosp_1000,
      including data from all mission phases and covering from launch,
      1997-10-15, through the end time of the latest spacecraft
      trajectory file supplied in the data set. Until the end of the
      spacecraft lifespan this data set is accumulating with new data
      added approximately every three to six months. In addition, old
      data may be revised and added to the data set over time. Users are
      urged to be sure that they use the most recent data available by
      selecting files from the latest release, where appropriate.
 
 
      Data Types (SPICE kernel types)
      ===============================
 
      SPK kernels contain ephemerides for spacecraft, planets, satellites,
      comets and asteroids as well as for moving or fixed spacecraft and
      instrument structures. They provide position and velocity, given
      in a Cartesian reference frame. SPK files are located under the
      ``data/spk&apos; directory on the volumes comprising this data set.
 
      PCK kernels contain certain physical, dynamical and cartographic
      constants for target bodies, such as size and shape specifications,
      and orientation of the spin axis and prime meridian, that are meant to
      be used with applications that incorporate the SPICE Toolkit. PCK
      files are located under the ``data/pck&apos; directory on the volumes
      comprising this data set.
 
      IK kernels (Instrument description kernels) give descriptive and
      operational data peculiar to a particular scientific instrument,
      such as internal timing relative to the spacecraft clock and
      field-of-view model parameters. IK files are located under the
      ``data/ik&apos; directory on the volumes comprising this data set.
 
      CK kernels describe pointing, containing a transformation
      traditionally called the C-matrix which is used to determine
      time-tagged pointing (orientation) angles for a spacecraft structure
      upon which science instruments are mounted. CK files are located
      under the ``data/ck&apos; directory on the volumes comprising this
      data set.
 
      EK (Events) kernels contain spacecraft and science instrument event
      related information. EK files are located under the ``data/ek&apos;
      directory on the volumes comprising this data set.
 
      LSK (Leapseconds) kernels contain the leapseconds and the values
      of other constants required to perform a transformation between
      Universal Time Coordinated (UTC) and Ephemeris time (ET). LSK
      files are located under the ``data/lsk&apos; directory on the volumes
      comprising this data set.
 
      SCLK (Spacecraft Clock) kernels contain on-board clock calibration
      data required to perform a mapping between Ephemeris time (ET) and
      spacecraft on-board time (SCLK.) SCLK files are located under the
      ``data/sclk&apos; directory on the volumes comprising this data set.
 
      FK (Frame Definitions) kernels contain information required
      to define reference frames, sources of frame orientation data
      and inter-connections between these frames and other frames
      supported within the SPICE system. This includes mounting alignment
      information for each instrument. FK files are located under the
      ``data/fk&apos; directory on the volumes comprising this data set.
 
 
      Kernel File Details
      ===================
 
      Details specific to individual files are found in the ``*info.txt&apos;
      files in the corresponding data directory. The most detailed
      description of the data in each file is provided in metadata
      included inside the file -- in the description area of text kernels
      or in the comment area of binary kernels.
 
 
      Software
      ========
 
      The SPICE Toolkit contains software modules needed to read SPICE
      kernel files. SPICELIB software is highly documented via internal
      headers. Additional documentation is available in separate ASCII
      text files called Required Reading files. For example, the S-
      and P- Kernel (SPK) Required Reading File, named SPK.REQ, describes
      use of the SPK kernel file readers and contains sample programs.
 
      The latest SPICE Toolkit for a variety of computer platforms
      such as PC, Mac, SUN, HP, SGI, VAX, DEC Alpha, etc. is available
      at the NAIF Node of PDS electronically (via anonymous FTP and
      WWW servers). Refer to information in ``software/softinfo.txt&apos;.
      Each version of the Toolkit is also archived at the NASA National
      Space Science Data Center.
 
 
      Loading Kernel Files into a SPICE-based Application
      ===================================================
 
      The easiest way to make data from a collection of SPICE kernels
      available to a SPICE-based application is to list these kernels
      in a meta-kernel and load it into the program using the high
      level SPICE data loader routine FURNSH. This data set provides
      such meta-kernel(s) under the ``extras/mk&apos; directory. For more
      information about the CASSINI meta-kernel(s), see the file
      ``extras/mk/mkinfo.txt&apos;.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      This volume contains SPICE kernel files created during mission
      operations and after mission data reconstruction and analysis.
      Some general information about this collection follows here, but
      the prospective user is also referred to extensive descriptions
      about each file that are stored inside each kernel file. These
      metadata provide detailed information regarding the information
      source from which the data were derived, the type of processing
      applied to the source data, applicability of the data, etc. Metadata
      are located in the ``comment area&apos; for binary kernel types (SPK,
      CK, EK), accessible using either the COMMNT or SPACIT utility
      program found in the NAIF Toolkit. Metadata are located after
      ``\begintext&apos; markers within the text kernel types (PCK, IK, FK,
      LSK, SCLK), accessible by using any available text file display
      tool such as a word processor, text editor, or the unix ``more&apos;
      or ``cat&apos; commands.
 
      In some cases data accuracy information does not exist, or may be
      estimated after mission completion.
 
      Where there are questions about data accuracy or ``confidence&apos;
      not addressed herein the reader is invited to examine subsequent
      SPICE archive volumes associated with this data set collection
      (if such exist), or to contact the NAIF node of the Planetary Data
      System for possible further information.
 
 
      SPK Files
      =========
 
      Two kinds of SPK files are provided in this archive: SPK files
      produced by the Cassini Navigation team containing reconstructed
      spacecraft trajectory and ephemeris information for the Solar
      system planets and major Saturnian satellites, and SPK files
      produced by the Gravity Science team containing ephemeris
      information for minor Saturnian satellites. For more information,
      see the file ``data/spk/spkinfo.txt&apos;.
 
      This data set also includes two kinds of supplementary files with
      the information either derived from or describing the
      reconstructed SPK files. These files are not SPICE kernels; for
      this reason they are provided in subdirectories under the
      ``extras&apos; directory.
 
      The first kind of supplementary files is the orbit number files
      generated at the archive preparation time using the NAIF&apos;s ORBNUM
      utility program for the NAV SPK files covering the orbital phases
      of the mission. These files are provided in the ``extras/orbnum&apos;
      directory. For more information about the orbit number files, see
      the file ``extras/orbnum/orbinfo.txt&apos;.
 
      The second kind of supplementary files is the covariance table
      files containing the formal position uncertainties of Cassini&apos;s
      reconstructed ephemeris provided in the SPK files produced by the
      CASSINI NAV Team. These files are provided in the
      ``extras/spkxtra/covtab&apos; directory. For more information about
      these files, see the file ``extras/spkxtra/covtab/covinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      CK Files
      =========
 
      Five kinds of CK files are provided in this archive. The Cassini
      Attitude Articulation Control Subsystem (AACS) has provided both
      predicted (1) and reconstructed (2) CK files for the spacecraft.
      In addition, the Imaging Science Subsystem (ISS) has produced
      image navigated CK files (3) containing the spacecraft attitude
      for certain image exposure times. Using data from the CDA team
      NAIF has created CK files (4) providing orientation of the CDA
      instrument relative to the spacecraft bus. Using data from
      telemetry MIMI/LEMMS team, APL has created CK files (5) providing
      orientation of the MIMI/LEMMS instrument relative to the
      spacecraft bus. For more information, see the file
      ``data/ck/ckinfo.txt&apos;.
 
      This data also contains auxiliary files with information relevant
      to image navigated C-Kernels as well as comparisons between
      predicted and reconstructed C-Kernels produced by AACS. Because
      these files are outside the scope of the PDS archive requirements
      they are provided in the ``extras&apos; directory of this data set.
      For more detailed information, see the file
      ``extras/ckxtra/ckxtinfo.txt&apos;.
 
      Caution on Using CK Files
      -------------------------
 
      While not a data accuracy issue, the CK user is nevertheless
      cautioned to understand and properly use the data found and
      tolerance arguments that are inputs to the CK reader provided in the
      SPICE Toolkit. Descriptions about how to read CK files are found
      in the CK reader routine headers (top of the source code files)
      and in the ``CK Required Reading&apos; document; these are contained
      in each SPICE Toolkit package. The user is also referred to the
      Cassini CK Tutorial in the ``document/ck&apos; directory. In addition,
      it is not unusual for CK files to be revised. The user is urged
      to be sure that CK data have not been superseded by searching
      the latest data releases for appropriate coverage.
 
 
      PCK Files
      =========
 
      PCK files provide size, shape and orientation data for ``target&apos;
      bodies such as Jupiter, Saturn and their major satellites. A
      description of these data items and references to their source
      is provided inside each PCK file, which is a simple text
      file that can be viewed using any word processor, text editor
      or text display utility. For more information, see the file
      ``data/pck/pckinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      FK Files
      =========
 
      Frames kernel files provide specifications for how one reference
      frame is defined relative to another frame. A description of
      each reference frame is provided inside each FK file, which is
      a simple text file that can be viewed using any word processor,
      text editor or text display utility. The Cassini frames kernel
      contains reference frames for the orbiter instruments and subsystems
      including communications antennae. For more information, see the
      file ``data/fk/fkinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      IK Files
      =========
 
      Instrument kernel files provide specifications for the mounting
      alignment and, where applicable, field-of-view size, shape and
      orientation for the named instrument. Metadata describing these
      estimates are provided in each IK file included in this archive.
      For more information, see the file ``data/ik/ikinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      SCLK Files
      =========
 
      Spacecraft Clock kernel files provide a tabulation of data needed
      for converting time measurements between ephemeris time (ET) and
      spacecraft clock time (SCLK). A SPICE SCLK file is made from a
      similar file produced by the Cassini AACS Team. Each newly made
      SCLK file fully replaces the previous SCLK file. For more
      information, see the file ``data/sclk/sclkinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      SPICE software does not prohibit an SCLK file from being used
      for time conversions occurring for ``future times&apos; (or more
      accurately, for epochs that occur later than the epoch of the
      last telemetry data used in producing the last correlation
      coefficients found in the SCLK file). Such ``predict&apos; time
      conversions are likely to be inaccurate (changed somewhat)
      once the epoch of interest has been passed.
 
 
      LSK Files
      =========
 
      Leapseconds kernel files provide a tabulation of ``leapseconds&apos;
      and some other terms used in converting time measurements between
      ephemeris time (ET) and Universal Time (UTC). ``Spacecraft Event
      Time&apos; (SCET) is the commonly used name for UTC events measured
      at the spacecraft. For more information, see the file
      ``data/lsk/lskinfo.txt&apos;.
 
      Metadata describing how the LSK data are obtained or computed is
      contained inside the LSK text file. The time conversion provided
      by SPICE LSK files is accurate to approximately 0.000030 seconds.
 
 
      EK Files
      =========
 
      Three kinds of Events kernel (EK) files are included in this
      archive: Command Database, Science Plan and Sequence EKs.
 
      Command database E-Kernels contain command and parameter descriptive
      information used with Sequence EK files (see below).
 
      Science Plan EKs contain detailed science requests and high-level
      observation plans.
 
      Sequence EKs contain commands, ground events, subsystem status
      and notes taken from the integrated sequence Predicted Events
      Files. They also contain ISS mechanical events (shutter
      and filter wheel movements) derived from the Multi-mission
      Image Processing Laboratory database used to process images.
      For a complete description of the files see the files
      ``document/ek/sis_ek_001_revc.pdf&apos;, ``data/ek/ekinfo.txt&apos;,
      and comments within the files.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>PSCM-00026</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

