<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ear-a-i0688-5-cmormetorb-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CMOR METEOROID STREAM SURVEY V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.support_archives::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.obs3340t1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:i0688.obs3340t1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:meteoroid.meteoroid::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-a-i0688-5-cmormetorb-v1.0__browserp_ear-a-i0688-5-cmormetorb-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Brown, P., R.J. Weryk, D.K. Wong, and J. Jones, A meteoroid stream survey using
                   the Canadian Meteor Orbit Radar I. Methodology and radiant catalog, Icarus 195,
                   317-339, 2008.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BROWNETAL2008</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>EAR-A-I0688-5-CMORMETORB-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CMOR METEOROID STREAM SURVEY V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2009-06-03</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2002-01-01</start_time>
        <stop_time>2006-12-31</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>CAROL NEESE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Brown, P., Weryk, R.J., Wong, D.K., and Jones, J., CMOR Meteoroid
            Stream Survey V1.0. EAR-A-I0688-5-CMORMETORB-V1.0. NASA Planetary
            Data System, 2009.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Survey of meteoroid streams by the Canadian Meteoroid Orbit Radar
            (CMOR), published in Brown et al. (2008).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            A seven-year radar survey of meteor showers has been carried out
            with the Canadian Meteor Orbit Radar (CMOR) from 2002-2006 (Brown
            et al. 2008). This survey resulted in the unambiguous detection
            and orbital characterization of 45 major and minor meteor
            showers. This data set includes this list of the detected meteor
            showers along with their orbital parameters.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
 
  The Canadian Meteor Orbit Radar, (CMOR), located near Tavistock, Ontario and
  operated by the University of Western Ontario, carried out a survey of
  meteor showers over the period 2002-2006.  A total of more than 2.5 million
  meteoroids were detected and their orbits determined over the course of the
  survey.  From these data, 45 meteoroid streams were identified using a
  wavelet transform approach.  Of the identified streams, 12 are previously
  unreported or unrecognized.
 
  This data set presents the orbital parameters measured for the 45 major and
  minor meteor streams which were unambiguously detected during the survey,
  with multiple radar frequencies and using two
  distinct detection methodologies.
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
  The list of the 45 detected meteor showers and their orbital elements,
  reproduced from Brown et al. (2008) Table 6, is included in the file
  browntab6.tab.  For each of the detected meteor showers, the file contains
  orbital elements derived using deceleration-corrected velocities, raw mean
  velocities, and velocities determined from a hybrid-Fresnel technique.  The
  range in orbital parameters as determined from these three methods provides
  a guide to the uncertainty of the measurements due to deceleration
  corrections alone.
 
  Information about the radiants of each of the detected showers is provided
  in the file radiants.tab, extracted from Brown et al. (2008) Table 4.  The
  file contains the solar longitude of the radiant at beginning, end, and
  maximum of the active period, the RA and dec of the radiant at the maximum
  of the shower, and the drift of RA and dec over the active period.
 
  For a full description of the survey and derivations, and a discussion of
  the results, see the original paper, Brown et al. (2008).
 
  Brown, P., R.J. Weryk, D.K. Wong, and J. Jones, A meteoroid stream survey
  using the Canadian Meteor Orbit Radar I. Methodology and radiant catalog,
  Icarus 195, 317-339, 2008.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    This list of 45 meteor showers includes only those showers which were
    detected unambiguously in multiple years, with multiple radar frequencies,
    and using two distinct detection methodologies.  Some other minor streams
    exist in the survey data, but only those with high confidence in their
    existence have been included in this published set.
 
    The derivation of the orbital parameters has been carried out using
    deceleration-corrected velocities, raw mean velocities, and velocities
    determined from a hybrid-Fresnel technique.  The range in orbital
    parameters as determined from these three methods provides a guide to the
    uncertainty of the measurements due to deceleration corrections alone.
 
    For further discussion of the survey data and analysis, see Brown et al.
    (2008).
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SUPERSEDED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

