<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.hp-ssa-disr-2-3-edr-rdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>HUYGENS PROBE DISR RESULTS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.hp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:disr.hp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.titan::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.hp-ssa-disr-2-3-edr-rdr-v1.0__browserp_atmos_hp-ssa-disr-2-3-edr-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.hp-ssa-disr-2-3-edr-rdr-v1.0__dvo_hp-ssa-disr-2-3-edr-rdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.atmos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lebreton, J.P., O. Witasse, C. Sollazzo, T. Blancquaert, P. Couzin, A.M.
                   Schipper, J.B. Jones, D.L. Matson, L.I. Gurvits, D.H. Atkinson, B. Kazeminejad,
                   and M. Perez-Ayucar, An overview of the descent and landing of the Huygens
                   Probe on Titan, Nature, Volume 438, pp 758-764, 2005
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEBRETONETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tomasko, M.G., B. Archinal, T. Becker, B. Bezard, M. Bushroe, M. Combes, D.
                   Cook, A. Coustenis, C. de Bergh, L.E. Dafoe, L. Doose, S. Doute, A. Eibl, S.
                   Engel, F. Gliem, B. Grieger, K. Holso, E. Howington-Kraus, E. Karkoschka, H.U.
                   Keller, R. Kirk, R. Kramm, M. Kuppers, P. Lanagan, E. Lellouch, M. Lemmon, J.
                   Lunine, E. McFarlane, J. Moores, G.M. Prout, B. Rizk, M. Rosiek, P. Rueffer,
                   S.E. Schroder, B. Schmitt, C. See, P. Smith, L. Soderblom, N. Thomas, and R.
                   West, Rain, winds and haze during the Huygens probe&apos;s descent to Titan&apos;s
                   surface, Nature 438, 765-778, 2005
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TOMASKOETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>HP-SSA-DISR-2/3-EDR/RDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>HUYGENS PROBE DISR RESULTS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2006-07-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2005-01-14T09:11:41Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2005-01-14T12:49:07Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. ELISABETH MCFARLANE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>Unknown</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>Unknown</data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>Unknown</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
N.B.: The Peer Review of the data set is not fully completed.
The review is ongoing, but no major issues are expected. A data set
version 2.0 shall be released in the near future, as soon as the review process
is complete.
 
Data Set Overview
=================
 
On January 14, 2005, the Huygens Probe, part of the joint
NASA/ESA Cassini-Huygens mission to Saturn, entered the atmosphere
of Titan, descended for 2.5 hours under a parachute and
eventually landed softly on the surface of Titan
[LEBRETONETAL2005].
Six experiments collected data during the descent and on ground.
The data set, which this data set catalog belongs to,
is the archive of the Huygens Descent Imager and Spectral Radiometer
(DISR).
 
The DISR consists of 14 instruments; Three imagers, four solar aureole
cameras, two imagers covering the visible spectrum, two imagers in the
near infrared, two violet photometers, and a sun sensor.
 
The data were taken from an altitude of approximately 145km down to
Titan&apos;s surface.  The data taking was optimized by altitude and spin
rate to meet the science objectives.
 
The DISR data are presented in the PDS archive as described below.
 
 
DATA Directory
==============
 
The DATA directory contains all the data collected by DISR during the
Titan descent arranged by detector system.  Although the data are
manipulated using a variant of IDL (Interactive Data Language, a
product of Research Systems, Inc. of Boulder, Colorado.), the data are
here presented in tabular or ASCII form for easy accessibility.
 
The DARK datasets are the readout from covered columns of the
CCD detector.  Their values indicate the dark current being
generated by the chip during the other measurements.
 
The DESCENT datasets record key parameters at the beginning of each
cycle of optimized data taking including the altitude and cycle type.
There were about 110 Descent Cycles during the descent, and another
50 or so on Titan&apos;s surface.
 
The HKEEPING (Housekeeping) datasets record DISR temperatures,
voltages, and software indices.
 
The IMAGE directory contains tables of the detector readout values for
each pixel, after the image has been decompressed (lossy hardware
compression).
 
The IR datasets contain the per pixel (wavelength) readout from each
IR measurement. These readings have been summed into regions, relative
to the azimuth of the sun, to allow for accurate determination of the
light intensity in the directions of interest.
 
LAMP datasets record when the calibration lamps and surface science
lamp are powered, their applied voltage and current draw.
 
The SOLAR directory contains the measurements of the light intensity
field around the sun (the solar aureole). The data are presented as
tables of pixel values.
 
The STRIP datasets are summed columns on each side of the side looking
imager, used to determine the position of the sun as well as the tip
of the probe.
 
The SUN sensor records the time when the sun passes in front of the
DISR instrument. It has a double V aperture slit, which allows
determination of the tip in the direction of the sun, by virtue of the
crossing times. The sun sensor data is used to &apos;time&apos; the taking of
all other data sets relative to the sun (clocking to the sun azimuth).
Its amplitude is an independent measurement of the solar absorption at
its pass band (938nm). The data are presented as a table of the times
(relative to DDB T0) that the sun passes in front of each of the 3
slits, as well as the detector reading in DN.
 
The TIME datasets record the DISR internal clock time, and DDB time,
at each Broadcast Pulse.
 
The VIOLET datasets contain the reading (amplitude) of the violet
photometer.
 
The VISIBLE directory contains the data from the Upward Looking and
Downward Looking Visible spectrometers as a table of values. The rows
of the tables are the wavelength dimension, and the columns are
spatial. In some cases the columns (spatial dimension) are summed to
reduce noise.
 
The VISIBLE_EXT datasets record the values of the column of pixels on
each side of the corresponding visible spectrometer. This data is used
to compensate for light bleeding through (scattered light) from the
adjacent CCD instruments.
 
 
DERIVED DATA PRODUCTS
=====================
 
The following Derived Data Products have been included in the archive:
 
DLIS/ULIS: A tabular presentation of the calculated light intensity at
each wavelength of the IR spectrometers averaged over the field of
view.
 
DLV/ULV: Two sets of tables, one presenting the Net counts measured
during the descent after the detector offset is removed. The other
presents the average violet light intensity over the photometer&apos;s pass
band assuming a quadratic spectral shape (see Violet calibration
documents for details).
 
DLVS/ULVS: Tables of the light intensity at each visible spectrometer
wavelength, averaged over the field of view.
 
 
 
DOCUMENT Directory
==================
 
This directory contains the documents which describe how the DISR was
calibrated, and how to convert the data into physical measurements. It
also contains information about the equipment used during calibration
and the method for compensating for the detectors&apos; dark current
offsets. The supporting documentation contains information about the
instrument design and science objectives.
 
The DISR instrument calibration reports contain complete descriptions
of each instrument detector system, the calibration data, methods, and
algorithms for converting the instrument data numbers into physical
units and intensities into data numbers.
 
Reduced mean intensities over the field of view (FOV) are provided for
the spectrometers. However for the broad band instruments (imagers, SA
camera) the mean intensity over the FOV is not a useful number since
the spectral variation is important, and the bandpass changes
significantly during the descent. It is felt that the best scientific
approach is to create models which reproduce data numbers rather than
mean intensities.
 
Although some lines of code exist as examples in the calibration
reports, no generic calibration software is available. Interpretation
of the DISR data is model dependent and selection of the model
parameters (i.e. atmospheric composition, intensity spectrum, surface
reflectance, variation over the field of view) is key in deciphering
the data. The scientist is encouraged to develop their own software to
explore the physical interpretations of the DISR data.
 
 
 
 
 
CATALOG Directory
=================
 
This directory contains general information about the data set,
such as involved personnel, instrument description, references, etc.
 
 
INDEX Directory
===============
 
needed internally by archive
 
Coordinate System
=================
 
The DISR measurements were designed to be taken in the Titan
coordinate system, relative to the Sun. Azimuths are relative to the
Sun, with Counter Clockwise rotation (to the left) taken to be
positive.
 
Data Coverage and Quality
=========================
 
A good, although not entirely complete dataset was collected during
the Titan descent. Most notably, only half of the DISR images taken
were transmitted back to the Earth. However, even with this
limitation, it has been possible to create a continuous view of the
Titan descent, with no &apos;holes&apos; in the construction. These assembled
datasets are available in the EXTRAS directory of the archive.
 
However, a primary result is the extensive loss of ability to perform
stenographic analysis of the topography of Titan&apos;s surface.
 
There we no incomplete or corrupted datasets. These would be removed
by the error checking in the data link.  Some datasets were lost after
an extended time on Titan&apos;s surface as the link margin degraded, but
in general the link, and probe telecommunications worked amazingly
well.
 
The signal to noise ratio in all of the data was better than targeted
100/1.
 
A good spectral dataset was collected from the near IR to the Violet,
with matching spectral overlap and good spacial coverage.  From this
data, coupled with the Solar Aureole measurements, it has been
possible to measure the atmosphere&apos;s optical depth, model Titan&apos;s
aerosols, determine methane absorption coefficients, and determine the
heating rates. Additionally, with the image measurement we have also
been able to calculate the winds and determine the reflectance spectra
of the various materials that make up Titan&apos;s surface.
 
 
Limitations
===========
 
Besides the problems mentioned above, there were other unexpected
limitations.
 
The probe swing rates underneath the parachute were about 3 time
faster than expected, especially high in the atmosphere. The result is
that the DISR sun sensor was not able to maintain sun lock throughout
the descent, and consequently not all data were taken at the proper
azimuths relative to the sun.
 
The sun sensor experience another problem in that its detector became
too cold during the descent, such that its sensitivity was so low that
it failed to operate below 30 km altitude above Titan&apos;s surface.
 
A compensating windfall was the realization that variations in the AGC
signal cause by the probe&apos;s rotation could be used to deduce the
instantaneous azimuth of the probe. This made reconstruction of the
image and spectral field possible.
 
The reverse in spin direction of the probe also caused unforeseen
difficulties with the placement of measurements, particularly the IR
spectra and the Solar Aureole (SA) Camera Measurements. We obtained no
SA data with the sun behind the shadow-baffle, and actually very
little SA data near the sun at low altitudes.
 
Another difficulty was that an anomaly of the radar altimeter caused
the loss of our coldest (lowest) calibration cycle, so the instrument
performance had to be extrapolated over a fairly wide temperature
range. Fortunately there was significant data taken over temperature
in the laboratory to make this possible.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
N/A
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

