<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-rtm-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESS MDIS MAP PROJ REGIONAL TARGETED MOSAIC RDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mdis-nac.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-rtm-v1.0__browserp_mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-rtm-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-rtm-v1.0__browser_geo_mercury_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-rtm-v1.0__browser_mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-rtm-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-rtm-v1.0__dvo_imaging_mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-rtm-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Becker, K.J., M.S. Robinson, T.L. Becker, L.A. Weller, K.L. Edmonson, G.A.
                   Neumann, M.E. Perry, S.C. Solomon, First digital elevation model of Mercury,
                   47th Lunar and Planetary Science Conference, abstract #2949, 2016.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BECKERETAL2016</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Domingue, D.L., B.W. Denevi, S.L. Murchie, and C.D. Hash, Application of
                   multiple photometric models to disk-resolved measurements of Mercury&apos;s surface:
                   insights into Mercury&apos;s regolith characteristics, Icarus, 268, 172-203, 2016
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DOMINGUEETAL2016</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hapke, B., Theory of Reflectance Spectroscopy (Topics in Remote Sensing, 3),
                   Cambridge University Press, 272, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAPKE1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hawkins, S.E., III, J. Boldt, E.H. Darlington, R. Espiritu, R.E. Gold, B.
                   Gotwols, M. Grey, C. Hash, J. Hayes, S. Jaskulek, C. Kardian, M. Keller, E.
                   Malaret, S.L. Murchie, P. Murphy, K. Peacock, L. Prockter, A. Reiter, M.S.
                   Robinson, E. Schaefer, R. Shelton, R. Sterner, H. Taylor, T. Watters, and B.
                   Williams, The Mercury Dual Imaging System on the MESSENGER spacecraft, Space
                   Science Reviews, 131, 247-338, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAWKINSETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hawkins, S.E., III, S.L. Murchie, K.J. Becker, C.M. Selby, F.S. Turner, M.W.
                   Noble, N.L. Chabot, T.H. Choo, E.H. Darlington, B.W. Denevi, D.L. Domingue,
                   C.M. Ernst, G.M. Holsclaw, N.R. Laslo, W.E. McClintock, L.M. Prockter, M.S.
                   Robinson, S.C. Solomon, and R.E. Sterner, II, In-flight performance of
                   MESSENGER&apos;s Mercury Dual Imaging System, Proceedings of the SPIE, Volume 7441,
                   pp. 74410Z-74410Z-12, 2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAWKINSETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-H-MDIS-5-RDR-RTM-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESS MDIS MAP PROJ REGIONAL TARGETED MOSAIC RDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-05-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-08-19T18:01:23Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-04-30T11:07:43Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>CHRISTOPHER HASH</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            C. Hash, MESS MDIS MAP PROJ REGIONAL TARGETED MOSAIC RDR V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 2015
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Regional mosaics of targeted images acquired by the MDIS WAC or
            NAC camera for regions of interest.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== The Mercury Dual Imaging System (MDIS) consists
            of two cameras, a Wide Angle Camera (WAC) and a Narrow Angle
            Camera (NAC), mounted on a common pivot platform. This dataset
            include regional mosaics of targeted observations directed at
            specific regions of interest. Four types of targeted observations
            are included: (a) WAC 3-color targeted observations acquired
            mainly during the primary mission, to complement 1 km/pixel
            8-color mapping with a higher spatial resolution 3-color product;
            (b) WAC observations of targets that were observed repeatedly at
            different photometric geometries in order to improve photometric
            models of Mercury; these were observed initially in 8 color and
            since early 2013 in 11 colors; (c) WAC 8- or 11-color science
            targeted observations; and (d) NAC image strips acquired either
            for high-resolution imaging of morphology or as context for MASCS
            or MLA observations. The images in each observation share a
            common SITE_ID in the file name and PDS label. The SITE_ID
            corresponds to a targeting request entered into a database, in
            response to which a series of images was acquired. There is one
            SITE_ID for each time the region of interest is observed; thus
            for photometry targets, the same geographic region of interest is
            covered by many sets of images, each set sharing a common SITE_ID
            and distinct photometric geometry. Each mosaic is map projected
            in an orthographic projection, and contains one or more image
            planes. NAC mosaics contain 4 backplanes: observation ID, solar
            incidence angle, emission angle, and phase angle. WAC color
            products contain 3 backplanes: solar incidence angle, emission
            angle, and phase angle.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      A major activity on MESSENGER has been acquisition of enhanced
      observations pointed at special regions of scientific interest,
      so-called targeted observations. Mostly these are directed at
      features for which higher-resolution morphological or multispectral
      imaging or denser spectral sampling could help in geological
      characterization or hypothesis testing. Other imaging is acquired
      as context for MLA or MASCS measurements, or to characterize
      photometric properties of Mercury&apos;s surface.
 
      These observations are scattered throughout the CDR data set linked
      by the SITE_ID in their PDS label. In the RTM data set, the
      images for each SITE_ID are collected, coregistered if they are
      multispectral, map projected, and photometrically corrected to
      a standard geometry of incidence angle i=30 degrees, emission
      angle e=0 degrees, and phase angle g=30 degrees. All map
      projections are orthographic and near the native resolution of
      the images to preserve spatial resolution.
 
      RTM products are named based on their SITE_ID, OBSERVATION_ID of
      the first image, and number of image bands:
 
      MDIS_ppp_cbb_siteid_observationid_v.IMG
 
      where:
 
        ppp = product type = RTM
        c = camera (W WAC or N NAC)
        bb = bands (01, 03, 08, 11 depending on type of observation)
        siteid = a 6-digit integer giving the unique SITE_ID of the
          region covered by the product
        observationid = image observation ID of the first image (lowest ID)
        v = version number
 
      The following is an example file name with a description of
      the individual components:
 
      MDIS_RTM_N01_000276_1214047_0.IMG
 
      For this image:
        Product type = RTM (RTM)
        Camera = NAC (N)
        Bands = 1 (01)
        SITE_ID = 276 (000276)
        OBSERVATION_ID = 1214047
        Version = 0
 
      The RTM directory, present in the RTM archive volume, is organized
      into subdirectories based on camera/band (cbb from the file name)
      followed by year and day of year with the naming format:
 
      MDIS_RTM_CBB/YYYY_DDD
 
      where
 
      C = camera (W WAC or N NAC)
      BB = bands (01, 03, 08, 11 depending on type of observation)
      YYYY = year of the beginning of acquisition of the first image in
        the observation
      DDD = day of year of the beginning of acquisition of the first
        image in the observation
 
      An RTM:
      - Consists of map-projected photometrically normalized I/F CDRs
        assembled into a regional mosaic;
      - Contains image data in I/F corrected photometrically to i=30
        degrees, e=0 degrees, g=30 degrees at a resolution close to
        the native resolution of the imaging data;
      - Is composed of images acquired by the NAC or through
        multiple spectral filters by the WAC;
      - Contains images acquired during a targeted observation of one
        region of interest denoted by a site ID; and
      - NAC mosaics contain 4 backplanes: (a) observation id, unique
        to each image, (b) solar incidence angle, (c) emission angle,
        and (d) phase angle. WAC color products contain 3 backplanes:
        (a) solar incidence angle, (b) emission angle, and (c) phase
        angle.
 
 
    Versions
    ========
 
      Version numbers of RTMs increment on reprocessing.
      - Version 0 is released at PDS release 13. It is built from
        version 4 CDRs projected onto a sphere using version 0 DDRs.
        It uses a Hapke-form photometric correction, with different
        parameters for low- and high-incidence angle products.
      - Version 1 is released at PDS release 15 at end of mission. It
        uses version 5 CDRs projected onto a digital elevation model
        using version 1 DDRs. It uses a Kasseleinen-Shkuratov
        photometric correction with a common set of parameters
        among all data products.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      MDIS observing variables pertaining to the RTMs are as follows.
 
      Pixel Binning: Some RTM images are unbinned and 1024x1024 pixels.
      Some images are 2x2 pixel binned in the focal plane hardware
      (also known as &apos;on-chip&apos; binning), resulting in 512 x 512
      images, only where needed to increase image cadence and
      along-track overlap. MP binning was used only for WAC photometric
      targets to control data volume.
 
      12-8 bit compression: Images are read off the detector in 12-bit
      format. 12 bit images may converted to 8 bit images using one of
      eight lookup tables (LUTs). Typically, WAC multispectral images
      are 12 bits except and NAC image strips have been converted to
      8 bits.
 
      FAST/DPCM compression: All images are compressed losslessly using
      FAST/DCPM compression as they are read out of the DPU, to conserve
      recorder space. Once the data are written to the recorder, they can
      be uncompressed and recompressed more aggressively in the spacecraft
      main processor (MP).
 
      Wavelet compression: Images may be integer wavelet transform-
      compressed in the MP, typically at 3:1 for color data and 4:1 for
      monochrome data, but any value from 1 to 32 can be used. The initial
      configuration in Mercury orbit was to perform 12 to 8 bit conversion
      using LUT0 for the WAC and LUT2 for the NAC, with a wavelet
      compression ratio of 8:1 for monochrome imaging and 4:1 for color
      imaging. Initial images exhibited unexpectedly visible compression
      artifacts. Beginning 19 April 2011, LUT0 and LUT2 were replaced
      with LUT1 which better preserves image dynamic range, and
      compression ratios were decreased to 4:1 or less for monochrome
      data and 3:1 or less for color data where possible. Lossless
      compression was used when downlink allowed, especially for WAC
      multispectral observations.
 
      Exposure Control: The exposure time of MDIS images can be set
      manually by command, or automatically by the software. In manual
      mode, exposure times from 1-989, 1001-1989, ..., to 9001-9989 ms
      are available. In autoexposure mode the exposure time of the next
      image is computed by the DPU software, and cannot exceed 989 ms
      in duration. If the time of the next image occurs before the
      calculation can be completed, and pixel binning or filter
      position change, then the algorithm compensates for predicted
      changes in scene brightness and filter transmission using an
      onboard data structure. Most images in RTMs were acquired using
      automatic exposure, with an upper limit on exposure time to limit
      image smear.
 
      Pointing: The MDIS imagers are mounted on a pivot platform, which
      is itself mounted to the MESSENGER spacecraft deck. The pivot
      platform is controlled by a stepper motor, which is controlled by
      the Data Processing Unit (DPU). The pivot platform can move in
      either direction. The total range of motion is 240 degrees, limited
      by mechanical &apos;hard&apos; stops, and is further constrained by &apos;soft&apos;
      stops applied by the software. The nominal pointing position for
      MDIS is defined as 0 degrees, aligned with the spacecraft +Z axis
      and the boresight for several other instruments. The range of the
      soft stops is set to 40 degrees in the spacecraft -Y direction
      (toward the MESSENGER sunshade) and +50 degrees in the +Y direction
      (away from the sunshade). The pivot position can be commanded in
      intervals of 0.01 degrees within this range. During acquisition of
      targeted observations, the pointing of the pivot varied depending
      on the type of target and whether the observation was coordinated
      with MASCS or MLA. NAC image strips are mostly pointed at low to
      moderate emission angles, and solar incidence angles near 68
      degrees. However NAC images taken to provide context for MASCS or
      MLA observations are pointed close to the +Z axis coaligned with
      the appropriate other instrument. WAC targeted 3- or 11-color
      image sequences are typically targeted at low solar incidence
      angles with constrained emission angles. WAC 8- or 11-color image
      sequences targeted for photometry have whatever pointing is
      required in order to meet specified bounds on incidence, emission,
      or phase angle for the particular region of interest.
 
      Filter selection: The WAC imager contains a 12 position filter
      wheel to provide spectral imaging over the spectral range of the
      CCD detector. WAC filter 7 (750 BP 5) was chosen to complement the
      NAC because its bandpass within that of the NAC lessens any
      discontinuities that might result from regional variations in
      spectral slope. RTMs may consist of only NAC images, or WAC
      images in 3, 8, or 11 filters. The usage of filters in types of
      WAC observations is given below:
 
      Filter  Filter    Center      Bandpass  3-     8-     11-
      Number  letter    wavelength  width     color  color  color
              in file   (nm)        (nm)
              name
      1       A         698.8       5.3                     x
      2       B         700       600.0
      3       C         479.9      10.1              x      x
      4       D         558.9       5.8              x      x
      5       E         628.8       5.5              x      x
      6       F         433.2      18.1       x      x      x
      7       G         748.7       5.1       x      x      x
      8       H         947.0       6.2                     x
      9       I         996.2      14.3       x      x      x
      10      J         898.8       5.1              x      x
      11      K        1012.6      33.3                     x
      12      L         828.4       5.2              x      x
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      A sequence of processing creates an RTM from CDRs and DDRs. A Derived
      Data Record (DDR) consists of multiband images whose line and sample
      dimensions and coordinates correspond one-for-one with those of a
      CDR. It has 5 bands of data used to help create an RTM, including for
      every image pixel: (a) latitude, (b) longitude, (c) incidence angle,
      (d) emission angle, and (e) phase angle. The DDRs are an intermediate
      product used to create RTMs and other map products, are defined as a
      distinct data product in the MDIS CDR/RDR Software Interface
      Specification, and are delivered to the PDS.
 
      The sequence of processing is as follows:
 
    (a) Experiment Data Records (EDRs) are assembled from raw data.
    (b) Radiance images are created from the EDRs and calibration files.
    (c) Radiance is converted to I/F CDRs by dividing by (pi * solar flux
        at 1 AU / heliocentricdistance_in_AU^2).
    (d) I/F is photometrically corrected to i = 30 degrees, e = 0 degrees,
        g = 30 degrees.
    (e) Gimbal positions are extracted from the spacecraft housekeeping
        and formatted as a gimbal C kernel.
    (f) Using the pivot C kernel and other SPICE kernels, DDRs are
        created. The surface intercept on a model of Mercury&apos;s surface
        is calculated for each spatial pixel. The angles of this pixel
        relative to the equatorial plane and reference longitude constitute
        the latitude and longitude of the pixel. For that latitude and
        longitude, solar incidence, emission, and phase angles are
        determined.
    (g) I/F corrected to i = 30 degrees, e = 0 degrees is map projected
        into RTMs using the latitude and longitude information
        in the DDRs. The same procedure is used on DDRs to assemble the
        backplanes with derived information. They are appended to the
        image band in the following order:
          OBSERVATION_ID (if applicable)
          Solar Incidence Angle
          Emission Angle
          Phase Angle
        where OBSERVATION_ID is taken from the CDR label, the
        ordinal number of the image among MDIS images taken
        post-launch. The values for all backplanes are those for the
        filter 7 image within the color sequence.
 
      The stacking order (&apos;which image is on top&apos;) is that the first
      image in time is map projected first, the second image in time
      overlays the first, and so on, so that the last image overlays
      all others and is &apos;on top&apos;.
 
      The photometric correction applied to MDIS images
      to create version 0 RTMs is based on bi-directional
      reflectance equations formulated by [HAPKE1993]. The general
      equation for I/F is given by:
 
      I/F=(w/4)[mu_not&apos;/(mu&apos; +mu_not&apos;)]{[1+B(g)]P(g)-
          1+H(mu_not&apos;)H(mu&apos;)}S(i,e,g,theta)
 
      where w is single scattering albedo, i is incidence angle, e is
      emission angle, g is phase angle, p(g) is the single particle
      scattering function, theta is a parameter representing
      macroscopic roughness, and mu_not&apos; and mu&apos; are modified versions
      of the cosines of the incidence and emission angle that take
      into account effects of theta. H(mu_not&apos;) and H(mu&apos;) describe
      approximations to the Chandrasehkar H-functions. The surface
      roughness function, S(i,e,g,theta), modifies the radiative
      transfer equation to account for surface roughness.
 
      In addition, a Henyey-Greenstein function is used to describe
      the single particle scattering function p(g). The form of the
      Henyey-Greenstein function used corresponds to the form
      utilized in the USGS ISIS software, and is given by:
 
      p(g)=c(1-b^2)(1-2b cos(g)+b^2)^(-3/2) + (1-c)(1-b^2)(1+2b
      cos(g)+b^2)^(-3/2),
 
      where g is the phase angle, b is the scattering amplitude
      parameter, and c is the partition parameter between forward and
      backward scattering.
 
      In version 0 RTMs, no single set of Hapke parameters was found that
      yields close matches for corrected I/F across boundaries of images
      taken at different photometric geometries, for both the 3- and 8-color
      maps taken predominantly at low solar incidence angles (average,
      about 45 degrees) included in MDRs and MD3s, and monochrome maps
      taken predominantly at high solar incidence angles (BDRs, HIEs, HIWs).
      Therefore map products emphasizing low or high incidence angles
      initially used different sets of photometric parameters optimized
      for each to minimize seams between images. RTMs were acquired at
      different photometric geometries depending on the type of
      observation. NAC image strips were acquired predominantly at
      high solar incidence angles like BDRs/HIEs/HIWs and therefore
      all use those parameters; WAC multispectral images were acquired
      predominantly at low solar incidence angles like MDRs/MD3s and
      therefore use their parameters instead.
 
      VERSION 0 PHOTOMETRIC CORRECTION FOR WAC TARGETED OBSERVATIONS:
      The parameters used, those for the MDR/MD3 photometric correction,
      were derived by modeling data acquired from multiple regions between
      24 degrees and 46 degrees south latitude and 330 degrees and 353
      degrees east longitude. These regions sample incidence angle (i),
      emission angle(e), and phase angle (g) coverage commensurate
      with low incidence angle mapping campaigns, plus additional
      supplementary observations intended to expand the phase angle
      range. The data from each of the regions was combined into a
      single data set and a single set of parameters derived for each
      filter.
 
      The photometric measurements were modeled using a least squares
      grid search routine over the available parameter space. The model
      parameter values were individually plotted as a function of wavelength
      over the MDIS filter central wavelength values. A polynomial trend was
      fit to each parameter as a function of wavelength. The polynomial
      trend value at each filter central wavelength was then used as the
      model parameter values for determining the photometric correction.
      Derivation of the photometric correction involved: (1) calculating the
      reflectance at the observed geometry for each pixel in each image
      (Ro), (2) calculating the reflectance at i=30 degrees, e=0 degrees,
      g=30 degrees (R30), (3) calculating the correction factor
      (R30/Ro), and (4) applying the correction factor to each pixel within
      each image. The Hapke model parameters used are listed below for each
      WAC filter included in 3-, 8- or 11-color RTMs, where w is the single
      scattering albedo, theta is the surface roughness parameter,
      and b and c are the Heyney-Greenstein single particle scattering
      function parameters defined above.
 
      filter, wavelength,      w,           b,          c ,       theta
      F,      433.2, 0.151360115, 0.155099698, 0.126102310, 14.60131926
      C,      479.9, 0.169685245, 0.147410229, 0.106108941, 14.74522393
      D,      558.9, 0.197384444, 0.136483073, 0.081821900, 14.78008707
      E,      628.8, 0.218696307, 0.129164430, 0.070385011, 14.65283436
      A,      698.8, 0.237307445, 0.124224188, 0.068452363, 14.44035788
      G,      748.7, 0.249052388, 0.122256228, 0.072924183, 14.27068804
      L,      828.4, 0.265449469, 0.121966502, 0.090225001, 14.02954160
      J,      898.8, 0.277789564, 0.124805212, 0.115960759, 13.90988549
      H,      947.0, 0.285371188, 0.128609684, 0.139801777, 13.91310187
      I,      996.2, 0.292068663, 0.133854741, 0.167852540, 14.00895011
      K,     1012.6, 0.293865419, 0.135640972, 0.176741965, 14.05611393
 
      For all wavelengths, the width of the opposition surge, h, is 0.09
      and the strength of the opposition surge, B0, is 3.086.
 
      VERSION 0 PHOTOMETRIC CORRECTION FOR NAC TARGETED OBSERVATIONS:
      The parameters used, for the BDR/HIE/HIW photometric correction, were
      derived by modeling whole-disk observations of Mercury taken at a
      large number of photometric geometries during the Mercury flybys
      using different filters in the wide-angle camera.
      Those data were modeled using a least squares grid search
      routine over the available model parameter space. The model
      parameter values were individually plotted as a function of wavelength
      over the MDIS filter central wavelength values. A polynomial trend was
      fit to each parameter as a function of wavelength. The polynomial
      trend value at each filter central wavelength was then used as the
      model parameter values for determining the photometric correction.
      The Hapke model parameters used for the RTMs containing NAC images
      is given in the table below, where w is the single scattering
      albedo, theta is the surface roughness parameter, and b and c are
      the Henyey-Greenstein single particle scattering function parameters
      defined above. Photometric behavior of Mercury in NAC images is
      assumed to be equivalent to that in the WAC G filter.
 
      WAC
      filter, wavelength,      w,           b,          c ,       theta
      G,      749  , 0.278080114, 0.227774899, 0.714203968, 17.76662946
 
      The width of the opposition surge, h, is 0.09
      and the strength of the opposition surge, B0, is 3.086.
 
      VERSION 1 PHOTOMETRIC CORRECTION FOR ALL TARGETED OBSERVATIONS:
      In version 1 RTMs delivered at the end of the mission, a different
      photometric correction is used for all filters and all geometries,
      a Kasseleinen-Shkuratov function described by [DOMINGUEETAL2016].
      The form of the function is given as:
 
      I/F = AN*exp[-(g*mu)]{c_sub_l[2cos i/(cos i + cos e)]+[1-c_sub_l]cos i}
 
      where AN is normal albedo at a given wavelength, and mu and c_sub_l
      are wavelength-dependent parameters. Their values were fit using
      multiple regions between 24 degrees and 46 degrees south latitude
      and 330 degrees and 353 degrees east longitude. These regions sample
      incidence angle (i), emission angle(e), and phase angle (g)
      coverage commensurate with global mapping campaigns. In addition
      whole-disk Mercury images taken at a large number of geometries during
      the Mercury flybys expand the phase angle range. Parameter values were
      fit in the same manner as the parameters for the Hapke model. The
      values are given in the table below:
 
      WAC
      Filter, Wavelength,    AN,              mu,              c_sub_l
      F       430            6.92413210E-02   6.37228563E-01   6.28836906E-01
      C       480.4          7.98153978E-02   6.21777913E-01   6.27629117E-01
      D       559.2          9.10849913E-02   5.97475375E-01   6.18544492E-01
      E       628.7          9.86118777E-02   5.80013748E-01   6.22758382E-01
      A       698.8          1.05807514E-01   5.68069278E-01   6.35596439E-01
      G       749            1.11116798E-01   5.62741989E-01   6.42377921E-01
      L       828.6          1.19413553E-01   5.56997602E-01   6.36801364E-01
      J       898.1          1.25034169E-01   5.49548099E-01   6.17408232E-01
      H       948            1.26684133E-01   5.38610109E-01   6.09847145E-01
      I       996.8          1.24975849E-01   5.19691856E-01   6.30847041E-01
      K       1010           1.23758640E-01   5.12689614E-01   6.45356466E-01
 
 
    Data
    ====
      There is one data type associated with this volume, RTMs consisting
      of mosaicked, photometrically corrected WAC 3-, 8-, or 11-color
      or NAC CDRs, appended with 4 backplanes describing the component
      CDRs and their photometric geometries.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
 
      There may be two types of ancillary data provided with this
      dataset:
 
      1. The EXTRAS directory in the RTM archive contains a list of all
         SITE_IDs targeted by MDIS or other instruments, describing their
         latitude/longitude coordinates and the motivation for their
         targeting. This list is the primary mechanism for tracing the
         science rationale for acquisition of the data in the RTM.
 
      2. There may be a BROWSE directory containing browse images in
         PNG and/or GeoTIFF format. See BROWINFO.TXT in that directory
         for more details.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
 
      The cartographic coordinate system used for the MDIS data products
      conforms to the J2000 celestial reference frame for star imaging,
      and the IAU planetocentric system with East longitudes being
      positive for planetary surfaces.
 
      In version 0 RTMs, the IAU2000 reference system for
      cartographic coordinates and rotational elements is used for
      computing latitude and longitude coordinates of planets. However
      a Mercury radius of 2440.0 km is used.
 
      In version 1 RTMs, the value for Mercury radius is updated to
      2439.4 km.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
 
      The MDIS archive is organized and stored in the directory
      structure described in the Mercury Dual Imaging System (MDIS)
      Calibrated Data Record (CDR) and Reduced Data Record (RDR)
      Software Interface Specification (SIS). The contents of the
      archive, along with fiduciary checksums, are compressed into
      a single &apos;zip archive&apos; file for transmittal to the PDS Imaging
      node.  The zip archive preserves the directory structure
      internally so that when it is decompressed the original
      directory structure is recreated at the PDS Imaging node.
      The zip archive is transmitted to the PDS Imaging node via
      FTP to the URL specified by the node for receiving it.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      Known issues of concern are described below.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was examined by a peer review panel
      prior to its acceptance by the Planetary Data System (PDS). The
      peer review was conducted in accordance with PDS procedures.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
 
      Only a subset of raw EDR data are calibrated to CDRs and then
      incorporated into RTM products. Briefly, the following criteria
      are met:
 
      (a) The data represent a scene and not the instrument test
      pattern, as indicated by data quality index (DQI) byte 0.
 
      (b) The exposure time is greater than zero (zero exposures
      occur in some images due to software features), as indicated
      by DQI byte 1.
 
      (c) Less than 20 percent of the image is saturated (empirically
      this is a threshold dividing wholly corrupted images from
      everything else).
 
      (d) The target of the image is MERCURY.
 
      (e) The image was taken as part of a targeted observation directed
      at the SITE_ID on which the RTM is based.
 
      The OBSERVATION_ID for a part of an RTM is a pointer back to the
      WAC filter 7 or NAC image used for that part of the RTM.
 
      Version 0 RTMs are based on version 4 CDRs which correct a number
      of earlier calibration artifacts. Version 1 RTMs are based on
      version 5 CDRs. The following issues may affect the component
      images.
 
      (1) COMPRESSION ARTIFACTS. Images may be integer wavelet transform-
      compressed in the MP, typically at 3:1 for color data and 4:1 for
      monochrome data, but any value from 1 to 32 can be used. The initial
      configuration in Mercury orbit was to perform 12 to 8 bit conversion
      using LUT0 for the WAC and LUT2 for the NAC, with a wavelet
      compression ratio of 8:1 for monochrome imaging and 4:1 for color
      imaging. Initial images exhibited unexpectedly visible compression
      artifacts. Beginning 19 April 2011, LUT0 and LUT2 were replaced
      with LUT1 which better preserves image dynamic range, and
      compression ratios were decreased to 4:1 or less for monochrome
      data and 3:1 or less for color data where possible. Lossless
      compression was used when downlink allowed.
 
      (2) RADIOMETRIC ACCURACY. The radiometric calibration of the
      WAC was updated several times over the mission to iteratively
      reduce residuals from 3 sources of error: (a) time-variable
      responsivity of the detector, (b) residuals in the flat-field
      correction, and (c) residuals in the correction to
      responsivity for detector temperature. For multispectral
      products, the residuals from time-variable responsivity
      initially led to distinct seams; correction of this artifact
      is treated in more detail below.
 
      In version 4 CDRs, an additional update to responsivity
      improved temperature dependence over the full operating range.
      The correction was derived empirically by fitting as a function
      of CCD temperature the median values of images acquired from
      Mercury orbit at a wide range of temperatures but a narrow
      range of photometric geometries. The flat field was updated
      empirically using the median of hundreds of photometrically
      corrected images of relatively bland field-filling images
      of Mercury.
 
      In version 5 CDRs, a new, final temperature correction used all
      Mercury images satisfying the illumination criteria. A new, final
      flat-field correction was derived similarly to the updated
      correction used in version 4, except using more images and
      a Kasseleinen-Shkuratov photometric correction.
 
      (3) SCATTERED LIGHT. In the NAC, scattered light from out-of-field
      sources is an issue. The geometry contributing most of the scatter
      is 1-2 fields-of-view sunward of the NAC boresight. For a very
      large, evenly illuminated source that overfills the field-of-view
      by a factor of several, ray-trace studies supported by testing
      during Venus flyby 2 suggest that 2-7% of the radiance measured in
      the field-of-view will have come from out-of-field sources. The
      spatial pattern of the scatter is variable, due to diffuse
      reflections off the internal instrument housing.
 
      The WAC is subject to scattered light
      originating from within the field-of-view or just outside it. One
      source is multiple reflections off of 13 optical surfaces (2
      sides of each of 4 lenses, the spectral filter, and the CCD cover
      glass, as well as the CCD surface itself). The scatter becomes
      worse at longer wavelengths. Just off the limb of a large
      extended source near 1 field-of-view in size, like Venus or
      Mercury, measured radiance increases with wavelength from 2% to 7%
      of the value measured on the extended source. The value decreases
      with distance off the target more quickly at longer than at
      shorter wavelengths, but remains at 1% hundreds of pixels from
      the source. Conversely, light must be scattering from bright
      parts of an image to dark parts of an image. Averaged over
      sources tens of pixels in area, and away from abrupt brightness
      contrasts, scattered light affects shapes of spectra measured
      from WAC data at least at the 1-2% level, worse near brightness
      boundaries or for small, bright crater ejecta. The expected effect
      is enhanced brightness at &gt;650 nm in dark areas, and decreased
      brightness at &gt;650 nm in small bright areas.
 
      (4) TIME-VARIABLE WAC RESPONSIVITY. During Mercury orbit it was
      recognized that filter-dependent changes in WAC responsivity on
      the order of +/- 15% occurred over timescales as short as several
      days. Because those variations were not consistent from filter to
      filter, they led to spurious spectral features, which were
      particularly conspicuous near 750 nm. The cause(s) of these
      variations in responsivity are not known, but they could include
      transient radiation effects on the detector or electronics, aging
      of filters, periodic deposition and burn-off of contaminants on
      filters, or incorrect recording of exposure time. An initial
      empirical correction for images acquired in the first year of
      operations was developed and utilized in version 4 WAC CDRs used
      to create version 0 RTMs.
 
      For version 5 WAC CDRs in delivery 15 at end of mission, an
      updated correction covers the full duration of the orbital
      phase. Overlaps between color image sets in color mapping campaigns
      were used to derive a multiplicative correction factor for each
      filter and for each Earth day (2-3 orbits). Version 1 RTMs use
      CDRs with this updated correction. An analysis of overlap among
      individual images shows that residual differences (which include
      errors from calibration, scattered light, and possible incomplete
      correction of photometric variation) average &lt;2% for the majority
      of the planet.
 
      (5) UNCONTROLLED MOSAIC PROJECTED ONTO A SPHERE. Version 0 RTMs were
      constructed by uncontrolled mosaicking, projecting the image data
      onto a sphere. Systematic errors in spacecraft position and in
      knowledge of spacecraft and MDIS attitude, systematic errors in
      range to the surface due to ignoring topography, and systematic
      errors in latitude and longitude due projecting onto a sphere instead
      of a shape model will all contributed to mosaicking errors. In
      general these are expected to be under 1 km but locally might
      exceed 4 km.
 
      Version 1 RTMs are constructed from images controlled using
      c-smithed kernels and a global digital elevation model (DEM), both
      derived using a least-squares bundle adjustment of common
      features, measured as tie point coordinates in overlapping NAC and
      WAC-G filter images of Mercury at favorable solar incidence and
      emission angles. Empirically, misregistration errors between images
      decreased generally to the pixel scale of the map (0.2 km) in
      most locations. Derivation of smithed kernels and the DEM for
      end of mission data products is described by [BECKERETAL2016].
 
      (6) INACCURACY IN THE PHOTOMETRIC CORRECTION. The Hapke correction
      applied to version 0 RTMs required the use of illumination-dependent
      parameters implying the possibility of systematic inaccuracy. As shown
      by [DOMGINUEETAL2016] the Kasseleinen-Shkuratov correction used in
      version 1 RTMs greatly reduces residuals between images acquired at
      different photometric geometries, implying reduced systematic errors.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      None
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

