<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mro-m-sharad-3-edr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MRO SHARAD EXPERIMENT DATA RECORD V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:sharad.mro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-sharad-3-edr-v1.0__browserp_mro-m-sharad-3-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-sharad-3-edr-v1.0__browser_geo_mars_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-sharad-3-edr-v1.0__dvo_geo_mro-m-sharad-3-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Orosei, R., and S. Slavney, Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter Shallow Radar
                   Experiment Data Record Software Interface Specification, Version 1.1,
                   March 22, 2006.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.OROSEI2006A</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MRO-M-SHARAD-3-EDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MRO SHARAD EXPERIMENT DATA RECORD V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2006-01-01</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>ROBERTO OROSEI</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Orosei, R., Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter Shallow Radar Experiment
            Data Record, MRO-M-SHARAD-3-EDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2006.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Experiment data records for the SHARAD (Shallow Radar) instrument
            on Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset contains EDR (raw) data from the SHARAD (Shallow
            Radar) instrument on Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter. SHARAD is the
            sub-surface sounding radar provided by the Italian Space Agency
            (ASI).
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      Data Set MARS RECONNAISSANCE ORBITER MARS SHARAD EXPERIMENT DATA
      RECORD V1.0 (Level 1-A data) consists of the instrument telemetry
      correlated with the auxiliary information needed to locate
      observations in space and time and to process data further. Level
      1-A data users will mainly be radar scientists interested in
      redoing the entire processing of the received signal. The fact
      that unprocessed Subsurface Sounding echoes do not show any
      obvious indication of subsurface interfaces will make EDRs of
      little use for geologists. The reader is referred to the SHARAD
      RDR data set (MRO-M-SHARAD-4-RDR-V1.0) for calibrated, processed
      SHARAD data suitable for science analysis.
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      SHARAD EDR Data Products are generated at the SHARAD operation
      center in Rome, Italy, under the responsibility of the Team Leader
      Institution (INFOCOM Department, University of Rome &apos;La
      Sapienza&apos;).
 
      To produce EDRs, data are ordered in time and sorted by instrument
      operative mode. Any duplicate packets are removed, while missing
      and corrupted packets are accounted for and substituted by zero-
      padding. Level 1A processing consists of the following functions:
 
      1) Deformatting data packets 2) Time ordering data packets 3)
      Sorting data packets by instrument operative mode 4) Testing
      quality of data packets 5) Formatting data packets into binary
      files 6) Generating auxiliary data to locate each observation in
      space and time 7) Generating PDS detached labels for data products
 
      Apart from editing of data to remove duplicates and transmission
      errors, no processing is applied to the scientific data of the
      instrument. Calibration information is provided in the form of
      calibration files containing the transfer function of the
      instrument.
 
      Input for Level 1A processing consists of: 1) SHARAD science
      telemetry in the form of Instrument Raw Science Products. 2)
      SHARAD engineering telemetry. 3) Spacecraft housekeeping
      telemetry. 4) Ancillary information on spacecraft trajectory and
      orientation in the form of SPICE SPK and CK kernels produced by
      the Navigation and Ancillary Information Facility (NAIF) at JPL.
      5) Spacecraft clock coefficients to convert spacecraft clock
      counts into Coordinated Universal Time (UTC), in the form of SPICE
      SCLK kernels produced by NAIF.
 
    Data
    ====
      Each SHARAD Data Product is an aggregation of SHARAD data blocks.
      A data block is produced through the processing of one or more
      received echoes, and constitutes a single observation of the
      instrument.
 
      Each Data Product contains data from one or more data blocks
      collected continuously using the same operation mode, instrument
      status and on-board processing scheme; that is, using a single OST
      line. The content of each SHARAD data product is highly variable
      in terms of number of data blocks, and depends on how operations
      for the instrument were planned during a given data collection
      period.
 
      Because each data block is a sequence of time samples of a
      received signal, complemented by ancillary information, the
      natural organization for data blocks within a Data Product is a
      table, in which each line contains data from a single data block,
      and each column contains the value of a single parameter or time
      sample across different data blocks.
 
      Each Data Product consists of three files:
 
      1) A binary file containing the scientific telemetry of the
      instrument. This is a sequence of echoes, each of which is
      preceded by a header containing information on the collection and
      on-board processing of the data. This file is called the Science
      Telemetry file.
 
      2) A binary table containing geometric quantities generated on-
      ground from spacecraft navigation data, parameters extracted from
      instrument and spacecraft housekeeping telemetry, and flags
      describing the completeness and usability of the associated
      scientific telemetry. This file is called the Auxiliary Data file
      and contains one record for every data block in the Science
      Telemetry file.
 
      3) A detached ASCII label file describing the content of the data
      product. The label is written according to standards defined by
      the Planetary Data System (PDS), and lists parameters describing
      both the observation in which data were acquired and the structure
      of the files in which data are stored.
 
      Binary files are structured as PDS Table data objects. The content
      of such tables is listed in format files, of which several exist
      according to operation mode, instrument status and on-board
      processing scheme, and which will be contained in the LABEL
      directory of the Data Set Volume.
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      Each Auxiliary Data file contains a binary table with one row for
      each record in the corresponding Science Telemetry file of an EDR
      data product. Columns of the table are described in a separate
      file called format file.
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      SHARAD EDR data products conform to a Project-determined set of
      cartographic standards. All map-projected data use planetocentric
      coordinates and east-positive longitudes in the range 0 to 360
      degrees, computed w.r.t. the IAU 2000 reference ellipsoid. Vector
      quantities such as spacecraft positions are expressed in a
      Cartesian planetocentric reference frame.
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      Each SHARAD EDR data product consists of two binary files in fixed
      record-length format, called respectively the Science Telemetry
      and the Auxiliary Data files. The structure of such files is
      described by a separate PDS label containing also information on
      source data, production process, relation between stored bytes and
      physical quantities, product identification, storing and
      organizing of ancillary data and descriptive information needed to
      interpret and process the data.
 
      The data contained in the Science Telemetry file and in the
      Auxiliary Data files are structured as a PDS Table object. The PDS
      label contains pointers to files containing definitions of the
      columns of such Table objects. Each record in a binary Science
      Telemetry file is a Science Data Format, some internal telemetry
      counters, the Start of Telemetry and End of Telemetry markers, and
      the checksum. It thus consists of an ancillary data header
      reporting the OST line used in collecting the data block,
      ancillary data reporting the time of acquisition of the data and
      listing parameter values used in processing the data block, and
      the data block itself, consisting of 3600 echo samples, each
      either 4-, 6- or 8-bits long. The resulting record length in bytes
      is thus dependent of the Operational Mode through which data were
      acquired.
 
      Each record in a binary Auxiliary Data file is the line of a table
      listing values of geometric and engineering parameters relevant
      for the location and processing of the corresponding data block in
      the Science Telemetry file. Most parameter values are expressed as
      an 8-byte or 4-byte IEEE real numbers. Values contained in this
      file are partly computed from SPICE kernels containing information
      on spacecraft trajectory and attitude, and partly extracted from
      SHARAD housekeeping telemetry.
 
      PDS labels are written in Object Description Language (ODL). PDS
      label statements have the form of &apos;keyword = value&apos;. Each label
      statement is terminated with a carriage return character (ASCII
      13) and a line feed character (ASCII 10) sequence to allow the
      label to be read by many operating systems.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      TBD
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This data set was examined by a peer review panel in accordance
      with PDS procedures. At this writing (May 21, 2007), some liens
      placed on the data set as a result of the review are still
      unresolved.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      TBD
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      TBD
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

