<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ro-rl-e-m-a-c-spice-6-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ROSETTA ORBITER/LANDER SPICE KERNELS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.international_rosetta_mission::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.rl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.ro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.rl::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.ro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.21_lutetia::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.2867_steins::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.67p-churyumov-gerasimenko_1_1969_r1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.9p-tempel_1_1867_g1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ro-rl-e-m-a-c-spice-6-v1.0__browserp_ro-rl-e-m-a-c-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ro-rl-e-m-a-c-spice-6-v1.0__browser_psa_ro-rl-e-m-a-c-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ro-rl-e-m-a-c-spice-6-v1.0__browser_ro-rl-e-m-a-c-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ro-rl-e-m-a-c-spice-6-v1.0__browser_wgc_ro-rl-e-m-a-c-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.naif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>RO/RL-E/M/A/C-SPICE-6-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ROSETTA ORBITER/LANDER SPICE KERNELS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2015-12-02</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-03-02T09:32:48Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-09-09T00:00:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>BORIS SEMENOV</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Vazquez-Garcia, J.L., J. Zender, M. Barthelemy, and B. Semenov,
            ROSETTA ORBITER/LANDER SPICE KERNELS V1.0,
            RO/RL-E/M/A/C-SPICE-6-V1.0, European Space Agency, 2015.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Navigation and ancillary data in the form of SPICE System kernel
            files for the Rosetta mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set includes the complete set of Rosetta mission SPICE
            data files (``kernel files&apos;), which can be accessed using
            SPICE software. The SPICE data contains geometric and other
            ancillary information needed to recover the full value of the
            science instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide
            spacecraft and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting
            alignments, spacecraft orientation, spacecraft sequences of
            events, and data needed for relevant time conversions.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
1. SPICE System Overview
   =====================
 
   SPICE data contain geometric and other ancillary information needed
   to recover the full value of science instrument data. In particular,
   SPICE kernels provide spacecraft and planetary ephemerides,
   instrument mounting alignments and spacecraft orientation. Data
   needed for relevant time conversions is also included.
 
   SPICE was designed by the Navigation and Ancillary Information
   Facility (NAIF) to aid scientists and engineers with ancillary and
   engineering data. This data comes from a wide range of sources such
   as the spacecraft, the mission control center and the designers of
   the spacecraft and its instruments.
 
   The ancillary data comprises information on data acquisition;
   position and orientation of the spacecraft at the time of
   acquisition; information on the target, such as location, shape and
   orientation; reference frame specifications and time conversion
   data.
 
   The primary SPICE data sets are often called &apos;kernels&apos; or &apos;kernel
   files&apos;.  These kernels are composed of ancillary information, which
   has been created in such a way as to allow easy access and correct
   usage by the space science and engineering communities.
 
   In addition to the kernels, there is software provided, known as the
   SPICE Toolkit, along with standards, documentation and software
   support. The SPICE Toolkit and documentation can be found at:
 
      http://naif.jpl.nasa.gov/naif/
 
   The SPICE Toolkit was freely offered to the worldwide space science
   and space mission engineering communities at the time this data set
   was released. The few rules governing its use are posted on the
   &apos;Rules&apos; page of the NAIF website:
 
      http://naif.jpl.nasa.gov/naif/rules.html
 
   SPICE is used on a number of space missions, such as ESA&apos;s Mars
   Express, SMART-1, Venus Express and Rosetta missions; NASA&apos;s Mars
   Global Surveyor, Stardust, Cassini, Mars Exploration Rovers, Mars
   Reconnaissance Orbiter and Deep Impact. The SPICE system has been
   produced and is maintained by Caltech&apos;s Jet Propulsion Laboratory
   under contract to the U.S. National Aeronautics and Space
   Administration.
 
   For an additional explanation of the SPICE system, please consult
   SPICE_INST.CAT.
 
 
2. Data Producers and Other Key Personnel
   ======================================
 
   The Rosetta SPICE data set has been produced by
 
      Barthelemy, M.   (RSSD/ESA)
      Semenov, B.      (NAIF/JPL)
      Vazquez, J.L.    (RSSD/ESA)
      Zender, J.       (RSSD/ESA)
 
   and archived by
 
      Barthelemy, M.   (RSSD/ESA)
 
 
3. The Rosetta SPICE data set
   =========================
 
   NOTE: This data set incorporates all kernels from and fully
   supersedes the ROS-E/M/A/C-SPICE-6-V1.0 data set that was originally
   produced in 2007, released in 2010 and updated in 2011.
 
   The Rosetta SPICE data set consists of SPICE kernels of several
   types, organized as follows:
 
   *  CK: These kernels contain information about orientation of the
      spacecraft and its articulating structures as well as orientation
      of the natural bodies that cannot be represented by standard IAU
      rotation models (e.g. the comet 67P/C-G). More information on CKs
      in this data set is provided in CKINFO.TXT.
 
   *  DSK: These kernels contain information about the shape of the
      Rosetta mission targets. More information on DSKs in this data set
      is provided in DSKINFO.TXT.
 
   *  FK: These kernels contain definitions of and specifications of
      relationships between reference frames (coordinate systems).
      Among the frames kernels included, there are kernels that specify
      reference frames related to the earth, mission targets, and the
      spacecraft and its instruments. More information on FKs in this
      data set is provided in FKINFO.TXT.
 
   *  IK: These kernels contain instrument information, such as field of
      view or internal timing  specifications. There are IKs provided
      for most of the Rosetta orbiter and lander instruments. More
      information on IKs in this data set is provided in IKINFO.TXT.
 
   *  LSK: These kernels contain a table with the leapseconds used to
      convert between ET and UTC. If there are multiple LSKs in this
      data set, the latest kernel supersedes the previous ones. More
      information on LSKs in this data set is provided in LSKINFO.TXT.
 
   *  PCK: These kernels provide information about the solar system
      bodies orientation and shape, and possibly parameters for
      gravitational, atmospheric or rings models. The data set contains
      PCKs for the planets, their satellites, the asteroids Lutetia and
      Steins, and the comet 67P/C-G. More information on PCKs in this
      data set is provided in PCKINFO.TXT.
 
   *  SCLK: These kernels contain data needed for conversion between ET
      and spacecraft clock. If there are multiple SCLKs in this
      data set, the latest kernel supersedes the previous ones. More
      information on SCLKs in this data set is provided in SCLKINFO.TXT.
 
   *  SPK: These kernels contain ephemeris data (position and velocity)
      of the spacecraft and solar system bodies. The data set provides
      kernels with such information for the planets, the Sun, the Moon,
      the comet 67P/C-G, the two fly-by asteroids Lutetia and Steins,
      the fly-by comet (Tempel 1), ground tracking stations, and the
      Rosetta orbiter and lander spacecraft. More information on SPKs
      in this data set is provided in SPKINFO.TXT.
 
 
   3.1 - Origin of the kernels.
 
      a) Generic kernels such as PCKs, LSKs and some of the SPKs are
         provided by NAIF.
 
      b) IKs have been developed NAIF in collaboration with the
         instrument teams and RSSD/ESA.
 
      c) The majority of SPKs and CKs containing mission specific data for
         the spacecraft and for the mission targets as well as SCLKs
         were generated by RSSD/ESA from ancillary data files produced
         by ESOC.
 
      d) DSKs were generated by NAIF from other format shape model
         files produced by ESOC and by science instrument teams.
 
 
   3.2 - Creation of SPK, CK and SCLK kernels from ESOC Ancillary
         Data.
 
      ESOC provided orbit and attitude data in the form of text files.
      These products were the source of the CK and SPK kernels.
 
      ESOC generated time correlation data records and stored them in
      the telemetry server. These records were the source for the SCLK
      kernel.
 
      An automated system, called ADCS (Automatic Data Conversion
      System) was responsible for the generation of CK, SPK and SCLK
      kernels from the ESOC flight dynamics data file products and
      telemetry server SCLK records. ADCS detected when a new product
      was generated or a new time correlation packet was available, and
      ran a series of processes in order to create the proper kernels.
 
      ADCS used the SPICE Toolkit in order to fulfill its task. It ran
      on a server physically located at ESTEC until December 2007;
      after that date, the server was located at ESAC.
 
 
   3.3 - Using the SPICE kernels.
 
      At least a basic knowledge of the SPICE system is needed in order
      to use these kernels. The SPICE Toolkit provides versions in
      Fortran (SPICELIB), C (CSPICE), IDL (icy), Matlab (Mice), and
      Java (JNISpice) and the user can choose any one that suits
      him/her.
 
      The SPICE routine FURNSH can be used to load a kernel file into a
      SPICE-based application to make kernel&apos;s data usable with SPICE
      APIs.
 
      In the case when two or more kernel files contain data
      overlapping in time for a given object, for binary kernels, the
      file loaded last takes precedence.
 
      If two (or more) text kernels assign value(s) using the &apos;=&apos;
      operator to identical keywords, the data value(s) associated with
      the last loaded occurrence of the keyword are used -all earlier
      values have been replaced with the last loaded value(s).
 
 
   3.4 - Meta-kernels
 
      The easiest way to make data from a collection of SPICE kernels
      available to a SPICE-based application is to list these kernels
      in a meta-kernel and load it into the program using the high
      level SPICE data loader routine FURNSH. This data set provides
      such meta-kernel(s) under the EXTRAS/MK directory. For more
      information about the Rosetta meta-kernels, see the file
      EXTRAS/MK/MKINFO.TXT.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
    The SPICE kernels in this data set are either provided by NAIF (for
    instance, kernels containing parameters describing the planets, or
    the LSK kernel containing information about leapseconds) or
    calculated from the orbit and attitude data information generated
    by ESOC. In both cases the archive team are confident that the
    SPICE data is correct and accurate within the precision provided by
    the software and the instruments at the time the data was archived.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>PRE_PEER_REVIEW</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

