<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-e-v-h-mascs-5-virs-dap-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER E/V/H MASCS 5 VIRS DERIVED ANALYSIS DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mascs.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-5-virs-dap-v1.0__browserp_mess-e-v-h-mascs-5-virs-dap-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-5-virs-dap-v1.0__browser_geo_mercury_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-5-virs-dap-v1.0__browser_mess-e-v-h-mascs-5-virs-dap-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-5-virs-dap-v1.0__dvo_geo_mess-e-v-h-mascs-5-virs-dap-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   McClintock, W.E., and M.R. Lankton, The Mercury Atmospheric and Surface
                   Composition Spectrometer for the MESSENGER mission, Space Science Reviews, 131,
                   481-521, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MCCLINTOCK-LANK2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-E/V/H-MASCS-5-VIRS-DAP-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESSENGER E/V/H MASCS 5 VIRS DERIVED ANALYSIS DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-05-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2011-088T02:02:41Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-120T09:47:22Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>NOAM IZENBERG</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Izenberg, N., MESSENGER E/V/H MASCS 5 VIRS DERIVED ANALYSIS DATA
            V1.0, MESS-E/V/H-MASCS-5-VIRS-DAP-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2013.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The MESSENGER MASCS VIRS derived analysis product dataset
            consists of a 500 meter per pixel mosaic map of 1 wavelength (750
            nm) of VIRS spectral data for footprints covering the planet
            Mercury.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== This data set consists of the MESSENGER MASCS
            VIRS derived analysis product, also known as the DAP. The DAP is
            a 500 meter per pixel mosaic map of 1 wavelength (750 nm) of VIRS
            spectral data for footprints covering the planet Mercury. Data
            products are derived from science data collected by the VIRS
            detector during orbital operations of Mercury.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
   Data Set Overview
   =================
     This data set consists of the MESSENGER MASCS VIRS derived
     anaylsis product (DAP).
 
     One DAP will contain a 500 meter per pixel mosaic map of 1
     wavelength (750 nm) of VIRS spectral data for footprints covering
     the whole planet. MASCS/VIRS mosaics include MASCS/VIRS
     footprints collected after orbit insertion. A metric defined as
     M = footprint_area / (cos(e)*cos(i)) is computed for each
     footprint of each observation. In the case of individual spectra
     that cover the same location, spectra with the lowest metric
     value are stacked on top, and are the only ones to be captured in
     the final map layer. The spectra examined for inclusion in the
     mosaic come from CDRs converted to photometrically corrected
     reflectance using the same method as the VIRS DDRs. Mosaicked
     spectra must have M &gt; 0, emission angle &lt; 80 degrees and
     incidence angle &lt; 70 degrees for footprints with latitude in
     [-65,65] or incidence angle &lt; footprint&apos;s latitude + 5 degrees
     for other footprints.
 
   Instrument Overview
   ===================
     The MASCS instrument consists of a small Cassegrain telescope
     that simultaneously feeds the UVVS and VIRS experiments. The
     MASCS VIRS experiment is a fixed concave grating spectrograph
     with a beam splitter that simultaneously disperses the spectrum
     onto two solid-state array detectors: a 512-element silicon
     photodiode array, with a sensitivity to visible wavelengths
     (300-1050 nm), and a 256-element indium-gallium-arsenide
     photodiode array, to measure near infrared wavelengths
     (850-1450 nm). The VIRS detector will help to measure the surface
     reflectance and search for ferrous bearing minerals, Fe-Ti
     bearing phases, and ferrous iron on the surface of Mercury. See
     the INST.CAT file for more information and [MCCLINTOCK&amp;LANK2007]
     for full details.
 
   Derived Product Overview
   ========================
     This data set consists of the MASCS VIRS Derived Analysis Product
     (DAP, calculated from the DDRs as described in the SIS). The
     DAP is a 500 meter per pixel mosaic map of 1 wavelength (750 nm)
     of VIRS spectral data for footprints covering the planet Mercury.
 
     The processing steps from the DDR to the DAP level include:
 
     1. Ingest DDR dataset and select footprints.
 
     2. Create map layers.
 
     More information on the DAP can be found in the document
     VIRS_CDR_DDR_DAP_SIS, located in the DOCUMENT directory.
 
   Coordinate Systems
   ==================
     MASCS VIRS data are represented in the following coordinate
     systems:
 
     * Planetocentric body fixed: The MBF coordinate system is defined
     by the planetocentric position, Cartesian X, Y, Z coordinates
     related to the planetocentric distance, latitude measured
     positive northward from the equator, and longitude measured
     positive eastward from the prime meridian.
 
     * Cartographic: Surface observations use IAU planetocentric
     system with East longitudes being positive for planetary
     surfaces. The MESSENGER-derived reference system
     (pck00010_msgr_v21.tpc) for cartographic coordinates and
     rotational elements was used for computing latitude and longitude
     coordinates of planets.
 
   Data
   ====
     There is one VIRS DAP data product, consisting of 9 layers. Each
     layer is provided as a separate image file (.IMG); the 9 layers
     are described by 1 detached PDS label (.LBL).
 
     Each layer information is derived from the CDR and the spectrum
     of the topmost spectrum at a given map location.
 
     1) Reflectance @750 nm, taken from DDR for spectrum with maximum
     M value.
     2) Interpolated reflectance @750nm derived from layer 1 using a
     spatial interpolation algorithm.
     3) Incidence angle (of maximum M value spectrum), taken from DDR
     4) Emission angle(of maximum M value spectrum), taken from DDR
     5) Phase angle (of maximum M value spectrum), taken from DDR
     6) observation area, derived from footprint dimension from DDR
     7) observation DDR date (of maximum M value spectrum)
     8) observation DDR time (of maximum M value spectrum)
     9) observation spectrum number (of maximum M value spectrum)
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
   Confidence Level Overview
   =========================
     The MASCS VIRS Derived Analysis Product (DAP) consists of the
     derived data converted to units of reflectance and represented in
     physical coordinate systems. Data presented here are an accurate
     representation of the VIRS data as received from the spacecraft,
     and reflect the processing steps from the MASCS VIRS Derived
     Data Records (DDRs) to DAP level. The UTC and MET time tags have
     been corrected for timing latencies in the instrument so that the
     UTC and MET correspond to the physical time of the observation.
 
   Review
   ======
     The VIRS DAP was reviewed internally by the MASCS team prior to
     release to the PDS. PDS also performed an external review of the
     MASCS VIRS DAP.
 
   Data Coverage and Quality
   =========================
     Data reported are the derived data received from the spacecraft
     during the orbital mission phases: Mercury Orbit, Mercury Orbit
     Year 2, Mercury Orbit Year 3, Mercury Orbit Year 4, and Mercury
     Orbit Year 5. These mission phases are defined as:
 
                                Start time         End time
     Phase Name                 Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)
     -------------------------  -----------------  ----------------
     ORB: Mercury Orbit         04 Mar 2011 (063)  17 Mar 2012 (077)
     OB2: Mercury Orbit Year 2  18 Mar 2012 (078)  17 Mar 2013 (076)
     OB3: Mercury Orbit Year 3  18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)
     OB4: Mercury Orbit Year 4  18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)
     OB5: Mercury Orbit Year 5  18 Mar 2015 (077)  30 Apr 2015 (120)
 
     To validate the initial DAP dataset, the MASCS team did the
     following:
 
        * Examined several locales of Mercury map data in detail.
 
            - Checked all backplanes for format and sanity numbers.
            - Compared calibration numbers for earlier independent
              analysis before DAP development.
 
        * Spot checked additional data sets from orbit.
 
     The orbital DAP dataset is evaluated on an ongoing basis,
     checking for completeness and data integrity.
 
     MASCS VIRS data were collected during all phases except
     Venus 1 Flyby, but only resolved Mercury surface data from orbit
     are converted to DAP.
 
   Limitations
   ===========
     This data set is derived data.  The data are received from the
     spacecraft telemetry and ingested into the MESSENGER Science
     Operations Center (SOC), then run through the MASCS pipeline. No
     data uncharacterized gaps have been identified for any of the
     MASCS operational periods.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

