<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mo-m-rss-1-oidr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MO MARS RADIO SCIENCE 1 ORIGINAL/INTERMEDIATE DATA REC V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_observer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.mo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mo-m-rss-1-oidr-v1.0__browserp_mo-m-rss-1-oidr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.en::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Asmar, S.W., and R.G. Herrera, Radio Science Handbook, JPL D-7938, Volume 4,
                   Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, 22 January 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ASMAR-HERRERA1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MO-M-RSS-1-OIDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MO MARS RADIO SCIENCE 1 ORIGINAL/INTERMEDIATE DATA REC V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1994-07-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1971-01-01</start_time>
        <stop_time>1993-12-31</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>RICHARD A. SIMPSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Simpson, R.A., MO MARS RADIO SCIENCE 1 ORIGINAL/INTERMEDIATE DATA
            REC V1.0, MO-M-RSS-1-OIDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 1994
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            MO MARS RADIO SCIENCE 1 ORIGINAL/INTERMEDIATE DATA REC V1.0
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The data set consists of several CD-WO volumes which contain
            radiometric and open loop data acquired from the Mars Observer
            spacecraft during its Cruise between Earth and Mars. The basic
            data are supplemented by ancillary data including DSN weather
            files and media calibrations, spacecraft maneuver information,
            and operations schedules. There are fourteen data types.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The data set consists of several CD-WO volumes which contain
      radiometric and open loop data acquired from the Mars Observer
      spacecraft during its Cruise between Earth and Mars.  The basic
      data are supplemented by ancillary data including DSN weather
      files and media calibrations, spacecraft maneuver information,
      and operations schedules.  The fourteen data types are listed
      in the table below, then explained in more detail in the
      sections that follow.
 
 
      Angular Momentum Desaturation Files DSN Ionosphere Calibration
      Files DSN Troposphere Calibration Files DSN Time and Polar
      Motion Files DSN Weather Data Light Time Files Manuever
      Implementation Files Maneuver Performance Data Files Orbit Data
      Files Original Data Records Original Data Streams Space Flight
      Operations Schedules Sequence of Events Files Tracking Data
      Files
 
 
    Data
    ====
      (1) ANGULAR MOMENTUM DESATURATION FILES
 
      Angular Momentum Desaturation files contain predicted times and
      durations of angular momentum desaturation events.  The Mars
      Observer hydrazine thrusters were used to unload momentum
      stored by the spacecraft reaction wheels.  The files were
      created by the Mars Observer Navigation Team under the
      direction of P. Esposito.  They are used by Mars Observer Radio
      Science investigators to interpret non-gravitational changes in
      the spacecraft trajectory and/or orientation.
 
      The files are described by Mars Observer Software Interface
      Specification EAE003, except that the SFDU header record has
      been removed and the simple &lt;line-feed&gt; delimiter specified by
      the SIS after each record (line) has been replaced by a
      &lt;carriage-return&gt; &lt;line-feed&gt; pair in this archival volume.
      Otherwise, the MO Radio Science Team has no independent
      knowledge of the content, format, or accuracy of the data in
      these files.
 
 
      (2) DSN IONOSPHERE CALIBRATION FILES
 
      DSN Ionosphere Calibration Files are one of three types of
      Media Calibration Files generated by the DSN Tracking System
      Analytic Calibration Team.  The calibrations comprise
      corrections for the effects of transmission media (troposphere,
      ionosphere, and solar plasma) on radiometric data and are used
      by Mars Observer Radio Science investigators and others.
 
      The files are described by Mars Observer Software Interface
      Specification DACE006, except that the SFDU header record has
      been removed and the simple &lt;line-feed&gt; delimiter specified by
      the SIS after each record (line) has been replaced by a
      &lt;carriage-return&gt; &lt;line-feed&gt; pair in this archival volume.
      Otherwise, the MO Radio Science Team has no independent
      knowledge of the content, format, or accuracy of the data in
      these files.
 
 
      (3) DSN TROPOSPHERE CALIBRATION FILES
 
      DSN Troposphere Calibration Files are one of three types of
      Media Calibration Files generated by the DSN Tracking System
      Analytic Calibration Team.  The calibrations comprise
      corrections for the effects of transmission media (troposphere,
      ionosphere, and solar plasma) on radiometric data and are used
      by Mars Observer Radio Science investigators and others.
 
      The files are described by Mars Observer Software Interface
      Specification DACE006, except that the SFDU header record has
      been removed and the simple &lt;line-feed&gt; delimiter specified by
      the SIS after each record (line) has been replaced by a
      &lt;carriage-return&gt; &lt;line-feed&gt; pair in this archival volume.
      Otherwise, the MO Radio Science Team has no independent
      knowledge of the content, format, or accuracy of the data in
      these files.
 
 
      (4) DSN TIME AND POLAR MOTION FILES
 
      DSN Time and Polar Motion Files contain predictions and past
      history of Earth rotation, including rate of rotation and
      changes in the rotation axis.  These data are used in
      performing precise orbit determinations by Mars Observer Radio
      Science investigators and others.
 
      The files are described by Mars Observer Software Interface
      Specification DACE007, except that the SFDU header record has
      been removed and the simple &lt;line-feed&gt; delimiter specified by
      the SIS after each record (line) has been replaced by a
      &lt;carriage-return&gt; &lt;line-feed&gt; pair in this archival volume.
      Otherwise, the MO Radio Science Team has no independent
      knowledge of the content, format, or accuracy of the data in
      these files.
 
 
      (5) DSN WEATHER DATA FILES
 
      DSN Weather Data files contain hourly records of temperature,
      barometric pressure, relative humidity, dew point, and water
      vapor partial pressure at each of the three DSN communication
      complexes.  They are compiled by the DSN Tracking System
      Analysis Calibration Team and were deposited on a regular basis
      in the MO PDB.
 
      The files are described by Mars Observer Software Interface
      Specification DACE022, except that the SFDU header record has
      been removed and the simple &lt;line-feed&gt; delimiter specified by
      the SIS after each record (line) has been replaced by a
      &lt;carriage-return&gt; &lt;line-feed&gt; pair in this archival volume.
      Otherwise, the MO Radio Science Team has no independent
      knowledge of the content, format, or accuracy of the data in
      these files.
 
 
      (6) LIGHT TIME FILES
 
      Light Time Files contain one-way light time data (set of points
      SCE vs OWCT) between Earth (geocentric or topocentric) and the
      Mars Observer spacecraft.  The files are produced by the Mars
      Observer Navigation Team.
 
      The files are described by Mars Observer Software Interface
      Specification NAE002, except that the SFDU header record has
      been removed and the simple &lt;line-feed&gt; delimiter specified by
      the SIS after each record (line) has been replaced by a
      &lt;carriage-return&gt; &lt;line-feed&gt; pair in this archival volume.
      Otherwise, the MO Radio Science Team has no independent
      knowledge of the content, format, or accuracy of the data in
      these files.
 
 
      (7) MANEUVER IMPLEMENTATION FILES
 
      Maneuver Implementation/Reconstruction Files contain commands,
      attitudes, velocities, and statistics associated with
      Trajectory Change Maneuvers.  The files were produced by the
      Mars Observer Spacecraft Team.
 
      The files are described by Mars Observer Software Interface
      Specification EAE014, except that the SFDU header record has
      been removed and the simple &lt;line-feed&gt; delimiter specified by
      the SIS after each record (line) has been replaced by a
      &lt;carriage-return&gt; &lt;line-feed&gt; pair in this archival volume.
      Otherwise, the MO Radio Science Team has no independent
      knowledge of the content, format, or accuracy of the data in
      these files.
 
 
      (8) MANEUVER PERFORMANCE FILES
 
      Maneuver Performance Data Files contain data necessary for the
      Mars Observer Navigation Team to plan and design specific
      spacecraft maneuvers.Included are spacecraft physical
      parameters and thruster information such as mass, location of
      the center mass, moments of inertia, effective thruster
      directions and magnitudes, thruster locations, and propellant
      flow rate.  Maneuver Performance Data Files were produced by
      the Mars Observer Spacecraft Team.
 
      The files are described by Mars Observer Software Interface
      Specification EAE008, except that the SFDU header record has
      been removed and the simple &lt;line-feed&gt; delimiter specified by
      the SIS after each record (line) has been replaced by a
      &lt;carriage-return&gt; &lt;line-feed&gt; pair in this archival volume.
      Otherwise, the MO Radio Science Team has no independent
      knowledge of the content, format, or accuracy of the data in
      these files.
 
 
      (9) ORBIT DATA FILES
 
      Orbit Data Files contain edited radiometric and VLBI data used
      to navigate the spacecraft.  They may also contain calibrations
      and corrections to range data for a tracking station and
      spacecraft signal time-delay.  Each ODF is made up of 36-byte
      records, of which there are 13 types: 6 header types, 6 data
      types, and one end-of-file marker.  The ODF is produced by the
      DSN Radio Metric Data Conditioning Team.
 
      Record formats are described in Mars Observer Software
      Interface Specification DACE005.  The archival form of the ODF
      has been modified by removal of its SFDU header.  Otherwise,
      the MO Radio Science Team has no independent knowledge of the
      content, format, or accuracy of the data in these files.
 
 
      (10) ORIGINAL DATA RECORD and ORIGINAL DATA STREAM
 
      Original Data Records and Original Data Streams are time-
      ordered 8- or 12-bit samples of Open-Loop Receiver baseband
      amplifier output voltages.  Individual records vary from 466 to
      4166 bytes (not including SFDU headers), of which the first 166
      bytes contain header information (time tags, settings for the
      receiver, channel assignments, local oscillator frequency) and
      the remaining bytes are the samples from up to four separate
      receiver outputs.  The length of the individual records depends
      on the sampling rate and the channel assignments.  The ODS is
      an electronic file, the successor to the (magnetic tape)
      Original Data Record (ODR).  The ODS is constructed from
      packets stored in the Mars Observer Project Data Base.  The
      format is described by Mars Observer Software Interface
      DACE046.  The ODR is described by DSN SIS RSC-11-11.  Radio
      science investigators use the digital data to derive amplitude
      and phase of the signal received from the spacecraft by the
      Deep Space Network antenna.
 
      In mid-April 1993 electronic transmission of Open-Loop data
      between the DSN stations and the Mars Observer PDB was enabled.
      With one exception, when electronic transmission failed, ODS
      data were obtained after that rather than ODR.
 
      Unless independent information is available, each ODS must be
      self-calibrated to determine the original signal strength,
      frequency, and phase.
 
      Summary notes on individual tests:
 
      Test #1: 1992-296 (22 Oct 92) at DSS 15 Equipment incorrectly
      configured: DSP mode 1 at 5000 samples per channel was set up
      instead of mode 2 at 2000 samples per channel.  This proved
      useful in analysis, however.  One A-D converter was defective;
      the others were not linear; redundancy from mode 1
      configuration allowed quantitative measurement of errors.  It
      also became apparent that the A-D converters had never been
      used/tested for 12-bit output; DSN personnel later admitted
      that accuracy was never guaranteed for more than about 7 bits.
 
      No signal for approximately the first 1000 seconds; operator
      adjustments continued in both frequency and amplitude until
      about 1600 secs.  Four tapes received, but none were
      contiguous.
 
      Modulation on the signal is apparent at long periods (100 min
      from spacecraft rotation), medium periods (a few minutes,
      perhaps from CONSCAN), and short periods.
 
 
      Test #2: 1992-312 (7 Nov 92) at DSS 15 Similar problems to Test
      #1, but configuration was for 2000 samples per second per
      channel instead of 5000.  In addition, pulse modulation (17
      percent duty cycle, 0.6 sec period with 90 deg phase shift)
      appears on signal output.  POCA frequencies and rates were
      inconsistent at break points.  Three tapes.
 
 
      Test #3: 1992-325 (20 Nov 92) at DSS 15 This test was run with
      the spacecraft in occultation configuration -- with telemetry
      off.  Ground problems were similar to those encountered during
      Test #1.  The first tape (of 3 total) was unreadable after
      about 4 minutes of data and was returned to JPL for analysis.
      60 Hz modulation was detected on the carrier.
 
 
      Test #4: 1992-340 (5 Dec 92) at DSS 15 A-D failure was
      repaired, but A-Ds remain non-linear and are not well matched.
      One tape was delivered to Stanford; two others were received at
      JPL but were not copied because they contained only about a
      minute of data.  Long- and medium-period modulation remains,
      presumably from spacecraft and/or ground antenna motions.
      Inconsistent POCA frequency and rate readings are noted at POCA
      break points.
 
 
      HGA Calibration: 1993-008 (8 Jan 93) at DSS 65 Data acquired
      for radio science analysis, but this was not an official test.
      First test using facility other than DSS 15.  Many
      operator-initiated gain changes, many artifacts of A-D non-
      linearity, and 60 Hz modulation on carrier.  On the other hand,
      there were no problems in POCA reading at break points in
      tuning profile.  Three tapes received at Stanford.
 
 
      USO Test #5: 1992-354 (19 Dec 92) at DSS 45 Failed.  No tapes
      received.
 
 
      USO Test #6: 1993-014 (14 Jan 93) at DSS 65 Similar to HGA
      Calibration, but more spurious signals identified during
      analysis.  May still be the best USO Test data so far.
      Sticksion events identified; 1 Hz modulation found.  One ODR
      tape covers almost 2 hrs.
 
 
      USO Test #7: 1993-049 (18 Feb 93) at DSS 15 Similar to Test #6.
      POCA inconsistencies seen previously at DSS 15 not present.  60
      Hz modulation not present, but 180 Hz spurs seen.  Overall,
      good data.
 
 
      USO Test #8: 1993-064 (5 Mar 93) at DSS 45 Single tape
      received, but its block size was far smaller than expected.DSN
      personnel were unable to explain how software settings could be
      over-ridden.  No analysis performed; tape returned to JPL for
      investigation.
 
 
      USO Test #9: 1993-079 (20 Mar 93) at DSS 65 Antenna stopped
      tracking after 35 minutes; resumed after about 1 hour.Four
      tapes of contiguous data were obtained covering more than 2-1/2
      hrs.Spurious signals 665 Hz from carrier.  Among the best data
      to date.
 
 
      USO Test #10: 1993-107 (17 Apr 93) No data
 
 
      USO Test #11: 1993-116 (26 Apr 93) at DSS 65 First attempt to
      transfer test data electronically (ODS).  Initially many
      records did not get through, but later queries resulted in
      almost complete recovery of data (36001 full records).  Many
      POCA offsets during test.
 
 
      RS ORT Test #1: 1993-129 (9 May 93) Spacecraft in contingency
      mode; test canceled.
 
 
      USO Test #12: 1993-131 (11 May 93) Spacecraft in contingency
      mode; test canceled.
 
 
      USO Test #13: 1993-146 (26 May 93) at DSS 45 All ODS records
      expected (28800) were recovered within 14 hrs.  Data quality,
      with the exception of A-D conversion artifacts, was excellent.
      Some modulation sidebands on carrier from unknown sources.  A-D
      #3 was not operating correctly in low bits.
 
 
      RS ORT Test #2: 1993-154 (3 Jun 93) at DSS 45 Test data were
      collected continuously over 7 hrs rather than in short bursts
      because Event File could not be loaded at station.  ODS
      transfer failed after first hour; resumed 90 minutes later.
      None of early data could ever be located, however.  Of the
      later data, only the 10 minutes of each scheduled test interval
      were analyzed.  Minor timing anomalies, some low level spurs,
      and one ailing A-D converter.
 
 
      USO Test #14: 1993-161 (10 Jun 93) at DSS 65 A few samples lost
      at the beginning.  Otherwise, this was a very good test.
 
 
      RS ORT Test #3: 1993-175 (24 Jun 93) at DSS 65 Nearly complete
      ODS data recovery.  Anomalous short records found at the end of
      data acquisition periods.  CONSCAN state was not always as
      requested.
 
 
      USO Test #15: 1993-177 (26 Jun 93) at DSS 45 Scattered records
      lost, but data quality excellent otherwise.  Usual problems
      with A-D artifacts.  170 Hz modulation spurs on each side of
      carrier
 
 
      USO Test #16: 1993-191 (10 Jul 93) at DSS 65 Data collected in
      occultation configuration (spacecraft telemetry off), but ODS
      transmission was not enabled so all data went to tape (3
      tapes).  Some data appeared in the MO PDB NERT Cache a few days
      later, however, but it had bad record numbers and time tags.
      Second (ODR) tape had scattered added samples; third tape had
      extra byte.
 
 
      USO Test #17: 1993-203 (22 Jul 93) at DSS 15 Incorrect
      configuration at station for first 22 minutes; otherwise data
      quality is good.
 
      (11) SPACE FLIGHT OPERATIONS SCHEDULES
 
      Space Flight Operations Schedule Files contain information
      about states and events of importance to the Mars Observer
      Project.  Although the SFOS file itself is ASCII, it is
      intended to be used in conjunction with the sfosedt application
      program, which displays the operations schedule graphically.
      SFOS Files were produced by the Mars Observer Planning and
      Sequencing Team, typically covering two week periods but issued
      every seven days.
 
      The SFOS file format is described by Mars Observer Software
      Interface Specification PSE003.
 
      The archival form of the SFOS File has been modified by removal
      of its original SFDU header, by removal of a leading
      &lt;line-feed&gt; character at the beginning of the data file, and by
      substitution of &lt;carriage-return&gt;&lt;line-feed&gt; pairs for the
      original &lt;line-feed&gt; record/line delimiters.  The SFOS File
      must be returned to its original format before it can be used
      with the sfosedt utility.
 
      Other than the comments above, the MO Radio Science Team has no
      independent knowledge of the content, format, or accuracy of
      the data in these files.
 
      (12) SEQUENCE OF EVENT FILES
 
      Sequence of Events Files are time-ordered lists of activities
      of interest to the Mars Observer Project.  Although the SOE
      file itself is ASCII, it is intended to be used in conjunction
      with the soeedt application program, which displays the
      schedule in a formatted table.  SOE Files were produced by the
      Mars Observer Planning and Sequencing Team, typically covering
      more than two week periods but issued every seven days.
 
      The SOE File format is described by Mars Observer Software
      Interface Specification PSE002.
 
      The archival form of the SOE File has been modified by removal
      of its original SFDU header, by removal of a leading
      &lt;line-feed&gt; character at the beginning of the data file, and by
      substitution of &lt;carriage-return&gt;&lt;line-feed&gt; pairs for the
      original &lt;line-feed&gt; record/line delimiters.  The SOE File must
      be returned to its original format before it can be used with
      the soeedt utility.
 
      Other than the comments above, the MO Radio Science Team has no
      independent knowledge of the content, format, or accuracy of
      the data in these files.
 
 
      (13) TRACKING DATA FILES
 
      Tracking Data Files contain all raw radiometric and VLBI data,
      subject to minor editing of &apos;bad&apos; points.  Data include angle,
      Doppler measurements, range measurements, differenced range vs
      integrated Doppler (DRVID) values, programmed frequency data,
      pseudo-residual data, and validation data.  A single TDF will
      contain data for only one spacecraft, but it may contain data
      collected from several tracking stations and for several days.
      Each TDF is produced by the DSN Radio Metric Data Conditioning
      Team.
 
      Each TDF is made up of one File Identification Logical Record,
      one Transponder Logical Record, and many time-ordered Tracking
      Data Logical Records.  Each record has a length of 288 bytes.
 
      Record formats are described in Mars Observer Software
      Interface Specification DACE004.  The archival form of the TDF
      has been modified by removal of its SFDU header.  Otherwise,
      the MO Radio Science Team has no independent knowledge of the
      content, format, or accuracy of the data in these files.
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      Quality of the ODR/ODS data from the Mars Observer Cruise tests
      is variable.  Initially hardware failures and incorrect
      configurations corrupted the data.  That is, the digital
      samples largely reflected the receiver output, but were not
      accurate representations of the microwave signal being captured
      by the antenna.  During later tests, the performance improved
      but it never reached the level required for Mars Observer
      Mapping.  See comments in DATA_SET_DESC on individual test
      results; spacecraft operations were always nominal, but ground
      performance varied.
 
      Quality of the other data sets is unknown.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>92-063A-01A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

