<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mex-m-marsis-2-edr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MARS EXPRESS MARS MARSIS EXPERIMENT DATA RECORD V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_express::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mex::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:marsis.mex::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.phobos::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mex-m-marsis-2-edr-v1.0__browserp_geo_mex-m-marsis-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mex-m-marsis-2-edr-v1.0__dvo_geo_mex-m-marsis-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.psa::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Picardi, G. et. al., MARSIS: Mars Advanced Radar for Subsurface and Ionosphere
                   Sounding, ESA-SP-1240, September 2004
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PICARDIETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MEX-M-MARSIS-2-EDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MARS EXPRESS MARS MARSIS EXPERIMENT DATA RECORD V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2007-11-30</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2005-06-01T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2005-12-31T00:00:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>GIOVANNI PICARDI</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Picardi, G. et al, MARS EXPRESS MARS MARSIS EXPERIMENT DATA
            RECORD V1.0, MEX-M-MARSIS-2-EDR-V1.0, Dipartimento INFOCOM, 2005.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains the CODMAC Level 2 MARSIS data for the
            Mars Express mission
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset contains the scientific telemetry produced by the
            MARSIS instrument after editing for duplicated and corrupted
            packets, together with geometric information computed on ground
            to locate observations in space and time. Both subsurface and
            ionosphere sounding data are included in the dataset.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      MARSIS Level 1b data products consist of the data produced by the
      instrument reconstructed from the scientific telemetry, sorted by
      instrument state and data type, and provided with spacecraft position,
      velocity and attitude information. Any other spacecraft telemetry
      relevant for calibration and processing (e.g. temperature of the
      receiver) is also be included.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      MARSIS data are organized into groups of echoes called frames. A frame
      contains one or more echoes, with or without on-board processing. Each
      echo, depending on the kind of processing it underwent, is recorded
      either as a time series of signal samples, or as the complex spectrum of
      the signal itself produced by means of a FFT. Scientific data in a frame
      are complemented by a set of ancillary data, produced by the instrument
      and recording parameter values used in pulse transmission, echo
      reception and on-board processing.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      Level 1b processing starts from the telemetry data, as produced by the
      C&amp;DH system on the spacecraft and passed to the telemetry subsystem:
      data are still in the form of transfer frame packets organised by
      contacts or ground tests data.
      Processing starts by cleaning, merging and time-ordering the packets.
      This means that duplicate data have been deleted, missing packets are
      padded out, and the data are organised by days (or orbits). Data then
      need to be sorted by instrument data types and instrument modes.
 
      MARSIS Level 1b processing orders data in a useful way for the intended
      users (i.e. radar scientists) and applications (i.e. quick look to
      monitor hardware performance and higher-level processing), altering and
      manipulating them as little as possible to avoid the risk of introducing
      errors and, at the same time, including all necessary information from
      all relevant sources. Level 1b data are in scientifically useful form,
      i.e. individual spectra. These data are still uncalibrated.
 
      MARSIS Level 1b data products consist of the data produced by the
      instrument reconstructed from the scientific telemetry, sorted by
      instrument state and data type, and provided with spacecraft position,
      velocity and attitude information. Any other spacecraft telemetry
      relevant for calibration and Processing (e.g. temperature of the
      receiver) is also be included.
 
      Level 1b processing requires the acquisition of MARSIS scientific
      telemetry and any relevant spacecraft auxiliary data from the Mars
      Express Data Disposition System (DDS) in ESOC, and of SPICE kernels
      describing the spacecraft state and attitude from the Auxiliary Data
      Conversion System (ADCS) in ESTEC.
 
      Both instrument telemetry and ancillary data are stored at the PI
      processing facility as they accumulate over the course of the mission,
      to provide the capability to reprocess data in case of errors or to
      accommodate new information referring to existing data sets.
 
      Level 1b data distribution to the Co-Is and to the Mars Express mission
      archive is performed by ASDC. It is required by ESA that data products
      are delivered in batches of six-months worth of data within six months
      from the last data take (i.e. one year after the beginning of that
      particular data collection period), but it is necessary that level 1b
      processing be completed in a much shorter period, to allow enough time
      for level 2 data processing and data analysis within the MARSIS team
      before the expiration of the data proprietary period (which is the same
      six-month time span).
 
 
    Data
    ====
      The MARS EXPRESS MARS MARSIS EXPERIMENT DATA RECORD V1.0 Data Set
      contains scientific telemetry generated by the instrument, edited to
      remove duplications, zero-padded for missing packets, and correlated
      with geometric information needed to locate observations in space and
      time. No other kind of processing is applied to the data.
 
      The list of EDR data Products is :
 
      AIS_EDR : Active Ionosphere Sounding data frames with geometry
                information.
      CAL_EDR : Data frames acquired in Calibration mode with geometry
                information.
      RXO_EDR : Data frames acquired in Receive Only mode with geometry
                Information.
      SSx_yyy_CMP_EDR : On-board processed Subsurface Sounding data
                       (either in Acquisition or Tracking state) with
                       geometry information
      SSx_yyy_IND_EDR : Individual Echoes from Subsurface Sounding data
                       (either in Acquisition or Tracking state).
      SSx_yyy_UNC_EDR : Uncompressed Subsurface Sounding data
                       (either in Acquisition or Tracking state).
      SSx_yyy_RAW_EDR : Raw Subsurface Sounding data
                        (either in Acquisition or Tracking state).
      Where   x   stands for a number between 1 and 5, while  yyy  stands
      either for ACQ or TRK.
 
      AIS_EDR, CAL_EDR, RXO_EDR and SSx_yyy_CMP_EDR Data Products is made by
      two files, each of which contains a PDS binary TABLE object preceded by
      a PDS attached label describing its structure. The first file, called
      Frame file (FRM) contains the instrument data proper, exactly in the
      same format (bit by bit) as they were produced by the instrument.
      Each frame corresponds to a record in the file, which is also a row in
      the PDS binary TABLE object into which frames are organised. A Data
      Product contains all frames acquired using the same instrument mode, in
      the same instrument state and after the same type of on-board processing
      during a single orbit. The second file constituting an EDR is called a
      Geometry file (GEO), and contains one record, corresponding to one line
      of the PDS binary TABLE object into which data are organised, for every
      frame in the corresponding FRM file.
 
      Subsurface data from Individual Echoes are the unprocessed version of
      data that are also down-linked in processed form. A frame of Individual
      Echoes consists of a variable number of raw echoes, because, to produce
      a constant along-track ground resolution, synthetic aperture (Doppler)
      processing performed on board requires a number of echoes that increases
      with altitude of the spacecraft. The Data Product consists in just one
      file containing a PDS header and the data themselves, because any
      additional geometric information would just duplicate similar
      information already provided in SSx_yyy_CMP_EDR GEO data files. File
      names contain the first ten digits of the spacecraft clock count
      corresponding to the time at which data were acquired.
 
      Each record in a file contains a single unprocessed echo, preceded by
      auxiliary data and by a counter starting from 0 and increasing by one at
      each new echo. Echoes are ordered according to the time at which they
      were collected. Ancillary information is produced once per frame, and is
      thus the same for all echoes in a file: this duplication has been deemed
      necessary to simplify the data structure as much as possible.
 
      The number of echoes required in Doppler processing is a function of
      frequency, as well as of spacecraft altitude. In a dual-frequency mode,
      the exact number of echoes collected at each frequency is contained in
      the Ancillary data and echoes within a frame are ordered by frequency
      before being ordered in time.
 
      Subsurface UNC data are the uncompressed version of data that are also
      down-linked in fully processed form. Because they are structured exactly
      as CMP data, the only difference being the compression of individual
      echo samples from 4-byte IEEE real numbers to 1-byte integers, it has
      been chosen to produce one Data Product per orbit, just as for CMP data.
      The Data Product consists in just one file containing a PDS header and
      the data themselves, because any additional geometric information would
      just duplicate similar information already provided in SSx_yyy_CMP_EDR
      GEO data files. File names contains  the four-digit number of the orbit
      at which data were acquired. The structure of UNC Data Products is
      identical to the one used in CMP FRM files. Because UNC data are down-
      linked through a dump of the flash memory, rather than through the
      scientific telemetry of the instrument, they do not come with a full set
      of ancillary data
 
      Subsurface Raw Data are the unprocessed version of data that are also
      down-linked in processed form. A frame of Raw Data consists of a
      variable number of raw echoes, because, to produce a constant along-
      track ground resolution, synthetic aperture (Doppler) processing
      performed on board requires a number of echoes that increases with
      altitude of the spacecraft.
 
      Because of this, it has been chosen to produce one Data Product per each
      frame of Raw Data, rather than one per orbit, similarly to Individual
      Echoes. The Data Product consists in just one file containing a PDS
      header and the data themselves, because any additional geometric
      information would just duplicate similar information already provided in
      SSx_yyy_CMP_EDR GEO data files. File names contain the first ten digits
      of the spacecraft clock count corresponding to the time at which data
      were acquired.
 
      The structure of RAW Data Products is identical to the one used in IND
      files. Because RAW data are down-linked through a dump of the flash
      memory, rather than through the scientific telemetry of the instrument,
      they do not come with a full set of ancillary data.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      Each frame of MARSIS data (with the exception of frames stored in flash
      memory) carries a 228 byte header of ancillary data, containing
      necessary information for subsequent analysis of the data and further
      processing. The exact content of the ancillary data depends on
      instrument mode. There are four major structure types of the ancillary
      data : acquisition, tracking / individual echoes for subsurface modes,
      calibration / receive only and active ionosphere
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      Locations on the surface of Mars are expressed in planetocentric
      coordinates. Longitude is comprised in the range 0 - 360 degrees.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      Marsis data products can be read by the PDS software NASAView, which
      reads a PDS label and displays the associated image or table. NASAView
      has been tested on both EDR and RDR data products.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The standard distribution format for the data is transfer through
      Internet from the Planetary Science Archive of ESA, which can be
      accessed at the following URL:
 
      http://www.rssd.esa.int/psa
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Review
    ======
      These data have been reviewed by the instrument team and are of the
      highest quality that can be generated at this time. Science results
      based on these data have been published in journals. The dataset is
      currently being reviewed by the Plannetary Science Archive of ESA.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Data in this dataset have been acquired only in the last six months of
      the nominal mission, because of the delay in the deployment of the
      MARSIS antenna. Because of this, coverage is limited mainly to southern
      latitudes.
 
      Data quality in a data product label is indicated through the
      DATA_QUALITY_ID element, and measures the integrity of the telemetry
      stream from the instrument. The permitted values of DATA_QUALITY_ID are
      the following:
 
      -1: percentage of corrupted data not available
       0: no corrupted data
       1: less than 2% corrupted data
       2: less than 5% corrupted data
       3: less than 10% corrupted data
       4: more than 10% corrupted data
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
 
      There are no known limitations at this time.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

