<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dif-c-hrii-3-4-epoxi-ison-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>EPOXI C/ISON (2012 S1) - HRII CALIBRATED SPECTRA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.epoxi::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:hrii.dif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.c-ison_2012_s1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dif-c-hrii-3-4-epoxi-ison-v1.0__browserp_dif-c-hrii-3-4-epoxi-ison-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Feaga, L.M., M.F. A&apos;Hearn, T.L. Farnham, D. Bodewits, J.M. Sunshine, A.M.
                   Gersch, S. Protopapa, B. Yang, M. Drahus, and D.G. Schleicher, Uncorrelated
                   Volatile Behavior During the 2011 Apparition of Comet C/2009 P1 Garradd, AJ,
                   147, 24, 2014, doi:10.1088/0004-6256/147/1/24.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FEAGAETAL2014</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hampton, D.L., J.W. Baer, M.A. Huisjen, C.C. Varner, A. Delamere, D.D.
                   Wellnitz, M.F. A&apos;Hearn, and K.P. Klaasen, An Overview of the Instrument Suite
                   for the Deep Impact Mission, Space Science Reviews, 117, 43-93, 2005,
                   doi:10.1007/s11214-005-3390-8.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAMPTONETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., M.F. A&apos;Hearn, M. Baca, A. Delamere, M. Desnoyer, T. Farnham, O.
                   Groussin, D. Hampton, S. Ipatov, J. Li, C. Lisse, N. Mastrodemos, S.
                   McLaughlin, J. Sunshine, P. Thomas, and D. Wellnitz, Deep Impact Instrument
                   Calibration, Rev. Sci. Instrum., 79, 091301, 2008, doi:10.1063/1.2972112.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2006</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Klaasen, K.P., M. A&apos;Hearn, S. Besse, D. Bodewits, B. Carcich, T. Farnham, L.
                   Feaga, O. Groussin, D. Hampton, M. Huisjen, M.S. Kelley, S. McLaughlin, F.
                   Merlin, S. Protopapa, J. Sunshine, P. Thomas, and D. Wellnitz, EPOXI Instrument
                   Calibration, Icarus, 225(1), 643-680, 2013, doi:10.1016/j.icarus.2013.03.024.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KLAASENETAL2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DIF-C-HRII-3/4-EPOXI-ISON-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>EPOXI C/ISON (2012 S1) - HRII CALIBRATED SPECTRA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2013-08-23</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2013-02-16T08:31:19.356Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2013-02-17T21:49:14.667Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>STEPHANIE MCLAUGHLIN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            McLaughlin, S.A., B. Carcich, S.E. Sackett, K.P. Klaasen, and L.
            Feaga, EPOXI C/ISON (2012 S1) - HRII CALIBRATED SPECTRA V1.0,
            DIF-C-HRII-3/4-EPOXI-ISON-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2014.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Calibrated 1.05- to 4.8-micron spectral images of comet C/ISON
            (2012 S1) acquired by the Deep Impact High Resolution Infrared
            Spectrometer on 16-17 February 2013 during the Cruise 3 phase of
            the EPOXI mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset contains calibrated, 1.05- to 4.8-micron spectral
            images of comet C/ISON (2012 S1) acquired by the High Resolution
            Infrared Spectrometer on 16-17 February 2013 during the Cruise 3
            phase of the EPOXI mission.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This dataset contains calibrated, 1.05- to 4.8-micron spectral images
    of comet C/ISON (2012 S1) acquired by the High Resolution Infrared
    Spectrometer on 16-17 February 2013 during the Cruise 3 phase
    of the EPOXI mission.
 
    While DI Flyby spacecraft (DIF) was officially in hibernation after
    the encounter with comet 103P/Hartley 2 in November 2010, it continued
    to carry out observations of comets from a distance as the opportunity
    arose.  One such observing program was carried out in 2013 on comet
    C/ISON (2012 S1) to monitor for outbursts.  The infrared spectra were
    obtained in a single observing sequence in the observing window (set
    by solar elongation as seen from the spacecraft) on 16-17 February
    2103, when the comet was approximately 4.75 AU from the Sun inbound,
    4.43 AU from the spacecraft, and at a phase angle of about 12.6
    degrees.  All observations consisted of spatial scans perpendicular to
    the length of the slit (in order to ensure that the comet was imaged,
    allowing for pointing uncertainties) consisting of 17 frames, obtained
    at a scan rate of 2 slit-widths per frame with an integration time of
    11 seconds per frame.  Each frame is a single, long-slit spectrum
    averaging over an effective area of 10x20 microradians. (The same
    scanning technique was used to observe comet C/Garradd (2009 P1) and
    is described in detail by Feaga, et al. (2014) [FEAGAETAL2014]).
    The sequence, which began at approximately 08:31 UTC on 16 February
    and continued for about 37.5 hours, consisted of 150 scans of 17
    binned full frames (512x256-pixels).  Visible-wavelength imaging was
    also obtained for context information during this observing session,
    but those data are archived separately.  See the &apos;Related Data Sets&apos;
    section below.
 
 
    Required Reading
    ---------------
      The documents listed below are essential for the understanding and
      interpretation of this dataset.  Although a copy of each document is
      provided in the DOCUMENT directory of this dataset, the most recent
      version is archived in the Deep Impact and EPOXI documentation set,
      DI-C-HRII/HRIV/MRI/ITS-6-DOC-SET-V4.0, available online at
      http://pds.nasa.gov.
 
      EPOXI_SIS.PDF
        - The Archive Volume and Data Product Software Interface
          Specifications document (SIS) describes the EPOXI datasets, the
          science data products, and defines keywords in the PDS labels.
 
      EPOXI_CAL_PIPELINE_SUMM.PDF
        - The EPOXI Calibration Pipeline Summary provides an overview
          of the final version of the calibration pipeline that processed
          the raw data products in this dataset.  For a thorough discussion
          of the pipeline, see &apos;EPOXI Instrument Calibration&apos; by Klaasen,
          et al. (2013) [KLAASENETAL2011].
 
      INSTRUMENTS_HAMPTON.PDF
        - The Deep Impact instruments paper by Hampton, et al. (2005)
          [HAMPTONETAL2005] provides very detailed descriptions of the
          instruments.
 
      HRII_3_4_EPOXI_ISON.TAB
        - This ASCII table provides image parameters such as the mid-obs
          Julian date, exposure time, image mode, mission activity type, and
          description or purpose for each observation (i.e., data product)
          in this dataset.  This file is very useful for determining which
          data files to work with.
 
 
    Related Data Sets
    -----------------
      The following PDS datasets are related to this one and may be useful
      for research:
 
      DIF-C-HRII-2-EPOXI-ISON-V1.0
        - Raw HRII infrared spectral images of comet ISON
 
      DIF-C-MRI-2-EPOXI-ISON-V1.0
      DIF-C-MRI-3/4-EPOXI-ISON-V1.0
        - Raw and calibrated MRI medium-resolution CCD images comet ISON,
          including context images for the IR scans
 
      DIF-C/E/X-SPICE-6-V1.0
        - EPOXI SPICE kernels
 
      DIF-CAL-HRII/HRIV/MRI-6-EPOXI-TEMPS-V3.0
        - HRII, HRIV, and MRI instrument thermal telemetry data for EPOXI
          which may be useful for determining how temperature fluctuations
          affect the science instruments, in particular the IR spectrometer.
          N.B. The pipeline does not use these thermal data to calibrate
          IR spectra of the target.  Instead it uses instrument temperatures
          recorded in the FITS headers.
 
      DI-C-HRII/HRIV/MRI/ITS-6-DOC-SET-V4.0
        - Deep Impact and EPOXI documentation set
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The calibrated two-dimensional (wavelength and spatial/along-slit) FITS
    spectral images and PDS labels in this dataset were generated by the
    Deep Impact/EPOXI calibration pipeline, maintained by the project&apos;s
    Science Data Center (SDC) at Cornell University.  The final version of
    the pipeline for HRII processing, dated January 2013, was used.  Known
    limitations and deficiencies of the pipeline and the resulting data are
    discussed in the EPOXI Calibration Pipeline Summary document in this
    dataset and by Klaasen, et al. (2013) [KLAASENETAL2011].
 
    For HRII spectra, the pipeline generates two types of calibrated
    products:
 
      - Uncleaned radiance data provided in units of
        Watts/(meter**2 steradian micron) and identified by the mnemonic
        &apos;RADREV&apos;.  The RADREV data are considered to be reversible
        because the calibration steps can be backed out to return to the
        original, raw data numbers.
 
      - Irreversibly cleaned radiance data provided in units of
        Watts/(meter**2 steradian micron) and identified by the mnemonic
        &apos;RAD&apos;.  The RAD data are considered to be irreversible because
        the calibration steps, such as smoothing over bad pixels, cannot
        easily be backed out to return to the original, raw data
        numbers.
 
    The calibration pipeline performed the following processes, in the
    order listed, on the raw HRII FITS data to produce the RADREV and
    RAD products found in this dataset (the pipeline uses the image
    mode to select the appropriate set of calibration files):
 
      - Calibration of temperatures and voltages in the FITS header
      - Per-pixel linearization of raw data numbers
      - Subtraction of dark noise, derived for per-pixel linearization
        (the prisms/spectral imaging module  and IR focal plane array
        temperatures, OPTBENT and IRFPAT in the FITS header, are used
        for scaling if dark modeling is required)
      - Division by a flat field, derived for per-pixel linearization
      - Determine spectral registration and bandwidth for each pixel
        (using OPTBENT from FITS headers)
      - Conversion of data numbers to units of radiance for an absolute,
        radiometric calibration that is reversible (RADREV) and that was
        derived for per-quadrant linearization
      - Interpolation over bad and missing pixels identified in the
        RADREV data to make a partially cleaned, irreversible, radiometric
        calibration with units of radiance (RAD);  Steps for despiking
        (i.e., cosmic ray removal) and denoising the data which are part
        of the RAD stream were not performed because the existing routines
        are not robust.
      - Set non-image pixels at the left, right, and bottom edges to zero in
        the RADREV and RAD products.  The &apos;real data&apos; window of an image
        is given by CALWINDW in the FITS header.  If edge pixels need to be
        analyzed, the original DN values can be found in the raw products
        located in the PDS dataset, DIF-C-HRII-2-EPOXI-ISON-V1.0.
 
    As part of the calibration process, the pipeline updated the per-pixel
    image quality map, the first FITS extension, to identify:
 
      - Pixels where the raw value was saturated,
      - Pixels where the analog-to-digital converter was saturated,
      - Pixels that were ultra-compressed and thus contain very little
        information, and
      - Pixels considered to be anomalous as indicated by bad pixel
        maps derived for per-pixel linearity (missing pixels were
        identified when the raw FITS files were created).
 
    The pipeline also created FITS image extensions for a spectral
    registration (wavelength) map, a spectral resolution (bandwidth) map,
    and a signal-to-noise ratio map, which are briefly described in the
    next section.  The calibration steps and files applied to each raw
    image are listed in the PROCESSING_HISTORY_TEXT keyword in the PDS
    data label.
 
 
  Data
  ====
 
    FITS Images and PDS Labels
    --------------------------
      Each calibrated spectral image is stored as FITS.  The primary
      data unit contains the two-dimensional spectral image, with the
      fastest varying axis corresponding to increasing wavelengths from
      about 1.05 to 4.8 microns and the slowest varying axis corresponding
      to the spatial or along-slit dimension.  The primary image is
      followed by four image extensions that are two-dimensional
      pixel-by-pixel maps providing additional information about the
      spectral image:
 
        - The first extension uses one byte consisting of eight,
          single-bit flags to describe the quality of each pixel
          in the primary image.  The PDS data label defines the
          purpose of each single-bit flag.
 
        - The second extension provides the spectral registration or
          wavelength for each pixel in the primary image.  This
          extension is required because the wavelength for each
          pixel changes as the temperature of the instrument
          increased or decreased.
 
        - The third extension provides the spectral bandwidth for
          each pixel in the primary image.  This extension is
          required because the bandwidth for each pixel changes as
          the temperature of the instrument increased or decreased.
 
        - The fourth extension provides a signal-to-noise ratio for
          each pixel in the primary image.
 
      Each FITS file is accompanied by a detached PDS data label.  The
      EPOXI SIS document provides definitions for the keywords found in
      a data label and provides more information about the FITS primary
      image and the extensions.  Many values in a data label were
      extracted from FITS image header keywords which are defined in the
      document EPOXI_FITS_KEYWORD_DESC.ASC found in the Deep Impact and
      EPOXI documentation dataset, DI-C-HRII/HRIV/MRI/ITS-6-DOC-SET-V4.0.
 
 
    File Naming Convention
    ----------------------
      The naming convention for calibrated data labels and FITS files is
      HIyymmddhh_eeeeeee_nnn_rr.LBL or FIT where &apos;HI&apos; identifies the HRII
      instrument, yymmddhh provides the UTC year, month, day, and hour at
      the mid-point of the observation, eeeeeee is the exposure ID
      (OBSERVATION_ID in data labels), nnn provides the image number
      (IMAGE_NUMBER in the data labels) within the exposure ID, and
      rr identifies the type of reduction:
 
        RR for RADREV data (reversibly calibrated, radiance units)
        R  for RAD data (partially cleaned RADREV data, radiance units)
 
      Up to 999 individual images can be commanded for one exposure ID.
      For a spectral scan, many frames are acquired for one specific
      exposure. Therefore, nnn in the file name provides the sequentially
      increasing frame number within an exposure ID and corresponds to
      IMAGE_NUMBER in the data labels.  For example, if 17 frames were
      commanded for a scan with an exposure ID of 4000001, the first FITS
      file name would be HI13021608_4000001_001_RR.FIT and the last would
      be HI13021608_4000001_017_RR.FIT.
 
 
    Image Compression
    -----------------
      All data products in this dataset are uncompressed.  Specifically
      all raw spectral images, from which these data products are derived,
      were never compressed on board the spacecraft.
 
 
    Image Orientation
    -----------------
      A true-sky &apos;as seen by the observer&apos; view is achieved by displaying
      the image using the standard FITS convention:  the fastest-varying
      axis (samples or wavelength) increasing to the right in the display
      window and the slowest-varying axis (lines or spatial/along-slit)
      increasing to the top.  This convention is identified in the data
      labels:  the SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION keyword is set to RIGHT and
      LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION to UP.
 
      The direction to celestial north, ecliptic north, and the Sun is
      provided in data labels by CELESTIAL_NORTH_CLOCK_ANGLE,
      ECLIPTIC_NORTH_CLOCK_ANGLE, and SUN_DIRECTION_CLOCK_ANGLE keywords
      and are measured clockwise from the top of the image when it is
      displayed in the correct orientation as defined by
      SAMPLE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION and LINE_DISPLAY_DIRECTION.  Please note
      the aspect of the North celestial pole in an image can be computed
      by adding 90 degrees to the boresight declination given by
      DECLINATION in the data labels.
 
      For a comparison of the orientation FITS image data from the three
      science instruments, see the quadrant nomenclature section of the
      the EPOXI SIS document.
 
 
    Spectral Scans
    --------------
      Each HRII scan in this dataset consists of multiple frames within
      one exposure ID (OBSERVATION_ID in the data labels).  To work with
      these spectral scans, it is recommended that all frames for one
      exposure ID be stacked into a three-dimensional cube.  Then, a
      spatial-spatial map can be produced for a specific wavelength by
      selecting the appropriate spectral column from the image cube.
      Spectral wavelengths are provided by the second FITS extension,
      the spectral registration (wavelength) map.
 
 
    IR Slit Location
    ----------------
      For a comparison of the relative locations of the IR slit with
      respect to the fields of view of the Medium Resolution Instrument
      Visible CCD (MRI) and the High Resolution Instrument Visible CCD
      (HRIV), see the instrument alignment section of the EPOXI SIS
      document or Klaasen, et al. (2013) [KLAASENETAL2011].
 
      In many cases, nearly simultaneous MRI images, located in the
      dataset DIF-C-MRI-2-EPOXI-ISON-V1.0, were acquired with
      each IR scan and should provide field of view context for the
      slit location.
 
 
    Timing for Spectra
    ------------------
      It is important to note that the readout order of the IR detector
      affects the timing of the spectra.  When a HRII spectral image is
      displayed using the true-sky convention, the wavelength increases
      horizontally to the right and the spatial or along-slit direction is
      vertical.  In this orientation, the IR detector was read out from the
      left and right edges and toward the center and starting with the
      first row at the bottom and ending with the last row at the top of
      the display.  Since the detector is reset and read out on a
      pixel-by-pixel basis, the read out order affects the time at which
      each pixel is exposed although each pixel has the same exposure
      duration -- except for the ALTFF mode that has different read and
      reset causing the effective exposure time to vary with line number,
      i.e., along the slit in the spatial direction.  Additionally, the end
      of the spectrometer slit that always points roughly towards the sun
      is the first line to be readout and the last line to be read out is
      furthest from the sun, assuming the spacecraft is in its usual
      orientation with the solar panels pointing roughly toward the sun.
      For more information about the timing of the spectra, see the zero
      exposure background section of the EPOXI instrument calibration paper
      by Klaasen, et al. (2013) [KLAASENETAL2011].
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
 
    Data Units
    ----------
      The calibrated RADREV and RAD spectral image data have units of
      radiance, W/(m**2 steradian micron).
 
 
    Imaging Modes
    -------------
      One mode was used for all images in this dataset:
 
                    X-Size  Y-Size  Bin
        Mode Name   (pix)   (pix)  Type  Comments
        ---- ------ ------  -----  ----- -------------------
          1  BINFF    512     256   2x2  Binned full frame
 
      In the table above, X-Size is the spectral dimension and Y-Size is
      the spatial dimension along the slit.  For more information see
      Hampton, et al. (2005) [HAMPTONETAL2005], Klaasen, et al. (2008)
      [KLAASENETAL2006] and Klaasen, et al. (2013) [KLAASENETAL2011].
 
 
    Time- and Geometry-Related Keywords
    -----------------------------------
      All time-related keywords in the data labels, except
      EARTH_OBSERVER_MID_TIME, are based on the clock on board the flyby
      spacecraft.  EARTH_OBSERVER_MID_TIME provides the UTC when an
      Earth-based observer should have been able to see an event recorded
      by the instrument.
 
      The SDC pipeline was not able to automatically determine the proper
      geometric information for the target of choice in some cases.  When
      these parameters could not be computed, the corresponding keywords
      in the data labels are set to a value of unknown, &apos;UNK&apos;.  Also if
      GEOMETRY_QUALITY_FLAG is set to &apos;BAD&apos; or GEOMETRY_TYPE is set to
      &apos;PREDICTED&apos; in the PDS labels, then this indicates the geometry
      values may not be accurate and should be used with caution.  The
      value &apos;N/A&apos; is used for some geometry-related keywords in the data
      labels because these parameters are not applicable.
 
      Observational geometry parameters provided in the data labels were
      computed at the epoch specified by the mid-obs UTC, IMAGE_MID_TIME,
      in the data labels.  The exceptions are the target-to-sun values
      evaluated at the time light left the target that reached the
      spacecraft at mid-obs time, and the earth-observer-to-target values
      evaluated at the time the light that left the target, which reached
      the spacecraft at mid-obs time, reached Earth.
 
      Since the pole of comet ISON is not well known, the pipeline
      used the default SPICE kernel, ISON_0000.TPC, which specifies
      a non-rotating body with the positive pole aligned with EMEJ2000.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    The timing and geometric parameters included in the data labels and
    FITS headers were computed using the best available SPICE kernels at
    the time the data products were generated.  Most kernels are available
    in the EPOXI SPICE dataset, DIF-C/E/X-SPICE-6-V1.0; others that had
    not yet been archived in the PDS when this dataset was produced are
    available online at the Operational Flight Project Kernels website
    maintained by the NASA Navigation and Ancillary Information Facility
    (NAIF), http://naif.jpl.nasa.gov/naif/data_operational.html.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    Earth Mean Equator and Vernal Equinox of J2000 (EME J2000) is the
    inertial reference system used to specify observational geometry
    parameters in the data labels.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The observations in this dataset are in standard FITS format with PDS
    labels, and can be viewed by a number of PDS-provided and commercial
    programs.  For this reason no special software is provided with this
    dataset.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The data files in this dataset were reviewed internally by the EPOXI
    project.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    This dataset was peer reviewed and certified for scientific use on
    21 March 2014.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    There are no unexpected gaps in this dataset.  All observations
    received on the ground were processed and included in this dataset.
 
    Any horizontal striping through some images indicates missing data.
    The image quality map extension identifies where pixels are missing.
    If the second most-significant bit of a pixel in the image quality map
    is turned on, then data for the corresponding image pixel is missing.
    For more information, refer to the EPOXI SIS document.  Additionally,
    any missing pixels in a frame (within an exposure ID) that is used as
    the in-scene dark will contaminate the calibrated observations of the
    same exposure ID, and those contaminated pixels will not be identified
    as missing in the image quality map extension but will appear as
    horizontal stripes in the calibrated spectra.
 
   Transient anomalous pixels may be present in the data.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
 
    Timing
    ------
      The EPOXI project plans to generate a complete and highly accurate
      set of UTC correlations since launch.  This will ultimately result
      in a future version of a SCLK kernel that will retroactively change
      correlation for **all** Deep Impact and EPOXI data.  When this
      kernel is available, it will be added to the SPICE datasets for
      the two missions and posted on the NAIF/SPICE web site at
      http://naif.jpl.nasa.gov/naif/.
 
 
    Predict Geometry
    ----------------
      Many ISON frames have predicted geometry because the observation
      times fell within gaps of the relevant reconstructed pointing kernel,
      DIF_SC_110301_130627_V2.BC.
 
 
    HRI Telescope Focus
    -------------------
      Images of stars acquired early during the Deep Impact mission in 2005
      indicated the HRI telescope was out of focus.  However, this focus
      problem does not significantly affect the HRII instrument.  For more
      details please see the Deep Impact instrument calibration paper by
      Klaasen, et al. (2008) [KLAASENETAL2006].
 
 
    Displaying Images
    -----------------
      Flight software writes an image header over the first 100 bytes of
      quadrant A.  These image header pixels are included in the calibrated
      FITS images.  Since the values in these pixels vary dramatically,
      it is recommended that the values of the EPOXI:MINIMUM and EPOXI:MAXIMUM
      keywords in the data label (or the MINPVAL and MAXPVAL in the FITS
      header) be used to scale an image for display because these values
      exclude the header bytes as well as the reference rows and columns
      located at the edges of the image.  For more information, see the
      quadrant nomenclature section of the EPOXI SIS document.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

