<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-hie-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESS MDIS MAP PROJ HIGH-INCIDENCE BASEMAP EAST RDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mdis-nac.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-hie-v1.0__browserp_mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-hie-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-hie-v1.0__browser_geo_mercury_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-hie-v1.0__browser_mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-hie-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-hie-v1.0__dvo_imaging_mess-h-mdis-5-rdr-hie-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Becker, K.J., M.S. Robinson, T.L. Becker, L.A. Weller, K.L. Edmonson, G.A.
                   Neumann, M.E. Perry, S.C. Solomon, First digital elevation model of Mercury,
                   47th Lunar and Planetary Science Conference, abstract #2949, 2016.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BECKERETAL2016</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Domingue, D.L., B.W. Denevi, S.L. Murchie, and C.D. Hash, Application of
                   multiple photometric models to disk-resolved measurements of Mercury&apos;s surface:
                   insights into Mercury&apos;s regolith characteristics, Icarus, 268, 172-203, 2016
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DOMINGUEETAL2016</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hapke, B., Theory of Reflectance Spectroscopy (Topics in Remote Sensing, 3),
                   Cambridge University Press, 272, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAPKE1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hawkins, S.E., III, J. Boldt, E.H. Darlington, R. Espiritu, R.E. Gold, B.
                   Gotwols, M. Grey, C. Hash, J. Hayes, S. Jaskulek, C. Kardian, M. Keller, E.
                   Malaret, S.L. Murchie, P. Murphy, K. Peacock, L. Prockter, A. Reiter, M.S.
                   Robinson, E. Schaefer, R. Shelton, R. Sterner, H. Taylor, T. Watters, and B.
                   Williams, The Mercury Dual Imaging System on the MESSENGER spacecraft, Space
                   Science Reviews, 131, 247-338, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAWKINSETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hawkins, S.E., III, S.L. Murchie, K.J. Becker, C.M. Selby, F.S. Turner, M.W.
                   Noble, N.L. Chabot, T.H. Choo, E.H. Darlington, B.W. Denevi, D.L. Domingue,
                   C.M. Ernst, G.M. Holsclaw, N.R. Laslo, W.E. McClintock, L.M. Prockter, M.S.
                   Robinson, S.C. Solomon, and R.E. Sterner, II, In-flight performance of
                   MESSENGER&apos;s Mercury Dual Imaging System, Proceedings of the SPIE, Volume 7441,
                   pp. 74410Z-74410Z-12, 2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAWKINSETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-H-MDIS-5-RDR-HIE-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESS MDIS MAP PROJ HIGH-INCIDENCE BASEMAP EAST RDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-05-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-08-19T18:01:23Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-04-30T11:07:43Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>CHRISTOPHER HASH</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            C. Hash, MESS MDIS MAP PROJ HIGH-INCIDENCE BASEMAP EAST RDR V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 2015
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            High solar incidence angle basemap illuminated from the east
            reduced data records for the MDIS camera system on MESSENGER.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== The Mercury Dual Imaging System (MDIS) consists
            of two cameras, a Wide Angle Camera (WAC) and a Narrow Angle
            Camera (NAC), mounted on a common pivot platform. This dataset
            includes Map Projected High- Incidence Angle Basemap Illuminated
            from the East RDRs (HIEs) which comprise a global map of I/F
            measured by the NAC or WAC filter 7 (both centered near 750 nm)
            during the the Extended Mission at high incidence angles to
            accentuate subtle topography, photometrically normalized to a
            solar incidence angle (i) = 30 degrees, emission angle (e) = 0
            degrees, and phase angle (g) = 30 degrees at a spatial sampling
            of 256 pixels per degree. The HIE data set is a companion to the
            Map Projected High-Incidence Angle Basemap Illluminated from the
            West RDR (HIW) data set. Together the two data sets are intended
            to detect and allow the mapping of subtle topography. They
            complement a Basemap Data Record (BDR) data set also composed of
            WAC filter 7 and NAC images acquired at moderate/high solar
            incidence angles centered near 68 degrees (changed to 74 degrees
            in the final end-of-mission data delivery), and a Low Incidence
            Angle (LOI) data set also composed of WAC filter 7 and NAC images
            acquired at lower incidence centered near 45 degrees, analogous
            to the geometry used for color imaging. The map is divided into
            54 &apos;tiles&apos;, each representing the NW, NE, SW, or SE
            quadrant of one of the 13 non-polar or one of the 2 polar
            quadrangles or &apos;Mercury charts&apos; already defined by the
            USGS. Each tile also contains 5 backplanes: observation ID; BDR
            metric, a metric used to determine the stacking order of
            component images, modified for the higher incidence angle
            centered near 78 degrees; solar incidence angle; emission angle;
            and phase angle.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      A major imaging campaign for MDIS in MESSENGER&apos;s primary mission
      was acquisition of a global data set at low emission angles for
      cartographic purposes, and moderate to high incidence angles that
      highlight topography. Those images were mosaicked into basemap
      data records (BDRs). The HIE data set is complementary in that it
      highlights low-relief topography that is less evident. The
      illumination from the east favors asymmetric topography more
      steeply sloped to the east than to the west. The companion
      HIW data set favors asymmetric topography more steeply sloped
      to that west than to the east.
 
      Map tiles are named based on the quadrant of the Mercury chart they
      span:
 
      MDIS_ppp_rrrPPD_Hxxddv.IMG
 
      where:
 
        ppp = product type = HIE
        rrr = resolution in pixels/degree (PPD)
        Hxx = Mercury chart designation
        dd = quadrant within Mercury chart (NW, NE, SW, or SE), or a
           polar chart (NP, SP)e limits
        v = version number
 
 
      The following is an example file name with a description of the
      individual components:
 
      MDIS_HIE_256PPD_H03NE0.IMG
 
      For this image:
        Product type = HIE (HIE)
        Resolution = 256 pixels/degree (256PPD)
        Mercury chart = Shakespeare (H03)
        Quadrant = Northeast (NE)
        Version = 0
 
      The HIE directory, present in the HIE archive volume, contains
      MDIS Map Projected High Incidence Angle Basemap Illuminated from
      the East Reduced Data Records (HIEs). The HIEs are organized
      into subdirectories based on the Mercury Chart containing the
      HIE.  Latitude and longitude limits of Mercury Charts,
      as named at the end of mission delivery, are:
 
      Quadrangle         Subdirectory   Lat. (degrees)  Long. (deg. east)
      H-1 Borealis       H01            65 to 90        0 to 360
      H-2 Victoria       H02            22.5 to 65      270 to 360
      H-3 Shakespeare    H03            22.5 to 65      180 to 270
      H-4 Raditladi      H04            22.5 to 65      90 to 180
      H-5 Hokusai        H05            22.5 to 65      0 to 90
      H-6 Kuiper         H06            -22.5 to 22.5   288 to 360
      H-7 Beethoven      H07            -22.5 to 22.5   216 to 288
      H-8 Tolstoj        H08            -22.5 to 22.5   144 to 216
      H-9 Eminescu       H09            -22.5 to 22.5   72 to 144
      H-10 Derain        H10            -22.5 to 22.5   0 to 72
      H-11 Discovery     H11            -65 to -22.5    270 to 360
      H-12 Michelangelo  H12            -65 to -22.5    180 to 270
      H-13 Neruda        H13            -65 to -22.5    90 to 180
      H-14 Debussey      H14            -65 to -22.5    0 to 90
      H-15 Bach          H15            -90 to -65      0 to 360
 
      An HIE:
      - Consists of map-projected photometrically normalized I/F CDRs
        mosaicked into a basemap map tile;
      - Contains image data in I/F corrected photometrically to i=30
        degrees, e=0 at a resolution of 256 pixels per degree (~166 m/pixel
        at the equator);
      - Represents one latitude-longitude bin in a global map;
      - Is composed of images acquired with by the NAC or by the WAC in
        filter 7, both centered near 750 nm;
      - Contains images acquired as part of the high-incidence angle
        basemap campaign for which SUBSOLAR_LONGITUDE is located east
        of the images&apos;s CENTER_LONGITUDE; and
      - Contains 5 backplanes:
        (a) observation id, (b) BDR metric, modified for the optimal
        incidence angle to be 78 degrees, (c) solar incidence angle,
        (d) emission angle, and (e) phase angle.
 
 
    Versions
    ========
 
      Version numbers of HIEs increment on reprocessing or addition of
      new data.  Polar tiles are in polar stereographic projections, other
      tiles in equirectangular projection.
 
      Version 0 is uncontrolled, projected onto an ellipsoidal model of
      Mercury, and photometrically corrected using a Hapke photometric
      model with parameters optimized to higher solar incidence angles
      (and different from parameters used in map products containing
      lower-incidence angle data). Version 1, released at end of mission,
      is compiled using NAC or WAC 750-nm images from any campaign that
      best fit the intended illumination geometry, i.e., low emission angle
      and incidence angle near 78 degrees. It is controlled and projected
      onto a global digital elevation model. It uses a Kasseleinin-Shkuratov
      photometric correction, whose parameters are the same for any given
      wavelength band across all MESSENGER end-of-mission map data products.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      MDIS observing variable pertaining to the HIEs are as follows.
 
      Pixel Binning: Some HIE images are unbinned and 1024x1024 pixels.
      Some images are 2x2 pixel binned in the focal plane hardware
      (also known as &apos;on-chip&apos; binning), resulting in 512 x 512
      images. The WAC was used to acquire HIE images from lower
      altitudes, and the NAC was used at higher altitudes. Within
      the altitude range for either camera, on-chip binning was used
      within the lower portion of the range, to control data volume and
      to manage data flow on the spacecraft. No further binning by the
      spacecraft main processor (MP) was used.
 
      12-8 bit compression: Images are read off the detector in 12-bit
      format. 12 bit images may converted to 8 bit images using one of
      eight lookup tables (LUTs). All images collected as part of
      the HIE basemap have been converted to 8 bits.
 
      FAST/DPCM compression: All images are compressed losslessly using
      FAST/DCPM compression as they are read out of the DPU, to conserve
      recorder space. Once the data are written to the recorder, they can
      be uncompressed and recompressed more aggressively in the MP.
 
      Wavelet compression: Images may be integer wavelet transform-
      compressed in the MP, typically at 3:1 for color data and 4:1 for
      monochrome data, but any value from 1 to 32 can be used. The initial
      configuration in Mercury orbit was to perform 12 to 8 bit conversion
      using LUT0 for the WAC and LUT2 for the NAC, with a wavelet
      compression ratio of 8:1 for monochrome imaging and 4:1 for color
      imaging. Initial images exhibited unexpectedly visible compression
      artifacts. Beginning 19 April 2011, LUT0 and LUT2 were replaced
      with LUT1 which better preserves image dynamic range, and
      compression ratios were decreased to 4:1 or less for monochrome
      data and 3:1 or less for color data where possible. Lossless
      compression was used when downlink allowed.
 
      Exposure Control: The exposure time of MDIS images can be set
      manually by command, or automatically by the software. In manual
      mode, exposure times from 1-989, 1001-1989, ..., to 9001-9989 ms
      are available. In autoexposure mode the exposure time of the next
      image is computed by the DPU software, and cannot exceed 989 ms
      in duration. If the time of the next image occurs before the
      calculation can be completed, and pixel binning or filter
      position change, then the algorithm compensates for predicted
      changes in scene brightness and filter transmission using an
      onboard data structure. All images in HIEs were acquired using
      automatic exposure.
 
      Pointing: The MDIS imagers are mounted on a pivot platform, which
      is itself mounted to the MESSENGER spacecraft deck. The pivot
      platform is controlled by a stepper motor, which is controlled by
      the Data Processing Unit (DPU). The pivot platform can move in
      either direction. The total range of motion is 240 degrees, limited
      by mechanical &apos;hard&apos; stops, and is further constrained by &apos;soft&apos;
      stops applied by the software. The nominal pointing position for
      MDIS is defined as 0 degrees, aligned with the spacecraft +Z axis
      and the boresight for several other instruments. The range of the
      soft stops is set to 40 degrees in the spacecraft -Y direction
      (toward the MESSENGER sunshade) and +50 degrees in the +Y direction
      (away from the sunshade). The pivot position can be commanded in
      intervals of 0.01 degrees within this range. During acquisition of
      the HIE basemap, the pivot was used to point the WAC or NAC
      to low emission angles on the surface, at times when the solar
      incidence angle was close as possible to 78 degrees.
 
      Filter selection: The WAC imager contains a 12 position filter
      wheel to provide spectral imaging over the spectral range of the
      CCD detector. WAC filter 7 (750 BP 5) was chosen to complement the
      NAC because its bandpass within that of the NAC lessens any
      discontinuities that might result from regional variations in
      spectral slope.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      A sequence of processing creates an HIE from CDRs and DDRs. A Derived
      Data Record (DDR) consists of multiband images whose line and sample
      dimensions and coordinates correspond one-for-one with those of a
      CDR. It has 5 bands of data used to help create an HIE, including for
      every image pixel: (a) latitude, (b) longitude, (c) incidence angle,
      (d) emission angle, and (e) phase angle. The DDRs are an intermediate
      product used to create HIEs and other map products, are defined as a
      distinct data product in the MDIS CDR/RDR Software Interface
      Specification, and are delivered to the PDS beginning with
      delivery 11.
 
      The sequence of processing is as follows:
 
    (a) Experiment Data Records (EDRs) are assembled from raw data.
    (b) Radiance images are created from the EDRs and calibration files.
    (c) Radiance is converted to I/F CDRs by dividing by (pi * solar flux
        at 1 AU / heliocentricdistance_in_AU^2).
    (d) I/F is photometrically corrected to i = 30 degrees, e = 0 degrees.
    (e) Gimbal positions are extracted from the spacecraft housekeeping
        and formatted as a gimbal C kernel.
    (f) Using the gimbal C kernel and other SPICE kernels, DDRs are
        created. The surface intercept on a sphere of Mercury&apos;s radius
        is calculated for each spatial pixel. The angles of this pixel
        relative to the equatorial plane and reference longitude constitute
        the latitude and longitude of the pixel. For that latitude and
        longitude, solar incidence, emission, and phase angles are
        determined.
    (g) I/F corrected to i = 30 degrees, e = 0 degrees is map projected
        into HIEs using the latitude and longitude information
        in the DDRs. The same procedure is used on DDRs to assemble the
        backplanes with derived information. They are appended to the
        image band in the following order:
          OBSERVATION_ID
          BDR metric
          Solar Incidence Angle
          Emission Angle
          Phase Angle
        where OBSERVATION_ID is taken from the CDR label, the
        ordinal number of the image among all MDIS images taken
        post-launch, and the photometric angles are taken from the DDR.
 
      The BDR metric or stacking order (&apos;which image is on top&apos;) was first
      defined for BDRs. For HIEs, the objective is to have &apos;on top&apos; those
      images with high spatial resolution, low emission angle, and a solar
      incidence angle as close as possible to 78 degrees. This incidence
      angle was chosen to highlight subtle topographic shading.
      For version 0 HIEs, any image taken as part of the high
      incidence angle campaign is a candidate to include. For
      version 1 HIEs, images from any campaign with suitable
      illumination can be included within the following criteria:
 
      - Controlled images are primarily used, but non-controlled images are
        used as needed to minimize gaps in coverage
      - Incidence angle at the center of the images is &lt; 90 degrees
      - The north polar tile (H01) trims pixels with incidence angle
        &gt; 88 degrees
      - The south polar tile (H15) trims pixels with incidence angle
        &gt; 89.5 degrees
      - The image pixel scale &gt; 100 m/pixel
 
      The stacking order is determined at the camera boresight using a
      metric that represents spatial resolution and image geometry;
      lowest values represent the &apos;best&apos; image. The &apos;worst&apos; complete, map-
      projected image with the highest value for the metric is laid into
      the HIE first; then the complete image with the second-highest value
      is laid in second, overwriting the first image where the coverage
      coincides, and so on until the complete &apos;best&apos; image with the lowest
      value for the metric is on top. There are 3 expressions for the
      modified BDR metric depending on latitude greater or less than
      65 degrees and solar incidence angle greater or less than 78 degrees.
 
      (a) Where abs(lat) &lt;= 65 degrees and i =&gt; 78 degrees, the metric is:
 
      PIXEL_SCALE / (cos e * ( cos ( flatten_factor * i)  /
        cos ( flatten_factor * 78 ) ) )
 
      where i is solar incidence angle, e is emission angle, lat is
      planetocentric latitude, and flatten_factor is set to 0.85 to
      de-emphasize low solar incidence angles.
 
      (b) Where abs(lat) &lt;= 65 degrees and i &lt; 78 degrees, the metric is:
 
      PIXEL_SCALE / (cos e * (cos 78 / cos i))
 
      (c) Where abs(lat) &gt; 65 degrees, the metric is:
 
      PIXEL_SCALE / (cos i * cos e )
 
      where i is solar incidence angle, e is emission angle.
 
      In each case, the value of PIXEL_SCALE is limited not to be below
      approximately 166 meters so that unfavorably illuminated images with
      high spatial resolutions not captured at the resolution of an HIE
      do not overwrite more favorably illuminated images.
 
      In version 0 HIEs, the photometric correction applied to MDIS WAC
      G filter and NAC images to create HIEs is based on bi-directional
      reflectance equations formulated by [HAPKE1993]. The general
      equation for I/F is given by:
 
      I/F=(w/4)[mu_not&apos;/(mu&apos; +mu_not&apos;)]{[1+B(g)]P(g)-
          1+H(mu_not&apos;)H(mu&apos;)}S(i,e,g,theta)
 
      where w is single scattering albedo, i is incidence angle, e is
      emission angle, g is phase angle, p(g) is the single particle
      scattering function, theta is a parameter representing
      macroscopic roughness, and mu_not&apos; and mu&apos; are modified versions
      of the cosines of the incidence and emission angle that take
      into account effects of theta. H(mu_not&apos;) and H(mu&apos;) describe
      approximations to the Chandrasehkar H-functions. The surface
      roughness function, S(i,e,g,theta), modifies the radiative
      transfer equation to account for surface roughness.
 
      In addition, a Henyey-Greenstein function is used to describe
      the single particle scattering function p(g). The form of the
      Henyey-Greenstein function used corresponds to the form
      utilized in the USGS ISIS software, and is given by:
 
      p(g)=c(1-b^2)(1-2b cos(g)+b^2)^(-3/2) + (1-c)(1-b^2)(1+2b
      cos(g)+b^2)^(-3/2),
 
      where g is the phase angle, b is the scattering amplitude
      parameter, and c is the partition parameter between forward and
      backward scattering.
 
      In version 0 HIEs, no single set of Hapke parameters was found that
      yields close matches for corrected I/F across boundaries of images
      taken at different photometric geometries, for both the 3- and 8-color
      maps taken predominantly at low solar incidence angles (average,
      about 45 degrees) included in MDRs and MD3s, and monochrome maps
      taken predominantly at high solar incidence angles (BDRs, HIEs, HIWs).
      Therefore map products emphasizing low or high incidence angles
      initially used different sets of photometric parameters optimized
      for each to minimize seams between images.
 
      The parameters for the version 0 HIE Hapke photometric correction were
      derived by modeling data acquired from multiple regions between
      24 degrees and 46 degrees south latitude and 330 degrees and 353
      degrees east longitude. These regions sample incidence angle (i),
      emission angle(e), and phase angle (g) coverage commensurate
      with global mapping campaigns. In addition whole-disk
      Mercury images taken at a large number of geometries during
      the Mercury flybys expand the phase angle range.
      The photometric measurements were modeled using a least squares
      grid search routine over the available parameter space. The model
      parameter values were individually plotted as a function of wavelength
      over the MDIS filter central wavelength values. A polynomial trend was
      fit to each parameter as a function of wavelength. The polynomial
      trend value at each filter central wavelength was then used as the
      model parameter values for determining the photometric correction.
      The parameter values applicable to LOIs are given in the
      table below. Photometric behavior of Mercury in NAC images is assumed
      to be equivalent to that in the WAC G filter.
 
      WAC
      filter, wavelength,      w,           b,          c ,       theta
      G,      749  , 0.278080114, 0.227774899, 0.714203968, 17.76662946
 
      In version 1 HIEs delivered at the end of the mission, a different
      photometric correction is used, a Kasseleinen-Shkuratov function
      described by [DOMINGUEETAL2016]. The form of the function is
      given as:
 
      I/F = AN*exp[-(g*mu)]{c_sub_l[2cos i/(cos i + cos e)]+[1-c_sub_l]cos i}
 
      where AN is normal albedo at a given wavelength, and mu and c_sub_l
      are wavelength-dependent parameters whose values were fit in the
      same manner as the parameters for the Hapke model. The values are
      given in the table below:
 
      WAC
      filter, wavelength,      AN,       mu,    c_sub_l
      G,             749,  0.1111,   0.5628,     0.6424
 
    Data
    ====
      There is one data type associated with this volume, HIEs consisting
      of mosaicked, photometrically corrected WAC filter 7 (G filter)
      CDRs and NAC CDRs, appended with 5 backplanes describing the
      component CDRs and their photometric geometries as recorded in DDRs.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
 
      There is one type of ancillary data provided with this
      dataset:
 
      1. There may be a BROWSE directory containing browse images in
      PNG and/or GeoTIFF format. See BROWINFO.TXT in that directory
      for more details.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
 
      The cartographic coordinate system used for the MDIS data products
      conforms to the J2000 celestial reference frame for star imaging,
      and the IAU planetocentric system with East longitudes being
      positive for planetary surfaces.
 
      In version 0 HIEs, the IAU2000 reference system for cartographic
      coordinates and rotational elements was used for computing latitude
      and longitude coordinates of planets. However a Mercury radius of
      2440.0 km is used.
 
      In version 1 HIEs, the value for Mercury radius is updated to
      2439.4 km.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
 
      The MDIS archive is organized and stored in the directory
      structure described in the Mercury Dual Imaging System (MDIS)
      Calibrated Data Record (CDR) and Reduced Data Record (RDR)
      Software Interface Specification (SIS). The contents of the
      archive, along with fiduciary checksums, are compressed into
      a single &apos;zip archive&apos; file for transmittal to the PDS Imaging
      node.  The zip archive preserves the directory structure
      internally so that when it is decompressed the original
      directory structure is recreated at the PDS Imaging node.
      The zip archive is transmitted to the PDS Imaging node via
      FTP to the URL specified by the node for receiving it.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      Known issues of concern are described below.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was examined by a peer review panel
      prior to its acceptance by the Planetary Data System (PDS). The
      peer review was conducted in accordance with PDS procedures.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
 
      Only a subset of raw EDR data are calibrated to CDRs and then
      incorporated into HIE products. Briefly, the following criteria
      are met:
 
      (a) The data represent a scene and not the instrument test
      pattern, as indicated by data quality index (DQI) byte 0.
 
      (b) The exposure time is greater than zero (zero exposures
      occur in some images due to software features), as indicated
      by DQI byte 1.
 
      (c) Less than 20 percent of the image is saturated (empirically
      this is a threshold dividing wholly corrupted images from
      everything else).
 
      (d) The target of the image is MERCURY.
 
      (e) In version 0 HIEs, the image was taken as part of the
      monochrome basemap campaign. In version 1 HIEs, the image may be
      taken from a different campaign if the illumination geometry more
      closely approaches that desired for HIE data products.
 
      Version 0 HIEs are based on version 4 CDRs which correct a number
      of earlier calibration artifacts, and on version 0 DDRs. Version 1
      HIEs are based on version 5 CDRs and version 1 DDRs. For version 1
      HIEs, some component images may contain residuals from
      the following issues.
 
      (1) COMPRESSION ARTIFACTS. Images may be integer wavelet transform-
      compressed in the MP, typically at 3:1 for color data and 4:1 for
      monochrome data, but any value from 1 to 32 can be used. The initial
      configuration in Mercury orbit was to perform 12 to 8 bit conversion
      using LUT0 for the WAC and LUT2 for the NAC, with a wavelet
      compression ratio of 8:1 for monochrome imaging and 4:1 for color
      imaging. Initial images exhibited unexpectedly visible compression
      artifacts. Beginning 19 April 2011, LUT0 and LUT2 were replaced
      with LUT1 which better preserves image dynamic range, and
      compression ratios were decreased to 4:1 or less for monochrome
      data and 3:1 or less for color data where possible. Lossless
      compression was used when downlink allowed. Images that are
      part of HIE products typically were compressed 4:1 or losslessly.
 
      (2) RADIOMETRIC ACCURACY. The radiometric calibration of the
      WAC was updated several times over the mission to iteratively
      reduce residuals from 3 sources of error: (a) time-variable
      responsivity of the detector, (b) residuals in the flat-field
      correction, and (c) residuals in the correction to
      responsivity for detector temperature. For multispectral
      products, the residuals from time-variable responsivity
      initially led to distinct seams; correction of this artifact
      is treated in more detail below.
 
      In version 4 CDRs, an additional update to responsivity
      improved temperature dependence over the full operating range.
      The correction was derived empirically by fitting as a function
      of CCD temperature the median values of images acquired from
      Mercury orbit at a wide range of temperatures but a narrow
      range of photometric geometries. The flat field was updated
      empirically using the median of hundreds of photometrically
      corrected images of relatively bland field-filling images
      of Mercury.
 
      In version 5 CDRs, a new, final temperature correction used all
      Mercury images satisfying the illumination criteria. A new, final
      flat-field correction was derived similarly to the updated
      correction used in version 4, except using more images and
      a Kasseleinen-Shkuratov photometric correction
 
      (3) SCATTERED LIGHT. In the NAC, scattered light from out-of-field
      sources is an issue. The geometry contributing most of the scatter
      is 1-2 fields-of-view sunward of the NAC boresight. For a very
      large, evenly illuminated source that overfills the field-of-view
      by a factor of several, ray-trace studies supported by testing
      during Venus flyby 2 suggest that 2-7% of the radiance measured in
      the field-of-view will have come from out-of-field sources. The
      spatial pattern of the scatter is variable, due to diffuse
      reflections off the internal instrument housing.
 
      The WAC is subject to scattered light
      originating from within the field-of-view or just outside it. One
      source is multiple reflections off of 13 optical surfaces (2
      sides of each of 4 lenses, the spectral filter, and the CCD cover
      glass, as well as the CCD surface itself). The scatter becomes
      worse at longer wavelengths. Just off the limb of a large
      extended source near 1 field-of-view in size, like Venus or
      Mercury, measured radiance increases with wavelength from 2% to 7%
      of the value measured on the extended source. The value decreases
      with distance off the target more quickly at longer than at
      shorter wavelengths, but remains at 1% hundreds of pixels from
      the source. Conversely, light must be scattering from bright
      parts of an image to dark parts of an image. Averaged over
      sources tens of pixels in area, and away from abrupt brightness
      contrasts, scattered light affects shapes of spectra measured
      from WAC data at least at the 1-2% level, worse near brightness
      boundaries or for small, bright crater ejecta. The expected effect
      is enhanced brightness at &gt;650 nm in dark areas, and decreased
      brightness at &gt;650 nm in small bright areas.
 
      In the end-of-mission delivery 15, a forward model of the
      expected WAC scatter from a given scene was derived using
      optical design software modeling CCD structure and hardware,
      with magnitudes of scatter calibrated against flight measurements.
      The ray trace analysis reveal an in-scene component from light
      diffracted by the CCD and reflected by the CCD cover glass, and
      an out-of-scene component from light reflected off metallic
      surfaces alongside the CCD and back off the cover glass.
      These analyses suggest that scattered light is present in
      monochrome map products but in general is not an issue in
      morphologic interpretations. However caution is urged in using
      quantitative photometric analysis in high-contrast or shadowed
      terrain in these products.
 
      (4) TIME-VARIABLE WAC RESPONSIVITY. During Mercury orbit it was
      recognized that filter-dependent changes in WAC responsivity on
      the order of +/- 15% occurred over timescales as short as several
      days. Because those variations were not consistent from filter to
      filter, they led to spurious spectral features, which were
      particularly conspicuous near 750 nm. The cause(s) of these
      variations in responsivity are not known, but they could include
      transient radiation effects on the detector or electronics, aging
      of filters, periodic deposition and burn-off of contaminants on
      filters, or incorrect recording of exposure time. An initial
      empirical correction for images acquired in the first year of
      operations was developed and utilized in version 4 WAC CDRs used
      to create version 0 HIEs.
 
      For version 5 WAC CDRs in delivery 15 at end of mission, an
      updated correction covers the full duration of the orbital
      phase. Overlaps between color image sets in color mapping campaigns
      were used to derive a multiplicative correction factor for each
      filter and for each Earth day (2-3 orbits). Version 1 HIEs use
      CDRs with this updated correction. An analysis of overlap among
      individual images shows that residual differences (which include
      errors from calibration, scattered light, and possible incomplete
      correction of photometric variation) average &lt;2% for the majority
      of the planet.
 
      (5) UNCONTROLLED MOSAIC PROJECTED ONTO A SPHERE. Version 0 HIEs were
      constructed by uncontrolled mosaicking, projecting the image data
      onto a sphere. Systematic errors in spacecraft position and in
      knowledge of spacecraft and MDIS attitude, systematic errors in
      range to the surface due to ignoring topography, and systematic
      errors in latitude and longitude due projecting onto a sphere instead
      of a shape model will all contributed to mosaicking errors. In
      general these are expected to be under 1 km but locally might
      exceed 4 km.
 
      Version 1 HIEs were constructed from images controlled using
      c-smithed kernels and a global digital elevation model (DEM), both
      derived using a least-squares bundle adjustment of common
      features, measured as tie point coordinates in overlapping NAC and
      WAC-G filter images of Mercury at favorable solar incidence and
      emission angles. Empirically, misregistration errors between images
      decreased generally to the pixel scale of the map, (0.2 km) in
      most locations. Derivation of smithed kernels and the DEM for
      end of mission data products is described by [BECKERETAL2016].
 
      (6) INACCURACY IN THE PHOTOMETRIC CORRECTION. The Hapke correction
      applied to version 0 HIEs required the use of illumination-dependent
      parameters implying the possibility of systematic inaccuracy. As shown
      by [DOMGINUEETAL2016] the Kasseleinen-Shkuratov correction used in
      version 1 HIEs greatly reduced residuals between images acquired at
      different photometric geometries, implying reduced systematic errors.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      None
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

