<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.dawn-a-rss-5-vegr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>DAWN VESTA GRAVITY SCIENCE DERIVED SCIENCE DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.dawn_mission_to_vesta_and_ceres::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rss.dawn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.4_vesta::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.dawn-a-rss-5-vegr-v1.0__browserp_dawn-a-rss-5-vegr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Konopliv, A.S., S.W. Asmar, R.S. Park, B.G. Bills, F. Centinello, A.B.
                   Chamberlin, A. Ermakov, R.W. Gaskell, N. Rambaux, C.A. Raymond, C.T. Russell,
                   D.E. Smith, P. Tricarico, and M.T. Zuber, The Vesta gravity field, spin pole
                   and rotation period, landmark positions, and ephemeris from the Dawn tracking
                   and optical data, Icarus 240, 103-117, doi:10.1016/j.icarus.2013.09.005, 2014.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KONOPLIVETAL2014B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Moyer, T.D., Mathematical Formulation of the Double-Precision Orbit
                   Determination Program (DPODP), TR 32-1527, Jet Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena,
                   CA, 1971.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MOYER1971</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Russell, C.T., and C.A. Raymond, The Dawn Mission to Vesta and Ceres, Space
                   Science Reviews, 163, 3-23, 2011.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.RUSSELL-RAYMOND2011</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Thornton, C.L. and J.S. Border, Radiometric Tracking Techniques for Deep Space
                   Navigation, John Wiley and Sons, Hoboken, NY, 2003.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.THORNTON-BORDER2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tyler, G.L., G. Balmino, D.P. Hinson, W.L. Sjogren, D.E. Smith, R. Woo, S.W.
                   Asmar, M.J. Connally, C.L. Hamilton, and R.A. Simpson, Radio Science
                   Investigations with Mars Observer, Journal of Geophysical Research, 97,
                   7759-7779, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TYLERETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>DAWN-A-RSS-5-VEGR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>DAWN VESTA GRAVITY SCIENCE DERIVED SCIENCE DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2015-01-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2011-07-10</start_time>
        <stop_time>2012-09-05</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DUSTIN R. BUCCINO</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Konopliv, A.S., Park, R.S., Asmar, S.W., and Buccino, D.R., Dawn
            Vesta Derived Gravity Data, NASA Planetary Data System,
            DAWN-A-RSS-5-VEGR-V1.0, 2014.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Dawn Vesta reduced gravity data.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains archival results from gravity
            investigations conducted during the Dawn mission while the
            spacecraft was in orbit around the asteroid Vesta. Radio
            measurements were made using the Dawn spacecraft and Earth-based
            stations of the NASA Deep Space Network (DSN). The data set
            includes a spherical harmonic model of Vesta&apos;s gravity field
            generated by the Jet Propulsion Laboratory and radial gravity
            acceleration map; these results were derived from raw radio
            tracking data.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
    The Dawn Gravity Archive Data Collection of Science Data Products (SDP)
    includes data products generated from gravity investigations
    conducted by members of the Dawn Gravity Team while the spacecraft
    was in orbit around the asteroid Vesta.
 
    Gravity SDPs include spherical harmonic models, maps or images
    of those models, and possibly line-of-sight acceleration profiles.
    A group at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory JPL under the direction of
    Sami Asmar produced spherical harmonic models and maps.
 
    At Vesta, the mission was divided into three science orbits.
    All the orbits were polar. The Survey orbit was performed at
    a nominal altitude of 2735 km. The High Altitude Mapping
    Orbit, or HAMO, was performed at a nominal altitude of 685 km.
    The Low Altitude Mapping Orbit, or LAMO, was performed at a
    nominal altitude of 200 km. The spacecraft spent 20 days in
    Survey orbit, 34 days in HAMO-1, 141 days in LAMO, and another
    40 days in HAMO-2. Between these science orbits, the spacecraft
    was in a transfer phase using the electric ion engines
    [RUSSELL&amp;RAYMOND2011].
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
    Spherical harmonic models are tables of coefficients GM, Cmn,
    and Smn -- as in equation (1) of [TYLERETAL1992]. These can
    be used to represent gravitational potential of Vesta, for
    example. ASCII (data type SHA) formatted spherical harmonics
    are defined. Because of the low degree field, no binary files
    (data type SHB) are provided. Each file contains up to four
    tables: a header table containing general parameters for
    the model (gravitational constant, its uncertainty, degree
    and order of the field, normalization state, reference longitude,
    and reference latitude); a names table, giving the order in
    which coefficients appear; a coefficients table (degree m,
    order n, coefficients Cmn and Smn, and their uncertainties).
 
    Radio Science Digital Map files are image representations
    of gravity and other parameters. Free air gravity, geoid,
    Bouguer anomaly, isostatic anomaly, and topographic values
    may be displayed using this data type. Data are formatted
    as PDS image objects. Provided in this data set is a map
    of radial acceleration using the VESTA20H field with the
    J2 coefficient removed.
 
    Processing
    ==========
    Spherical harmonic models, maps, and line-of-sight acceleration
    profiles are derived from raw radio tracking data in several
    steps.
 
    The tracking data are processed in large orbit determination
    programs that integrate the equations of motion (DPODP at JPL
    [MOYER1971]), and model mathematically the radio science observables
    (ramped Doppler and range data). The observations are related to
    the geophysical parameters through the numerical integration and the
    detailed mathematical modeling of the radio science observables, and of
    all forces acting on the spacecraft trajectory, including
    planetary and third body gravity, solar radiation pressure,
    planetary radiation pressure, atmospheric drag, solid body tides,
    and relativity, where applicable.
 
    The gravity field coefficients are obtained by accumulating
    normal equations from often hundreds of data arcs, and
    solving these systems of linear equations with thousands of unknowns.
    The unknowns include arc parameters, particular to one data arc (such
    as the spacecraft state, radiation pressure scale factors,
    atmospheric drag scale factors, etc.) and common parameters
    (such as the gravity coefficients, the planetary gravitational
    constant or GM). Radio tracking data are processed in arcs delimited by
    propulsive maneuvers, occultations, etc.
 
    The spacecraft periodically performed angular momentum
    desaturation maneuvers. These maneuvers allowed the reaction
    wheels to spin down to avoid damage, but they had be countered
    the use of thrusters. Arcs may be delimited by these maneuvers.
    The details of each of these maneuvers specified in the small forces
    file of the Dawn Vesta Raw Data Archive.
 
    Useful references which describe the procedures applied in
    general to processing Vesta orbiter tracking data include
    [KONOPLIVETAL2014B].
 
    [THORNTON&amp;BORDER2003] is a general reference for Orbit Determination.
 
    Data
    ====
    Data are available online through the Planetary Data System
    (http://pds.nasa.gov). A volume of reduced data was prepared for
    the Dawn mission at Vesta and a similar volume will be produced for
    the Ceres phase.
 
    ASCII spherical harmonic models are stored in the DATA/SHA directory
    with file names of the form GTsss_nnnnvv_SHA.TAB where:
 
      &apos;G&apos;   denotes the generating institution
                      &apos;J&apos;       for the Jet Propulsion Laboratory
      &apos;T&apos;         indicates the type of data represented
                      &apos;G&apos;       for gravity field
      &apos;sss&apos;    is a 3-character modifier specified by the data producer.
               This modifier is used to indicate the source spacecraft or
               project, such as V for Vesta or C for Ceres.
      &apos;_&apos;      the underscore character is used to delimit modifiers in
               the file name for clarity.
      &apos;nnnnvv&apos; is a 4- to 6-character modifier specified by the data
               producer.  Among other things, this modifier may be used to
               indicate the target body, whether the SHADR contains primary
               data values as specified by &apos;T&apos; or uncertainties/errors,
               and/or the version number.  For Dawn, this specifies the
               degree and version of the field.
       &apos;_&apos;     the underscore character is used to delimit information in
               the file name for clarity.
       &apos;SHA&apos;   denotes that this is an ASCII file of Spherical Harmonic
               coefficients
       &apos;.TAB&apos;  indicates the data is stored in tabular form.
 
    Each SHADR file is accompanied by a detached PDS label; that label is
    a file in its own right, having the name GTsss_nnnnvv_SHA.LBL.
 
    Radio Science Digital Map products are stored in the DATA/RSDMAP
    directory with file names of the form GTsss_ffff_nnnn_cccc.IMG where:
 
      &apos;G&apos;       denotes the generating institution
                      &apos;J&apos;      for the Jet Propulsion Laboratory
      &apos;T&apos;       indicates the type of mission data represented
                      &apos;G&apos; for gravity field
      &apos;sss&apos;     is a 3-character modifier specified by the data producer.
                This modifier is used to indicate the source spacecraft or
                project, such as V for Vesta or C for Ceres.
      &apos;_&apos;       the underscore character is used to delimit information
                in the file name for clarity.
      &apos;ffff&apos;    is a 4- to 6-character modifier specified by the data
                producer to indicate the degree and order of the
                solution for the gravity field, topography or magnetic
                field.
      &apos;_&apos;       the underscore character is used to delimit information
                in the file name for clarity.
      &apos;nnnn&apos;    is a 4- to 8-character modifier indicating the type
                of data represented
                      &apos;ANOM&apos;      for free air gravity anomalies
                      &apos;ANOMERR&apos;   for free air gravity anomaly
                                  errors (1)
                      &apos;GEOID&apos;     for geoid
                      &apos;GEOIDERR&apos;  for geoid errors (1)
                      &apos;BOUG&apos;      for Bouguer anomaly
                      &apos;ISOS&apos;      for isostatic anomaly
                      &apos;TOPO&apos;      for topography
                      &apos;MAGF&apos;      for magnetic field
 
               (1) Geoid and gravity anomaly errors are computed
                   from a mapping of the error covariance matrix
                   of the gravity field solution.
        &apos;_&apos;     the underscore character is used to delimit information
                in the file name for clarity.
        &apos;cccc&apos;  is a 4-character modifier specified by the data producer
                to indicate the degree and order to which the potential
                solution (gravity, topography or magnetic field) has
                been evaluated. In the case of the error maps for the
                gravity anomalies or geoid error, this field indicates to
                which maximum degree and order the error covariance was
                used to propagate the spatial errors
        &apos;.IMG&apos;  indicates the data is stored as an image.
 
    Each RSDMAP file is accompanied by a detached PDS label; that label is a
    file in its own right with name GTsss_ffff_nnnn_cccc.LBL.
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
    Dawn Gravity SDP files use a Vesta centered body-fixed coordinate system
    similar to the IAU coordinate system. The values differ slightly
    because the the orientation of Vesta is estimated in the orbit
    determination process.
 
    See labels of specific gravity products for details.
 
    Software
    ========
    None.
 
    Media/Format
    ============
    This data set is stored online at the Planetary Data System
    (http://pds.nasa.gov/) and may be downloaded using a web browser
    or FTP software. A copy may be requested on physical media if
    downloading is not possible. The Planetary Data System maintains
    backup copies of this data set on various media.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
    Data in this archive have been reduced as part of mission data
    analysis activities of the Dawn Gravity Team.
 
    Review
    ======
    This archival data set was reviewed by the Dawn Gravity
    Team prior to submission to the Planetary Data System (PDS).
    Data set design, documentation, and sample products have passed
    a PDS peer review.
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
    This volume contains gravity models and maps generated from Dawn data
    collected between July 2011 and July 2012.
 
    JGDWN_VES20H_SHA.TAB is an ASCII file of coefficients and related data
    for a 20th degree and order Vesta gravity field produced at the
    Jet Propulsion Laboratory. The name of this gravity model is
    VESTA20H. The model used is described in the file&apos;s
    detached label.
 
    JGDWN_VES20H_RADIAL_0020.IMG is a digital map of the Vesta radial
    acceleration due to gravity with the J2 coefficient removed. The radial
    accelerations are computed with the VESTA20H field described in the
    JGDWN_VES20H_SHA.TAB file. This Vesta gravity field was produced at
    the Jet Propulsion Laboratory.  The model used is described in the
    file&apos;s detached label.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
    The limitations in this data set follow from the quality of
    the execution, which is described above under Data Coverage
    and Quality.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

