<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.cfht-s-quirc-1-3-rpx-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CFHT SR QUIRC RAW AND CALIBRATED RING PLANE CROSSING 1.O</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.saturn_ring_plane_crossing_1995::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.cfht::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:quirc.cfht::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.saturn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:ring.s_rings::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.dione::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.tethys::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.titan::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.cfht-s-quirc-1-3-rpx-v1.0__browserp_cfht-s-quirc-1-3-rpx-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.rings::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Bauer, J., J.J. Lissauer, and M. Simon, Edge-on Observations of Saturn&apos;s E and
                   G rings in the near-IR, Icarus 125, 440-445, 1997.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BAUERETAL1997</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Bosh, A.S. and A.S. Rivkin, Observations of Saturn&apos;s inner satellites during
                   the May 1995 ring-plane crossing, Science, 272, 518-521, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BOSH-RIVKIN1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Burns, J. A., Some background about satellites, Satellites, J. A. Burns and M.
                   S. Matthews Eds., pp. 14-15, University of Arizona Press, Tucson, 1986.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BURNS1986</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Casali, M., T. Hawarden, A set of faint standards for UKIRT, JCMT-UKIRT
                   Newsletter, 4, 33-35, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CASALI-HAWARDEN1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hodapp,K.-W., J. L. Hora, D.N.B. Hall, L.L. Cowie, M. Metzger, E.M. Irwin, T.J.
                   Keller, K. Vural, L. J. Kozlowski, and W. E. Kleinhans, Astronomical
                   Characterization of 1024x1024 HgCdTe HAWAII Detector Arrays, Proc. SPIE Int.
                   Soc. Opt. Eng. 2475, 8-14, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HODAPPETAL1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Roddier, F., M. Northcott, and J. E. Graves, A Simple Low-Order Adaptive Optics
                   System for Near-Infrared Applications, Publ. Astron. Soc. Pac. 103, 131-149,
                   January 1991.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.RODDIERETAL1991</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Roddier, F., C. Roddier, J. E. Graves, and M. J. Northcott, Discovery of an Arc
                   of Particles near Enceladus&apos; Orbit: A Possible Key to the Origin of the E Ring,
                   Icarus 136, 50-59, 1998.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.RODDIERETAL1998</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Roddier, F., C. Roddier, A. Brahic, C. Dumas, J.E. Graves, M.J. Northcott, and
                   T. Owen, Adaptive optics observations of Saturn&apos;s ring plane crossing in August
                   1995, Icarus, 143, 299-307, 2000.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.RODDIERETAL2000</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CFHT-S-QUIRC-1/3-RPX-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CFHT SR QUIRC RAW AND CALIBRATED RING PLANE CROSSING 1.O</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2006-11-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1995-08-09T14:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1995-08-12T16:00:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DANIEL M. OLSON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Roddier, F., C. Roddier, and D. Olson, CFHT Observations of the
            August 1995 Saturn Ring Plane Crossing,
            CFHT-S-QUIRC-1/3-RPX-V1.0, USA_NASA_PDS_RPX_0301, NASA Planetary
            Data System, 2006.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            CFHT Quick Infrared Camera images from the August 1995 Saturn
            Ring Plane Crossing.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains images of the Saturn system from the
            CANADA-FRANCE-HAWAII telescope with the Quick Infrared Camera in
            early August 1995.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
     This dataset contain images of the Saturn system taken at the
     Canada France Hawaii Telescope at Mauna Kea observatory using
     the Quick Infrared Camera (QUIRC) in early August 1995.
     This period coincides with the August plane crossing of
     that year. The Viewing geometry was such that the Earth
     and the Sun were on opposite sides of the ring plane,
     and the opening was less than 0.2 degrees.
 
     Every image showing Saturn, its rings or the region of the
     inner satellites has been included in this data set, regardless
     of the original intended purpose.
 
     The CFHT observing program whose results are included in
     this dataset is:
 
     Proposal: NAGW 4935 and NAG 5-3731
     Title:    Unknown
     PI:       Roddier, Francois and Roddier, Claude
               (Institute for Astronomy, University of Hawaii)
 
  Objectives
  ==========
     The primary objective for this set of observations was to
     obtain photometry for the small satellites of Saturn.
 
     A secondary objective was to obtain detailed information
     about the fine structure of the F ring. Such as various
     clumps including HST S5 and S7 objects.
 
  Parameters
  ==========
     The PDS label for each file contains a broad variety of
     additional parameters enabling the user to determine image
     geometry and to convert pixel values to physically meaningful
     quantities.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The calibrated images have been processed using IRAF. This
    includes: analog bias correction, dark current correction,
    flat field correction, and sky correction.
 
    In at least some cases there was some additional processing.
    It is unknown exactly what was done. However, there was at
    least reorientation and resampling( to facilitate co-adding
    and moving object analysis ).
 
  Data
  ====
    The data provided here are images in FITS format. For each data
    file, a detached PDS label is provided containing additional
    parameters.
 
    Most users will probably prefer to focus on the calibrated images
    or the processed data.
 
    The calibrated data may be found in:
 
         /CALIB/1995xxxx_yyyy/
 
    where xxxx refers to the day of observation and yyyy refers
    to the type of calibration. See the file /CALIB/CALINFO.TXT
    for more detail.
 
    The particular data can be found at:
 
         /DATA/1995xxxx_zzzzz/
 
    Where as before xxxx refers to the day of observation. The string
    zzzzz is either S_RINGS or the name of a satellite.
    there are two subdirectories below each of these one for raw data
    and one for processed data, see AAREADME.TXT for more info.
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
    All geometric quantities appearing in the labels are in J2000
    coordinates.  In this coordinate frame, the z-axis points
    northward along the Earth&apos;s J2000 rotation axis and the x-axis
    points toward the First Point of Aries.  In some cases, B1950
    coordinate values are also included.
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    This data set is archived on DVD media.
    Organization and formats are according to PDS and ISO 9660
    level 2 standards.
 
    Most binary data files are in least-significant-byte first, which
    is the native format for PCs and Digital workstations.  Users of
    Suns and other workstations may need to swap bytes in some data
    files before use. Note that the software tools provided on this
    volume swap the bytes automatically if this is necessary.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
     The Quick Infrared Camera was primarily calibrated with the UKIRT
     standard stars FS2 and FS4. It was necessary to use secondary standards.
     The Secondary standard used were the satellites Dione and Tethys.
 
     The best small satellite data obtained was photometric at the
     10% level. The seeing was the roughly the same on all four nights.
 
  Peer Review
  ===========
    This data set passed peer review on August 29, 2007.
    The members of the peer review panel were James Bauer, Steve Larson,
    Cathy Olkin and Ron Joyner.
 
 
  Data Coverage
  =============
     Observations were made in August 1995, the most favorable period
     for ground based observations. Either Dione or Tethys were used
     as a guide source. The offset mirror was used to record
     images of the nearest ring side at different positions of the
     camera. Saturn was carefully left outside the field-of-view
     to avoid saturation of the detector array.
 
     For more specific information on what objects were covered
     see the file:
 
         /DOCUMENT/OBJECT_LOG.TAB
 
  Citing this dataset
  ===================
    The following is the recommended information to include in a
    journal citation of this dataset: &apos;Roddier, F., C. Roddier,
    and D. Olson, CFHT Observations of the August 1995 Ring Plane
    Crossing, CFHT-S-QUIRC-1/3-RPX-V1.0, USA_NASA_PDS_RPX_0301,
    NASA Planetary Data System, 2006.&apos;
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>PSRI-00002</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

