<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ear-a-i1063-3-neat-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>NEAR EARTH ASTEROID TRACKING V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.support_archives::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.obs347t2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.obs6490t1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.obs6491t1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:i1063.obs347t2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:i1349.obs6490t1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:i1349.obs6491t1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:i1496.obs347t2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.asteroid::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.dark::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.flat_field::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-a-i1063-3-neat-v1.0__browserp_ear-a-i1063-3-neat-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Baltay, C., D. Rabinowitz, P. Andrews, A. Bauer, N. Ellman, and 15 others, The
                   QUEST Large Area CCD Camera, Publications of the Astronomical Society of the
                   Pacific (PASP) 119, 1278-1294, doi 10.1086/523899, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BALTAYETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Landolt, A.U., UBVRI Photometric Standard Stars in the Magnitude Range
                   11.5&lt;V&lt;16.0 Around the Celestial Equator, Astron. J., 104, 340, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LANDOLT1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Pravdo, S.H., E.F. Helin, D.L. Rabinowitz, K.J. Lawrence, R.J. Bambery, and 9
                   others, The Near-Earth Asteroid Tracking (NEAT) Program: An Automated System
                   for Telescope Control, Wide-Field Imaging, and Object Detection, Astronomical
                   Journal 117, 1616-1633, doi:10.1086/300769, 1999.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PRAVDOETAL1999</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>EAR-A-I1063-3-NEAT-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>NEAR EARTH ASTEROID TRACKING V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2014-12-09</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1996-04-17</start_time>
        <stop_time>2007-04-15</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>KENNETH LAWRENCE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Bauer, J. M. and Lawrence, K. J., Eds., Near Earth Asteroid
            Tracking V1.0. EAR-A-I1063-3-NEAT-V1.0. NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2013.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Near-Earth Asteroid Tracking (NEAT) images, 2013.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Near-Earth Asteroid Tracking (NEAT) project began as a
            collaborative effort with the United States Air Force (USAF) in
            December 1995. It concentrated on the discovery and observations
            of near-Earth asteroids and comets, collectively called
            near-Earth objects (NEOs). NEAT ended its observations in April
            2007. Throughout its history, NEAT utilized three 1m class
            telescopes - two on the Hawaiian island of Maui and the 1.2m
            Oschin Schmidt telescope at Palomar Observatory near San Diego,
            CA. Three unique cameras were developed and used throughout the
            program. These data are intended to be usable for photometric
            analysis of the various objects within the NEAT data. Most nights
            included calibration data, and the lists of photometric standard
            calibration fields.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
 
    This dataset contains the Near-Earth Asteroid Tracking (NEAT)
    observations, associated darks, flats, log files and a list
    of Landolt standards.  The data are archived in a series of volumes
    within the same data set.  For a description of the individual
    volumes, see the aareadme.txt file at the root level of each
    individual volume.
 
    The images have been changed to fits format, but no image processing
    performed.  Nightly, master (averaged) darks and sky-background images
    have been created for each night using standard IRAF software tools.
    A list of images used to create these calibration files are
    provided, although all the files reside with the original data
    under the obsdata sub-directory.
 
    Landolt standard stars (Landolt 1992) were not generally targeted
    during the survey.  However, they did routinely fall on NEAT
    fields.  A list provides the Landolt star, its position as listed
    from the Landolt catalog, its visual magnitude and the NEAT images
    with the field center and exposure time.  Some fields were regularly
    observed, and these fields, if observed during the night, are
    included with the Landolt stars as potential calibration fields.
 
    SITE DESCRIPTION:
    NEAT began observations with the USAF 1.0m Ground-based
    Electro-Optical Deep Space Surveillance (GEODSS) telescope on
    Mt. Haleakala, Maui, HI (Pravdo 1999).  In 2000, NEAT
    transitioned to the Maui Space Surveillance Site (MSSS) 1.2m
    telescope located at the same facility.  The site is located
    at an elevation of 3040.35 meters and a latitude/longitude of
    +20deg 42.5&apos;/156deg 15.5&apos; west.  The local time at the site
    is ten hours prior to Greenwich mean time.
 
    In 2001, the Palomar 1.2m Oschin Schmidt telescope located in
    northern San Diego, CA was incorporated into the NEAT inventory.
    The Oschin Schmidt is located at an elevation of 1726.3 meters,
    a latitude/longitude of +33deg 21.4&apos;/116deg 51.8 west and is
    eight hours prior to GMT.
 
 
 
    CAMERA DESCRIPTION:
    The primary camera at the Maui site was a single 4096 x 4096
    camera with 15 micron pixels.  The pixel scale is 1.43 arc-sec/
    pixel with the 1.0m GEODSS telescope and 1.36 arc-sec/pixel
    with the MSSS 1.2m. No filters were used and the bandpass is
    0.4 - 0.8 microns, however the peak response matches closely
    with the Bessel-type R filter at 0.6 microns.  A thermoelectric
    cooler (TEC) maintains an approximate operating temperature of -5 and -20
    degrees C for the GEODSS and MSSS cameras, respectively.
    Four amplifiers readout the CCD in four quadrants.
 
    The Palomar &apos;Tri-camera&apos; consists of three separate 4096 x 4096
    pixel CCDs.  The CCDs are arranged in a linear, north-south, orientation
    and denoted by &apos;A, B or C.&apos;  An approximate one-degree gap is between each
    CCD and each covers nearly 1.0 square degree.
    The 15 micron pixels yield a pixel scale of 1.01 arc-sec/pixel.
    As with the Maui system, no filters were used, but matches closely
    with a Bessel-type R filter at 0.6 microns and TECs maintained an
    operating temperature of approximately -30 degrees C.  Four amplifiers
    readout the CCD in four quadrants.  See tables 1 and 2 for instrument and
    site summary.  These two cameras used &apos;CCD485&apos; chips produced by Fairchild
    Imaging.  The central wavelength is
    702 nm.
 
 
    ----------------------------------------------------------
    |  Site                  Maui/GEODSS     Maui/MSSS       |
    |  Dates of Operation:  12/95 - 2/99    2/00 - 4/07      |
    |  Telescope Diameter:       1.0m           1.2m         |
    |  f/ratio:                  2.15           3.14         |
    |  Camera:               4096 x 4096    4096 x 4096      |
    |  Pixel Size:             15 x 15 u      15 x 15 u      |
    |  Pixel Scale:           1.43&apos;/pix      1.36&apos;/pix       |
    |  Cooling:               TEC @ ~-5C    TEC @ ~-20C      |
    |  Filter:                   None           None         |
    |  IAU Site Code:            566            608          |
    |  Latitude / Longitude: +20deg 42.5&apos;   156deg 15.5&apos;W    |
    |  Elevation / Timezone:   3040.35m       UTC - 10       |
    |________________________________________________________|
    Table 1 - A comparison of telescopes and instruments
              used by NEAT on Mt. Haleakala, Maui, HI
 
 
 
    --------------------------------------------------------------
    |  Site                  Pal/Tri-cam      Palomar/QUEST      |
    |  Dates of Operation:  4/01 - 6/03       6/03 - 4/07        |
    |  Telescope Diameter:      1.2m               1.2m          |
    |  f/ratio:                 2.50               2.50          |
    |  Camera:              4096 x 4096 x 3   600 x 2400 x 112   |
    |  Pixel Size:             15 x 15 u          13 x 13 u      |
    |  Pixel Scale:           1.01&apos;/pix           0.87&apos;/pix      |
    |  Cooling:              TEC @ ~-30C        LN2 @ -120C      |
    |  Filter:                   None             610 nm         |
    |  IAU Site Code:            644                644          |
    |                                                            |
    |  Latitude / Longitude: +33deg 21.4&apos;    116deg 51.8&apos;W       |
    |  Elevation / Timezone:   1726.3m           UTC - 8         |
    |____________________________________________________________|
    Table 2 - A comparison of the instruments used by NEAT at
               Palomar Observatory.
 
 
    The QUEST camera began operations at Palomar Observatory in June
    2003 and replaced the tri-camera (Baltay 2007).  It was designed
    and constructed at Yale University and consists of 112 CCD chips
    manufactured by the Sarnoff corporation.  Four rows, or fingers,
    each contain twenty-eight CCDs.  Each CCD is 600 x 2400 with 13 micron
    square pixels.  The pixel scale is 0.87 arc-sec/pixel.  The camera covers
    an area of 4.6 degrees by 3.6 degrees with an effective area of 9.6 square
    degrees of sky.  The central wave-
    length is 760 nm.  During the point-and-track observations used
    by NEAT, a red (effective wavelength 610 nm) Bessel filter was
    used.
 
 
    The fingers are symmetrical about the bore sight.  As a result,
    the pointing centers listed in the logs are the pointing centers
    of the bore sight; not CCD chip centers.  Fingers B and C are
    offset from the bore sight by +/-30.07 arc-secs (0.5012 deg.)
    while fingers A and D are offset by +/-90.17 arc-secs (1.5028 deg.),
    respectively.  The twenty-eight CCDs are laid out in an North-South
    orientation (chips 01-28) from +/-2.25 degrees (chips 01 - 28) from the
    bore sight pointing coordinates (see table 3).
 
 
 
              Finger
    CCD     D        C
           RA       RA       DEC
    01  -1.5028  -0.5012   2.2483
    02  -1.5028  -0.5012   2.0819
    03  -1.5028  -0.5012   1.9155
    04  -1.5028  -0.5012   1.7490
    05  -1.5028  -0.5012   1.5826
    06  -1.5028  -0.5012   1.4160
    07  -1.5028  -0.5012   1.2495
    08  -1.5028  -0.5012   1.0829
    09  -1.5028  -0.5012   0.9164
    10  -1.5028  -0.5012   0.7498
    11  -1.5028  -0.5012   0.5832
    12  -1.5028  -0.5012   0.4166
    13  -1.5028  -0.5012   0.2499
    14  -1.5028  -0.5012   0.0833
    15  -1.5028  -0.5012  -0.0833
    16  -1.5028  -0.5012  -0.2499
    17  -1.5028  -0.5012  -0.4155
    18  -1.5028  -0.5012  -0.5832
    19  -1.5028  -0.5012  -0.7498
    20  -1.5028  -0.5012  -0.9164
    21  -1.5028  -0.5012  -1.0829
    22  -1.5028  -0.5012  -1.2495
    23  -1.5028  -0.5012  -1.4160
    24  -1.5028  -0.5012  -1.5826
    25  -1.5028  -0.5012  -1.7490
    26  -1.5028  -0.5012  -1.9155
    27  -1.5028  -0.5012  -2.0819
    28  -1.5028  -0.5012  -2.2483
    --------------------------------
    Table 3:  QUEST CCD chip offsets for fingers C and D.  Fingers
              B and A are mirror copies and consist of the same,
              positive, values (ie finger B&apos;s RA offset is 0.5012
              degrees and A&apos;s RA offset is 1.5028 degrees).
 
 
    IMAGE DESCRIPTION:
    Regardless of the camera, each CCD chip read to a unique output
    file.  Filenames are based on the universal start time of the
    exposure and, if appropriate, identify the specific chip used.
    The Maui and tri-camera images contain the 4080 x 4080 imaging
    area.  Because the NEAT survey was interested in astrometry and
    not photometry, the data are not bias corrected, nor were the
    bias saved.  Within the QUEST data, however, the overscan regions
    are available in the 40 extra rows (rows 600-640).
 
    The initial orientation of the Maui and Palomar tri-camera images
    has East towards to left and North downward.  Each uncompressed,
    4k x 4k, (Palomar tri-camera and Maui) image is 66.6 and 33.3 Mb in size,
    respectively.  The QUEST images are 3.1 Mb in size,
    uncompressed, with North towards the left and West downward initially.
 
 
    OBSERVING STRATEGIES:
    NEAT concentrated its observations to the ecliptic with highest
    priority to opposition.  The Palomar and Maui sites worked in
    conjunction with each other and rarely observed identical search
    fields on the same night.  The same follow-up field may have been
    taken by both telescopes to assure acquisition of newly discovered
    NEAs.
 
    The NEAT detection software required three observations at the
    same location.  These &apos;triplets&apos; were obtained with revisit or
    cadence times between fifteen to thirty minutes.  Integration
    times were, typically, 20 seconds at the Maui site and 60 seconds
    at Palomar.  However, it was not uncommon to vary exposure times
    to 120 and/or 150 seconds at Palomar.  When NEAT began observations
    with the Maui camera, integration times varied from 40 seconds to
    60 seconds.
 
    Two log files list the RA and DEC, in J2000 coordinates, in
    sexagesimal format and decimal of degrees, the integration times
    and filenames.  The &apos;log dot group&apos; file (filenames in the format
    of YEARMMDD_log_group.tab) displays the approximate cadence time
    between revisits and the files associated with a particular RA/DEC and the
    closest dark frame obtained prior to the observation.  These log files are
    in the following format:
 
 
      Center of chip   Center of Chip                 Apprx.
       Sexagesimal     Decimal of Deg Shtr  Bin       Cadnce  No. &amp; List
       RA       DEC      RA     Dec   Opn?  fctr  Exp  Time   of Images
    hh mm ss  dd mm ss   deg    deg   y/n    1   (sec) (sec)
 
 
    Similarly, the &apos;log dot obs&apos; file (usually with a filename in the
    format of YEARMMDD_log_obs.tab) lists every image obtained with
    its associated RA and DEC (J2000) and integration time.  The &apos;log
    dot obs&apos; files are formatted as the following:
 
      Center of chip   Center of Chip
       Sexagesimal     Decimal of Deg Shutter  Bin          Image
       RA       DEC      RA     Dec    Open?  factor  Exp  Filename
    hh mm ss  dd mm ss   deg    deg     y/n     1    (sec)
 
 
    Within the header of each image, the chip center in sexagesimal
    format (hour and degrees, minutes and seconds) are clearly labeled.
    In addition, these RA and DEC values are listed in degrees under
    the &apos;CRVAL1&apos; and &apos;CRVAL2&apos; keywords, respectively.  These are for
    reference only and do not represent the center&apos;s astrometric solution.
 
    Nearly all of the data is binned 1x1 and only the darks respond
    &apos;n&apos; to the shutter question.  There are a few, rare, occasions
    when the data was binned 2x2.
 
 
    FILE AND DIRECTORY NAMING CONVENTION:
	The data file and directory naming conventions vary by instrument.
	This is documented further in the aareadme.txt file for that
	instrument&apos;s volume.
 
	All data subdirectories have the same internal directory structure. All
	image files reside under the &apos;obsdata&apos; subdirectory.   Darks
	and flats are stored under their respective names.  A file containing
	the list of Landolt standards observed resides under the &apos;landolts&apos;
	subdirectory.  The log files are kept under the &apos;logs&apos; subdirectory.
 
    NEAT was nearly an autonomous system and was chartered to
    operate with little disruption to on-site personnel.
    Observing log files for each site have been maintained with
    filenames in the format of SITE_nightly_log (with SITE equal
    to Pal (for Palomar data - both QUEST and the tri-camera) and
    MS3 (for the Maui data - both GEODSS and MSSS)).  However, the
    observing logs stating the nightly sky conditions are brief.
    At times, Air Force personnel at the Maui site made generic
    comments about the nightly observing conditions.  It is not
    uncommon for no comments to be made.
 
    Conversely, the Palomar log, Pal_nightly_logPDSdelivery2.pdf,
    contains notes on the weather conditions and seeing as reported
    by the 200-inch telescope operator.  Note, this is the weather
    reported at the 200-inch.  Although the 48-inch, Oschin Schmidt
    is not far away, it may be effected by slightly different weather
    and seeing.  Entries include cloud cover, relative humidity and
    wind speed, as well as the seeing.
 
 
    PROCESSING:
    Limited processing has been applied to the data.  All data have
    been changed from a unique NEAT format to a generic fits format.
    All headers have been modified to agree to the PDS&apos; formats and
    standards.  Additional information for each observation has been
    determined including the air mass (SECZ) and readnoise (READN).
 
 
 
    REFERENCES:
    Baltay, C., D. Rabinowitz, P. Andrews, A. Bauer, N. Ellman,
    W. Emmet, R. Hudson, T. Hurteau, J. Jerke, R. Lauer, J. Silge,
    A. Szymkowiak, B. Adams, M. Gebhard, J. Musser, M. Doyle,
    H. Petrie, R. Smith, R. Thicksten, J. Geary, &apos;The QUEST
    Large Area CCD Camera,&apos; PASP 119 (2007), pp. 1278--1294.
 
    Landolt, A.U., 1992, UBVRI photometric standard stars in the
    magnitude range 11.5-16.0 around the celestial equator.
    Astron. J. 104, 340-371.
 
    Pravdo, S. H., E. F. Helin, D. L. Rabinowitz, K. J. Lawrence,
    R. J. Bambery, C. C. Clark, S. L. Groom, S. M. Levin, J. J. Lorre, &apos;The
    Near-Earth Asteroid Tracking (NEAT) Program: An Automated
    System for Telescope Control, Wide-Field Imaging, and Object Detection&apos;,
    Astronomical Journal 117 (1999), pp. 1616-1633.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    ANOMALIES:
    Like all ground-based observations, the data is effected by local
    weather and atmospheric conditions.  In addition, telescope guiding,
    focus and hardware problems can further degrade the data.  Frost and
    condensation have appeared periodically on the camera window, especially
    on the Maui data.
 
    All data, except the QUEST data, are obtained from multi-amplifer
    detectors.  As such, each quadrant (1024 x 1024 pixels) is subject
    to gain and bias offset anomalies and may not be persistent across
    the entire field or throughout the night.  Consequently, the
    calibration frames may not compensate for these anomalies of the
    individual frames and it is left to the user to correct.
 
    Six QUEST CCDs were bad and un-operational.   These were chips
    A10, A15, B01, B07, C06, D07.  Others performed intermittently
    and have been noted and identified in the &apos;dead.txt&apos; file under
    the logs subdirectory .  Other chips are affected with bad columns,
    moire patterns, amplifier glow and LED glow.
 
    The log files are for reference only and do not represent the centers&apos;
    astrometric solution.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

