<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-h-xrs-3-rdr-maps-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER H XRS REDUCED DATA RECORD (RDR) MAPS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:xrs.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-xrs-3-rdr-maps-v1.0__browserp_mess-h-xrs-3-rdr-maps-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-xrs-3-rdr-maps-v1.0__browser_geo_mercury_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-h-xrs-3-rdr-maps-v1.0__dvo_mess-h-xrs-3-rdr-maps-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Schlemm, C.E., II, R.D. Starr, G.C. Ho, K.E. Bechtold, S.A. Benedict, J.D.
                   Boldt, W.V. Boynton, W. Bradley, M.E. Fraeman, R.E. Gold, J.O. Goldsten, J.R.
                   Hayes, S.E. Jaskulek, E. Rossano, R.A. Rumpf, E.D. Schaefer, K. Strohbehn, R.G.
                   Shelton, R.E. Thompson, J.I. Trombka, and B.D. Williams, The X-Ray Spectrometer
                   on the MESSENGER spacecraft, Space Science Reviews, 131, 393-415, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SCHLEMMETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-H-XRS-3-RDR-MAPS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESSENGER H XRS REDUCED DATA RECORD (RDR) MAPS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-05-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2011-097T03:19:53Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2015-114T21:05:34Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>LARRY R. NITTLER</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            L. R. Nittler, MESSENGER H XRS REDUCED DATA RECORD MAPS V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 2013.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The MESSENGER XRS RDR data consist of maps of the ratio of
            elements detected by the XRS instrument during orbital operations
            at Mercury.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== This data set consists of the MESSENGER XRS
            reduced data record observations, also known as RDRs, which are
            derived from the calibrated data records, CDRs. Each XRS
            observation results in four X-ray spectra. When an X-ray
            interacts with one of the four detectors, a charge or voltage
            pulse is generated. This signal is converted into one of 2^8
            (256) channels, which are correlated to energy. Over a commanded
            integration time period a histogram of counts as a function of
            energy (channel number) is recorded. The EDRs are the number of
            events in each channel of the four detectors accumulated over the
            integration period. Channels above or below the useful energy
            range of the detectors are not transmitted. The result is three
            244-channel GPC histograms and one 231-channel solar monitor
            histogram, each of which is designated as a single X-ray
            spectrum. Each observation is calibrated and processed into the
            CDR data set and then further processed to produce a map of
            elemental ratios, the maps of which compose the RDR data set.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
   Data Set Overview
   =================
     Each observation is calibrated and processed into the CDR data set
     and then further processed to produce a map of elemental ratios,
     the maps of which compose the RDR data set.  The orbital mechanics
     of the instrument and field-of-view of each measurement are
     accounted for in the products of the elemental ratio maps, and are
     also a part of the processing that produces the uncertainty map
     that corresponds to each ratio map.
 
   Instrument Overview
   ===================
     The X-Ray Spectrometer (XRS) experiment is comprised of three
     identical gas proportional counters (GPC) that measure X-rays
     emitted from the surface of Mercury in the energy range from about
     1 to 10 keV.  X-rays in this energy range sample the planetary
     surface to depths of a few tens of microns.
 
     See the INSTRUMENT.CAT file for more information and [SCHLEMMETAL2007]
     for full details.
 
   Calibration Overview
   ====================
     The supernova remnant X-ray source Cassiopeia-A (Cas-A) is being
     used for periodic in-flight calibration because of its relatively
     high intensity in the XRS energy range. Once or twice a year XRS is
     pointed to Cas-A for about 48 hours and then away from that source
     for another 48 hours to accumulate background measurements. These
     measurements provide an evaluation and calibration of the XRS anti-
     coincidence and rise-time discrimination background rejection
     systems.
 
   Parameters
   ==========
     The principal parameters when observing with the XRS are as
     follows:
 
 
     * Integration Period: Normal (quiet Sun) or Flare. In Normal mode
     three different integration intervals are used, depending on
     distance to the planet. These may be set over a wide range, but the
     default values are:
 
                  Integration  Collection Time
       Closest:        40 s       2000 s
       Mid-Range:     200 s      10000 s
       Greatest:      450 s      31200 s
 
     In flare mode integration periods are automatically shortened to a
     pre-determined level, typically 20 s, for 60 minutes or less.
 
     * Veto Event: Accept or reject events with a simultaneous signal
     from the anti-coincidence wires.
 
     * Rise-Time Validation: Accept or reject events with an invalid
     rise time measurement.
 
   Data
   ====
     The XRS instrument telemetry conveys science data, configuration
     data and status (housekeeping) data. Several telemetry packets are
     used to downlink this information:
 
        Status Housekeeping Packets
        Uncompressed Science Packets
        Compressed Science Packets
        Raw Sensor Data Packets
 
     The useful science and housekeeping measurements from the telemetry
     are decompressed and decomutated and are correlated and accumulated
     into one binary table, which constitutes the primary experimental
     data record.
 
     Each record of the table contains four energy spectra,
     housekeeping, status, and rate data for one integration period. The
     spectra correspond to the Mg-filtered detector (GPC1), the
     Al-filtered detector (GPC2), the unfiltered detector (GPC3), and
     the solar monitor (SAX). All the spectra have 256 bins, but only
     the highest 244 bins for the GPC and the highest 231 bins for the
     SAX are telemetered. All bins are 16 bits deep. There are five
     32-bit rate counters for SAX and nine 24-bit rate counters for each
     of the three gas proportional counters.
 
     Rate counters for all four detectors include raw, valid event,
     analyzed, pileup, and high-energy rates. The gas detectors also
     have counters for the veto-anode, veto, rise-pileup, and
     rise-rejection rates.
 
     Housekeeping data provide voltage, current, and temperature
     readings measured at the end of each integration period. Also
     reported are record and software status, hardware settings and
     integration and reporting times.
 
     The CDR data products are aggregated to produce the RDRs; in
     combination with the relevant SPICE kernels and the instrument&apos;s
     field-of-view parameters, a planetary footprint can be calculated
     for each CDR record.  These footprints form the basis for placing
     CDR data onto the aggregate map that forms the basis of the
     elemental ratio maps.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
   Confidence Level Overview
   =========================
     The XRS CDR data are the calibrated data records released for the XRS.
     They include all of the EDR data plus other information such as detector
     energy calibration, engineering data conversions, and spatial data which
     will be necessary to convert raw XRS counts to planetary surface
     compositions. The XRS RDR maps are created using the calibrated XRS CDR
     products.
 
   Review
   ======
     The XRS CDR was reviewed internally by the XRS team prior to release to
     the PDS.  PDS also performed an external review of the XRS CDR. Likewise,
     the XRS RDR products are reviewed both internally by the XRS science team
     and by PDS.
 
   Data Coverage and Quality
   =========================
     XRS RDR maps are generated from data collected only while in orbit at
     Mercury, which is from phases Mercury Orbit through Mercury Orbit Year 5.
     It is, however, helpful to review the larger mission from which these
     data are derived.
 
     Nineteen mission phases: Launch, Earth Cruise, Earth Flyby, Venus 1
     Cruise, Venus 1 Flyby, Venus 2 Cruise, Venus 2 Flyby, Mercury 1 Cruise,
     Mercury 1 flyby, Mercury 2 Cruise, Mercury 2 flyby, Mercury 3 Cruise,
     Mercury 3 flyby, Mercury 4 Cruise, Mercury Orbit, Mercury Orbit Year 2,
     Mercury Orbit Year 3, Mercury Orbit Year 4, and Mercury Orbit Year 5.
     These mission phases are defined as:
 
                           Start time          End time
     Phase Name            Date (DOY)          Date (DOY)
     -------------------   -----------------  -----------------
     Launch                03 Aug 2004 (216)  12 Sep 2004 (256)
     Earth Cruise          13 Sep 2004 (257)  18 Jul 2005 (199)
     Earth Flyby           19 Jul 2005 (200)  16 Aug 2005 (228)
     Venus 1 Cruise        17 Aug 2005 (229)  09 Oct 2006 (282)
     Venus 1 Flyby         10 Oct 2006 (283)  07 Nov 2006 (311)
     Venus 2 Cruise        08 Nov 2006 (312)  22 May 2007 (142)
     Venus 2 Flyby         23 May 2007 (143)  20 Jun 2007 (171)
     Mercury 1 Cruise      21 Jun 2007 (172)  30 Dec 2007 (364)
     Mercury 1 Flyby       31 Dec 2007 (365)  28 Jan 2008 (028)
     Mercury 2 Cruise      29 Jan 2008 (029)  21 Sep 2008 (265)
     Mercury 2 Flyby       22 Sep 2008 (266)  20 Oct 2008 (294)
     Mercury 3 Cruise      21 Oct 2008 (295)  15 Sep 2009 (258)
     Mercury 3 Flyby       16 Sep 2009 (259)  14 Oct 2009 (287)
     Mercury 4 Cruise      15 Oct 2009 (288)  03 Mar 2011 (062)
     Mercury Orbit         04 Mar 2011 (063)  17 Mar 2012 (077)
     Mercury Orbit Year 2  18 Mar 2012 (078)  17 Mar 2013 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 3  18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 4  18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 5  18 Mar 2015 (077)  30 Apr 2015 (120)
 
     No XRS data were collected during Earth Flyby or Venus 1 Flyby phases.
     The XRS was on for some of each of the other seventeen mission phases.
     During these planned operational periods, the XRS functioned nominally
     and the data quality was good. Specific XRS operational periods were:
 
                           Start time         End time
     Phase Name            Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)
     -----------------     ----------------   ----------------
     Launch                30 Aug 2004 (243)  30 Aug 2004 (243)
     Earth Cruise          07 Feb 2005 (038)  11 Feb 2005 (042)
                           14 Apr 2005 (104)  14 Apr 2005 (104)
                           09 Jul 2005 (190)  13 Jul 2005 (194)
     Earth Flyby           No Data
     Venus 1 Cruise        16 Jan 2006 (016)  13 Feb 2006 (044)
                           06 Sep 2006 (249)  10 Sep 2006 (253)
     Venus 1 Flyby         No Data
     Venus 2 Cruise        27 Jan 2007 (027)  31 Jan 2007 (031)
     Venus 2 Flyby         26 May 2007 (146)  20 Jun 2007 (171)
     Mercury 1 Cruise      21 Jun 2007 (172)  08 Aug 2007 (220)
                           17 Aug 2007 (229)  25 Aug 2007 (237)
                           21 Dec 2007 (355)  30 Dec 2007 (364)
     Mercury 1 Flyby       31 Dec 2007 (365)  21 Jan 2008 (021)
     Mercury 2 Cruise      28 Mar 2008 (088)  02 Jun 2008 (154)
                           11 Jun 2008 (163)  21 Sep 2008 (265)
     Mercury 2 Flyby       22 Sep 2008 (266)  20 Oct 2008 (294)
     Mercury 3 Cruise      21 Oct 2008 (295)  19 Nov 2008 (324)
                           15 Jan 2009 (015)  04 May 2009 (124)
                           07 May 2009 (127)  17 May 2009 (137)
                           28 Aug 2009 (240)  01 Sep 2009 (244)
                           04 Sep 2009 (247)  15 Sep 2009 (258)
     Mercury 3 Flyby       16 Sep 2009 (259)  29 Sep 2009 (272)
     Mercury 4 Cruise      22 Jan 2010 (022)  03 Dec 2010 (337)
                           06 Dec 2010 (340)  03 Mar 2011 (062)
     Mercury Orbit         04 Mar 2011 (063)  16 Mar 2011 (075)
                           23 Mar 2011 (082)  07 Mar 2012 (067)
                           12 Mar 2012 (072)  17 Mar 2012 (077)
     Mercury Orbit Year 2  23 Mar 2012 (083)  17 Mar 2013 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 3  18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 4  18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 5  18 Mar 2015 (077)  30 Apr 2015 (120)
 
     The XRS detectors were on continuously during orbital mission phases
     except where spacecraft operations (eclipses) and instrument health and
     safety (temperature and count rate) required some or all of the detectors
     to be turned off.  Details of these off periods and other operational
     issues may be found in the XRS EDR and CDR data confidence notes.
 
     The XRS RDR maps were produced from data collected during the Mercury
     Orbit, Mercury Orbit Year 2, Mercury Orbit Year 3, Mercury Orbit Year 4,
     and Mercury Orbit Year 5 mission phases. The maps are for elemental
     ratios Mg/Si, Al/Si, S/Si, Ca/Si, and Fe/Si. The Mg/Si and Al/Si maps
     include data acquired both during solar flares and more quiescent
     &apos;Quiet Sun&apos; conditions. The dynamic range of Al/Si on Mercury is
     considerably smaller than that of Mg/Si and the errors on individual
     quiet sun Al/Si analyses are relatively large.  The other three ratio
     maps all require flare data and as a result the spatial coverage is
     more spotty.
 
     Because of the MESSENGER spacecraft elliptical orbit which achieves
     periapse over the northern hemisphere, spatial resolution is finer in the
     northern hemisphere, but coverage is more complete in the southern
     hemisphere.  Three sets of maps are provided for each element ratio:
     elemental ratio, error, and effective resolution.
 
     The maps are 1440 x 720 pixels corresponding to 1/4-degreee pixels in
     cylindrical projection centered on lat,lon=0,0. Thus, the first column
     represents longitude =-180 to -179.75 degrees, the bottom row is -90 to
     -89.75 degrees south latitude, etc. Images are 8-bit.
 
     All maps are linearly scaled such that the maximum pixel value (255)
     corresponds to a maximum value listed in the table below. Thus, to get
     the actual value from a pixel, one would multiply the pixel values by the
     maximum pixel value divided by 255.  Zero values indicate no data.
 
     Mg/Si
     xrs_map_mg_si_20150424     max =      0.782
     xrs_unc_mg_si_20150424     max =      0.149
     xrs_res_mg_si_20150424     max =       1957
 
     Al/Si
     xrs_map_al_si_20150424     max =      0.353
     xrs_unc_al_si_20150424     max =      0.084
     xrs_res_al_si_20150424     max =       1916
 
     S/Si
     xrs_map_s__si_20150424     max =      0.147
     xrs_unc_s__si_20150424     max =      0.037
     xrs_res_s__si_20150424     max =       2697
 
     Ca/Si
     xrs_map_ca_si_20150424     max =      0.316
     xrs_unc_ca_si_20150424     max =      0.077
     xrs_res_ca_si_20150424     max =       2695
 
     Fe/Si
     xrs_map_fe_si_20150424     max =      0.098
     xrs_unc_fe_si_20150424     max =      0.028
     xrs_res_fe_si_20150424     max =       2894
 
     Data selection criteria for the maps were as follows:
 
     FOV=1 or 3 data from the five Mercury Orbit mission phases only.
 
     Data which had contributions from charged particles were excluded, based
     on the count rate around 8 keV due to electron induced fluorescence of
     the collimator material, as well as derived Mg/Si and Al/Si count ratios,
     where higher count rate ratios are generally due to electron fluorescence
     of the Mg and Al filters.
 
     To improve statistical precision, quiet-Sun data (Mg/Si and Al/Si maps)
     were spatially binned such that XRS count rates acquired within a given
     spatial bin were co-added prior to derivation of elemental ratios. A
     quiet-Sun measurement was only included in the maps if the statistical
     uncertainty on Mg/Si was lower than 0.5 (absolute) and that for Al/Si
     was lower than 0.2. Only a subset of southern quiet-Sun data was
     included because there was so much coverage in the southern hemisphere,
     however, a random selection of southern quiet-Sun data from throughout
     the orbital mission period is included in the maps so as not to
     introduce any bias.
 
     When coverage included many overlapping footprints, footprint
     measurements that differed by more than 4 sigma from all others were
     excluded.
 
   Limitations
   ===========
     This is a calibrated data set.  It includes the data that are received
     from the spacecraft telemetry as well as calibration information and
     other ancillary data necessary for data analysis.  The XRS RDR maps are
     created using the calibrated XRS CDR products.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

