<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-e-v-h-grns-4-ns-ddr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER E/V/H GRNS 4 NEUTRON SPECTROMETER DDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:ns.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-grns-4-ns-ddr-v1.0__browserp_mess-e-v-h-grns-4-ns-ddr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-grns-4-ns-ddr-v1.0__browser_mess-e-v-h-grns-4-ns-ddr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-grns-4-ns-ddr-v1.0__dvo_mess-e-v-h-grns-4-ns-ddr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Goldsten, J.O., E.A. Rhodes,, W.V. Boynton, W.C. Feldman, D.J. Lawrence, J.I.
                   Trombka, D.M. Smith, L.G. Evans, J. White, N.W. Madden, P.C. Berg, G.A. Murphy,
                   R.S. Gurnee, K. Strohbehn, B.D. Williams, E.D. Schaefer, C.A. Monaco, C.P.
                   Cork, J.D. Eckels, W.O. Miller, M.T. Burks, L.B. Hagler, S.J. Deteresa, and
                   M.C. Witte, The MESSENGER Gamma-Ray and Neutron Spectrometer, Space Science
                   Reviews, 131, 339-391, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GOLDSTENETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-E/V/H-GRNS-4-NS-DDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESSENGER E/V/H GRNS 4 NEUTRON SPECTROMETER DDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2015-03-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2011-03-25</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID LAWRENCE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            D. J. LAWRENCE (APL), MESSENGER E/V/H GRNS 4 NEUTRON SPECTROMETER
            DDR V1.0, MESS-E/V/H-GRNS-4-NS-DDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2013.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The MESSENGER Neutron Spectrometer (NS) Derived Data Records
            (DDRs) consist of science and engineering data collected by the
            NS instrument.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== This data set consists of the MESSENGER Neutron
            Spectrometer (NS) &apos;derived&apos; data records (DDRs). The NS
            experiment is a neutron spectrometer designed to observe neutrons
            emitted from Mercury&apos;s surface in the energy range from 0.01
            eV to 7 MeV. There is 1 NS DDR standard data product (Neutron
            Count Rate, NS_DDR_NCR) and 1 NS DDR special data product
            (Neutron Composition, NS_DDR_NCP). The NCR data products contain
            net neutron count rates from the LG1, LG2, and BP sensors and
            uncertainties from each of these sensors. The NCP data product
            contains fast and epithermal count rates as a function of
            latitude, along with simulated count rates for the cases of no
            hydrogen and for a thick layer of 100 wt. percent water ice in
            all radar bright regions.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
   Instrument Overview
   ===================
     The MErcury Surface, Space ENvironment, GEochemistry, and Ranging
     (MESSENGER) Neutron Spectrometer (NS) sensor consists of three
     scintillators, each wrapped separately and coupled to separate
     photo-multiplier tubes. The three scintillators are sensitive to
     neutrons of different energies: thermal neutrons (0.025 - 1 eV),
     epithermal neutrons (1eV - 500 keV), and fast neutrons
     (500 keV - 7 MeV). The first and third scintillators are lithium
     (6Li)-glass scintillators (LG1 and LG2) which respond to a combination
     of thermal and epithermal neutrons. The middle scintillator is a
     borated plastic (BP) scintillator that responds only to epithermal and
     fast neutrons due to its electronics setup. The interaction of galactic
     cosmic rays (GCR) with the surface of Mercury produces neutrons, some
     of which escape the surface and produce a neutron signal that can be
     measured by the orbiting NS sensor. The measured neutron energy
     spectrum reflects the transport properties of the surface composition
     and is sensitive to depths down to about 1 m. Thermal neutrons are
     sensitive to a variety of elements, including Fe, Ti, Gd, Sm, Cl, and
     C. Epithermal neutrons are mostly sensitive to H abundance. Fast
     neutrons can provide a good measure of average atomic mass. For the
     MESSENGER mission, the NS sensor will establish and map the abundance
     of H over most of the northern hemisphere of Mercury, providing
     significant new information regarding the potential presence of water
     ice within and near permanently shaded craters near the north pole.
 
     See the NS_INST.CAT file for more information and [GOLDSTENETAL2007]
     for full details.
 
   Data Set Overview
   =================
     This data set consists of MESSENGER NS &apos;derived&apos; data records (DDRs).
     There is 1 NS DDR standard data product (Neutron Count Rate,
     NS_DDR_NCR) and 1 NS DDR special data product (Neutron Composition,
     NS_DDR_NCP).
 
     The NCR data products are derived data consisting of net (background
     subtracted) neutron count rates from each of the three NS sensors,
     namely the two lithium glass (LG) sensors and the epithermal neutron
     singles data from the borated plastic (BP) sensor.  A single DDR NCR
     data file contains the observations with a time tag corresponding to a
     given Earth day. Uncertainty values for each of these net count rates
     are also provided along with spacecraft ephemeris/geometry
     information.  This ephemeris/geometry data are the same as given in the
     NS CDR files.
 
     The NS_DDR_NCP file contains fast and epithermal count rates as a
     function of latitude, along with simulated count rates for the cases of
     no hydrogen and for a thick layer of 100 wt. percent water ice in all
     radar bright regions.
 
   Processing Overview
   ===================
     The following operations are applied to the Calibrated Data Records
     (DDRs) to arrive at the Derived Data Records (DDRs):
 
     1) Selection of valid data to eliminate times where the backgrounds
     from solar particle events are too high to enable net count rates to be
     derived.
     2) Corrections to the NS spectra for gain varations.
     3) Background subtraction from the NS spectra to arrive at the net
     neutron count rates.
 
     These corrections are not reversible such that the DDR is not directly
     derivable from the CDR dataset.  Details of the processing are given in
     the document messns_processing.pdf located in the CALIB directory.
 
   Coordinate Systems
   ==================
     For planetary orbital and flyby data, the NS-specific data also have
     two coordinate systems (in addition to standard J2000 and
     Planetocentric body fixed) for expressing spacecraft velocity and
     attitude data: the nadir fixed coordinate system and the spacecraft
     fixed coordinate system.
 
     The nadir fixed coordinate system is defined as follows:
     * The z-axis is defined as the vector from the spacecraft center to the
     flyby or orbiting planet center.
     * The nadir fixed y-axis is defined as the cross product of the nadir
     z-axis and the spacecraft velocity vector (where both are expressed in
     the J2000 coordinate system).
     * The nadir fixed x-axis is defined as the cross product of the nadir
     fixed y-axis with the nadir fixed z-axis.
 
     The spacecraft fixed coordinate system is defined as follows:
     * The spacecraft fixed x-axis is the vector normal to the NS LG1 sensor
     and is parallel to the spacecraft solar panel booms.
     * The spacecraft fixed y-axis is in the direction from the spacecraft
     down the magnetometer boom.
     * The spacecraft fixed z-axis is the viewing direction from the
     instrument deck.
 
   Data
   ====
     There is 1 NS DDR standard data product (Neutron Count Rate,
     NS_DDR_NCR) and 1 NS DDR special data product (Neutron Composition,
     NS_DDR_NCP).
 
     The NS_DDR_NCR files contain net neutron count rate data as derived
     from the LG and BP singles spectra.  The net count rates are given in
     units of counts per second for each accumulation time interval.
     Derived uncertainty values for each count rate are also provided for
     each time step.  Each NS_DDR_NCR file is organized as an ASCII text
     file and contains data collected over one Earth day.  In addition to
     the count rates, spacecraft time and geometry information associated
     with each measurement are provided.  These time and geometry values
     are the same as is given in the CDR files for each corresponding
     measurement.  Three main processing steps are carried out for the
     derivation of the net neutron count rate data.  First, data selections
     are made to exclude data taken during times of solar particle events
     when the charged particle flux is sufficiently high to affect the
     background in the NS sensors.  The times of these exclusions are given
     below.  Second, gain corrections are made to the NS spectra prior to
     deriving any net neutron counts.  Finally, background subtraction
     algorithms are applied to the NS spectra through which the next neutron
     counts are derived.  Details of the processing are given in the
     document messns_processing.pdf located in the CALIB directory.  Please
     note that DDRs were generated for data collected during the &apos;Mercury
     Orbit&apos; phase only.
 
     The general form of the NS_DDR_NCR file names is
     &apos;NS_DDR_ZZZYYYYDDDWWW.XXX,&apos; where
 
     NS       instrument identifier: represents the NS instrument.
     DDR      data product identifier: DDR
     ZZZ      data product name
                NCR - Neutron Count Rates
     YYYY     four digit year corresponding to the start-time of the first
                record in the NS data file.
     DDD      three digit day of the year corresponding to the start time of
                the first record in the NS CDR data file.
     WWW      reserved character string to use during the course of the
                mission as necessary to identify &apos;special&apos; data products.
                Nominal data products will be identified by ZZZ.
     .XXX     the file extension (.DAT for binary files, .TAB for ascii
                files).
 
     The NCP data product contains latitude-binned relative neutron count
     rates taken during the primary MESSENGER mission from 26 March 2011 to
     25 February 2012.  Specifically, these data are the exact data points
     given in Figure 2 and Figure 3A from Lawrence et al., Science, 339,
     292-296, 2013.  The delivered values include measured and simulated
     data for fast and epithermal neutron data.  The simulated data include
     two cases: one case assumes there is no hydrogen in Mercury&apos;s north
     polar radar bright regions; the other case assumes that the north polar
     radar bright regions contain 100 wt. percent H2O.
 
     The general form of the NS_DDR_NCP file names is
     &apos;NS_DDR_ZZZ.XXX,&apos; where
 
     NS       instrument identifier: represents the NS instrument.
     DDR      data product identifier: DDR
     ZZZ      data product name
                NCP - Neutron Composition Product
     .XXX     the file extension (.TAB).
 
     See NS_CDR_DDR_SIS.PDF in the DOCUMENT folder of this volume for more
     information.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
   Confidence Level Overview
   =========================
     The NS DDR data have been processed as described in the &apos;MESSENGER
     Neutron Spectrometer (NS) EDR-to-CDR-to-DDR Processing&apos; document
     (MESSNS_PROCESSING.PDF, CALIB directory). Data presented here are an
     accurate representation of the NS data as processed from the CDR files,
     where the processing includes data selection, gain correction, and
     background subtraction.
 
   Review
   ======
     The NS DDR was reviewed internally by the NS team prior to release to
     the PDS.  PDS also performed an external review of the NS DDR.
 
   Data Coverage and Quality
   =========================
     Data reported are the &apos;derived&apos; data received from the spacecraft
     during the the following mission phases: &apos;Mercury Orbit&apos;, &apos;Mercury
     Orbit Year 2&apos;, and &apos;Mercury Orbit Year 3&apos;. These mission phases are
     defined as:
 
                           Start time         End time
     Phase Name            Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)
     -----------------     -----------------  -----------------
     Mercury Orbit          4 Mar 2011 (063)  17 Mar 2012 (077)
     Mercury Orbit Year 2  18 Mar 2012 (078)  17 Mar 2013 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 3  18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)
 
     PDS delivery 9 included NS DDR data acquired from March 25, 2011 to
     March 25, 2012.
 
     During this data delivery phase, the NS was shut off for nine
     consecutive days when the MESSENGER spacecraft passed through its first
     long eclipse period. The specific off period was from May 24, 2011
     21:34:49 to June 3, 2011 0:17:49.
 
     Also during this data delivery phase, the high voltage (HV) to the LG
     and BP sensors was shut down six times during spacecraft thrusting
     maneuvers. Each time, the HV was shut down for approximately four hours
     while the spacecraft was near apoapsis. The specific times for the HV
     shut down are:
 
     June 15, 2011 16:12:08 - June 15, 2011 20:30:16;
     July 26, 2011 17:40:16 - July 26, 2011 21:55:16;
     September 7, 2011 11:38:16 - September 7, 2011 16:05:50;
     October 24, 2011 18:29:00 - October 24, 2011 23:16:00;
     December 5, 2011 12:36:00 - December 5, 2011 17:18:00;
     March 2, 2012 22:09:22 - March 3, 2012 02:47:54.
 
     The HV to the LG and BP sensors was shut down during a large solar
     particle event when the NS sensors were safed because of the large
     charged particle flux.  The times for this HV shut down period were:
     March 7, 2012 0:24:42 - March 12, 2012 15:50:42.
 
     PDS delivery 11 included NS DDR data acquired from March 26, 2012
     through March 17, 2013.
 
     The NS HV for the BP sensor was shut down twice from September 2012 to
     March 2013: first from September 20, 2012 at 09:40 UTC to September 24,
     2012 at 17:38 UTC when the NS BP sensor went into safe mode due to an
     energetic particle event; second on March 16, 2013 from 06:53 UTC to
     08:00 UTC when the NS BP sensor went into safe mode due to an energetic
     particle event.
 
     PDS delivery 13 includes NS DDR data acquired from March 18, 2013 to
     March 17, 2014.
 
     From March 18, 2013 to September 17, 2013 the NS HV was shut down six
     times into safe mode due to high rates from energetic particles:
     1) April 24, 2013 to April 25, 2013;
     2) May 2, 2013, 8:45 UTC to May 2, 2013, 9:16 UTC;
     3) May 21, 2013, 8:57 UTC to May 21, 2013, 9:32 UTC;
     4) May 21, 2013, 17:02 UTC to May 21, 2013, 17:33 UTC;
     5) June 21, 2013 to June 24, 2013;
     6) August 19, 2013 to August 22, 2013.
 
     From September 18, 2013 to March 17, 2014 the NS HV for the BP and/or
     LG sensor was shut down 6 times:
     1) for approximately two hours on October 25, 2013; 2) October 28, 2013,
     16:00 UTC to October 29, 2013 02:00 UTC; 3) For less than an hour on
     November 5, 2013; 4) For less than an hour on December 14, 2013;
     5) December 26, 2013 07:00 UTC to December 31, 2013 20:00 UTC;
     6) For less than an hour on Jan 25, 2014.
 
   Quality and Limitations
   =======================
     This data set has been processed as described in the &apos;MESSENGER Neutron
     Spectrometer (NS) EDR-to-CDR-to-DDR Processing&apos; document. All data have
     been successfully processed through the NS data processing codes and
     all data are found to be nominal.  Other than the scheduled &apos;instrument
     off&apos; periods described above, no data gaps or corrupted data have been
     identified for any of the NS operational periods. Although there may be
     some data not identified as missing or corrupted, such data should be
     minimal and a very small fraction of the available data.
 
     Regarding data quality, the primary factor that affects the quality of
     the NS data are solar particle events.  The table below lists the times
     during the data delivery period where it was determined that there were
     fluxes of solar energetic particles high enough to affect the data
     background.  The columns of the table are:  Name (numeric label for the
     solar particle event); start time in UTC indicating the starting time
     of the solar particle event; stop time in UTC indicating the stopping
     time of the solar particle event; type (All stands for all sensors, LG1
     or LG2 stands for lithium glass sensor 1 or 2 only; BPS stands for
     borated plastic scintillator only).
 
     Name    Start Time             End Time                Type
     ------------------------------------------------------------
     001     03/24/2011 11:48:19    03/24/2011 18:50:03     All
     002     03/25/2011 05:52:23    03/25/2011 10:15:36     All
     003     03/25/2011 23:01:18    03/26/2011 04:28:38     LG2
     004     03/30/2011 17:00:00    03/30/2011 22:00:00     All
     005     04/04/2011 09:48:40    04/04/2011 13:56:56     LG2
     006     05/24/2011 22:00:00    06/03/2011 03:45:00     All
     007     06/04/2011 06:13:13    06/10/2011 22:00:00     BPS
     008     06/04/2011 06:13:13    06/12/2011 07:00:00     LG1
     009     06/04/2011 06:13:13    06/15/2011 22:00:00     All
     010     08/02/2011 05:39:24    08/02/2011 18:24:21     All
     011     08/04/2011 03:33:28    08/05/2011 17:00:00     All
     012     08/09/2011 07:00:00    08/10/2011 03:00:00     All
     013     09/05/2011 05:39:00    09/08/2011 14:00:00     LG2
     014     09/06/2011 04:45:00    09/06/2011 07:10:00     BPS
     015     09/07/2011 04:01:00    09/07/2011 06:32:00     BPS
     016     09/07/2011 18:58:00    09/08/2011 06:00:00     BPS
     017     09/08/2011 22:20:00    09/10/2011 02:00:00     All
     018     09/22/2011 11:25:40    09/24/2011 08:00:00     All
     019     10/04/2011 12:53:49    10/06/2011 02:55:42     All
     020     10/14/2011 12:56:57    10/15/2011 10:13:16     All
     021     10/17/2011 08:10:30    10/17/2011 11:38:16     LG2
     022     11/03/2011 22:50:16    11/06/2011 02:00:00     All
     023     11/09/2011 12:56:40    11/09/2011 18:45:00     All
     024     11/17/2011 20:52:37    11/18/2011 16:50:00     All
     025     12/14/2011 14:20:00    12/14/2011 22:30:00     All
     026     12/25/2011 17:48:00    12/26/2011 15:55:00     All
     027     01/02/2012 14:54:00    01/03/2012 13:50:00     All
     028     01/23/2012 05:36:00    02/06/2012 00:01:00     All
     029     03/03/2012 20:11:00    03/17/2012 00:00:00     All
     030     04/05/2012 21:13:05    04/06/2012 00:14:30     All
     031     04/09/2012 11:04:13    04/09/2012 17:17:43     All
     032     04/26/2012 08:25:36    04/26/2012 12:10:43     All
     033     04/27/2012 16:00:00    04/28/2012 02:58:00     All
     034     05/17/2012 02:32:33    05/19/2012 02:37:40     All
     035     05/26/2012 20:16:48    05/30/2012 02:42:00     All
     036     06/28/2012 16:04:00    06/29/2012 17:00:00     All
     037     07/01/2012 18:58:00    07/02/2012 02:00:00     All
     038     07/02/2012 10:18:10    07/02/2012 18:09:00     All
     039     07/03/2012 03:03:15    07/03/2012 11:04:13     All
     040     07/12/2012 16:26:11    07/14/2012 19:30:00     All
     041     07/17/2012 17:00:00    07/21/2012 02:00:00     All
     042     07/23/2012 03:52:00    07/29/2012 12:00:00     All
     043     07/30/2012 18:34:28    07/30/2012 21:59:08     All
     044     07/31/2012 21:47:30    08/01/2012 03:00:00     All
     045     09/08/2012 11:14:27    09/08/2012 17:33:04     All
     046     09/19/2012 10:48:00    09/25/2012 02:00:00     All
     047     09/28/2012 09:50:00    10/01/2012 02:00:00     All
     048     10/08/2012 12:22:25    10/09/2012 09:52:50     All
     049     10/14/2012 00:30:30    10/14/2012 20:27:11     All
     050     10/23/2012 02:57:19    10/23/2012 03:27:48     All
     051     10/26/2012 11:29:47    10/26/2012 19:51:10     All
     052     11/08/2012 01:45:18    11/08/2012 09:47:18     All
     053     11/18/2012 03:33:20    11/18/2012 10:06:41     All
     054     11/21/2012 13:42:49    11/22/2012 03:54:25     All
     055     02/05/2013 08:10:15    02/05/2013 11:09:20     All
     056     03/15/2013 17:58:39    03/17/2013 04:40:28     All
     057     04/11/2013 05:52:06    04/13/2013 02:12:05     All
     058     04/21/2013 06:33:02    04/23/2013 02:00:00     All
     059     04/24/2013 21:13:05    04/26/2013 12:00:00     All
     060     04/27/2013 21:43:47    04/28/2013 02:06:58     All
     061     04/28/2013 12:10:43    04/28/2013 14:59:34     All
     062     05/10/2013 18:34:28    05/11/2013 02:00:00     All
     063     05/13/2013 15:30:16    05/14/2013 13:37:42     All
     064     05/15/2013 03:28:50    05/15/2013 05:16:17     All
     065     05/31/2013 19:40:00    06/01/2013 02:37:40     All
     066     06/21/2013 03:08:22    06/25/2013 02:00:00     All
     067     08/19/2013 22:29:50    08/22/2013 22:00:00     All
     068     10/05/2013 06:27:55    10/07/2013 22:00:00     All
     069     10/11/2013 06:33:02    10/16/2013 05:16:17     All
     070     10/20/2013 06:02:20    10/20/2013 13:01:53     All
     071     10/22/2013 20:32:00    10/23/2013 20:37:16     All
     072     10/25/2013 07:29:00    10/27/2013 12:00:00     All
     073     10/28/2013 04:09:00    10/31/2013 12:00:00     All
     074     11/02/2013 04:35:00    11/03/2013 06:00:00     All
     075     11/04/2013 05:46:00    11/05/2013 04:25:00     All
     076     11/05/2013 21:43:00    11/05/2013 23:01:00     All
     077     11/07/2013 10:48:00    11/09/2013 22:00:00     All
     078     11/19/2013 09:57:00    11/21/2013 12:00:00     All
     079     11/29/2013 03:59:00    11/29/2013 20:07:00     All
     080     11/30/2013 02:37:00    12/02/2013 03:23:00     All
     081     12/05/2013 11:34:00    12/05/2013 20:53:00     All
     082     12/13/2013 20:06:00    12/15/2013 12:00:00     All
     083     12/26/2013 03:13:00    12/31/2013 22:00:00     All
     084     01/06/2014 07:19:05    01/11/2014 22:00:00     All
     085     01/22/2014 03:59:32    01/23/2014 07:00:00     All
     086     01/27/2014 22:00:00    01/31/2014 05:52:00     All
     087     02/11/2014 03:03:15    02/11/2014 21:02:00     All
     088     02/12/2014 06:07:27    02/12/2014 12:10:00     All
     089     02/14/2014 15:45:00    02/15/2014 12:32:00     All
     090     02/18/2014 00:29:45    02/19/2014 04:00:00     All
     091     02/20/2014 07:00:00    02/21/2014 06:00:00     All
     092     02/25/2014 03:44:11    03/05/2014 06:00:00     All
     093     03/14/2014 21:28:00    03/14/2014 12:00:00     All
 
     It has been determined that the deadtime correction for nominal solar
     quiet conditions is minimal and is therefore not being applied.
     Deadtime remains an important uncorrected effect for periods of intense
     solar activity.  However, those periods of intense solar activity,
     which are listed above, do not provide valid planetary data and are not
     used in the normal planetary data processing.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

