<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.co-ssa-radar-5-bidr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CASSINI ORBITER SSA RADAR 5 BIDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:radar.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.titan::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.co-ssa-radar-5-bidr-v1.0__browserp_co-ssa-radar-5-bidr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.co-ssa-radar-5-bidr-v1.0__browser_co-ssa-radar-5-bidr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Bugayevskiy, L.M., and J.P. Snyder, Map projections: A reference manual, Taylor
                   &amp; Francis, London and Bristol, Pennsylvania, 328 pp., 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BUGAYEVSKIY-SNYD1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Elachi, C., M.D. Allison, L. Borgarelli, P. Encrenaz, E. Im, M.A. Janssen,
                   W.T.K. Johnson, R.L. Kirk, R.D. Lorenz, J.I. Lunine, D.O. Muhleman, S.J. Ostro,
                   G. Picardi, F. Posa, C.G. Rapley, L.E. Roth, R. Seu, L.A. Soderblom, S.
                   Vetrella, S.D. Wall, C.A. Wood and H.A. Zebker, RADAR: The Cassini Titan RADAR
                   Mapper, Space Science Reviews, Vol. 115, No. 1-4, pp. 71-110, 2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ELACHIETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Elachi, C., S. Wall, M. Allison, Y. Anderson, R. Boehmer, P. Callahan, P.
                   Encrenaz, E. Flamini, G. Franceschetti, Y. Gim, G. Hamilton, S. Hensley, M.
                   Janssen, W. Johnson, K. Kelleher, R. Kirk, R. Lopes, R. Lorenz, J. Lunine, D.
                   Muhleman, S. Ostro, F. Paganelli, G. Picardi, F. Posa, L. Roth, R. Seu, S.
                   Shaffer, L. Soderblom, B. Stiles, E. Stofan, S. Vetrella, R. West, C. Wood, L.
                   Wye, and H. Zebker, Cassini Radar Views the Surface of Titan, Science, Vol.
                   308, No. 5724, pp. 970-974, 2005.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ELACHIETAL2005</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Eliason, E.M., 1997. Production of digital image models using the ISIS system.
                   Lunar Planet. Sci., XXVIII pp. 331-332, Lunar and Planetary Institute, Houston.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ELIASON1997</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Gaddis, L. et al., 1997. An overview of the Integrated Software for Imaging
                   Spectrometers (ISIS). Lunar Planet. Sci., XXVIII pp. 387-388, Lunar and
                   Planetary Institute, Houston.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GADDISETAL1997</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Greeley, R., and R.M. Batson, Planetary Mapping, Cambridge Univ. Press,
                   Cambridge, 296 pp., 1990.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GREELEY-BATSON1990</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Seidelmann, P.K., V.K. Abalakin, M. Bursa, M.E. Davies, C. de Bergh, J.H.
                   Lieske, J. Oberst, J.L. Simon, E.M. Standish, P. Stooke, and P.C. Thomas,
                   Report of the IAU/IAG working group on cartographic coordinates and rotational
                   elements of the planets and satellites: 2000, Celestial Mechanics and Dynamical
                   Astronomy, 82, 83-111, 2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SEIDELMANNETAL2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Snyder, J.P., Map Projections - A Working Manual, U.S. Geol. Surv. Professional
                   Paper 1395, 1987.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SNYDER1987</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Torson, J., and K. Becker, 1997. ISIS: A software architecture for processing
                   planetary images. Lunar Planet. Sci., XXVIII, pp. 143-1444, Lunar and Planetary
                   Institute, Houston.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TORSON-BECKER1997</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Yang, Q.H., J.P. Snyder, and W.R. Tobler, Map projection transformations:
                   Principles and applications, Taylor &amp; Francis, London and Bristol,
                   Pennsylvania, 367 pp., 2000.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.YANGETAL2000</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CO-SSA-RADAR-5-BIDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CASSINI ORBITER SSA RADAR 5 BIDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-06-17</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-300T10:20:10.828Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>Bryan W. Stiles</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>Unknown</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Cassini Basic Image Data Record product is a gridded map of
            Titan produced from synthetic aperture radar data.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>Unknown</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
* Data Set Overview
 
Full resolution basic image data records (BIDR) consist of SAR
(synthetic aperture radar) normalized backscatter data (sigma0) at 13.78
GHz (Ku band) acquired in one pass of the Cassini spacecraft near Titan.
The primary image data and the additional &apos;backplanes&apos; of geometry and
beam mask are provided at 256 pixels per degree on Titan&apos;s surface
(approximately 175 m per pixel).
 
The USGS will produce 128-pixel/degree versions of all the floating
point BIDR images (backplanes and primary image).  USGS will also
produce 8-bit versions of primary (incidence angle corrected sigma0)
image BIDRs at 256, 128, 32, 8, and 2 pixel per degree resolutions.
 
The primary image data and the backplanes are provided on a rectangular
grid which is an oblique cylindrical coordinate system whose equator
is the nadir track of the spacecraft on the current pass and the zero
of longitude is the point of closest approach.  Two of the backplanes
are longitude and latitude in standard Titan coordinates.
 
A particular index pair specifying a location in the data grid provides
data for the same point for each full resolution file and similarly for
the averaged 128 pixel per degree files (primary image and backplanes).
 
For more information about the format and content of the BIDR files,
see the Cassini Radar Basic Image Data Record Software Interface
Specification, JPL D-27889.  A copy of the document is located on
this volume as file BIDRSIS.PDF in the DOCUMENT directory.
 
 
* Parameters
 
The original image data and the 128 pixel per degree data are floating-
point values of sigma0 in linear units (not dB).  Lower resolution images
are 1-byte scaled values in dB.
 
The data are
 
  (1) Primary dataset (e.g., incidence angle corrected sigma0) in
      32-bit floating-point format (linear scale values, not in dB).
 
  (2) Sigma0 without incidence angle correction in 32-bit floating
      point format (linear scale values, not in dB).
 
  (3) Incidence angle, floating point values in degrees.
 
  (4) Latitude, floating point values in degrees.
 
  (5) Longitude (positive-west), floating point values in degrees.
 
  (6) Beam mask, 8 bit values.
 
  (7) Number of looks, 32 bit integer values.
 
 
* Processing
 
The encoded raw active mode data in the Burst Ordered Data Product
(LBDR) files is decoded and processed into SAR images by the Cassini
RADAR Instrument Team.  Each of the five beams is treated separately
by typical SAR processing (azimuth and range compression).  The image
strip is then produced by selecting the best beam for each pixel.  The
selection is performed by choosing the beam with the most looks.  In
the event of a tie the highest SNR beam is chosen.
 
The pixel values in the primary BIDR images will be normalized
backscatter cross-section values corrected for incidence angle effects.
The incidence angle correction algorithm is TBD and will be determined
jointly by the Cassini RADAR Instrument and Science Teams after enough
data is acquired to estimate the variation of sigma0 due to incidence
angle over the surface of Titan.  Until the final correction algorithm is
determined, the primary BIDR image will be computed with a preliminary
incidence angle correction.  The exact form of this correction can be
found in the PDS label for the primary BIDR image file.
 
These files will be converted into 8-bit formats at various resolutions by
members of the Astrogeology Team of the U. S. Geological Survey (USGS) in
Flagstaff, Arizona.  The processing used to produce the 8-bit formats is
the same as that done for the Cassini Radar Digital Map products as
described in the Cassini Radar Digital Map Software Interface
Specification.
 
 
* Data
 
See Parameters.
 
 
* Ancillary Data
 
No ancillary data beyond the collection of BIDR files is needed to
interpret the images.
 
 
* Coordinate System
 
The oblique cylindrical coordinate system is fully described in the
data set map projection catalog DSMAP.CAT, which is located in the
CATALOG directory on this volume.
 
 
* Software
 
No software is provided within this volume.  Cassini BIDR files can be read
using PDS image handling software or by using the Integrated Software for
Imagers and Spectrometers (ISIS) developed by the Astrogeology Team of the
U.S.  Geological Survey.  ISIS may be of use for scientists wishing to
read, display, manipulate, and analyze BIDR data.  ISIS including C and
FORTRAN source code is in the public domain and versions configured to run
under Solaris or Red Hat Linux may be obtained by qualified researchers
from (http://astrogeology.wr.usgs.gov/Projects/ISIS).  Documentation for
the system is available from the same website.
 
 
* Media/Format
 
The data are provided on media as determined by PDS.  The BIDR data files
are ZIPPED as described in the PDS standard.  Detached labels are provided
for the ZIPPED files; the ZIPPED files also include their attached labels.
Detailed formats are defined within the attached labels of the files and
in the Cassini Radar Basic Image Data Record Software Interface
Specification.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
* Confidence Level Overview
 
The BIDR data set contains synthetic aperture radar (SAR) images and
coregistered backplanes of geometry and beam mask.  (See DATA_SET_DESC
below.)  The data has been calibrated and empirical range and doppler
corrections have been applied in order to minimize image artifacts due
to errors in pointing and emphemeris knowledge.  The images are elongated
strips.  The long (along track) dimension corresponds to the motion of the
spacecraft during the observation.  The short (cross track) dimension
corresponds to the combined width of the 5 radar beams.
 
 
* Review
 
BIDR data will be validated internally by the Cassini Radar Team prior
to each release of data to the PDS.  The overall data set organization
will also be peer reviewed once by the PDS prior to the release of the
first volume.
 
 
* Data Coverage and Quality
 
Currently 20 SAR observations comprising roughly 20% of the surface of
Titan are planned for the nominal Cassini mission.  BIDR data will be
obtained for each such observation.  SAR observations of Titan occur
at irregular intervals throughout the mission.  Each observation is
nominally 40 minutes long.  Shorter-duration cases occur whenever RADAR
shares a Titan observation with another Cassini instrument.  The BIDR
data set contains SAR image data only.  Other Cassini RADAR data such
as altimetry, scatterometry, and radiometry are available in the SBDR,
LBDR, and ABDR data sets.
 
The SAR image pixel values are normalized radar cross-section, a unitless
quantity related to the slope, roughness, and composition of the observed
surface.  We currently estimate the accuracy of this quantity to be + or -
3 dB absolute and + or - 2 dB relative for the majority of image pixels.
(See image artifacts discussion in the Limitations section.)  The full
resolution BIDRs are oversampled to insure no loss of information content.
The intrinsic spatial resolution of the data varies from 300 m for the
portion of the swath obtained at closest approach to 1 - 2 km at the
extreme ends of the swath.  Location error of the pixels is dominated
by ephemeris and pointing knowledge errors and is expected to be less
than 5 km throughout the mission.
 
 
* Limitations
 
Ephemeris error is expected to improve throughout the mission.  Since
there is no plan to recompute the ephemeris of previous observations as
new measurements are obtained, however, earlier observations may have
poorer location accuracy.
 
The dominant calibration error term is error in our knowledge of the
gain of the attenuators in the receiver.  Engineering tests are currently
planned to improve our knowledge of the attenuator gains.
 
SAR images are prone to artifacts such as:
 
1) poor calibrations at the edge of the beams
2) extreme noisiness in regions with a small number of overlapping
   measurements (looks)
3) scalloping and antenna calibration misalignment due to errors in
   ephemeris and pointing knowledge
4) distorted imagery near the ends of the swath due to non-optimal
   pointing while turning to make altimeter measurements.
 
Artifacts of type 2 and 4 are unavoidable.  Types 1 and 3 can be minimized
by empirically correcting range and doppler biases in the data.  We have
sought to minimize the occurrence of these artifacts in the BIDR images,
but there are still noticeable seams between beams and poor calibration
near the edges of the swath.  The artifact minimization algorithm does not
attempt to use the estimated range and doppler biases to correct ephemeris
or pointing.  For this reason location errors of a few kilometers are
possible.
 
The TA Titan Observation on October 25, 2004, was the first SAR
observation.  It has some special features.  The first (earliest) third
of the swath has noticeable scalloping in the along track dimension and
is noisier than the rest of the image.  This portion of the swath has
non-optimal viewing geometry and a small number of looks due to pointing
constraints for other Cassini instruments.  A substantial portion of the
last (latest) third of the swath is in low resolution SAR mode.  This
mode coarsens the cross track resolution of the image by a factor of 2.
It was used on TA in order to accommodate conservative SNR expectations.
In the same region of the image, an experiment was performed in which the
data compression technique typically used by SAR was turned off.  Due to
data volume and data rate constraints this resulted in fewer looks and
noisier data.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

