<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ro-a-rpclap-2-ast2-edited-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ROSETTA-ORBITER LUTETIA RPCLAP 2 AST2 EDITED V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.international_rosetta_mission::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.ro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rpclap.ro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.21_lutetia::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ro-a-rpclap-2-ast2-edited-v1.0__browserp_ro-a-rpclap-2-ast2-edited-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Edberg, N.J.T. et al., Simultaneous measurements of Martian plasma boundaries
                   by Rosetta and Mars Express, Planetary and Space Science, Volume 57, Issue 8-9,
                   1085-1096, July 2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.EDBERGETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Eriksson, A.I. et al., RPC-LAP: The Rosetta Langmuir probe instrument, Space
                   Sci. Rev., 128(1-4), 729-744, Feb. 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ERIKSSONETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>RO-A-RPCLAP-2-AST2-EDITED-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ROSETTA-ORBITER LUTETIA RPCLAP 2 AST2 EDITED V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2012-01-13</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2010-05-10T00:00:00.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2010-09-11T00:00:00.000Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>REINE GILL</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Eriksson, A.I., R. Gill and L. Dackborn, Rosetta RPC-LAP archive
            of edited data from the Lutetia flyby,
            RO-A-RPCLAP-2-AST2-EDITED-V1.0, ESA Planetary Science Archive,
            2013.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This dataset contains EDITED raw data from Rosetta RPC-LAP,
            gathered during the flyby of asteroid Lutetia.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This dataset contains EDITED raw data from Rosetta RPC-LAP,
            acquired during the flyby of asteroid 21 Lutetia.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
Data Set Overview
=================
 
Contents:
A. Operations overview
B. Dataset status
C. Scientific use
 
A. Operations overview
----------------------
 
This dataset contains Rosetta LAP data from the Rosetta flyby of
asteroid 21 Lutetia.
 
Operation dates: July 7 - 13, 2010
Objective: science, diagnostics
Environment: solar wind at 2.7 AU
Scientific potential of LAP data acquired: Good.
 
Description of operations:
 
The LAP operations are further described in the relevant operations
report, IRFU-ROS-OPR-LUT in the DOCUMENT/FLIGHT_REPORTS directory
of this archive.
 
LAP was on during the full Lutetia flyby, monitoring the solar wind
density variations through the measurement of the probe-to-spacecraft
potential most of the time, with some operations also in Langmuir
probe sweep mode to provide information on photoemission.
 
From CA-2h50min to CA+3h10min, LAP was in burst mode with higher telemetry
rate, sampling the probe-to-spacecraft potential at 57.8 s-1. Outside
this time span, LAP had normal telemetry rate, usually sampling at
0.9 s-1.  In both modes, LAP also produces shorter records at 18.75 kHz
sampling typically every 32 s (burst mode) or 160 s (normal mode).
 
One hour after closest approach, LAP handed over probe 2 to MIP for use in
the MIP LDL (Long Debye Length) mode. During this period, the only
LAP data available derives from probe 1. More LDL operations were run
at the end of operations.
 
Operations were fully nominal. The LAP data acquired are good and
scientifically useful, though any user must take great care of the
limitations set by the varying pointing, the tenuous plasmas, and
the spacecraft-plasma interaction. In particular, the large
pointing variations at closest approach make any data analysis
here extremely difficult and prone to spurious effects.
 
 
B. Dataset status
-----------------
 
This dataset contains scientifically useful data from the Rosetta
RPC-LAP instrument. The data contained are primary instrument data,
calibrated to physical units (volts and amperes) and with instrumental
offsets removed. See the caveats in Section C below for data use.
 
The main differences of this version 1.0 to the version previously
available on the PSA are:
- Addition of geometry files (see EAICD for details).
- Major documentation upgrade, particularly the EAICD.
- Bug affecting some bias values corrected.
- Bug affecting truncated 20-bit voltage measurements corrected.
 
 
C. Scientific use
-----------------
 
The data can be used for scientific analysis, but this requires some
familiarity with this type of data. At a later stage, a DERIVED data
archive will be delivered, providing directly useful scientific
quantities (e.g. plasma density, wave spectra, electron temperature).
 
Caveats:
 
a. For probe-to-spacecraft potential (Vps) time series: this is a commonly
   used proxy for the plasma density in tenuous plasmas. However, because the
   perturbations from the solar panels, the wake formed behind the s/c and
   solar panels in e.g. the solar wind, and the photoelectron cloud around
   the spacecraft are all sensitive to the probe location, Vps can be used
   as a density proxy only during intervals of constant pointing. See the
   paper by [EDBERGETAL2009] (&apos;Simultaneous measurements of the Martian plasma
   environment by Rosetta and Mars Express&apos;, Planet. Space Sci., 57,
   1085-1096, 2009. doi:10.1016/j.pss.2008.10.016) for an example of how
   Vps may be used as a plasma density proxy. Perturbations from wake
   and photoemission have been studied by Sjogren (report available at
   http://www.space.irfu.se/exjobb/2009_alex_sjogren/).
b. For the same reasons, the probe bias sweeps are also sensitive to
   the spacecraft pointing. However, for all sweeps
   obtained prior to the comet phase, except some acquired in Earth&apos;s
   plasmasphere, the ion contribution to the data is so low that the
   photoemission saturation current can be obtained at all angles for
   which the probe is sunlit. Note however that the probe may be
   partially shadowed by its supporting rod (the stub), and that
   surface inhomogeneities may cause the photoemission to vary
   also with the pointing.
c. For all sweeps obtained prior to the comet phase, except some
   acquired in Earth&apos;s plasmasphere, the dominating contributions to
   the probe current are probe photoemission (at negative bias voltage)
   and collection of photoelectrons emitted by the spacecraft and
   solar panels (at positive bias voltage). Hence, probe sweep data
   can be interpreted in terms of local plasma parameters only in the
   Earth&apos;s plasmasphere. The main reasons for occasionally running
   such sweeps in other environments, e.g. the solar wind and the
   Earth&apos;s magnetosphere, are to gather data for investigation of
   spacecraft-plasma-probe interactions and to monitor probe
   photoemission.
d. It is also necessary to only compare data acquired at the same
   bias. This is why data are presented as (current, voltage) pairs.
e. There sometimes is an unexplained slope in the sweep data at negative
   bias, in the photoemission dominated region. This means an uncertainty
   to the data, and the details of this are yet unknown. Please see
   discussion in the latest version of the operations report,
   IRFU-ROS-OPR-LUT_Vxx, available in the DOCUMENTS/FLIGHT_REPORTS
   of this archive.
f. The bias values in the files, current and voltage alike, is not
   measured but constructed from the instrument command log and known
   modes. Bias settings changes therefore show up in the data files
   when a bias command is issued, while it can be seen in the data
   that it really takes effect 2-3 seconds later. This caveat does
   not apply to probe bias sweeps.
 
 
Parameters
==========
 
Primary data:
 
1. Probe-to-spacecraft potential time series, measured at controlled
   bias current.
   Available at two time resolutions:
   - Sampled at 57.8 Hz, further downsampled to typically 0.9 Hz when
     not in burst mode, quasi-continuous data with short gaps every
     32 s.
   - Sampled at 18.75 kHz, in brief snapshots repeated with
     cycle which is a multiple of 32 s (typically between 32 and 160 s)
2. Probe current measured at controlled bias voltage.
   Available in three varieties:
   - Probe bias voltage sweeps. Bias voltage stepped, probe current measured,
     duration a few seconds, repeated with a cycle which is a multiple of 32s.
   - Sampled at 57.8 Hz, further downsampled to typically 0.9 Hz when
     not in burst mode, quasi-continuous data with short gaps every
     32 s.
   - Sampled at 18.75 kHz, in brief snapshots repeated with
     cycle which is a multiple of 32 s (typically between 32 and 160 s).
   - In addition, there are a few calibration sweeps taken with the
     probe disconnected to evaluate instrument offsets. These are used
     in the preparation of the CALIBRATED data but have no scientific
     value on their own. Data from these are included in the EDITED data.
3. Housekeeping data. These are only included with the EDITED archive
   and consist mainly of instrument digital status. They have no
   direct scientific value on their own.
 
      Processing
      ==========
Processing of the CALIBRATED data involves the following steps:
 
1. Time tagging.
2. Determination of instrument offsets from instrument calibration
   runs (operational macro 0x104). This is done by a stand-alone
   application. The resulting offsets are stored in the CALIB
   directory as (bias, offset) pairs in TM units.
3. Compensation of probe current measurements for instrument offsets,
   using the most recently determined of the offset calibration files
   of step 2 above.
4. For each measured value (volts or amperes), the corresponding bias
   value (amperes or volts, respectively) is added to the data. All
   data are thus presented as (current, voltage) pairs, where the bias
   is not measured but reconstructed from the instrument command history
   (see Caveat f above).
5. Generation of table files and corresponding PDS label files.
 
      Data
      ====
All data are presented as ASCII tables with stand-alone PDS labels.
The content of the data is described in each label. There is one
file for every acquisition period (32 s in duration) and data type,
meaning there is a large number of files.
 
The files names indicate the data content, as described in Section
3.1.4 of the EAICD. In brief, the convention is as follows:
 
File name: RPCLAPYYMMDD_AAAa_bcdefghxx.EXT
 
YYMMDD = year, month and day, all with two digits.
AAA = Alphanumeric counter reseting at zero every new day.
a    = Type, T=20 bit ADC, S=16 bit ADC, H = Houskeeping
b    = Format, R=Edited Raw C=Calibrated D=Derived
c    = Instrument mode
       E = E-Field (Current bias and voltage measurments)
       D = Density (Voltage bias and current measurments
d    = Bias mode, S=Sweeping B=Constant Bias
e    = Sensor: 1 = Probe 1, 2 = Probe 2, or 3 = Derived from 1 and 2
f    = Analog filters, 8 = 8 Khz 4 = 4 Khz
g    = Telemetry rate, M = Minimum N = Normal B = Burst
h    = For science data this character is always an S.
x    = For contingency, not present if not needed.
 
Example:
 
EXT is either LBL or TAB. Note that the alphanumeric counter is
independently generated for EDITED and CALIBRATED archives, so
EDITED and CALIBRATED data from the same time do not necessarily
reside in files with similar (except for the b = R or C above)
names.
 
 
      Ancillary Data
      ==============
 
For any scientific analysis, needed ancillary information would
be spacecraft position and attitude. This can be found in the daily
geometry files provided with the data.
 
 
Coordinate System
=================
The geometry files provide positions and velocities related to the
ECLIPJ2000 axes directions, centred in the sun or in the target body.
The spacecraft pointing is specified by the transformation matrix
between ECLIPJ2000 and the s/c coordinate axes.
 
 
Software
========
N/A
 
 
Media/Format
============
Electronic transfer
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
UNK
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

