<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mgn-v-rdrs-5-dim-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MGN V RDRS DERIVED DIGITAL IMAGE MAP DATA RECORD V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.magellan::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mgn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rdrs.mgn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgn-v-rdrs-5-dim-v1.0__browser_mgn-v-rdrs-5-dim-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgn-v-rdrs-5-dim-v1.0__dvo_imaging_mgn-v-rdrs-5-dim-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kirk, R. L., K. B. Edwards, H. F. Morgan, T. L. Stoewe, Global
                   Magellan-Image Map of Venus at Full Resolution (abstract), Lunar Planetary
                   Science, 24, 805-806, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KIRKETAL1993A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kirk, R. L., H. F. Morgan, J. F. Russell, Cartography of Venus with
                   Magellan Data (abstract), Lunar Planetary Science, 24, 807, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KIRKETAL1993B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Planetary Data System Standards Reference, Jet Propulsion Laboratory Document
                   D-7669, Part 2, 20 November 1992
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PDSSR1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MGN-V-RDRS-5-DIM-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MGN V RDRS DERIVED DIGITAL IMAGE MAP DATA RECORD V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1994-06-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1989-05-04</start_time>
        <stop_time>1994-10-12</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>HAIG F. MORGAN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Magellan Radar Full Resolution Global Mosaic of Venus
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains the Magellan the FMAP, a full-resolution
            (75 meters/pixel) global mosaic, produced by the U.S. Geological
            Survey from Magellan F-BIDR data. The complete dataset consists
            of 340 quadrangles in Sinusoidal equal-area projection.
            Quadrangles extend approximately 12 degrees in latitude, except
            for those between 84 and 90 degrees North and South. Quadrangles
            near the equator extend 12 degrees in longitude longitudinal
            extent is increased to maintain a roughly constant number of
            samples.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The FMAP is a full-resolution (75 meters/pixel) global mosaic
      produced by the U.S.  Geological Survey from Magellan F-BIDR
      data.  The complete dataset consists of 340 quadrangles in
      Sinusoidal equal-area projection.  Quadrangles extend
      approximately 12 degrees in latitude, except for those between
      84 and 90 degrees North and South.  Quadrangles near the
      equator extend 12 degrees in longitude; at higer latitudes, the
      longitudinal extent is increased to maintain a roughly constant
      number of samples.  The data between 84 and 90 degrees North is
      also available in Polar Stereographic projection on a separate
      volume.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      N/A
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      Cosmetic techniques (spatial filtration and blending) have been
      used to remove seams between adjacent F-BIDRs caused by
      radiometric artifacts.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      N/A
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      N/A
 
 
    Software
    ========
      Refer to the SOFTINFO.TXT file in the SOFTWARE directory on
      this CD-ROM volume for information on the software provided
      with this data set.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The FMAP dataset will be delivered to the Magellan Project (or
      its sucessor) using CD-ROM media.  Formats will be based on
      standards for such products established by the Planetary Data
      System (PDS) [PDSSR1992].
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      These image mosaics should be considered a preliminary product.
      They were assembled by the U.S.  Geological Survey from
      Magellan Full-resolution Basic Image Data Records (F-BIDRs)
      [Pettengill et al.  1992, Saunders et al.  1992] processed and
      provided by the Jet Propulsion Laboratory.  There are several
      known problems with the Magellan image data that either have
      led to reprocessing of a subset of the FBIDRs or that may be of
      sufficient importance to warrant future processing.  The
      mosaics on this disk were created on a &apos;best effort&apos; basis,
      using the most current versions of the constituent FBIDRs
      available to the USGS at the time of processing (1993-1994).
      Given the limitations of the available data, no other quality
      control was possible or was attempted.  The present FMAP may be
      superseded by later versions utilizing reprocessed and improved
      data.  The major known problems with the Magellan image data
      are the following:
 
 
      The SAR Image Data
      ------------------
        The synthetic-aperture radar (SAR) image data were
        reprojected from the radar coordinates (delay-doppler) onto
        the surface of Venus by using information about the
        spacecraft location based on a priori predictions and
        earth-based tracking; self-consistency of the image data from
        multiple orbits was not used to refine the ephemeris accuracy
        as is commonly done with optical imaging data.  The FBIDR
        data contain known positional errors of up to several
        kilometers, and, in particular, discontinuities of this
        magnitude between adjacent BIDRs whose ephimerides were
        processed separately.  Reprocessing of the Magellan SAR data
        with ephimerides refined by matching features in multiple
        BIDRs is technically feasible and might be carried out at
        some future date.
 
        For the orientation of the Magellan spacecraft, only a priori
        information was available.  The positional accuracy of SAR
        imaging is not dependent upon knowledge of the spacecraft
        orientation and hence was not affected.  Orientation
        information is needed, however, to correct for the varying
        sensitivity of the instrument across the width of the radar
        beam.  There are radiometric (tonal) mismatches between
        almost all neighboring F-BIDRS because of errors in the
        correction for beam sensitivity.  These mismatches were
        suppressed in the FMAP by the use of purely cosmetic
        processing techniques: highpass spatial filtering of each
        BIDR with a boxcar elongated in the direction of the flight
        path, followed by linear blending of the data from adjacent
        BIDRs in the area of overlap.  The effect of this processing
        on absolute radiometric accuracy is not known.
 
 
      Venus Topographical Model
      -------------------------
        A topographic model of the surface of Venus is needed in
        order to project the SAR data into map coordinates.  Most
        BIDRs were processed with a topographic model based on
        pre-Magellan (Pioneer Venus and Venera 15/16) data; the
        limited resolution of this dataset leads to planimetric
        inaccuracies in the BIDRs and FMAP mosaics.  During the
        Magellan mission, an attempt was made to process the BIDRs
        with a higher resolution topographic model based on Magellan
        data.  This topographic model proved to have a higher
        resolution than could be handled by the Magellan SAR
        processor, leading to severe interpolation errors and
        distortion of the data.  The affected BIDRs (revs ??--??,
        longitudes ??--??) were reprocessed with the earlier
        topographic model, and the reprocessed versions were used in
        this mosaic when available, but the FMAP may contain some
        data with this defect.
 
 
      Magellan SAR Processor
      ----------------------
        An error in the Magellan SAR processor resulted in the
        production of BIDRs with limited dynamic range (specifically,
        all data values less than about 70 DN were set to this
        value).  This problem affected revs ??--??, of which only
        revs ??--?? (longitudes ??--??) were obtained with
        illumination from the west (&apos;left looking SAR&apos;) and were used
        in the FMAP.  Again, reprocessed versions of these BIDRs were
        incorporated in the mosaic as available, but some erroneously
        processed data may be present.  It was not feasible to track
        the version of each F-BIDR incorporated in the FMAP.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      The FMAP will be reviewed internally by the Magellan Project
      prior to release to the planetary community.  The FMAP will
      also be reviewed by the PDS.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      The FMAP incorporates all Magellan images of Venus obtained
      with the nominal incidence angle profile for left-looking
      (illuminated from the west) observations.  Data obtained during
      the first 243-day cycle of operations cover approximately 84%
      of the surface; some additional left-look data filling gaps in
      this coverage were obtained in the second cycle [Saunders et
      al. 1992].  The division of the mosaicked data into quadrangles
      covering 12 degrees of latitude and longitude at the equator,
      and the division of the quadrangles into tiles 2 by 2 degrees
      at the equator is described under the keyword DATA_SET_DESC and
      in more detail by Kirk et al. 1993b.  For a variety of reasons,
      data may be unavailable for portions of the FMAP ranging from a
      few kilometers in north-south extent to entire F-BIDRs.
      Regions of missing data are flagged by a data value of 0; valid
      data are in the range from 1 to 255.  The F-BIDRs contain
      information flagging certain pixels as &apos;substandard&apos; because
      they contain information from less than four statistically
      independent &apos;looks&apos; at the surface [Petengill et al. 1991].
      Both standard and substandard pixels were used identically in
      producing the FMAP and are not flagged in it.
 
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      N/A
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>89-033B-01p</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

