<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-e-v-h-mascs-2-uvvs-edr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER E/V/H MASCS 2 UVVS UNCALIBRATED DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mascs.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-2-uvvs-edr-v1.0__browserp_mess-e-v-h-mascs-2-uvvs-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-2-uvvs-edr-v1.0__browser_geo_mercury_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-2-uvvs-edr-v1.0__browser_mess-e-v-h-mascs-2-uvvs-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-mascs-2-uvvs-edr-v1.0__dvo_geo_mess-e-v-h-mascs-2-uvvs-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   McClintock, W.E., and M.R. Lankton, The Mercury Atmospheric and Surface
                   Composition Spectrometer for the MESSENGER mission, Space Science Reviews, 131,
                   481-521, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MCCLINTOCK-LANK2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-E/V/H-MASCS-2-UVVS-EDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESSENGER E/V/H MASCS 2 UVVS UNCALIBRATED DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2015-03-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-09-13</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>NOAM IZENBERG</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Izenberg, N., MESSENGER E/V/H MASCS 2 UVVS UNCALIBRATED DATA
            V1.0, MESS-E/V/H-MASCS-2-UVVS-EDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2007.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The MESSENGER MASCS UVVS uncalibrated observations consist of
            science and instrument data collected by the UVVS detector.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== This data set consists of the MESSENGER MASCS
            UVVS uncalibrated observations, also known as EDRs. The MASCS
            UVVS experiment is a scanning grating monochromator equipped with
            three photomultiplier tubes. There are three UUVS EDR data
            products, one for each detector, which cover the wavelength
            ranges of the far ultraviolet (FUV), middle ultraviolet (MUV),
            and visible (VIS).
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
   Data Set Overview
   =================
     This data set consists of the MESSENGER MASCS UVVS uncalibrated
     observations, also known as EDRs. The UVVS experiment is
     equipped with three photomultiplier tubes, which are sensitive
     to three different wavelength ranges. Resulting spectra cover
     the wavelength ranges of the far ultraviolet (FUV)(115-190 nm),
     middle ultraviolet (MUV) (160-320 nm), and visible (VIS)
     (250-600 nm), with a resolution of 0.5 nm for the FUV channel
     and 1.0 nm for the MUV and VIS channels. There are four standard
     data products: FUV data, MUV data, VIS data, and Housekeeping
     data. The housekeeping EDR contains instrument parameters that
     may be useful in analyzing the UVVS data.
 
   Instrument Overview
   ===================
     The MASCS instrument consists of a small Cassegrain telescope
     that simultaneously feeds the UVVS and VIRS experiments. MASCS
     UVVS experiment is a scanning grating monochromator equipped
     with three photomultiplier tubes, providing spectral
     information in the far ultraviolet (115-190 nm), middle
     ultraviolet (160-320 nm), and visible (250-600 nm) wavelength
     ranges. The UVVS detector will help determine the composition
     of Mercury&apos;s exosphere by measuring the spatial and vertical
     distribution of known species as well as search for new ones.
 
     See the INST.CAT file for more information and
     [MCCLINTOCK&amp;LANK2007] for full details.
 
   Calibration Overview
   ====================
     This data set is NOT calibrated; it only provides the
     uncalibrated detector measurements.
 
   Parameters
   ==========
    The principal parameters when observing with the MASCS UVVS are
    as follows:
 
    * Start Position: The start position where the grating drive
    begins a scan.
 
    * Step Size: The step size in units of grating step. One grating
    step is equal to one arcmin.
 
    * Step Count: The number of steps the grating drive will take in
    a scan. The Step Count multiplied by the Step Size relates to
    the range of wavelengths that will be observed in one UVVS
    observation.
 
    * Integration Time: Integration time in grating drive loop
    control interrupt periods (nominally 3000 Hz).
 
    * Step Time: The step time in the grating drive loop control
    interrupt periods (nominally 3000 Hz).
 
    * Phase Offset: The phase offset between the beginning of the
    grating drive step and the start of a PMT integration in units
    of 0.3 milliseconds. Default value is 0 (no phase offset). By
    setting the phase offset to a non-zero value (reserved for
    contingency operations), the user will tell the software to
    initiate a step before the end of an integration, accounting for
    latencies in the motor controller.
 
    * Number of Scan Cycles: The number of times to repeat a scan.
 
    * Zigzag Option: Indicates whether grating drive moves in a
    &apos;triangle&apos; (stepping up, then stepping down), or &apos;sawtooth&apos;
    (stepping up, then &apos;flying&apos; down) motion. A &apos;triangle&apos; observation
    takes one grating scan stepping up the grating, then reverses
    direction and takes the next grating scan stepping back down the
    grating. A &apos;sawtooth&apos; observation takes one grating scan stepping
    up the grating, then &apos;flies&apos; the grating back to the START_POSITION
    to take the next observation.
 
    * Compression: Selects between 16 bit data (uncompressed) or 9
    bit data (compressed).
 
    * Slit Mask Position: Indicates whether the slit mask is in the
    atmospheric (open) or surface (closed) position. Atmospheric slit
    results in a 1 deg. by 0.04 deg. instantaneous field of view
    (iFOV). Surface slit results in a 0.05 deg. by 0.04 deg. iFOV.
 
    * FUV On: Select if the far ultraviolet photomultiplier tube is
    powered on or off.
 
    * MUV On: Select if the middle ultraviolet photomultiplier tube
    is powered on or off.
 
    * VIS On: Select if the visible photomultiplier tube is powered
    on or off.
 
   Data
   ====
     There are three UUVS EDR data products, one for each detector
     (FUV, MUV, VIS). There is also a MASCS housekeeping EDR data
     product generated by the MASCS instrument, which is the same for
     both the UVVS and VIRS components of the MASCS experiment.
 
     The EDR for one of the three detectors consists of entries for the
     spacecraft time and orientation, target location, values for the
     observing parameters set for the given observation, information
     about the observation, and is followed by the science scan data.
     The science scan data are the counts accumulated by the
     photomultiplier tube at a given position of the grating, in the
     order that the counts were collected. By using the values of the
     specific observing parameters that are related to the grating start
     position, number of grating steps, pattern of grating steps, and
     number of scans, each grating position can be determined and mapped
     to a specific wavelength.
 
     A separate EDR is created for each commanded scan set of one of the
     three detectors. Due to power considerations, a maximum of two
     photomultiplier tubes may record data at any given time; if two
     detectors acquire data simultaneously, two separate EDRs are still
     created. Data for the three UVVS detectors of the FUV, MUV, and VIS
     are always in separate EDRs.
 
     The MASCS Housekeeping EDR provides data about the voltage,
     current, and temperature readings, as well as record and software
     status, hardware settings, instrument status, and integration and
     reporting times. The MASCS Housekeeping EDR will contain all
     housekeeping packets generated in a given day.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
   Confidence Level Overview
   =========================
     The MASCS UVVS EDR data are the least processed data set released
     for the UVVS.  Data presented here are an accurate representation
     of the UVVS data as received from the spacecraft, with minimal
     timing and spatial processing.
 
   Review
   ======
     The UVVS EDR was reviewed internally by the MASCS team prior to
     release to the PDS. PDS also performed an external review of the
     MASCS UVVS EDRs (FUV, MUV and VIS photomultiplier tube (PMT) data
     each have seperate EDR types).
 
   Data Coverage and Quality
   =========================
     Data reported are the minimally processed data received from the
     spacecraft during the eighteen mission phases: Launch,
     Earth Cruise, Earth Flyby, Venus 1 Cruise, Venus 1 Flyby,
     Venus 2 Cruise, Venus 2 Flyby, Mercury 1 Cruise, Mercury 1 Flyby,
     Mercury 2 Cruise, Mercury 2 Flyby, Mercury 3 Cruise,
     Mercury 3 Flyby, Mercury 4 Cruise, Mercury Orbit, Mercury Orbit
     Year 2, Mercury Orbit Year 3, and Mercury Orbit Year 4. These
     mission phases are defined as:
 
                             Start time         End time
     Phase Name              Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)
     -----------------       -----------------  -----------------
     Launch                  03 Aug 2004 (216)  12 Sep 2004 (256)
     Earth Cruise            13 Sep 2004 (257)  18 Jul 2005 (199)
     Earth Flyby             19 Jul 2005 (200)  16 Aug 2005 (228)
     Venus 1 Cruise          17 Aug 2005 (229)  09 Oct 2006 (282)
     Venus 1 Flyby           10 Oct 2006 (283)  07 Nov 2006 (311)
     Venus 2 Cruise          08 Nov 2006 (312)  22 May 2007 (142)
     Venus 2 Flyby           23 May 2007 (143)  20 Jun 2007 (171)
     Mercury 1 Cruise        21 Jun 2007 (172)  30 Dec 2007 (364)
     Mercury 1 Flyby         31 Dec 2007 (365)  28 Jan 2008 (028)
     Mercury 2 Cruise        29 Jan 2008 (029)  21 Sep 2008 (265)
     Mercury 2 Flyby         22 Sep 2008 (266)  20 Oct 2008 (294)
     Mercury 3 Cruise        21 Oct 2008 (295)  15 Sep 2009 (258)
     Mercury 3 Flyby         16 Sep 2009 (259)  14 Oct 2009 (287)
     Mercury 4 Cruise        15 Oct 2009 (288)  03 Mar 2011 (062)
     Mercury Orbit           04 Mar 2011 (063)  17 Mar 2012 (077)
     Mercury Orbit Year 2    18 Mar 2012 (078)  17 Mar 2013 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 3    18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 4    18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)
 
     MASCS UVVS data were collected during all phases except
     Venus 1 Flyby. During these planned operational periods, the UVVS
     functioned nominally and the data quality was good. Additional
     numbered notes added as necessary. This is a high-level
     presentation of EDR validation. Lower level EDR (and CDR) details,
     including, e.g. SBOS trips, temperature alarms, and footprints
     on/off planet are best obtained through the Data Quality Index
     (DQI) of the UVVS CDR. Specific MASCS operational periods were:
 
                         Start time         End time
   Phase Name            Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)         Operations
   --------------------  -----------------  -----------------  -------------
 
   Launch                03 Aug 2004 (216)  12 Sep 2004 (256)  Checkout
   Earth Cruise          13 Sep 2004 (257)  18 Jul 2005 (199)  Starcals (1),
                                                               Cover Open
   Earth Flyby           19 Jul 2005 (200)  16 Aug 2005 (228)  Earth/Moon (2)
   Venus 1 Cruise        17 Aug 2005 (229)  09 Oct 2006 (282)  Starcals
   Venus 1 Flyby         10 Oct 2006 (283)  07 Nov 2006 (311)  n/a
   Venus 2 Cruise        08 Nov 2006 (312)  22 May 2007 (142)  Starcals (3,4),
                                                               Venus,
                                                               Operation Tests
   Venus 2 Flyby         23 May 2007 (143)  20 Jun 2007 (171)  Venus (5)
   Mercury 1 Cruise      21 Jun 2007 (172)  30 Dec 2007 (364)  Starcals (6),
                                                               Operation Tests
   Mercury 1 Flyby       31 Dec 2007 (365)  28 Jan 2008 (028)  Mercury,
                                                               Lyman Alpha
   Mercury 2 Cruise      29 Jan 2008 (029)  21 Sep 2008 (265)  Starcals,
                                                               Operation Tests
   Mercury 2 Flyby       22 Sep 2008 (266)  20 Oct 2008 (294)  Mercury (7),
                                                               Lyman Alpha
   Mercury 3 Cruise      21 Oct 2008 (295)  15 Sep 2009 (258)  Starcals (8),
                                                               Venus
   Mercury 3 Flyby       16 Sep 2009 (259)  14 Oct 2009 (287)  Mercury (9),
                                                               Lyman Alpha
   Mercury 4 Cruise      15 Oct 2009 (288)  03 Mar 2011 (062)  Starcals,
                                                               Venus (10),
                                                               Operation Tests
   Mercury Orbit         04 Mar 2011 (063)  17 Mar 2012 (077)  Mercury
                                                               (11-12),
                                                               Starcals,
                                                               Venus
   Mercury Orbit Year 2  18 Mar 2012 (078)  17 Mar 2013 (076)  Mercury (13),
                                                               Starcals
   Mercury Orbit Year 3  18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)  Mercury (14),
                                                               Starcals
   Mercury Orbit Year 4  18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)  Mercury,
                                                               Comet Encke,
                                                               Comet ISON,
                                                               Starcals
 
 
   Notes:
     (1)  Starcals before June 2005 viewed through cover window.
     (2)  UVVS command errors in corona scans reduced number of scans
          executed by ~1/2. SBOS trips at moon stopped UVVS VIS-PMT
          data as expected. 10 Missing MUV packets at this time.
     (3)  One starcal missed target due to star tracker error.
     (4)  Test and switch over to macro-based commanding of UVVS.
     (5)  SBOS trips at Venus stopped green line scan.
     (6)  S/C event during starcal; instrument turned off during
          Starcal.
     (7)  UVVS grating offset affects data during first Mercury flyby.
          The only effect in the EDRs is that the range of wavelengths
          actually measured is different from the nominal range and
          spectra will be shifted to longer wavelengths. The offset
          was 4 grating steps.
     (8)  Pointing error during May 2009 starcal; star not observed.
     (9)  Flyby anomaly - no data after Mercury Closest Approach until
          post-flyby Mercury-as-star observations.
     (10) Missing packet in Dec 2010 turn-on sequence.
          Missing packets (5 second observations) noted in some H
          Lyman alpha scans, possibly simply timing cutoffs, no data
          quality compromise.
     (11) Elevated hot season temperatures.
     (12) Lost data Events during Orbit:
          11123 FPP &apos;High Temperature&apos; warning, Instrument off for 2
          days, setting set too low. FPP temps reset to higher value.
     (13) Occasional single event upsets, usually related to solar
          activity, usually affecting the VIRS component of MASCS,
          resulted in unscheduled power cycling of MASCS.
     (14) UVVS grating offset affects data from September 5 through
          November 22, 2013. See note #7 for description of effects
          on data. The offset was 6 grating steps.
 
     Cruise operations/observations have additional details in the
     Master Cruise Operations Table (a Microsoft Excel file) in the
     Extras directory.
 
     There are slightly fewer UVVS Science CDRs because there were a
     few EDRs that contained no data at all, just header information
     (i.e. loop was begun, but halted by normal macro operations
     before data were taken.)
 
   Limitations
   ===========
     This data set is minimally processed data. The data are received
     from the spacecraft telemetry and ingested into the MESSENGER
     Science Operations Center (SOC). No data gaps other than
     understood UVVS command loop errors and SBOS trips have been
     identified for any of the MASCS operational periods.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

