<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.go-a-nims-4-idacube-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>HIRES NIMS IDA SPECTRAL IMAGE CUBES</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.galileo::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:nims.go::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.ida::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.go-a-nims-4-idacube-v1.0__browserp_go-a-nims-4-idacube-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Carlson, R.W., P.R. Weissman, W.D. Smythe, J.C. Mahoney, and the NIMS Science
                   and Engineering Teams, Near-Infrared Mapping Spectrometer Experiment on
                   Galileo, Space Science Reviews 60: 457-502, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CARLSONETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GO-A-NIMS-4-IDACUBE-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>HIRES NIMS IDA SPECTRAL IMAGE CUBES</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2013-07-22</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1993-08-28T16:47:45Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1993-08-28T16:45:30Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. JAMES C. GRANAHAN</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Granahan, J.C., HiRes Galileo NIMS Ida Spectral Image Cube
            GO-A-NIMS-4-IDACUBE-V1.0. NASA Planetary Data System, 2013.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Radiance spectral image cube of the spatially resolved Galileo
            NIMS observations of asteroid 243 Ida.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data volume contains 17 channel spectral image cubes of
            asteroid 243 Ida ranging from 0.7 to 5.2 micrometers in
            wavelength in cgs units of radiance. These data were obtained by
            the Galileo spacecraft Near Infrared Mapping Spectrometer on
            August 28, 1993. They were radiometrically calibrated using
            calibration measurements obtained by the Near Infrared Mapping
            Spectrometer during its observations of Europa on June 28, 1996.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      This data volume contains a radiometrically corrected spectral image
      cube of the spatially resolved observations of asteroid 243 Ida as
      acquired by the Galileo spacecraft Near Infrared Mapping Spectrometer
      (NIMS) on August 28, 1993.  These are products of the calibration of
      the raw data number files idu002tn.qub and idu004tn.qub with calibration
      factors contained in the file g1e003ci.qub and projected in a point
      perspective geometry. All of the source files are contained within
      the NASA pds archive of Galileo NIMS data. These spectral image cubes,
      ida_nims_002_scan1_radiance.fit, ida_nims_002_scan2_radiance.fit,
      ida_nims_002_scan3_radiance.fit, and ida_nims_004_radiance.fit, combine
      data acquired during the asteroid 243 Ida encounter and the Galilean
      Satellite encounters to produce radiometrically calibrated products.
 
      The Near-Infrared Mapping Spectrometer (NIMS) instrument is an imaging
      spectrometer covering the wavelength region 0.7 to 5.2 micrometers --
      a region not studied by the Pioneer and Voyager spacecraft.  Its
      spectral resolution is 0.025 micron beyond 1 micron, and 0.0125
      microns below 1 micron, yielding 204 spectral elements in nominal
      mode.  The nominal pixel size is a square 0.5 x 0.5 milliradians.
      The instrument acquires data in the order: (1) sampling of 17
      detectors, (2) stepping of the scan mirror (20 elements in cross-cone),
      (3) stepping of the grating (nominally 12 steps per cycle).  The
      nominal 204 wavelength cycle requires 4 1/3 seconds.  The detectors
      (2 Silicon, 15 Indium Antimonide) sample approximately uniformly
      across the spectrum.  A detailed description of the instrument may be
      found in [CARLSONETAL1992] and in the document directory of this
      data volume.
 
      The natural form of imaging spectrometer data is the spectral image
      cube.  It is normally in band sequential format, but has a dual
      nature.  It is a series of &apos;images&apos; of the target, each in a different
      wavelength.  It is also a set of spectra, each at a particular line
      and sample, over the area observed.  Each spectrum describes a small
      portion of the area.  When transformed into cubes, the data may be
      analyzed spatially, an image at a time, or spectrally, a spectrum at
      a time, or in more complex spatial-spectral fashion.
 
      The HIRES NIMS SPECTRAL IMAGE CUBE data products are spectral image
	  cubes of the spatially resolved NIMS observations of asteroid 243 Ida.
	  They are derived from data archived in the NASA Planetary Data Systems
	  files idu002tn.qub and idu004tn.qub consisting of data in raw data
	  number values stored as spectral image cubes in a band sequential
	  integer arrays.  These raw data numbers were converted into little
	  endian floating point values using sensor sensitivity values contained
	  in the NIMS Galilean satellite observations g1e003ci.qub archived in
	  the NASA Planetary Data System.  The HIRES NIMS SPECTRAL IMAGE CUBES
	  pixels were rectified by creating a point perspective instrument
	  projection and limbfitting pixels to the corresponding 243 Ida Galileo
	  spacecraft CCD (Solid State Imager).  The result are rectified band
	  sequential radiance spectral image cubes of 243 Ida that are stored in
	  the HIRES NIMS SPECTRAL IMAGE CUBE FITS files.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      A band in a NIMS tube is generated for each of the 17 detectors at
      each grating step.  (The detectors cover the range 0.7 to 5.2
      microns.)  The motion of the grating is determined by the commanded
      instrument mode:
 
        Mode                         Grating   Grating   Bands  Samples/RIM
                                      steps   increment
 
        Fixed Map/Spectrometer          1         0        17      182
        Short Map/Spectrometer          6         4       102       26
        Full Map/Spectrometer          12         2       204       14
        Long Map/Spectrometer          24         1       408        7
 
      A secondary mirror moves through twenty cross-track positions in the
      map modes, or is fixed near the center of its scan in the
      spectrometer modes.  The number of lines in each image of a tube is
      always twenty, whether or not the mirror is moving.  The number of
      samples is determined by the mode and the duration of the
      observation.  (In the mosaic dataset, the image dimensions are
      determined by the pattern created by the motions of the secondary
      mirror and the scan platform.)
 
      The approximate wavelengths of the bands are determined by the mode,
      and by offset and start grating positions.  The true wavelengths are
      functions of the temperature of the grating and parameters
      determined from the ground calibration and frequent optical flight
      calibrations.  Known absorptions on some targets are also useful in
      determining these parameters.
 
      The commanded gain state is one of four sets of gains for the 14
      non-thermal detectors.  The three thermal detectors have two gains,
      automatically switching to the lower one near the mid-point of their
      range.  Raw data values of each detector and grating step are
      functions of the gain state and the temperature of the focal plane
      assembly (FPA).  Radiances are determined from raw data values using
      sensitivities based on the original ground calibration corrected by
      frequent photometric and radiometric flight calibrations.  I/F
      values are simply radiances divided by the solar absorption at the
      target&apos;s distance from the sun for the wavelength in question.
 
      Further details may be found in VOLINFO.TXT in the DOCUMENT
      directory of the archive volume, and in the instrument paper
      [CARLSONETAL1992].
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The HIRES NIMS SPECTRAL IMAGE CUBES data products are spectral image
	  cubes of the spatially resolved NIMS observations of asteroid 243 Ida.
	  They are derived from data archived in the NASA Planetary Data Systems
	  files idu002tn.qub and idu004tn.qub consisting of data in raw data
	  number values stored as spectral image cubes in a band sequential
	  integer array.  These raw data numbers were converted into little endian
      floating point values using sensor sensitivity values contained in the
      NIMS Galilean satellite observations g1e003ci.qub archived in the NASA
      Planetary Data System.  The HIRES NIMS SPECTRAL IMAGE CUBES pixels were
      rectified by creating a point perspective instrument projection and
      limbfitting pixels to the corresponding 243 Ida Galileo spacecraft CCD
      (Solid State Imager) images.  The results are rectified band sequential
	  radiance spectral image cubes of 243 Ida that are stored in the
      HIRES NIMS SPECTRAL IMAGE CUBES FITS files.
 
    Data structure
    ==============
      The HIRES NIMS SPECTRAL IMAGE CUBES spectral image files are FITS
	  formatted files.  Each file contains three little endian floating point
	  arrays with associated header data.  The first array is a three
	  dimensional that is a radiance spectral image cube of the asteroid 243
	  Ida in a band sequential format. The second array is another three
      dimensional array that contains the per pixel wavelength value
      of the pixels in the first array.  The third array is a three
      dimensional array that contains the radiance precision of each
      pixel of the radiance spectral image cube.
 
      This FITS file has a detached PDS label file that describes
      the FITS data file structure, spacecraft mission, and
      the observation geometry.
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      A Postscript-format Guide to the planned observations, including
      footprint plots on the target, instrument parameters, etc. is
      included in the data set, as are tables of parameters for each
      observation. A copy of the NIMS instrument paper [CARLSONETAL1992]
      is also included.
 
      Tagged Image File Format (TIFF) and Adobe Acrobat Portable Document
	  files contain sample images and plots of the data in the HIRES NIMS
	  SPECTRAL IMAGE CUBES can be found in the BROWSE directory.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      NIMS tubes were designed to be accessed by the ISIS system, which
      No software is provided with the HIRES NIMS SPECTRAL IMAGE CUBES data
	  volume. The FITS formatted file can be read with astronomical image
	  software packages that can ingest the FITS file format.  This includes
	  IDL, a product of ITTVIS (http://www.ittvis.com) with the IDL Astronomy
      User&apos;s Library at NASA Goddard Space Flight Center at
      http://idlastro.gsfc.nasa.gov .  ISIS (Integrated Software for Imagers
      and Spectrometers) 3.0 may also be used to ingest the FITS file for
      analysis and is available from the USGS via
      http://isis.astrogeology.usgs.gov/ .
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      The radiance and reflectance cubes in this volume have not been
	  photometrically corrected, nor have they been corrected for
	  thermal emission.  Thus, apparent surface variations will be
	  affected by viewing geometry and thermal properties.
 
      The radiance values contained in the HIRES NIMS SPECTRAL IMAGE CUBES
      data set were checked against corresponding values obtained by
      the Galileo Solid State Imager (SSI) multi-spectral imagery,
      NASA Infrared Telescope Facility spectra, and Eight Color
      Asteroid Survey data for asteroid 243 Ida.  These were used to
      find the best calibration factors for the first grating step of
      the 243 Ida NIMS observations.  Data from other grating steps
      were found to vary from these values.  This variations in this
      data is thought to be caused by unplanned scan platform motions
      durint the NIMS 243 Ida observations.
 
      The shape of the limb of asteroid 243 Ida as observed by SSI
      was also used as a constraint for the position of the NIMS
      pixels in the data set.  Each NIMS scan line was aligned with
      the SSI imaged asteroid limb during the time of the observation.
      The updated alignment was used to position the NIMS pixels
      in the HIRES NIMS SPECTRAL IMAGE CUBES data products.
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      The HIRES NIMS SPECTRAL IMAGE CUBES data volume contains the spatially
      resolved NIMS observations of asteroid 243 Ida as archived as images
      in the NASA PDS Imaging Node.  It contains data from the NIMS
      observations that are of a high signal to noise and that are consistent
      with other data sets.  Lower signal to noise scans of the asteroid were
      omitted from this data set.  Inconsistent data, those belonging to
      observations beyond the first grating step, were also omitted. It is
      thought that the 243 Ida data beyond the first grating step suffered
      from non-standard scan motions due to malfunctions of the Galileo
      Orbiter scan platform during the asteroid encounter.  This resulted
      in archived image files with some spectral data that are not properly
      calibrated by coefficients obtained during the Galilean satellite
      encounter observations.
    ===========
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

