<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lp-l-mag-5-lunar-field-bins-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LP MOON MAG LEVEL 5 LUNAR MAGNETIC FIELD BINS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_prospector::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mag.lp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lp-l-mag-5-lunar-field-bins-v1.0__browserc_lp-l-mag-5-lunar-field-bins-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lp-l-mag-5-lunar-field-bins-v1.0__browserp_lp-l-mag-5-lunar-field-bins-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   unk
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.unk</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LP-L-MAG-5-LUNAR-FIELD-BINS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LP MOON MAG LEVEL 5 LUNAR MAGNETIC FIELD BINS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2003-10-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1998-01-16</start_time>
        <stop_time>1999-07-29</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>LON L. HOOD</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>not applicable</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            LUNAR PROSPECTOR MAGNETOMETER (MAG) LEVEL 3 DATA (CODMAC LEVEL
            5). REGIONAL FIELD BINS AT THE S/C ALTITUDE.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>not applicable</abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    Lunar Prospector magnetometer (MAG) Level 3 Data (CODMAC Level 5).
    Regional Field Bins at the S/C Altitude.  Interpolation
    and two-dimensional filtering are applied to the Level 2 data to
    produce gridded field component data files on a surface defined by
    the slowly varying S/C altitude.  The spatial resolution of the
    grid is chosen to be much less than the mean S/C altitude.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The measured parameters consist of the three vector components
    of the lunar crustal magnetic field in East, North, and Radial
    (ENR) coordinates, the field magnitude, and the spacecraft
    altitude.  The units of the field measurements are nanoTeslas (nT).
    1 nT = 0.00001 Gauss.  The units of the spacecraft altitude are
    kilometers (km).  ENR coordinates are centered at the instantaneous
    spacecraft location with X directed eastward, Y directed northward,
    and Z directed radial to the Moon.
 
 
  Processing
  ===========
    Step 1:  A two-dimensional filtering algorithm is applied to
    final selected LP magnetometer Level 2 orbit segments to produce
    a gridded file suitable for mapping.  The program first sorts the
    data into latitude / longitude bins and averages values within
    a single bin (e.g., 0.5 by 0.5 degrees for data acquired at
    altitudes near 100 km).  A moving boxcar method is
    then applied to two-dimensionally filter the mean gridded
    measurements.  A 5 bin by 5 bin filter size is
    normally chosen.  This step is repeated twice, separately for
    each field component and the S/C altitude.  Finally, the
    resulting field magnitude is calculated from the smoothed
    component files on the same two-dimensional grid.
    The resulting two-dimensionally filtered gridded files are
    the Level 3 data.  They contain latitude, longitude, the
    field component in nT (or the altitude in km), and the number
    of data points in each bin.
 
    Step 2:  If a significant longitudinal gap between
    usable orbit segments is present, linear interpolation between the
    two nearest orbit segments is applied to create an interpolated
    orbit segment.  This interpolated segment is then read into the
    two-dimensional filtering code to fill in the missing grid values.
    This method is applied only when the gap between usable orbits is
    smaller than the 5-bin size of the two-dimensional filter.
 
    Step 3:  For visualization purposes, a suitable
    graphics utility is applied to construct regional shaded contour
    plots of the vector components of the crustal field, the field
    magnitude, and the mean S/C altitude.  These are contained in a
    postscript file that is included with the filtered gridded files.
    The file naming convention for the postscript files is the same
    as for data files (see below), but with a .PS extension.
 
 
  File Names and Format
  =====================
    The two-dimensionally filtered gridded files are named as follows:
 
      For 1998 data:
 
        MAP98_mmp_xxx.TAB
 
      where mm indicates the month (01 for January, etc.),
            p (optional) indicates the map number for this
                month,
            xxx is either RAD, EAS, NOR, TOT or ALT, indicating
                what type of data are in the file (radial B component,
                east B component, north B component, total B, or
                altitude).
 
      For 1999 data:
 
        MAP99_dddp-dddp_xxx.TAB or MAP99_dddp_xxx.TAB
 
      where ddd indicates a day (and thus ddd - ddd is a range of days),
            p and xxx are as for 1998 data.
 
 
    Each file (in ascii format) contains the latitude, east longitude,
    the field component (or total field, or altitude) at the grid
    point, and the number of data points in the bin centered at the
    grid point. The altitude is estimated by subtracting the mean lunar
    radius (1738 km) from the radial distance of the spacecraft to the
    lunar center of figure.
 
    The columns in each data file are as follows:
 
      Column 1: Latitude at this grid point (South is negative;
          North is positive).
      Column 2: East longitude at this grid point.
      Column 3: Magnetic field value in nanoTeslas or altitude in
          kilometers.  The last part of the file name before the dot
          indicates what is contained in this column (EAS = East field
          component; NOR = North field component; RAD = Radial field
          component; TOT = total field; ALT = Altitude).
      Column 4: Number of data points in this latitude/longitude bin.
          The bin size can be deduced from the difference between
          successive latitude and longitude values (e.g., 0.5 degrees
          by 0.5 degrees for altitudes near 100 km; 0.25 degrees by
          0.25 degrees for altitudes near 25 km).
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Review
  ======
    These data have been examined by the data producer, and as of
    2003-10-01 are being prepared for peer review by the PDS.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    The quality of the measurements is a
    strong function of the spacecraft altitude, which varies from a
    minimum of about 80 km during the first year of the mission to a
    minimum of about 15 km during the final six months of the
    mission.  The best crustal field measurements were therefore
    obtained during the final &apos;&apos;extended mission&apos;&apos; phase when the
    orbit periapsis was lowest.  The surface resolution of the
    measurements is normally of the same order as the spacecraft
    altitude.  However, at the lowest altitudes (about 15 km), the
    resolution is limited also by the orbit track separation, which
    is approximately 30 km at the lunar equator.  The accuracy to
    which the crustal field is measured at a single point along the
    spacecraft trajectory is limited by residual external field
    variations and is approximately 0.1 nT.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

