<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mess-e-v-h-grns-3-ns-cdr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MESSENGER E/V/H GRNS 3 NEUTRON SPECTROMETER CDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.messenger::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:ns.mess::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.calibration::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mercury::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-grns-3-ns-cdr-v1.0__browserp_mess-e-v-h-grns-3-ns-cdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-grns-3-ns-cdr-v1.0__browser_mess-e-v-h-grns-3-ns-cdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mess-e-v-h-grns-3-ns-cdr-v1.0__dvo_mess-e-v-h-grns-3-ns-cdr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Goldsten, J.O., E.A. Rhodes,, W.V. Boynton, W.C. Feldman, D.J. Lawrence, J.I.
                   Trombka, D.M. Smith, L.G. Evans, J. White, N.W. Madden, P.C. Berg, G.A. Murphy,
                   R.S. Gurnee, K. Strohbehn, B.D. Williams, E.D. Schaefer, C.A. Monaco, C.P.
                   Cork, J.D. Eckels, W.O. Miller, M.T. Burks, L.B. Hagler, S.J. Deteresa, and
                   M.C. Witte, The MESSENGER Gamma-Ray and Neutron Spectrometer, Space Science
                   Reviews, 131, 339-391, 2007.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GOLDSTENETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MESS-E/V/H-GRNS-3-NS-CDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MESSENGER E/V/H GRNS 3 NEUTRON SPECTROMETER CDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2015-03-06</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2004-09-13</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID LAWRENCE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            D. J. LAWRENCE (APL), MESSENGER E/V/H GRNS 3 NEUTRON SPECTROMETER
            CDR V1.0, MESS-E/V/H-GRNS-3-NS-CDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2009.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The MESSENGER Neutron Spectrometer (NS) Calibrated Data Records
            (CDRs) consist of science and engineering data collected by the
            NS instrument.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Abstract ======== This data set consists of the MESSENGER Neutron
            Spectrometer (NS) calibrated data records (CDRs). The NS
            experiment is a neutron spectrometer designed to observe spectra
            of neutrons emitted from Mercury&apos;s surface in the energy
            range from 0.01 eV to 7 MeV. There are five NS CDR data products:
            raw neutron spectra, NS counter data, galactic cosmic ray (GCR)
            spectra, engineering data, and gamma-ray burst data.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
   Instrument Overview
   ===================
     The MErcury Surface, Space ENvironment, GEochemistry, and Ranging
     (MESSENGER) Neutron Spectrometer (NS) sensor consists of three
     scintillators, each wrapped separately and coupled to separate
     photo-multiplier tubes. The three scintillators are sensitive to
     neutrons of different energies: thermal neutrons (0.025 - 1 eV),
     epithermal neutrons (1eV - 500 keV), and fast neutrons
     (500 keV - 7 MeV). The first and third scintillators are lithium
     (6Li)-glass scintillators (LG1 and LG2) which respond to a combination
     of thermal and epithermal neutrons. The middle scintillator is a
     borated plastic (BP) scintillator that responds only to epithermal and
     fast neutrons due to its electronics setup. The interaction of galactic
     cosmic rays (GCR) with the surface of Mercury produces neutrons, some
     of which escape the surface and produce a neutron signal that can be
     measured by the orbiting NS sensor. The measured neutron energy
     spectrum reflects the transport properties of the surface composition
     and is sensitive to depths down to about 1 m. Thermal neutrons are
     sensitive to a variety of elements, including Fe, Ti, Gd, Sm, Cl, and
     C. Epithermal neutrons are mostly sensitive to H abundance. Fast
     neutrons can provide a good measure of average atomic mass. For the
     MESSENGER mission, the NS sensor will establish and map the abundance
     of H over most of the northern hemisphere of Mercury, providing
     significant new information regarding the potential presence of water
     ice within and near permanently shaded craters near the north pole.
 
     See the NS_INST.CAT file for more information and [GOLDSTENETAL2007]
     for full details.
 
   Data Set Overview
   =================
     This data set consists of MESSENGER NS calibrated data records
     (CDRs). A single CDR data file contains the observations with a time
     tag corresponding to a given Earth day. There are five standard data
     products associated with the NS instrument. NS_CDR_SPECTRA include LG1
     singles, LG2 singles, BP singles, Time Correlated (TC) early, and TC
     late spectra. Net fast neutron spectra are the difference between TC
     early and TC late (i.e., fast neutron spectra = TC early - TC late).
     NS_CDR_COUNTS include NS counting rate data for 17 different monitored
     counting rates. NS_CDR_GCR_SPECTRA include spectra from LG1 and LG2
     when a coincidence condition is detected in both LG sensors and the BP
     sensor. The NS_CDR_ENG data products include instrument engineering
     data. The NS_CDR_GAB data product contains the values from the NS Gamma
     Ray Burst EDR in ASCII form with some additional time tag columns.
 
   Calibration Overview
   ====================
     The following operations are applied to the Experiment Data Records
     (EDRs) to arrive at calibrated spectra (CDRs):
 
     1) Normalization of total counts to the accumulation time, so that the
     units are in counts per second;
     2) Corrections (if needed) for gain variations in the spectra data;
     3) Corrections (if needed) for GCR variations in the spectra and
     counting rates;
     4) Corrections for deadtime (if needed) in the spectra and counting
     rates.
 
     All of these corrections are reversible such that the EDR and CDR
     datasets can be derived from each other.
 
   Coordinate Systems
   ===================
     For planetary orbital and flyby data, the NS-specific data also have
     two coordinate systems (in addition to standard J2000 and
     Planetocentric body fixed) for expressing spacecraft velocity and
     attitude data: the nadir fixed coordinate system and the spacecraft
     fixed coordinate system.
 
     The nadir fixed coordinate system is defined as follows:
     * The z-axis is defined as the vector from the spacecraft center to the
     flyby or orbiting planet center.
     * The nadir fixed y-axis is defined as the cross product of the nadir
     z-axis and the spacecraft velocity vector (where both are expressed in
     the J2000 coordinate system).
     * The nadir fixed x-axis is defined as the cross product of the nadir
     fixed y-axis with the nadir fixed z-axis.
 
     The spacecraft fixed coordinate system is defined as follows:
     * The spacecraft fixed x-axis is the vector normal to the NS LG1 sensor
     and is parallel to the spacecraft solar panel booms.
     * The spacecraft fixed y-axis is in the direction from the spacecraft
     down the magnetometer boom.
     * The spacecraft fixed z-axis is the viewing direction from the
     instrument deck.
 
   Data
   ====
     There are five standard data products associated with the NS
     instrument. A single CDR data file will contain the observations with a
     time tag corresponding to a given Earth day.
 
     The NS Spectra CDRs are organized as binary data files and include LG1
     singles, LG2 singles, BP singles, Time Correlated (TC) early, and TC
     late spectra, along with associated timing, spatial, and engineering
     data taken at the beginning of the spectral collection period.
 
     The NS Counts CDR are organized as binary data files and include
     counting rate data for 17 different monitored counting rates, along
     with associated timing, spatial, and engineering data taken at the
     beginning of the spectral collection period.
 
     The NS Galactic Cosmic Ray CDRs are organized as binary data files and
     include spectra from LG1 and LG2 when a triple coincidence is detected
     in all three sensors, along with associated timing, spatial, and
     engineering data taken at the beginning of the spectral collection
     period.
 
     The NS Engineering CDRs are organized as ASCII tables and include
     instrumental engineering data.
 
     The NS Gamma Ray Burst CDRs are organized as ASCII tables containing the
     data from the NS Gamma Ray Burst EDR in ASCII format along with
     additional time tags.
 
    The general form of the NS CDR file names is
     &apos;NS_CDR_ZZZYYYYDDDWWW.XXX,&apos; where
 
     NS       instrument identifier: represents the NS instrument.
     CDR      data product identifier: CDR
     ZZZ      data product name
                SPE - NS CDR Spectra with associated engineering, timing and
                  spatial data.
                CTS - NS CDR Counts with associated engineering, timing, and
                  spatial data.
                GCR - NS CDR Galactic Cosmic Ray spectra with associated
                  engineering, timing and spatial data.
                ENG - Engineering data.
                GAB - Gamma-Ray Burst data.
     YYYY     four digit year corresponding to the start-time of the first
                record in the NS data file.
     DDD      three digit day of the year corresponding to the start time of
                the first record in the NS CDR data file.
     WWW      reserved character string to use during the course of the
                mission as necessary to identify &apos;special&apos; data products.
                Nominal data products will be identified by ZZZ.
     .XXX      the file extension (.DAT for binary files, .TAB for ascii
                files).
 
 
     See NS_CDR_DDR_SIS.PDF in the DOCUMENT folder of this volume for more
     information.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
   Confidence Level Overview
   =========================
     The NS CDR data have been processed as described in the &apos;MESSENGER
     Neutron Spectrometer (NS) EDR-to-CDR-to-DDR Processing&apos; document
     (MESSNS_PROCESSING.PDF, CALIB directory). Data presented here are an
     accurate representation of the NS data as processed from the EDR files,
     where the processing includes time normalization, and merging of
     spacecraft spatial and rotational information to the data.
 
   Review
   ======
     The NS CDR was reviewed internally by the NS team prior to release to
     the PDS.  PDS also performed an external review of the NS CDR.
 
   Data Coverage and Quality
   =========================
     Data reported are the calibrated data received from the spacecraft
     during the the following mission phases: Launch, Earth Cruise,
     Earth Flyby, Venus 1 Cruise, Venus 1 Flyby, Venus 2 Cruise,
     Venus 2 Flyby, Mercury 1 Cruise, Mercury 1 flyby, Mercury 2 Cruise,
     Mercury 2 flyby Mercury 3 Cruise, Mercury 3 Flyby, Mercury 4 Cruise,
     Mercury Orbit, Mercury Orbit Year 2, Mercury Orbit Year 3, and Mercury
     Orbit Year 4. These mission phases are defined as:
 
                             Start time         End time
     Phase Name              Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)
     -----------------       -----------------  -----------------
     Launch                  03 Aug 2004 (216)  12 Sep 2004 (256)
     Earth Cruise            13 Sep 2004 (257)  18 Jul 2005 (199)
     Earth Flyby             19 Jul 2005 (200)  16 Aug 2005 (228)
     Venus 1 Cruise          17 Aug 2005 (229)  09 Oct 2006 (282)
     Venus 1 Flyby           10 Oct 2006 (283)  07 Nov 2006 (311)
     Venus 2 Cruise          08 Nov 2006 (312)  22 May 2007 (142)
     Venus 2 Flyby           23 May 2007 (143)  20 Jun 2007 (171)
     Mercury 1 Cruise        21 Jun 2007 (172)  30 Dec 2007 (364)
     Mercury 1 Flyby         31 Dec 2007 (365)  28 Jan 2008 (028)
     Mercury 2 Cruise        29 Jan 2008 (029)  21 Sep 2008 (265)
     Mercury 2 Flyby         22 Sep 2008 (266)  20 Oct 2008 (294)
     Mercury 3 Cruise        21 Oct 2008 (295)  15 Sep 2009 (258)
     Mercury 3 Flyby         16 Sep 2009 (259)  14 Oct 2009 (287)
     Mercury 4 Cruise        15 Oct 2009 (288)  03 Mar 2011 (062)
     Mercury Orbit           04 Mar 2011 (063)  17 Mar 2012 (077)
     Mercury Orbit Year 2    18 Mar 2012 (078)  17 Mar 2013 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 3    18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 4    18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)
 
     A nonscience &apos;aliveness&apos; test was conducted in August 2004. The first
     full function test was conducted April-May 2005. In August and
     September 2005 and March 2006, engineering tests were conducted to
     determine origin and magnitude of gain changes in a Li-glass detector
     channel. A second full function test was conducted in June 2006 after
     new software was uploaded. In January 2007 a calibration period was
     begun and the NS was left on. The NS was off from mid-October 2007
     through mid-December 2007 and from February 26, 2008 through March 28,
     2008.
 
     The NS had four off periods during the Mercury 3 Cruise phase:  Nov.
     2008-Jan 2009; July 2009; Four days in August 2009; Two days in early
     September 2009.  The NS had one off period during the Mercury_3_Flyby
     period due to the spacecraft safing event that occurred during the
     Mercury 3 flyby.
 
     The NS had three off periods during the Mercury 4 Cruise phase:
     Oct. 2009-Dec. 2009; four days in May 2010; and three days in Dec.
     2010.
 
     The NS had one off period during the Mercury Orbit phase in March 2011.
     This off period was two days prior to Mercury Orbit Insertion (MOI) and
     continued during the first week of orbit operations.
 
     During the PDS data delivery from May 18, 2011 to September 17, 2011,
     the NS was shut off for nine consecutive days when the MESSENGER
     spacecraft passed through its first long eclipse period.  The specific
     off period was from May 24, 2011 21:34:49 to June 3, 2011 0:17:49.
 
     During the PDS data delivery from May 18, 2011 to September 17, 2011,
     the high voltage (HV) to the LG and BP sensors was shut down three
     times during spacecraft thrusting maneuvers.  Each time, the HV was
     shut down for approximately four hours while the spacecraft was near
     apoapsis.  The specific times for the HV shut down are:
     June 15, 2011 16:12:08 - June 15, 2011 20:30:16;
     July 26, 2011 17:40:16 - July 26, 2011 21:55:16;
     September 7, 2011 11:38:16 - September 7, 2011 16:05:50.
 
     During the PDS data delivery from September 18, 2011 to March 25, 2012,
     the NS HV to the LG and BP sensor was shut down four times.  Three
     times, the HV was shut down during spacecraft thrusting maneuvers.  The
     specific times for these HV shut downs are:
     October 24, 2011 18:29:00 - October 24, 2011 23:16:00;
     December 5, 2011 12:36:00 - December 5, 2011 17:18:00;
     March 2, 2012 22:09:22 - March 3, 2012 02:47:54.
     The HV to the LG and BP sensors was shut down a fourth time during a
     large solar particle event when the NS sensors were safed because of
     the large charged particle flux.  The times for this HV shut down
     period were: March 7, 2012 0:24:42 - March 12, 2012 15:50:42.
 
     During the data delivery from March 26, 2012 to September 17, 2012, the
     NS HV was shut down once from April 16, 2012, ~18:00 UTC to
     April 21, 2012, ~0:00 UTC for the MESSENGER spacecraft change from
     12-hour orbit to 8-hour orbit.
 
     During the data delivery from September 18, 2012 to March 17, 2013, the
     NS HV for the BP sensor was shut down twice: first from
     September 20, 2012 at 09:40 UTC to September 24, 2012 at 17:38 UTC when
     the NS BP sensor went into safe mode due to an energetic particle
     event; second on March 16, 2013 from 06:53 UTC to 08:00 UTC when the NS
     BP sensor went into safe mode due to an energetic particle event.
 
     During the data delivery from March 18, 2013 to September 17, 2013 the
     NS HV was shut down six times into safe mode due to high rates from
     energetic particles:
     1) April 24, 2013 to April 25, 2013;
     2) May 2, 2013, 8:45 UTC to May 2, 2013, 9:16 UTC;
     3) May 21, 2013, 8:57 UTC to May 21, 2013, 9:32 UTC;
     4) May 21, 2013, 17:02 UTC to May 21, 2013, 17:33 UTC;
     5) June 21, 2013 to June 24, 2013;
     6) August 19, 2013 to August 22, 2013.
 
     During the data delivery from September 18, 2013 to March 17, 2014 the
     NS HV for the BP and/or LG sensor was shut down 6 times:
     1) for approximately two hours on October 25, 2013; 2) October 28, 2013,
     16:00 UTC to October 29, 2013 02:00 UTC; 3) For less than an hour on
     November 5, 2013; 4) For less than an hour on December 14, 2013;
     5) December 26, 2013 07:00 UTC to December 31, 2013 20:00 UTC;
     6) For less than an hour on Jan 25, 2014.
 
     During the data delivery from March 18, 2014 to September 17, 2014 the
     NS HV for the BP and LG sensors was shut down twice for a few hours for
     spacecraft thrusting maneuvers.  These times were June 17, 2014 at
     12:00 UTC and September 12, 2014 at 13:00 UTC.
 
     The specific operational periods in relation to the mission phases
     were:
 
                           Start time         End time
     Phase Name            Date (DOY)         Date (DOY)
     -----------------     -----------------  -----------------
     Launch                12 Aug 2004 (225)  13 Aug 2004 (226)
     Earth Cruise          18 Apr 2005 (108)  23 May 2004 (143)
     Earth Flyby           16 Aug 2005 (228)  16 Aug 2005 (228)
     Venus 1 Cruise        07 Sep 2005 (250)  11 Sep 2005 (254)
                           07 Mar 2006 (066)  11 Mar 2006 (070)
                           16 Jun 2006 (167)  16 Jun 2006 (167)
                           21 Jun 2006 (172)  22 Jun 2006 (173)
     Venus 1 Flyby         No Data
     Venus 2 Cruise        31 Jan 2007 (031)  22 May 2007 (142)
     Venus 2 Flyby         23 May 2007 (143)  20 Jun 2007 (171)
     Mercury 1 Cruise      21 Jun 2007 (172)  17 Oct 2007 (290)
     Mercury 1 Cruise      21 Dec 2007 (355)  30 Dec 2007 (364)
     Mercury 1 Flyby       31 Dec 2007 (365)  28 Jan 2008 (028)
     Mercury 2 Cruise      29 Jan 2008 (029)  25 Feb 2008 (056)
     Mercury 2 Cruise      29 Mar 2008 (089)  21 Sep 2008 (265)
     Mercury 2 Flyby       22 Sep 2008 (266)  20 Oct 2008 (294)
     Mercury 3 Cruise      21 Oct 2008 (295)  19 Nov 2008 (324)
                           11 Jan 2009 (011)   07 Jul 2009 (188)
                           22 Jul 2009 (203)  18 Aug 2009 (230)
                           23 Aug 2009 (235)  01 Sep 2009 (244)
                           04 Sep 2009 (247)  15 Sep 2009 (258)
     Mercury 3 Flyby       16 Sep 2009 (259)  29 Sep 2009 (272)
                           01 Oct 2009 (274)  12 Oct 2009 (285)
     Mercury 4 Cruise      09 Dec 2009 (343)  21 May 2010 (141)
                           26 May 2010 (146)  03 Dec 2010 (337)
                           06 Dec 2010 (340)  03 Mar 2011 (062)
     Mercury Orbit         04 Mar 2011 (063)  16 Mar 2011 (075)(for MOI)
                           23 Mar 2011 (082)  24 May 2011 (144)
                           03 Jun 2011 (154)  07 Mar 2012 (067)
                           12 Mar 2012 (072)  17 Mar 2012 (077)
     Mercury Orbit Year 2  18 Mar 2012 (078)  16 Apr 2012 (107)
                           21 Apr 2012 (112)  20 Sep 2012 (264)
                           24 Sep 2012 (268)  17 Mar 2013 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 3  18 Mar 2013 (077)  17 Mar 2014 (076)
     Mercury Orbit Year 4  18 Mar 2014 (077)  17 Mar 2015 (076)
 
   Quality and Limitations
   =======================
     This data set has been processed as described in the &apos;MESSENGER Neutron
     Spectrometer (NS) EDR-to-CDR-to-DDR Processing&apos; document. All data have
     been successfully processed through the NS data processing codes and
     all data are found to be nominal.  Other than the scheduled &apos;instrument
     off&apos; periods described above, no data gaps or corrupted data have been
     identified for any of the NS operational periods. Although there may be
     some data not identified as missing or corrupted, such data should be
     minimal and a very small fraction of the available data.
 
     Regarding data quality, the primary factor that affects the quality of
     the NS data are solar particle events.  The table below lists the times
     during the data delivery period where it was determined that there were
     fluxes of solar energetic particles high enough to affect the data
     background.  The columns of the table are:  Name (numeric label for the
     solar particle event); start time in UTC indicating the starting time
     of the solar particle event; stop time in UTC indicating the stopping
     time of the solar particle event; type (All stands for all sensors, LG1
     or LG2 stands for lithium glass sensor 1 or 2 only; BPS stands for
     borated plastic scintillator only).
 
     Name    Start Time             End Time                Type
     ------------------------------------------------------------
     001     03/24/2011 11:48:19    03/24/2011 18:50:03     All
     002     03/25/2011 05:52:23    03/25/2011 10:15:36     All
     003     03/25/2011 23:01:18    03/26/2011 04:28:38     LG2
     004     03/30/2011 17:00:00    03/30/2011 22:00:00     All
     005     04/04/2011 09:48:40    04/04/2011 13:56:56     LG2
     006     05/24/2011 22:00:00    06/03/2011 03:45:00     All
     007     06/04/2011 06:13:13    06/10/2011 22:00:00     BPS
     008     06/04/2011 06:13:13    06/12/2011 07:00:00     LG1
     009     06/04/2011 06:13:13    06/15/2011 22:00:00     All
     010     08/02/2011 05:39:24    08/02/2011 18:24:21     All
     011     08/04/2011 03:33:28    08/05/2011 17:00:00     All
     012     08/09/2011 07:00:00    08/10/2011 03:00:00     All
     013     09/05/2011 05:39:00    09/08/2011 14:00:00     LG2
     014     09/06/2011 04:45:00    09/06/2011 07:10:00     BPS
     015     09/07/2011 04:01:00    09/07/2011 06:32:00     BPS
     016     09/07/2011 18:58:00    09/08/2011 06:00:00     BPS
     017     09/08/2011 22:20:00    09/10/2011 02:00:00     All
     018     09/22/2011 11:25:40    09/24/2011 08:00:00     All
     019     10/04/2011 12:53:49    10/06/2011 02:55:42     All
     020     10/14/2011 12:56:57    10/15/2011 10:13:16     All
     021     10/17/2011 08:10:30    10/17/2011 11:38:16     LG2
     022     11/03/2011 22:50:16    11/06/2011 02:00:00     All
     023     11/09/2011 12:56:40    11/09/2011 18:45:00     All
     024     11/17/2011 20:52:37    11/18/2011 16:50:00     All
     025     12/14/2011 14:20:00    12/14/2011 22:30:00     All
     026     12/25/2011 17:48:00    12/26/2011 15:55:00     All
     027     01/02/2012 14:54:00    01/03/2012 13:50:00     All
     028     01/23/2012 05:36:00    02/06/2012 00:01:00     All
     029     03/03/2012 20:11:00    03/17/2012 00:00:00     All
     030     04/05/2012 21:13:05    04/06/2012 00:14:30     All
     031     04/09/2012 11:04:13    04/09/2012 17:17:43     All
     032     04/26/2012 08:25:36    04/26/2012 12:10:43     All
     033     04/27/2012 16:00:00    04/28/2012 02:58:00     All
     034     05/17/2012 02:32:33    05/19/2012 02:37:40     All
     035     05/26/2012 20:16:48    05/30/2012 02:42:00     All
     036     06/28/2012 16:04:00    06/29/2012 17:00:00     All
     037     07/01/2012 18:58:00    07/02/2012 02:00:00     All
     038     07/02/2012 10:18:10    07/02/2012 18:09:00     All
     039     07/03/2012 03:03:15    07/03/2012 11:04:13     All
     040     07/12/2012 16:26:11    07/14/2012 19:30:00     All
     041     07/17/2012 17:00:00    07/21/2012 02:00:00     All
     042     07/23/2012 03:52:00    07/29/2012 12:00:00     All
     043     07/30/2012 18:34:28    07/30/2012 21:59:08     All
     044     07/31/2012 21:47:30    08/01/2012 03:00:00     All
     045     09/08/2012 11:14:27    09/08/2012 17:33:04     All
     046     09/19/2012 10:48:00    09/25/2012 02:00:00     All
     047     09/28/2012 09:50:00    10/01/2012 02:00:00     All
     048     10/08/2012 12:22:25    10/09/2012 09:52:50     All
     049     10/14/2012 00:30:30    10/14/2012 20:27:11     All
     050     10/23/2012 02:57:19    10/23/2012 03:27:48     All
     051     10/26/2012 11:29:47    10/26/2012 19:51:10     All
     052     11/08/2012 01:45:18    11/08/2012 09:47:18     All
     053     11/18/2012 03:33:20    11/18/2012 10:06:41     All
     054     11/21/2012 13:42:49    11/22/2012 03:54:25     All
     055     02/05/2013 08:10:15    02/05/2013 11:09:20     All
     056     03/15/2013 17:58:39    03/17/2013 04:40:28     All
     057     04/11/2013 05:52:06    04/13/2013 02:12:05     All
     058     04/21/2013 06:33:02    04/23/2013 02:00:00     All
     059     04/24/2013 21:13:05    04/26/2013 12:00:00     All
     060     04/27/2013 21:43:47    04/28/2013 02:06:58     All
     061     04/28/2013 12:10:43    04/28/2013 14:59:34     All
     062     05/10/2013 18:34:28    05/11/2013 02:00:00     All
     063     05/13/2013 15:30:16    05/14/2013 13:37:42     All
     064     05/15/2013 03:28:50    05/15/2013 05:16:17     All
     065     05/31/2013 19:40:00    06/01/2013 02:37:40     All
     066     06/21/2013 03:08:22    06/25/2013 02:00:00     All
     067     08/19/2013 22:29:50    08/22/2013 22:00:00     All
     068     10/05/2013 06:27:55    10/07/2013 22:00:00     All
     069     10/11/2013 06:33:02    10/16/2013 05:16:17     All
     070     10/20/2013 06:02:20    10/20/2013 13:01:53     All
     071     10/22/2013 20:32:00    10/23/2013 20:37:16     All
     072     10/25/2013 07:29:00    10/27/2013 12:00:00     All
     073     10/28/2013 04:09:00    10/31/2013 12:00:00     All
     074     11/02/2013 04:35:00    11/03/2013 06:00:00     All
     075     11/04/2013 05:46:00    11/05/2013 04:25:00     All
     076     11/05/2013 21:43:00    11/05/2013 23:01:00     All
     077     11/07/2013 10:48:00    11/09/2013 22:00:00     All
     078     11/19/2013 09:57:00    11/21/2013 12:00:00     All
     079     11/29/2013 03:59:00    11/29/2013 20:07:00     All
     080     11/30/2013 02:37:00    12/02/2013 03:23:00     All
     081     12/05/2013 11:34:00    12/05/2013 20:53:00     All
     082     12/13/2013 20:06:00    12/15/2013 12:00:00     All
     083     12/26/2013 03:13:00    12/31/2013 22:00:00     All
     084     01/06/2014 07:19:05    01/11/2014 22:00:00     All
     085     01/22/2014 03:59:32    01/23/2014 07:00:00     All
     086     01/27/2014 22:00:00    01/31/2014 05:52:00     All
     087     02/11/2014 03:03:15    02/11/2014 21:02:00     All
     088     02/12/2014 06:07:27    02/12/2014 12:10:00     All
     089     02/14/2014 15:45:00    02/15/2014 12:32:00     All
     090     02/18/2014 00:29:45    02/19/2014 04:00:00     All
     091     02/20/2014 07:00:00    02/21/2014 06:00:00     All
     092     02/25/2014 03:44:11    03/05/2014 06:00:00     All
     093     03/14/2014 21:28:00    03/14/2014 12:00:00     All
     094     03/29/2014 16:41:00    03/30/2014 07:00:00     All
     095     04/29/2014 19:09:00    04/29/2014 23:00:00     All
     096     05/05/2014 14:44:00    05/05/2014 20:48:00     All
     097     06/04/2014 19:24:00    06/05/2014 07:00:00     All
     098     06/10/2014 11:19:00    06/10/2014 14:20:00     All
     099     06/12/2014 21:38:00    06/13/2014 15:14:00     All
     100     07/11/2014 12:56:46    07/11/2014 13:58:10     All
     101     08/08/2014 12:05:36    08/09/2014 12:00:00     All
     102     08/24/2014 11:45:00    08/24/2014 21:00:00     All
     103     09/01/2014 08:35:00    09/07/2014 07:10:00     All
     104     09/08/2014 20:00:00    09/09/2014 07:49:47     All
     105     09/10/2014 16:41:00    09/13/2014 00:45:00     All
     106     09/25/2014 00:55:00    09/28/2014 09:57:00     All
 
     It has been determined that the deadtime correction for nominal solar
     quiet conditions is minimal and is therefore not being applied.
     Deadtime remains an important uncorrected effect for periods of intense
     solar activity.  However, those periods of intense solar activity,
     which are listed above, do not provide valid planetary data and are not
     used in the normal planetary data processing.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SUPERSEDED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

