<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lro-l-mrflro-4-cdr-insar-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LRO MOON MINI-RF 4 INSAR CALIBRATED DATA REC V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mrflro.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-mrflro-4-cdr-insar-v1.0__browserp_lro-l-mrflro-4-cdr-insar-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-mrflro-4-cdr-insar-v1.0__dvo_geo_lro-l-mrflro-4-cdr-insar-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-mrflro-4-cdr-insar-v1.0__pds.geo.lro.orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Nozette, S., P. Spudis, B. Bussey, K. Raney, H. Winters, C.L. Lichtenberg, W.
                   Marinelli, J. Crusan, and M. Gates, The LRO Miniature Radio Frequency (Mini-RF)
                   technology demonstration, Space Sci. Rev., submitted, 2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NOZETTEETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LRO-L-MRFLRO-4-CDR-INSAR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LRO MOON MINI-RF 4 INSAR CALIBRATED DATA REC V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>Unknown</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2009-01-01</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>MINI-RF POC</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            LRO Mini-RF Continuous Mode Calibrated Level 1 Data Set V1.0,
            LRO-L-MRFLRO-4-CDR-INSAR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2008.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Calibrated Level 1 data records and ancillary files from the LRO
            Mini-RF lunar mission collected in scatterometry mode.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains Level 1 archival calibrated continuous
            mode data acquired from the Mini-RF instrument during the LRO
            mission and associated ancillary data.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The InSAR products are produced from continuous mode data acquisition.
      The Mini-RF Calibrated Data Archive is a time-ordered collection of
      calibrated Level 1 continuous mode images.  This data set also
      contains stokes parameters files, polarization ratio files, a
      browse image, ancillary data, and calibration data.
 
      Please see documentation in the DOCUMENT directory for
      additional information on the data files and their format.
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      See individual SIS documents, which are located in the
      DOCUMENT directory, for detailed descriptions of each file
      contained in this data archive.
 
    Processing
    ==========
      The POC produces Level 1 continuous mode CDRs by ingesting the Level 0
      PDRs and associated Level 0 ancillary files into the Vexcel(TM) SWATH
      processor.  The data are created in single-look complex format with
      pixel spacing in the native sampling aspect ratios.  Calibration is
      applied. A full PDS label accompanies each data file and gives a
      detailed description of the content and format.
 
    Data
    ====
      The Level 1 CDRs are images in range and azimuth orientation
      with pixel values in beta naught, which have been radiometrically
      and polarmetrically calibrated. They are continuous mode Horizontal
      channel interferometry image strips.  Each pixel is a complex number
      consisting of a 4-byte floating point real and 4-byte floating point
      imaginary part for a total of 8-bytes.
 
      All Level 1 CDR image products are each accompanied by four Stokes
      parameters files. Mini-RF transmits a right circular polarized signal,
      and receives Horizontal and vertical polarized signals, and the phase
      between the polarizations.  The Level 1 file consists of four pieces
      of information per pixel.  The received power on the horizontal
      polarization (ERH), the received power in the vertical polarization
      (ERV) and the real and imaginary portions of the cross product between
      the two polarization signals (Re ERH ERV* &amp; Im ERH ERV* ).
 
      The four Stokes parameters (S1, S2, S3, and S4) are related to the
      data in the level 1 files by the following equations:
 
      S1   =   ERH + ERV
      S2   =   ERH - ERV
      S3   =   2 Re  ERH ERV*
      S4   =   -2 Im  ERH ERV*
 
      These data are stored in the DATA/SAR/&lt;orbit&gt;/LEVEL1 directory on
      archival volumes. File names are described in LRO_DP_SIS.PDF.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      Each science product is accompanied by a text metadata file
      that contains the parameters that describe the state the instrument
      was in at the time of data collection and location and timing
      information about the data set.  This file is referenced in the
      PDS label associated with the science data product.
 
 
    Calibration Data
    ================
      Calibration files produced by the Vexcel(TM) CalPro processor are
      included with the Level 1 data set.  Consult the Mini-RF Calibration
      Plan included in the DOCUMENT directory of this archive and the
      MRF_INST.CAT file for details.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      Level 1 data products are not dependent on definition of a
      coordinate system.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      No software is included with this archival data set.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
 
      These products are delivered on a hard-drive or by ftp and
      not on a specific formatted medium.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this data are collected from orbits around the Moon.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was reviewed by the Mini-RF
      Team prior to submission to the Planetary Data System (PDS).
 
      Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data
      set, key elements of the archive were distributed for
      preliminary review.  These included electronic versions of
      example PDS labels, CATALOG files, and Software Interface
      Specifications.  These materials were distributed to PDS
      personnel, the experiment investigator, and others,
      as appropriate.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      The coverage on each archival volume is associated with the
      orbit number.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

