<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.grail-l-spice-6-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>GRAIL SPICE KERNELS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.gravity_recovery_and_interior_laboratory::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.grail-a::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.grail-b::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.grail-a::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:spice.grail-b::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.grail-l-spice-6-v1.0__browserp_grail-l-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.grail-l-spice-6-v1.0__browser_grail-l-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.grail-l-spice-6-v1.0__browser_wgc_grail-l-spice-6-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.naif::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Acton, C.H., The SPICE System - A Brief Overview, Navigation and Ancillary
                   Information Facility, JPL, 1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ACTON1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>GRAIL-L-SPICE-6-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>GRAIL SPICE KERNELS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2012-10-30</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2011-09-10T13:08:52Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2012-12-17T22:29:15Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>BORIS V. SEMENOV</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Semenov, B.V., and C.H. Acton, GRAIL SPICE KERNELS V1.0,
            GRAIL-L-SPICE-6-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2012.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Navigation and ancillary data in the form of SPICE System kernel
            files for the GRAIL spacecraft.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set includes the complete set of GRAIL SPICE data files
            (``kernel files&apos;), which can be accessed using SPICE
            software. The SPICE data contain geometric and other ancillary
            information needed to recover the full value of science
            instrument data. In particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft
            and planetary ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments,
            spacecraft orientation, and data needed for relevant time
            conversions.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
      Data Set Overview
      =================
 
      This data set includes the complete set of GRAIL SPICE data files
      (``kernel files&apos;), which can be accessed using SPICE software.
      The SPICE data contain geometric and other ancillary information
      needed to recover the full value of science instrument data. In
      particular SPICE kernels provide spacecraft and planetary
      ephemerides, instrument mounting alignments, spacecraft
      orientation, and data needed for relevant time conversions.
 
      This data set is contained on a single virtual volume,
      GRLSP_1000, including data from all mission phases and covering
      from launch, 2011-09-10T13:08:52, through the end time of the
      latest spacecraft trajectory file supplied in the data set. Until
      the end of the spacecraft lifespan this data set is accumulating
      with new data added according the project archive release
      schedule.
 
      Data Types (SPICE kernel types)
      ===============================
 
      SPK kernels contain ephemerides for spacecraft, planets,
      satellites, comets and asteroids as well as for moving or fixed
      spacecraft and instrument structures. They provide position and
      velocity, given in a Cartesian reference frame. SPK files are
      located under the ``data/spk&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      PCK kernels contain certain physical, dynamical and cartographic
      constants for target bodies, such as size and shape
      specifications, and orientation of the spin axis and prime
      meridian. PCK files are located under the ``data/pck&apos; directory
      of this data set.
 
      IK kernels (Instrument description kernels) give descriptive and
      operational data peculiar to a particular scientific instrument,
      such as internal timing relative to the spacecraft clock and
      field-of-view model parameters. IK files are located under the
      ``data/ik&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      CK kernels describe pointing, containing a transformation
      traditionally called the C-matrix which is used to determine
      time-tagged pointing (orientation) angles for a spacecraft
      structure upon which science instruments are mounted. CK files
      are located under the ``data/ck&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      EK (Events) kernels are derived from the integrated sequence of
      events used to produce actual spacecraft commands. EK files are
      located under the ``data/ek&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      LSK (Leapseconds) kernels contain the leapseconds and the values
      of other constants required to perform a transformation between
      Universal Time Coordinated (UTC) and Ephemeris time (ET). LSK
      files are located under the ``data/lsk&apos; directory of this data
      set.
 
      SCLK (Spacecraft Clock) kernels contain on-board clock
      calibration data required to perform a mapping between Ephemeris
      time (ET) and spacecraft on-board time (SCLK). SCLK files are
      located under the ``data/sclk&apos; directory of this data set.
 
      FK (Frame Definitions) kernels contain information required to
      define reference frames, sources of frame orientation data and
      connections between these frames and other frames supported
      within the SPICE system. This includes mounting alignment
      information for each instrument. FK files are located under the
      ``data/fk&apos; directory of this data set.
 
 
      Kernel File Details
      ===================
 
      A brief overview of the different types of GRAIL kernels included
      in this data set is provided in the CONFIDENCE_LEVEL_NOTE section
      of this file while details specific to individual files are found
      in the ``*info.txt&apos; files in the corresponding data directory.
      The most detailed description of the data in each file is
      provided in metadata included inside the file -- in the
      description area of text kernels or in the comment area of binary
      kernels.
 
 
      Software
      ========
 
      The SPICE Toolkit contains software modules needed to read SPICE
      kernel files. SPICE software is highly documented via internal
      headers. Additional documentation is available in separate ASCII
      text files called Required Reading files. For example, the S- and
      P- Kernel (SPK) Required Reading File, named SPK.REQ, describes
      use of the SPK kernel file readers and contains sample programs.
 
      The latest SPICE Toolkit for a variety of computer platforms such
      as PC, Mac, SUN, etc. is available at the NAIF Node of PDS
      electronically (via anonymous FTP and WWW servers). Refer to
      information in ``software/softinfo.txt&apos; for details regarding
      obtaining this software. Each version of the Toolkit is also
      archived at the NASA National Space Science Data Center.
 
 
      Loading Kernel Files into a SPICE-based Application
      ===================================================
 
      The easiest way to make data from a collection of SPICE kernels
      available to a SPICE-based application is to list these kernels
      in a meta-kernel and load it into the program using the high
      level SPICE data loader routine FURNSH. This data set provides
      such meta-kernel(s) under the ``extras/mk&apos; directory. For more
      information about the GRAIL meta-kernel(s), see the file
      ``extras/mk/mkinfo.txt&apos;.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
      This data set contains SPICE kernel files created during mission
      operations and after mission data reconstruction and analysis.
      Some general information about this collection follows here, but
      the prospective user is also referred to extensive descriptions
      about each file that are stored inside each kernel file. These
      metadata provide detailed information regarding the information
      source from which the data were derived, the type of processing
      applied to the source data, applicability of the data, etc.
      Metadata are located in the ``comment area&apos; for binary kernel
      types (SPK, CK, ESQ), accessible using either the COMMNT or
      SPACIT utility program found in the NAIF Toolkit. Metadata are
      located after ``\begintext&apos; markers within the text kernel types
      (PCK, IK, FK, LSK, SCLK, MK), accessible by using any available
      text file display tool such as a word processor, text editor, or
      the unix ``more&apos; or ``cat&apos; commands.
 
      Where there are questions about data accuracy or ``confidence&apos;
      not addressed herein the reader is invited to contact the NAIF
      node of the Planetary Data System for possible further
      information.
 
 
      SPK Files
      =========
 
      Three kinds of SPK files are provided in this archive: SPK files
      for the spacecraft orbit, SPK files for the crash sites, and SPK
      files for the Solar System planets and satellites.
 
      The spacecraft orbit SPK files contain the spacecraft trajectory
      determined by the GRAIL Navigation (NAV) Team, JPL or by the
      GRAIL Science Team, JPL.
 
      The NAV spacecraft SPKs are available for all phases of the
      mission. Since the NAV team team did not have a formal trajectory
      reconstruction requirement, these SPKs contain a mix of
      reconstruction and short-term prediction segments with trajectory
      errors reaching up to a few hundred meters (based on segment
      boundary discontinuities).
 
      The science spacecraft SPKs are available for only for the
      science phases of the mission. They are based on Deep Space
      Network one-way Doppler and two-way Doppler tracking data and the
      inter-satellite range rate measurements. The gravity field used
      for the GRAIL science orbits was a GRAIL internal gravity field
      of degree and order 420 (420b8a), which had all primary mission
      inter-satellite range data included. The resulting orbit accuracy
      of the orbit in absolute sense is a the meter level and in
      relative range rate error between the spacecraft is better than
      20 um/sec.
 
      The crash site SPKs included in this data set contain the
      locations of the spacecraft crash sites of the Moon surface
      relative to the Moon center, and fixed, zero-offset positions of
      the spacecraft relative to these sites, covering from the crash
      times far into the future. The 3-sigma accuracy of the crash site
      locations provided by the NAV team is 2.75 meters downtrack / 65
      meters crosstrack for GRAIL-A and 3.33 meters downtrack / 17
      meters crosstrack for GRAIL-B.
 
      The DE421 planetary ephemeris SPK file included in this data set
      contains ephemeris data for the Solar System planet barycenters,
      Sun, Mercury, Venus, Earth, Moon, and Mars. This version of
      ephemerides was officially used by the project during mission
      operations. The internal comments included this SPK file provide
      detailed accuracy information.
 
      More information about GRAIL SPK files is available in the file
      ``data/spk/spkinfo.txt&apos;.
 
      This data set also includes the orbit number files generated by
      the NAIF&apos;s ORBNUM utility program using the archive spacecraft
      SPKs. These files are not SPICE kernels; for this reason they are
      provided in the ``extras/orbnum&apos; directory. For more information
      about the GRAIL orbit number files, see the file
      ``extras/orbnum/orbinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      CK Files
      ========
 
      One kind of C-kernel files is provided in this archive: the
      reconstructed spacecraft bus (SC) orientation CKs.
 
      The reconstructed spacecraft bus (SC) CK files were created from
      engineering telemetry downlinked from the spacecraft by NAIF.
      Neither formal nor informal accuracy estimates for the spacecraft
      bus attitude provided in these reconstructed CK files were
      available at the time when this archive was created.
 
      More information about GRAIL CK files is available in the file
      ``data/ck/ckinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      PCK Files
      =========
 
      Two PCK files are provided in this data set, one is a text PCK
      containing on the official IAU/IAG/COSPAR values accepted in
      2006, the other is a binary PCK containing high-accuracy
      orientation data for the lunar principal axes (PA) reference
      frame, from the JPL Solar System Dynamics Group&apos;s planetary
      ephemeris DE-421. Both files were the versions used by the
      project during operations.
 
      More information about the PCK files included in this data set is
      available in the file ``data/pck/pckinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      FK Files
      ========
 
      This data set includes the GRAIL mission FK file, a generic Lunar
      FK file, and the crash site topocentric frame FK file. The GRAIL
      FK file defines the frames for the GRAIL spacecraft and their
      science instruments. The instrument frames defined in it
      incorporate the instrument mounting alignment data. The generic
      Lunar FK file defines a number of lunar body-fixed frames
      associated high-accuracy lunar orientation data provided by the
      JPL Solar System Dynamics Group&apos;s planetary ephemerides. The
      crash site topocentric frame FK file defines the topocentric frames
      at the spacecraft crash sites.
 
      More information about the GRAIL FK files is available in
      the file ``data/fk/fkinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      IK Files
      ========
 
      This data set includes IK files for instruments on the GRAIL
      spacecraft, including the Lunar Gravity Ranging System, MoonKAM
      cameras, and the star trackers.
 
      Because the sets of geometric parameters included in the IKs vary
      from instrument to instrument users are encouraged to carefully
      examine the IKs before using them.
 
      More information about GRAIL IK files is available in the file
      ``data/ik/ikinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      SCLK Files
      ==========
 
      This data set includes the GRAIL Spacecraft Clock kernel files
      provide a tabulation of data needed for converting time
      measurements between ephemeris time (ET) and spacecraft clock
      time (SCLK). The GRAIL SPICE SCLK files were made from similar
      files--SCLK/SCET files, or SCLKvSCET files--produced by another
      mission entity. Each newly made SCLK file fully replaces the
      previous SCLK file.
 
      For GRAIL, the time correlation accuracy provided in the SCLK
      kernel files for the science phases is informally reported to be
      better than 40 milliseconds.
 
      SPICE software does not prohibit an SCLK file from being used for
      time conversions occurring for ``future times&apos; (or more
      accurately, for epochs that occur later than the epoch of the
      last telemetry data used in producing the last correlation
      coefficients found in the SCLK file). Such ``predict&apos; time
      conversions are likely to be inaccurate (changed somewhat) once
      the epoch of interest has been passed.
 
      More information about the GRAIL SCLK files is available in the
      file ``data/sclk/sclkinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      LSK Files
      =========
 
      Leapseconds kernel files provide a tabulation of ``leapseconds&apos;
      and some other terms used in converting time measurements between
      ephemeris time (ET) and Universal Time (UTC). ``Spacecraft Event
      Time&apos; (SCET) is the commonly used name for UTC events measured
      at the spacecraft.
 
      Metadata describing how the LSK data are obtained or computed is
      contained inside the LSK text file. The time conversion provided
      by SPICE LSK files is accurate to approximately 0.000030 seconds.
 
      More information about the LSK files is available in the file
      ``data/lsk/lskinfo.txt&apos;.
 
 
      EK Files
      ========
 
      The GRAIL project did not produce any EK files; therefore, no EKs
      are included in this data set.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

