<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lro-l-dlre-2-edr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LRO DLRE LEVEL 2 EDR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:dlre.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-dlre-2-edr-v1.0__browserp_lro-l-dlre-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-dlre-2-edr-v1.0__dvo_geo_lro-l-dlre-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-dlre-2-edr-v1.0__pds.geo.lro.orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Paige, D.A., et al., The Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter Diviner Lunar Radiometer
                   Experiment, Space Sci. Rev., doi: 10.1007/s11214-009-9529-2, 2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PAIGEETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LRO-L-DLRE-2-EDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LRO DLRE LEVEL 2 EDR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-06-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2009-07-05T16:50:26.259Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2016-03-15T23:59:59.897Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID PAIGE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Paige et al., LRO DLRE LEVEL 2 EDR V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, LRO-L-DLRE-2-EDR-V1.0, 2010.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Unpacked, uncalibrated LRO DLRE engineering and science
            measurements
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set consists of the Diviner Lunar Radiometer Experiment
            uncalibrated observations, also known as EDRs. The DLRE is a
            surface pushbroom mapper that measures emitted thermal radiation
            and reflected solar radiation from the surface of the moon. Two
            Diviner solar channels measure 0.3-3 micrometers reflected solar
            radiation. Three Diviner channels near 8 micrometers classify
            regolith mineralogy by mapping the location of the Christiansen
            feature. The remaining four Diviner channels measure surface
            temperature in four spectral bands ranging from 12.5 micrometers
            to beyond 200 micrometers.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
Data Product Overview
===========================================================================+
 
Every 2.048 seconds Diviner collects a data &apos;frame&apos; containing
the following:
 
* 16 sets of science data, with each set containing 192 sixteen-bit
  science measurements from the focal plane interface electronics
  obtained over integration periods of 0.128 seconds
* A single set of instrument engineering and housekeeping
  measurements (or &apos;engineering data&apos;)
 
The data are downlinked to the LRO Ground Data System (GDS) and are
pushed to the Diviner SOC at the end of each downlink pass. Diviner
software assembles the telemetry files into EDR data tables, each
covering a one-hour time period.
 
Each Diviner EDR data product will consist of two files.  The first
file is an ASCII formatted detached PDS label.  The second file is
the ASCII data table file.
 
Each ASCII record contains 2656 bytes, and there will be a record
every 0.128 seconds (unless there is a data gap; time periods which
contain no data will not produce data records).  Each one-hour
Diviner EDR ASCII data table will be up to approximately 75 MB. The
volume of the EDR data product will be up to approximately 1800 MB
per day.
 
While there is only a single set of engineering data for the 16 sets
of science data, it is known during which of the 16 science data
sets a given engineering measurement was taken. In the EDR, the
engineering data are propagated across each science data set for a
completely uniform and flat file. Each engineering measurement will
contain a valid value during the appropriate science data set, and
the UNKNOWN_CONSTANT (-9999) during the other science data sets
where engineering data were not obtained.
 
In the ASCII data tables, each complete set of science data plus
engineering data is considered a &apos;record&apos;, and is contained on a
single line.    Where a data measurement is not valid or applicable,
the UNKNOWN_CONSTANT will be found.
 
 
Data Processing Level
=====================
 
This document uses the Committee on Data Management and Computation
(CODMAC) data level numbering system to describe the processing
level of the EDR data product. Diviner EDR data products are
considered CODMAC &apos;Level 2&apos;, equivalent to NASA level 0. The EDR
data files are generated from CODMAC Level 1 or &apos;Raw Data&apos;, which
are the telemetry packets within the project specific Standard
Formatted Data Unit (SFDU) record.
 
 
Data Product Generation
=======================
 
The Diviner EDR data products will be generated by the Diviner
Instrument Team at JPL. The EDR data products will be reconstructed
from telemetry data products and formatted according to the EDR SIS.
Meta-data acquired from the telemetry data headers will be used to
populate the PDS label. The PDS archives will be assembled and
delivered to the PDS from UCLA.
 
Data Flow
=========
 
Diviner science and engineering telemetry are transferred to the
Diviner JPL SOC. Once transferred, the Diviner software
automatically processes the telemetry into Level 0 EDR data
products. The Diviner EDR data products are then archived locally
at the Diviner operation center.
 
After an initial data validation period, the Diviner team will
assemble the data products and ancillary files into archive
volumes and will transfer the assembled volume to the PDS
Geosciences Node.  The Diviner EDR archive will be made available
via data releases scheduled at three month intervals as specified
in the Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter Project Data Management and
Archive Plan.
 
For more information please see the document DP_SIS.HTM
(HTML format) or DP_SIS.PDF (Adobe Acrobat format) located
in the DOCUMENT directory of this archive.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
Overview
========
 
With respect to the EDR data, the data exists in 2 states -- Absent
or Present.  For the data that is present, the confidence level is
high due to simplicity of the processing and structure of the data.
 
The quality flag (column 1) has limited meaning for the EDR
records.  A value of 0 indicates present and completely valid
data; a value of 1 indicates a record header line.
 
Individual columns in the data records will contain the
UNKNOWN_CONSTANT (-9999) where data is missing or unknown.
 
 
Review
======
 
This archival data set was examined by a peer review panel prior to
its acceptance by the Planetary Data System (PDS). The peer review
was conducted in accordance with PDS procedures.
 
Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data set,
key elements of the archive were distributed for preliminary
review.  These included electronic versions of example PDS labels,
CATALOG files, and Software Interface Specifications (SISs).
These materials were distributed to PDS personnel, the experiment
investigator, and others, as appropriate.
 
 
Data Coverage and Quality
=========================
 
The Diviner instrument has a 98% data return rate of expected data.
Data loss is typically seen during data transmission or spacecraft and
instrument anomalies.  Diviner performed a Warm Reset after failing to
see a valid equator crossing from LRO on August 22, 2009.  The Warm
Reset was needed to clear the bad equator crossing value.  Diviner
lost a few soundings.  The LRO spacecraft triggered a sun-safed event
that powered off all instruments on October 10, 2009. Approximately
eight hours of Diviner data was lost due to the anomaly.  Two more
sun-safed events occurred on both January 12, 2010 and February 9, 2010.
The Diviner instrument was powered off for both events.  On July 23, 2010
Diviner was powered off for almost five hours during a spacecraft maneuver
during which Diviner data were not collected.  On December 23, 2010
Diviner was powered off during for about 12 hours during an eclipse.
On February 23, 2011 Diviner was powered off for about 46 hours due
to a spacecraft safing event.  On April 03, 2011 Diviner was powered off
for about 23 hours due to a spacecraft safing event.  On June 06, 2011
Diviner lost about 14 hours of data due to a Ka-comm problem.
On March 22, 2012 Diviner was powered off for about 40 hours due to a
spacecraft safing event.  On September 04, 2012 Diviner was powered off
for about 17 hours due to a spacecraft safing event.  One September 08,
2012 Diviner was powered off for about 13 hours due to a spacecraft safing
event.
 
 
The following files were affected by the anomalies and are either partial
files or completely missing:
 
2009082202_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data between times
    02:03:55.171-02:04:06.422 due to invalid equator crossing from LRO.
 
2009101016_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data after 16:14:38.980
2009101017_EDR.TAB through 2009101023_EDR.TAB ---------&gt; 7 files missing
2009101100_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data before 00:41:15.607
 
2010011210_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data after 10:00:00:468
2010011211_EDR.TAB through 2010011220_RDR.TAB ---------&gt; 10 files missing
2010011221_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data before 21:18:56:194
 
2010020914_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data after 14:59:48:182
2010020915_EDR.TAB through 2010021520_EDR.TAB --------&gt; 150 files missing
2010021521_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data before 21:54:34:397
 
2010072414_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data after 14:34:04:253
2010072415_EDR.TAB through 2010072418_EDR.TAB --------&gt; 4 files missing
2010072419_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data before 19:24:37:058
 
2010122105_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data after 05:08:03:297
2010122106_EDR.TAB through 2010122116_EDR.TAB --------&gt; 11 files missing
2010122117_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data before 17:08:15:134
 
2011022314_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data after 14:24:57:290
2011022315_EDR.TAB through 2011022512_EDR.TAB --------&gt; 46 files missing
2011022513_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data before 13:07:28:380
 
2011040317_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data after 17:29:04:698
2011040318_EDR.TAB through 2011040413_EDR.TAB --------&gt; 20 files missing
2011040414_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data before 14:44:47:900
 
2011061409_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data after 09:37:20:572
2011061410_EDR.TAB through 2011061423_EDR.TAB --------&gt; 14 files missing
2011061500_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data before 00:07:20:869
 
2012032202_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data after 02:30:26:215
2012032203_EDR.TAB through 2012032317_EDR.TAB --------&gt; 39 files missing
2012032318_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data before 18:15:47570
 
2012090405_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data after 05:15:27:414
2012090406_EDR.TAB through 2012090420_EDR.TAB --------&gt; 15 files missing
2012090421_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data before 21:01:36:575
 
2012090801_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data after 01:15:04:908
2012090802_EDR.TAB through 2012090812_EDR.TAB --------&gt; 11 files missing
2012090813_RDR.TAB - partial - missing data before 13:51:51:681
 
2013112704_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data after 04:09:51:689
2013112705_EDR.TAB through 2013112919_EDR.TAB --------&gt; 63 files missing
2013112920_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data before 20:51:58:203
 
2014022611_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data after 11:20:42:962
2014022612_EDR.TAB through 2014022620_EDR.TAB --------&gt; 9 files missing
2014022621_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data before 21:29:57:716
 
2014041504_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data after 04:25:43:225
2014041505_EDR.TAB through 2014041516_EDR.TAB --------&gt; 12 files missing
2014041517_EDR.TAB - partial - missing data before 17:31:47:179
 
 
Limitations
===========
 
Data seen immediately after the instrument is powered on or after
a restart is suspect for a few seconds to a few minutes.  The pointing
information is typically incorrect or missing.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

