<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mro-m-crism-5-rdr-mptargeted-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MRO CRISM MAP-PROJECTED TARGETED REDUCED DATA RECORD V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:crism.mro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-crism-5-rdr-mptargeted-v1.0__browserp_mro-m-crism-5-rdr-mptargeted-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-crism-5-rdr-mptargeted-v1.0__browser_geo_mars_orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mro-m-crism-5-rdr-mptargeted-v1.0__dvo_mro-m-crism-5-rdr-mptargeted-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Seelos, F.P., M.F. Morgan, H.W. Taylor, S.L. Murchie, D.C. Humm, K.D. Seelos,
                   O.S. Barnouin, C.E. Viviano, and CRISM Team, CRISM Map Projected Targeted
                   Reduced Data Records (MTRDRs) - High level analysis and visualization data
                   products, in Summary and Abstracts of the Planetary Data Workshop, June 2012,
                   edited by L.R. Gaddis, T. Hare, and R. Beyer, USGS Open-File Report 2014-1056,
                   http://dx.doi.org/10.3133/ofr20141056, 2014.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SEELOSETAL2014</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Swayze, G.A., R.N. Clark, A.F.H. Goetz, T.G. Chrien, and N.S. Gorelick, Effects
                   of spectrometer band pass, sampling, and signal-to-noise on spectral
                   identification using the Tetracorder algorithm, J. Geophys. Res., Vol. 108, No.
                   E9, doi:10.1029/2003JE001975, 2003.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SWAYZEETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Viviano-Beck, C.E., F.P. Seelos, S.L. Murchie, E.G. Kahn, K.D. Seelos, H.W.
                   Taylor, K. Taylor, B.L. Ehlmann, S.M. Wiseman, J.F. Mustard, and M.F. Morgan,
                   Revised CRISM Spectral Parameters and Summary Products Based on the Currently
                   Detected Mineral Diversity on Mars, J. Geophys. Res., Vol. 119, pp. 1403-1431,
                   doi:10.1002/2014JE004627, 2014.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.VIVIANO-BECKETAL2014</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MRO-M-CRISM-5-RDR-MPTARGETED-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MRO CRISM MAP-PROJECTED TARGETED REDUCED DATA RECORD V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2016-03-04</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2016-03-04</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>FRANK SEELOS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Seelos, F., Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter Compact Reconnaissance
            Imaging Spectrometer for Mars Map-projected Targeted Reduced Data
            Record, MRO-M-CRISM-5-RDR-MPTARGETED-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2016.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Map-projected Targeted Reduced Data Records derived from CRISM
            (Compact Reconnaissance Imaging Spectrometer for Mars) VNIR and
            IR image cubes.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This volume contains the CRISM Map-projected Targeted Reduced
            Data Record (MTRDR) archive, a collection of multiband image
            cubes derived from targeted (gimbaled) observations of Mars&apos;
            surface acquired by the Compact Reconnaissance Imaging
            Spectrometer for Mars (CRISM) instrument on the Mars
            Reconnaissance Orbiter (MRO) spacecraft. Post-processing attempts
            to represent the spectrum the instrument would have measured
            looking at the surface of Mars at a standard illumination
            geometry, in the absence of atmospheric gases, with aerosol
            scattering normalized to that at the geometry within the
            observation that is closest to nadir, in the absence of
            instrument artifacts. A series of value added products represent
            spatial variability in signatures of minerals of interest. The
            data are map projected using terrain models of the Martian
            surface. A companion Targeted Empirical Record (TER) archive
            contains mostly the same data in the sensor space of the IR
            detector to support map projection using future more accurate
            terrain models.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
 
      This volume contains the CRISM Map-projected Targeted Reduced Data
      Record (MTRDR) archive, a collection of multiband image cubes derived
      from targeted (gimbaled) observations acquired by the Compact
      Reconnaissance Imaging Spectrometer for Mars (CRISM) instrument on the
      Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter (MRO) spacecraft. The primary MTRDR product
      (IF) consists of spectral reflectance (I/F) data corrected for
      photometric, atmospheric, and instrumental effects, that has been
      map-projected in accordance with MRO project standards, with an
      associated text file that contains wavelength information (WV) for each
      spectral band. For observations for which both VNIR (S-detector) and
      IR (L-detector) hyperspectral image cubes were acquired, the data
      from the VNIR detector has been spatially registered and concatenated
      to the IR data to form a full spectral range image cube that is
      map-projected with bad bands removed. The MTRDR product set also
      includes a spectral summary parameter (SU) image cube
      calculated using an updated version of the CRISM spectral summary
      parameter library [VIVIANO-BECKETAL2014], a refined spectral summary
      parameter (SR) image cube which is a noise-remediated version of
      the SU product, a series of browse product (BR) spectral content
      visualizations which are composed of thematically related summary
      parameters, a set of data processing information (IN) maps that
      illustrate spatial/spectral residuals related to the VNIR/IR spectral
      concatenation and empirical atmospheric correction, and a map-projected
      version of the IR (L-detector) Derived Data Record (DE) for the
      subject targeted observation. The DE multiband image contains
      the same information as the DDR for the IR part of the observation
      (photometric angles, MOLA topography, etc.) except that it is in
      map-projected form.
 
      The constituent products can be identified by the filename/product ID
      activity string prefix and the product type string:
      CCCNNNNNNNN_XX_AAAAAD_TTTV
 
      CCC = Class Type (e.g. FRT, HRL, HRS)
      NNNNNNNN = Hexadecimal observation ID
      XX = Hexadecimal observation segment counter
      AAAAA = Activity string - composed of a 2-character prefix followed by
              3-digit macro ID. The 2-character prefix describes the contents
              of the file, and includes
                IF - Corrected I/F
                SU - Spectral summary parameters
                SR - Refined spectral summary parameters
                BR - Browse product
                IN - Data processing information
                DE - Derived data product
                WV - Wavelength information for the corrected I/F image
              The 3-digit macro ID identifies the instrument macro that was
              being run to collect the central scan part of the observation
              that was processed and is represented in the product
      D = sensor ID (S = VNIR; L = IR; J = Joined (VNIR + IR))
      TTT = Product type string
                MTR - Map-projected Targeted Reduced Data Record, or MTRDR
      V = Version number
 
      In the MTR data product set the version number (V) is the
      radiometric calibration version number inherited from the source TRDRs,
      and the product type string (TTT) is MTR for Map-projected Targeted
      Reduced Data Record. For browse product (BR) files, the 3-digit macro
      ID is replaced with a 3-character product identifier.
 
      All MTRDR image data have been map-projected in accordance with MRO
      project standards. The image data are stored as multi-band images
      (.IMG) with associated PDS labels (.LBL) and ENVI headers (.HDR). The
      wavelength information is stored in text files (.TAB) also with
      associated PDS labels (.LBL). The browse products (BR) are
      stored in the Portable Network Graphics (.PNG) format with
      alpha channel transparency, referenced by the associated PDS
      labels (.LBL). MTRDR browse products also include the scaled data
      values of the .PNG file in a PDS image file (.IMG) and have an
      associated ENVI header file (.HDR), allowing the user to load the PDS
      image file into the ENVI software application.
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      The Map-projected Targeted Reduced Data Record (MTRDR) data processing
      pipeline produces both TERs and MTRs. It integrates a series of
      standard and empirical spectral corrections, spatial transforms,
      parameter calculations, and renderings in the generation of a high level
      suite of analysis and visualization products. The TER/MTR data
      processing flow is illustrated in Figure 2-9a in the CRISM Data Product
      SIS and the TER/MTR data processing pipeline is described in detail in
      the CRISM Data Product SIS Appendix P1. The CRISM TERs and MTRs are
      paired data product types where an MTR is a map-projected version of a
      TER. The only exception to pairing of the products is that the MTR
      suite contains a DE product which is a map-projected version of the IR
      (L-detector) DDR associated with the source targeted observation.
      All of the TER products are in the IR (L-detector) sensor
      space, so the same map-projection transformation is used to generate all
      of the MTRs for a given source targeted observation. The bands in the
      MTR SU, SR, BR, and IN products match the TER precursors (and the bands
      in the MTR DE product match the DDR precursor). The TER IF products also
      contain all the channels in the source VNIR and IR TRDRs, whereas
      spectral channels with questionable radiometry (&apos;bad bands&apos;) are
      not propagated from the TER IF to the MTR IF product (thus there are
      fewer spectral channels in the MTR spectral image cube as compared to
      the TER precursor).
 
      The TER/MTR data processing procedures through the generation of the
      MTR product set are summarized below. Detailed descriptions are provided
      in Appendix P1 of the CRISM Data Product SIS. Steps 1 through 10
      describe processing done during generation of a TER and steps 11
      through 13 describe post processing and map projection that is
      conducted to transform that to an MTR.
 
      1. Lambertian Photometric Correction (PHT)
       The spectrum of each spatial pixel is divided by the cosine of the
       incidence angle at that pixel.
 
      2. Modified &apos;Volcano Scan&apos; Atmospheric Correction (ATM) (IR only)
       The spectrum of each spatial pixel is divided by an empirically
       derived atmospheric transmission spectrum scaled to match the
       depth of the 2000-nm CO2 absorption. The correction is derived
       from CRISM nadir-pointed observations crossing the full range of
       relief of Olympus Mons. To account for small wavelength shifts of
       the IR detector over the mission, the &apos;best&apos; out of a series of
       temporally variable corrections is selected from a menu based
       on minimizing the residual from the correction. In addition, not
       all parts of the 2000-nm CO2 absorption - actually an overlapping
       series of narrower absorptions - scale the same with path length.
       An additional correction of the resulting artifact near 2070 nm
       is superimposed to mitigate the artifact.
 
      3. Ratio Shift Correction (RSC) (IR only)
       A statistically robust &apos;destriping&apos; procedure is applied to
       the ATM-corrected image cube to mitigate the reintroduction of
       spatial column-oriented residuals, as viewed in IR detector
       space. These originate from spurious values in either ground
       calibration data or flight scene or calibration data, and were
       filtered out of the IF version of the source TRDR in a
       statistically robust fashion. However some are reintroduced at
       a low level when the empirically based ATM correction is
       applied. An analogous procedure to that used in the IF version
       of the source TRDR is reapplied to correct reintroduced artifacts.
 
      4. Empirical Geometric Normalization (EGN)
       Systematic brightness variations in the along-track direction of
       a CRISM targeted observation result from the continuously varying
       observation geometry (gimbal motion) that is used to take out
       along-track motion of the field of view. The variable phase
       angle and atmospheric path lengths that result from this
       procedure modulate the fractions of radiance at sensor that are
       contributed by the surface and atmosphere as a function of
       wavelength. The effects are characterized as a function of the
       continuously variable observation geometry along-track, and
       normalized to the geometry at the frame of the observation which
       is closest to nadir.
 
      5. Empirical Smile Correction (ESC)
       Spectral smile is an optical artifact whereby a single wavelength
       does not translate uniquely to a single row of detector elements
       on either the VNIR or IR detector. As a result, the wavelength of
       a single detector row - which translate into a single band of a
       multiband image file - drifts up and down across the field of
       view. Where at-sensor radiance changes as a function of
       wavelength, the sampled radiance also therefore systematically
       changes. Spectral smile effects are mitigated using a fit of
       along-track-averaged cross-track variation in radiance that is
       constrained to have a form consistent with spectral smile
       effects. Cross-track variation is normalized to the 100-colunm
       wide strip near the center of the detector that corresponds to
       the reference wavelength sampling vector (also called the &apos;SW&apos;
       CDR, in the CDR directory of the CRISM EDR archive).
 
      6. VNIR/IR Sensor Space Transform (XFM)
       The focal lengths of the VNIR and IR parts of the CRISM
       instrument are slightly different, resulting in about a 1 percent
       difference in pixel scale. Post-processing is required to
       register the two parts of the data set; however, how they map onto
       Mars&apos; surface is known very accurately. The corrected VNIR
       spectral data are remapped into the correct location in IR sensor
       space based on the known surface intercepts of each spatial
       pixel, using a nearest-neighbor sampling. The spectral
       concatenation of the transformed corrected VNIR data and the
       corrected IR data results in a fully corrected, full spectral
       range data product (a TER IF image cube, accompanied by a
       TER WV wavelength table).
 
      7. Data Processing Information Generation (INF)
       Residuals from the joining of the VNIR and IR data around 1000 nm
       and from correction for atmospheric CO2 around 2000 nm are
       parameterized in the IN image cube, to identify for data
       users the wavelengths and spatial locations of data artifacts.
       There is also traceability back to line and sample coordinates
       in the source VNIR and IR image cubes. The bands in the IN
       product consist of:
 
        &apos;VNIR/IR Spectral Continuity Residual&apos; - the difference in corrected
           I/F between the VNIR and IR data at the wavelength of the join.
        &apos;VNIR/IR Spatial Gradient Residual&apos; - the difference in the
           sampling effects between the VNIR and IR, which can create a
           spectral artifact, measured as the dot product of the normals to
           a brightness gradient fitted to 3x3 spatial pixel kernels at
           wavelengths above and below that of the join.
        &apos;ATM Correction Spectral Shift Artifact&apos; - a measure of the
           magnitude of a ringing-like artifact of correction for the
           atmospheric CO2 band near 2000 nm that arises when the
           IR wavelength calibrations of the source IR data and the IR
           data used to derive the atmospheric correction spectrum
           are slightly misaligned, typically by a fraction of a
           nanometer.
        &apos;VNIR Sample&apos; - sample coordinate of the VNIR part of the
           TER spectrum in the source VNIR TRDR.
        &apos;VNIR Line - line coordinate of the VNIR part of the
           TER spectrum in the source VNIR TRDR.
        &apos;IR Sample&apos; - sample coordinate of the IR part of the
           TER spectrum in the source IR TRDR.
        &apos;IR Line&apos; - line coordinate of the IR part of the
           TER spectrum in the source IR TRDR.
        &apos;VNIR/IR Offset&apos; - the difference in meters between the centers
           of the corresponding pixels of the VNIR and IR source
           products projected onto the Martian surface.
        &apos;VNIR/IR Mask&apos; - a boolean indicator of which pixels are
           populated from the VNIR and IR source products, where 0 =
           populated and 1 = not populated.
 
      8. Spectral Summary Parameter Generation (SUM)
       A suite of mineral indicators and other measures of spectral
       shape and reflectivity, collectively called spectral summary
       parameters, is calculated from the TER IF data using the revised
       and expanded spectral summary parameter library of
       [VIVIANO-BECKETAL2014] and stored in the SU product. The bands in
       the SU and refined summary parameter (SR) image cube are given below
       along with a brief description of their significance. Users are
       referred to Table 3-12 of the CRISM Data Product SIS for detailed
       formulations and caveats.
 
           R770         = 0.77-micron reflectance (higher value more dusty
                          or icy)
           RBR          = Red/blue ratio (higher value indicates more
                          nanophase iron oxide or sky illumination)
           BD530_2      = 0.53-micron band depth (higher value has more
                          fine-grained crystalline hematite)
           SH600_2      = 0.6-micron shoulder height (select ferric
                          minerals esp. hematite, goethite, or
                          compacted texture)
           SH770        = 0.77-micron shoulder height (select ferric
                          minerals, less sensitive to LCP than SH600_2)
           BD640_2      = 0.64-micron band depth (select ferric minerals,
                          esp. maghemite, but obscured by VNIR detector
                          artifact)
           BD860_2      = 0.86-micron band depth (select crystalline
                          ferric minerals, esp. hematite)
           BD920_2      = 0.92-micron band depth (crystalline ferric minerals
                          and low-Ca pyroxene, or LCP)
           RPEAK1       = Reflectance peak 1 near 0.77 microns (&lt;0.75
                          suggests olivine, 0.75 pyroxene, &gt;0.8 dust)
           BDI1000VIS   = 1-micron integrated band depth; VNIR wavelengths
                          (olivine, pyroxene, or Fe-bearing glass)
           BDI1000IR    = 1-micron integrated band depth; IR wavelengths
                          (crystalline Fe2+ silicates)
           R1330        = IR albedo
           BD1300       = 1.3-micron absorption associated with Fe2+
                          substitution in plagioclase
           OLINDEX3     = Broad absorption centered at 1 micron
                          (olivine strongly &gt;0, also Fe-phyllosilicate)
           LCPINDEX2    = Broad absorption centered at 1.81 micron
                          (pyroxene is strongly +; favors LCP)
           HCPINDEX2    = Broad absorption centered at 2.12 microns
                          (pyroxene is strongly +; favors HCP)
           VAR          = 1.0-2.3-micron spectral variance
           ISLOPE1      = Spectral slope 1 (from 1.185 to 2.530 microns;
                          ferric coating on dark rock)
           BD1400       = 1.4-micron H2O and -OH band depth
                          (hydrated or hydroxylated minerals)
           BD1435       = 1.435-micron CO2 ice band depth
           BD1500_2     = 1.5-micron H2O ice band depth
           ICER1_2      = CO2 and H2O ice band depth ratio
           BD1750_2     = 1.75-micron H2O band depth (gypsum or alunite)
           BD1900_2     = 1.9-micron H2O band depth (hydrated minerals
                          except monohydrated sulfates)
           BD1900r2     = 1.9-micron H2O band depth (hydrated minerals
                          except monohydrated sulfates)
           BDI2000      = 2-micron integrated band depth (pyroxene)
           BD2100_2     = 2.1-micron shifted H2O band depth
                          (monohydrated sulfates)
           BD2165       = 2.165-micron Al-OH band depth
                          (pyrophyllite, kaolinite-group minerals)
           BD2190       = 2.190-micron Al-OH band depth
                          (beidellite, allophane, imogolite)
           MIN2200      = 2.16-micron Si-OH band depth and 2.21-micron
                          H-bound Si-OH band depth (doublet; kaolinite)
           BD2210_2     = 2.21-micron Al-OH band depth (Al-OH minerals)
           D2200        = 2.2-micron dropoff (Al-OH minerals)
           BD2230       = 2.23-micron band depth
                          (hydroxylated ferric sulfate)
           BD2250       = 2.25-micron broad Al-OH and Si-OH band depth
                          (opal, Al-OH minerals)
           MIN2250      = 2.21-micron Si-OH band depth and 2.26-micron
                          H-bound Si-OH band depth (opal)
           BD2265       = 2.265-micron band depth (jarosite, gibbsite,
                          acid-leached nontronite)
           BD2290       = 2.29-micron Mg,Fe-OH band depth / 2.292-micron
                          CO2 ice band depth (Mg-OH and Fe-OH minerals,
                          Mg carbonate, and CO2 ice)
           D2300        = 2.3-micron dropoff (hydroxylated Fe,Mg
                          silicates strongly &gt;0)
           BD2355       = 2.35-micron band depth (chlorite, prehnite,
                          pumpellyite, carbonate, serpentine)
           SINDEX2      = Inverse lever rule to detect convexity at 2.29
                          microns due to 2.1- and 2.4-micron absorptions
                          (hydrated sulfates strongly &gt;0)
           ICER2_2      = 2.7-micron CO2 ice band
           MIN2295_2480 = Mg Carbonate overtone band depth and metal-OH
                          band
           MIN2345_2537 = Ca/Fe Carbonate overtone band depth and
                          metal-OH band
           BD2500_2     = Mg Carbonate overtone band depth
           BD3000       = 3-micron H2O band depth (adsorbed and bound
                          H2O and ice)
           BD3100       = 3.1-micron H2O ice band depth
           BD3200       = 3.2-micron CO2 ice band depth
           BD3400_2     = 3.4-micron carbonate band depth
           CINDEX2      = Inverse lever rule to detect convexity at 3.6
                          micron due to 3.4- and 3.8-micron
                          carbonate absorptions
           R440         = 0.44-micron reflectance
           R530         = 0.53-micron reflectance
           R600         = 0.60-micron reflectance
           IRR1         = IR ratio 1 (R880/R997; aphelion ice clouds &gt;1,
                          seasonal ice clouds and dust &lt;1))
           R1080        = 1.08-micron reflectance
           R1506        = 1.51-micron reflectance
           R2529        = 2.53-micron reflectance
           BD2600       = 2.6-micron H2O band depth
           IRR2         = IR ratio 2 (R2530/R2210; aphelion ice clouds
                          vs. seasonal ice clouds or dust)
           IRR3         = IR ratio 3 (R3500/R3390; aphelion ice clouds
                          vs. seasonal ice clouds or dust)
           R3920        = 3.92-micron reflectance, evaluated from the
                          5 &apos;good bands&apos; closest in wavelength to
                          3920 nm
 
     9. Refined Spectral Summary Parameters (SRE)
       The majority of the parameter bands are filtered using a variant of
       the filtering algorithm used on IR TRDR I/F image cubes, to
       mitigate spurious noise structure that remains and is accentuated
       in the summary products. The noise remains because the filtering
       applied to the TRDRs uses a conservative threshold for calling an
       outlying pixel &apos;noise&apos; and interpolating through it, to avoid
       altering the actual information content of the data. Low-magnitude
       noise that &apos;leaks though&apos; TRDR processing appears larger in some
       of the summary products prior to filtering because their dynamic
       range is typically small compared to the I/F data.
 
     10. Browse Product Generation (BRS)
       Browse products are greyscale or RGB composites of 1 or 3
       thematically related summary products remapped to 8 bits that allow
       for a quick assessment of the information content of the source
       spectral data TER IF image cubes).
 
       The MTRDR browse product set consists of three data files and a
       detached PDS label file. The label file contains the metadata and
       pointers to the three data files. The three data files are 1) an IMG
       file containing the browse product image as a three-band PDS IMAGE
       object; 2) a PNG file containing the browse product image in the
       Portable Network Graphics file format (three bands and an alpha
       transparency channel); and 3) a HDR file associated with the IMG file
       which stores file format (and map projection information) in
       the ENVI header format. This allows users of the ENVI image
       processing software to readily read in the image data. The
       SOURCE_PRODUCT_ID keyword in the PDS label links the browse products
       to the source MTRDR.
 
       The following formulations are used.
 
          Abbreviation = TRU
          Name         = True color
          R Component  = R600
          G Component  = R530
          B Component  = R440
          Additional description: An enhanced natural color representation
          of the scene composed of spectral channels across the visible
          spectrum. Contrast greater than the human eye would see.
 
          Abbreviation = VNA
          Name = VNIR albedo
          R Component = R770
          G Component = R770
          B Component = R770
          Additional description: Reflectance at 770 nm as a proxy for VNIR
          albedo and may be used to correlate spectral variations with
          morphology.
 
          Abbreviation = FEM
          Name = Fe Minerals
          R Component = BD530_2
          G Component = SH600_2
          B Component = BDI1000VIS
          Additional description: Mafic minerals appear blue, nanophase
          ferric oxides red, and dust-coated mafic rocks or lithified
          dust yellow/green.
 
          Abbreviation = FM2
          Name = Fe minerals, v2
          R Component = BD530_2
          G Component = BD920_2
          B Component = BDI1000VIS
          Additional description: Mafic minerals appear blue, crystalline
          hematite green or yellow, and nanophase ferric oxides red.
 
          Abbreviation = TAN
          Name = Tandem
          R Component = R2529
          G Component = IRA
          B Component = R770
          Additional description: Enhanced visible to infrared false color
          representation of the scene, incorporating spectral data from
          both (VNIR and IR) detectors.
 
          Abbreviation = IRA
          Name = IR albedo
          R Component = R1300
          G Component = R1300
          B Component = R1300
          Additional description: Reflectnace at 1330 nm as a proxy for IR
          albedo and may be used to correlate spectral variations with
          morphology.
 
          Abbreviation = FAL
          Name = False color
          R Component = R2529
          G Component = R1506
          B Component = R1080
          Additional description: Red to orange coloration is
          typically characteristic of olivine-rich material, blue/green
          colors are often indicative of clay mineralogy, green colors
          may indicate carbonate, and gray/brown colors often indicate
          basaltic material.
 
          Abbreviation = MAF
          Name = Mafic mineralogy
          R Component = OLINDEX3
          G Component = LCPINDEX2
          B Component = HCPINDEX2
          Additional description: Olivine and Fe-phyllosilicate share
          a 1000-1700 nm bowl-shaped absorption and will appear red in
          the MAF browse product.  Low- and high-Ca pyroxene display
          an additional ~2000-nm absorption and appear green/cyan and
          blue/magenta respectively.
 
          Abbreviation = HYD
          Name = Hydrated mineralogy
          R Component = SINDEX2
          G Component = BD2100_2
          B Component = BD1900_2
          Additional description: Polyhydrated sulfates have strong
          1900 nm and 2400 nm absorption bands, and thus appear magenta
          in the HYD browse product. Monohydrated sulfates have a
          strong 2100 nm absorption and a weak 2400 nm absorption band,
          and thus appear yellow/green in the HYD browse product.
          Blue colors are indicative of other hydrated minerals (such as
          clays, glass, carbonate, or zeolite).
 
          Abbreviation = PHY
          Name = Phyllosilicates
          R Component = D2300
          G Component = D2200
          B Component = BD1900r2
          Additional description: Fe/Mg-OH bearing minerals
          (e.g., Fe/Mg-phyllosilicate) will appear red, or magenta
          (when hydrated). Al/Si-OH bearing minerals (e.g.,
          Al-phyllosilicates or hydrated silica) will appear green,
          or cyan (when hydrated). Blue colors are indicative of other
          hydrated minerals (such as sulfates, glass, carbonate, or
          water ice).
 
          Abbreviation = PFM
          Name = Phyllosilicates with Fe and Mg
          R Component = BD2355
          G Component = D2300
          B Component = BD2290
          Additional description: Red/yellow colors indicate the
          presence of prehnite, chlorite, epidote, or Ca/Fe carbonate,
          while cyan colors indicate the presence of Fe/Mg-smectites
          or Mg-carbonate.
 
          Abbreviation = PAL
          Name = Phyllosilicates with Al
          R Component = BD2210_2
          G Component = BD2190
          B Component = BD2165
          Additional description: Red/yellow colors indicate the
          presence of Al-smectites or hydrated silica, cyan colors may
          indicate the alunite, and light/white colors indicate the
          presence of kaolinite group minerals.
 
          Abbreviation = HYS
          Name = Hydrated silica
          R Component = MIN2250
          G Component = BD2250
          B Component = BD1900r2
          Additional information: Light red/yellow colors indicate
          the presence of hydrated silica, whereas cyan colors indicate
          Al-OH minerals.  Additionally, jarosite will appear yellow.
          Blue colors are indicative of other hydrated minerals (such
          as sulfates, clays, glass, carbonate, or water ice).
 
          Abbreviation = ICE
          Name = Ices
          R Component = BD1900_2
          G Component = BD1500_2
          B Component = BD1435
          Additional information: CO2 frost or ice displays a sharp
          1435-nm absorption and thus appears blue in the ICE browse
          product. Water ice or frost has a strong 1500 nm absorption and
          thus appears green in the ICE browse product.  Red colors are
          indicative of hydrated minerals (such as sulfates, clays,
          glass, carbonate, or water ice).
 
          Abbreviation = IC2
          Name = Ices, v2
          R Component = R3920
          G Component = BD1500_2
          B Component = BD1435
          Additional information: CO2 frost or ice displays a sharp
          1435-nm absorption and thus appears blue in the IC2 browse
          product. Water ice or frost has a strong 1500 nm absorption and
          thus appears green in the IC2 browse product.  The 3920-nm
          spectral channel is a discriminator for icy vs. ice-free material
          with ices having a lower solar reflected and thermal emission
          radiance at this wavelength, so ice-free material appears red.
 
          Abbreviation = CHL
          Name = Chloride
          R Component = ISLOPE
          G Component = BD3000
          B Component = IRR2
          Additional information: Martian chloride deposits have a
          relatively positive near-infrared spectral slope and are
          comparatively desiccated, so chlorides appear blue in the
          CHL browse product. Yellow/green colors are indicative of
          hydrated minerals, especially phyllosilicates.
 
          Abbreviation = CAR
          Name = Carbonates
          R Component = D2300
          G Component = BD2500H2
          B Component = BD1900_2
          Additional information: Blueish- or yellowish-white colors
          indicate Mg-carbonate, while red/magenta colors indicate
          Fe/Mg-phyllosilicate. Blue colors are indicative of other
          hydrated minerals (such as sulfates, clays, glass, or
          carbonate).
 
          Abbreviation = CR2
          Name = Carbonates, v2
          R Component = MIN2295_2480
          G Component = MIN2345_2537
          B Component = CINDEX2
          Additional information: Red/magenta colors indicate
          Mg-carbonates, while green/cyan colors indicate
          Fe/Ca-carbonates.
 
      11. Removal of Spectral Bad bands
       A canonical set of spectral &apos;bad bands&apos; has been identified through the
       evaluation of a set of prototype TER IF data products. The identified
       &apos;bad bands&apos; are not forwarded into the MTR IF image cube from the TER
       IF image cube. These bands are known and understood from previous work
       on CRISM data, and are:
 
       10 wavelengths less than 436 nm (due to artifacts from the scattered
       light correction in high contrast scenes).
 
       11 wavelengths between 631 and 710 nm (due to optical artifacts at the
       boundary between zones of the VNIR detector).
 
       VNIR wavelengths above 1010 nm and IR wavelengths below 1067 nm
       (leaving a gap equivalent to about 4.6 wavelength increments, due to
       various calibration artifacts at the VNIR/IR join).
 
       21 wavelengths between 2654 and 2806 nm (due to optical artifacts at
       a zone boundary in the IR detector).
 
       4 wavelengths above 3897 nm (due to low signal to noise ratio).
 
      12. Generation of Map-Projection Transform
       A spatial transform that maps data in the IR (L-detector) sensor
       space into the designated map-projected space is calculated using the
       ESRI Projection Engine (PE) through the ENVI Application Programming
       Interface (API). The resulting Geographic Lookup Table (GLT)
       encodes the spatial transformation.
 
       CRISM MTRDRs employ Mars Reconnaissance Orbiter (MRO) map projection
       conventions - planetocentric latitude, positive east longitude, and
       the IAU 2000 prime meridian, pole of rotation, and equatorial and
       polar planetary radii. A rolling equirectangular projection with the
       reference latitude (center of map projection) at the 5 degree
       latitude increment in the equatorward direction is used for
       observations centered between -65 and 65 degrees north, and
       a north or south polar stereographic projection is used for
       observations poleward of that latitude range. The rolling
       equirectangular map projection uses a sphere with a radius equal to
       the IAU 2000 ellipsoid radius (Equatorial radius = 3396.190 km;
       Polar radius = 3376.200 km) at the reference latitude. The pixel scale
       of the map projection is equal to 18 meters per pixel, and the number
       of pixels per degree depends on the radius of the sphere evaluated at
       the reference longitude. That latitude and longitude at which
       each pixel is projected derives from the DDR of the source IR
       observation.
 
       The EQUIRECTANGULAR projection is based on the formula for a sphere.
       To eliminate confusion in the IMAGE_MAP_PROJECTION object all three
       radius keywords (A_AXIS_RADIUS, B_AXIS_RADIUS, and C_AXIS_RADIUS) have
       been set to the same value. The value recorded in the three radii
       keywords is the local radius at the CENTER_LATITUDE on the Mars
       ellipsoid. The CENTER_LATITUDE is the center of the projection, not
       the center of the observation. Using the local radius of the ellipsoid
       implies that the MAP_SCALE and MAP_RESOLUTION are true at the
       CENTER_LATITUDE.
 
       The POLAR STEREOGRAPHIC projections use the ellipsoid form of the
       equations.  However, most cartographic processing software cannot
       support planetocentric coordinates for this projection with the
       ellipsoid equation. The fallback is to use the spherical equations.
 
       More detail is provided in the MTR_MAP.CAT catalog file.
 
       It is important to note that although projection is on a sphere, the
       latitude and longitude of each pixel takes Mars surface topography
       into account. When the DDR containing the latitudes and longitudes
       is being generated, gimbal positions are extracted from the
       table of housekeeping values accompanying the Experiment Data
       Record (EDR) and formatted as a gimbal C kernel. Using that and
       other MRO SPICE kernels, the surface intercept on the MOLA shape
       model is calculated for each spatial pixel (sampled at the
       reference detector row, closest to 2300 nm). The angles of this
       pixel relative to the equatorial plane and reference longitude
       constitute the latitude and longitude of the pixel. For that
       latitude and longitude, solar incidence, emission, and phase
       angles are determined at a surface parallel to the areoid but
       having a radius from planetary center equivalent to that of the
       surface intercept of the shape model. Solar incidence and
       emission are also determined relative to the shape model itself.
       These values are also included in the DDR, and map projected in the
       DE MTRDR image cube.
 
     13. Map-Projection
       The GLT is applied to the corrected I/F (IF), summary product (SU),
       refined summary product (SR), browse product (BR), and informational
       (IN) TER image products to produce the corresponding MTR data
       products. The GLT is applied to the source IR DDR to produce the DE
       MTR data product.
 
       The 14 image bands in the DE product come directly from the source
       DDR and include the following, all represented as 32-bit real
       numbers arranged in band-sequential format:
 
       a. Solar incidence angle relative to areoid, at the same planetary
       radius as surface projection of pixel, units degrees.
 
       b. Emission angle relative to areoid, at the same planetary radius as
       surface projection of pixel, units degrees.
 
       c. Solar phase angle, units degrees.
 
       d. Areocentric latitude, units degrees N.
 
       e. Areocentric longitude, units degrees E.
 
       f. Solar incidence angle relative to planetary surface as estimated
       using MOLA shape model, units degrees.
 
       g. Emission angle relative to planetary surface as estimated using
       MOLA shape model, units degrees.
 
       h. Slope magnitude, using MOLA shape model and reference ellipsoid,
       units degrees.
 
       i. Slope azimuth, using MOLA shape model and reference ellipsoid,
       units degrees clockwise from N.
 
       j. Elevation relative to MOLA datum, units kilometers.
 
       k. TES thermal inertia, units J m^-2 K^-1 s^-0.5.
 
       l. TES bolometric albedo, unitless.
 
       m. Local solar time, hours.
 
       n. Spare.
 
 
    Extras
    ======
      The MTRDR EXTRAS directory contains one visualization for each processed
      observation that illustrates the spatial/spectral information content of
      the primary MTRDR I/F data product. All TER/MTRDR EXTRAS visualizations
      are Portable Network Graphics (PNG) format files. Detailed descriptions
      of the TER/MTRDR EXTRAS products are provided in the CRISM Data Product
      SIS Appendix P2.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
      None.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
By design many of the sources of
      uncertainty in interpretation of the data relevant to calibrated
      data or TRDRs are reduced or eliminated in TERs and MTRs. Remaining
      issues of most concern to data users follow.
 
      (1) Variable spectral resolution
      In order to distinguish spectrally similar minerals that
      have different geological implications for their environments
      of formation, adequate spectral resolution is necessary. This
      requires sufficiently high density spectral sampling, as well
      as a sufficiently narrow full width half maximum (FWHM) of the
      instrument response in the spectral direction. This &apos;slit
      function,&apos; the effective bandpass for a single detector
      element, represents the convolution of spectral sampling and
      the point-spread function in the spectral direction. CRISM&apos;s
      benchmark is distinguishing the minerals montmorillonite and
      kaolinite, which form in hydrothermal environments under
      different temperature regimes [SWAYZEETAL2003]. The requirements
      for this are (a) &lt;20 nm FWHM and (b) sampling of the spectrum
      at this or smaller increments. CRISM&apos;s spectral sampling
      requirement is &lt;10 nm/channel to provide oversampling, and the
      actual performance is better at 6.55 nm/channel. FWHM is 8 nm
      in the VNIR across the FOV. In the IR it increases from 10 nm
      at short wavelengths to 15 nm at the longest wavelengths at the
      center of the FOV, and broadens by about 2 nm at 0.8 degrees
      from the center of the field of view. Outside +/-0.9 degrees
      from the center of the field of view the telescope is slightly
      vignetted, so further degradation is expected at extreme field
      angles. Although the spectral sampling and resolution meet
      requirements, their variation across the field-of-view must be
      accounted for when comparing with rock and mineral analog
      spectra. The FWHM of the slit function is given for the reference
      columns of the source TRDR as part of the WV table accompanying
      the MTR.
 
      (2) Long-wavelength calibration uncertainty
      The responsivity correction at IR wavelengths 3000-3920 is suspected
      to contain low wavelength frequency errors, perhaps leading to a
      broad &apos;bump&apos; centered near 3400 nm. This is currently under
      investigation and may be corrected in a future version of the IR
      radiometric calibration.
 
      (3) Residuals from correction of the 2000-nm CO2 gas absorption
      As described above, parts of many scenes contain a ringing-like
      artifact of using a correction for atmospheric gases derived from
      data where the IR wavelength calibration has drifted slightly.
      An indicator of parts of an image subject to this effect is
      included in the informational IN image cube.
 
      (4) Artifacts near 1 micron
      For reasons that are not well understood, the quality of the
      calibration of VNIR and IR data on either side of the &apos;join&apos; near
      1 micron drifts in time. The IN informational image cube contains
      indicators of where in an image this is most severe. The calibration
      of data away from the join is only suspect where elsewhere indicated.
 
      (5) Calibration residuals
      In MTR IF image products, wavelengths with routinely deficient
      radiometric calibration are omitted by design. However wavelengths
      that exhibit only intermitted artifacts, or artifacts that are
      corrected by ratioing to a spectrally blank material measured by the
      same detector column in the source observation, are included.
      These are:
 
       a. In some observations, there is a column-dependent artifact in
       the form of a broad dip near 1220 nm, whose origin is unknown. The
       artifact disappears when a spectrum containing it is ratioed to
       spectrally bland material within the same observation, in or near
       the source IR detector column.
 
       b. In some observations, there is a spike or trough at the boundary
       between the short and intermediate wavelength segments of the IR
       detector, near 1660 nm. The artifact disappears when a spectrum
       containing it is ratioed to spectrally bland material within the
       same observation, in or near the source IR detector column.
 
       c. The shape of the spectrum at 3100-3800 nm is suspect and there
       may be a broad, low &apos;bump&apos;.
 
      (6) Scene-dependent opacity of dust and ice aerosols
      The processing that normalizes atmospheric effects does not attempt
      to remove scattering effects of dust and ice aerosols, only to
      normalize them to the effects at the nearest-to-nadir geometry in
      the scene in question. Scenes with high opacities of dust or ice, for
      example observed during global dust events, are by design excluded
      from the TER archive. Thresholds used were dust opacity (tau) &gt; 1.39
      and ice opacity (tau) &gt; 0.28. However overlapping scenes within the
      archive may have different dust or ice loads below these limits, so
      overlapping spectra measured at different times may have distinct
      values. The effects will be greatest at shorter wavelengths,
      and in absorptions related to iron minerals. In addition some scenes
      are observed through a thin water ice haze. These will have
      characteristic weak ice absorption near 1500 and 2000 nm.
 
      (7) Summary product and browse product cautions
      Summary products and browse products are intended to provide rapid
      overviews of the content of CRISM hyperspectral data, and to convey
      spatial variations in mineral spectral signatures in a compact
      fashion. However they are not conclusive indicators of the presence
      of particular minerals; false positives and false negatives are
      not uncommon. Users are referred to Table 3-12 of the CRISM Data
      Product SIS for detailed caveats regarding false positives, and to
      [VIVIANO-BECKETAL2014] for an extended discussion of the topic.
 
      (8) Uncertainties in contents of the DE product.
      The major sources of uncertainty in the source DDRs arise from
      uncertainties in instrument pointing knowledge, from coverage of
      the MOLA data set, and from the scale of the Thermal Emission
      Spectrometer (TES) data.
 
      The formal pointing uncertainty for the CRISM gimbal plane is 1
      mrad each in the spacecraft yaw(z), roll(x), or pitch/gimbal(y)
      axes. The formal uncertainty in reconstructed spacecraft
      attitude is similar. Uncertainty in CRISM&apos;s gimbal attitude is
      negligible, about 0.006 mrad. The formal error in projection
      onto a surface location depends on the angle of the
      gimbal and typically is of order several hundreds of meters.
      Experience during operations suggests that the actual errors
      are smaller than expected formal errors, so that typical error
      in surface location is about 200 meters.
 
      Latitude and longitude are described by the intersection of
      CRISM field of view with the MOLA shape model. Given the
      uncertainties in location of a point on the surface, expected
      uncertainty near the equator is of the order of 0.005 degrees.
      Uncertainties in incidence, emission, and phase angles relative
      to the areoid are similar.
 
      Errors in incidence and emission angle relative to the MOLA
      shape model are dominated by the lower sampling density of the
      shape model. MOLA points are typically a few hundred meters
      apart. This compares to CRISM&apos;s sampling scale of 18 meters per
      spatial pixel, for a full spatial resolution observation.
      In areas of smooth topography the errors are small, but in areas
      with topography that is rough at scales less than a few hundred
      meters, uncertainty is several degrees. The same uncertainties
      apply to slope magnitude.
 
      Errors in bolometric albedo and thermal inertia will have a
      large contribution from the different scales of the CRISM and
      TES data sets. The TES data from which these values are
      retrieved are sampled at 8 pixels per degree, yet depending on
      instrument configuration, the native spatial sampling of the
      CRSIM data set is 256-4096 pixels per degree. Thus in areas with
      heterogeneous surface properties, large errors in bolometric
      albedo and thermal inertia may occur.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

