<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mpfr-m-rvrcam-2-edr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MARS PATHFINDER ROVER MARS ROVER CAMERA 2 EDR VERSION 1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.mars_pathfinder::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mpfr::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rcrr.mpfr::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mpfr-m-rvrcam-2-edr-v1.0__browserp_mpfr-m-rvrcam-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mpfr-m-rvrcam-2-edr-v1.0__dvo_imaging_mpfr-m-rvrcam-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Golombek, M.P., R.A. Cook, T. Economou, W.M. Folkner, A.F.C. Haldemann,
                   P.H. Kallemeyn, J.M. Knudsen, R.M. Manning, H.J. Moore, T.J. Parker, R.
                   Rieder, J.T. Schofield, P.H. Smith, and R.M. Vaughan, Overview of the Mars
                   Pathfinder Mission and Assessment of Landing Site Predictions, Science,
                   278, 1743-1748, 1997.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GOLOMBEKETAL1997B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Matijevic, J., Microrover Flight Experiment Requirements, Architecture and
                   Verification Document, JPL Document 10925, PF-R00-5.0-02, Rev B, 68 pp.,
                   April 15, 1994.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MATIJEVIC1994</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Matijevic, J.R., L.W. Avril, R.S. Banes, D.B. Bickler, R.S. Blomquist, G.S.
                   Bolotin, D.F. Braun, D.R. Burger, B.K. Cooper, J. Crisp, F. Deligiannis,
                   W.C. Dias, H.J. Eisen, D. Ferguson, B.H. Fujiwara, R.D. Galletly, G.S.
                   Hickey, P. Jenkins, K.A. Jewett, E.J. Jorgensen, J. Kilecki, H.A. Kubo,
                   G.A. Landis, W.E. Layman, L.H. Matthies, D.P. McQuarie, R.J. Menke, A.H.
                   Mishkin, D.S. Mittman, H.J. Moore, J.C. Morrison, T.T. Nguyen, D.E. Noon,
                   L. Oberle, T.R. Ohm, G.M. Shinn, D.L. Shirley, A.R. Sirota, C.B. Stell, S.
                   Stevenson, H.W. Stone, L.F. Sword, H.C. Ta, A.D. Thompson, L.M. van
                   Nieuwstadt, M.T. Wallace, L. -C. Wen, B.H. Wilcox, and Y.C. Wu, The
                   Pathfinder Microrover, J. Geophys. Res., 102, 3989-4001, 1997.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MATIJEVICETAL1997A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Matijevic, J.R., J. Crisp, R.S. Banes, D.B. Bickler, B.K. Cooper, H.J.
                   Eisen, D. Ferguson, J. Gensler, A. Haldemann, F. Hartman, P. Jenkins, K.A.
                   Jewett, J. Kolecki, G.A. Landis, S.L. Laubach, L.H. Matthies, A.H. Mishkin,
                   H.J. Moore, J.C. Morrison, T.T. Nguyen, A.R. Sirota, H.W. Stone, S. Stride,
                   L.F. Sword, J.A. Tarsala, A.D. Thompson, M.T. Wallace, R. Welch, E.
                   Wellman, B.H. Wilcox, and D. Wilt, Characterization of the Martian Surface
                   Deposits by the Mars Pathfinder Rover, Sojourner, Science, 278, 1765-1768,
                   1997.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MATIJEVICETAL1997B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Mellstrom, J. and K. Lau, Mars Pathfinder AIM Phasing and Coordinate Frame
                   Document, JPL Document 12103, PF-300-4.0-04, 38 pp., 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MELLSTROM-LAU1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Vaughan, R., Mars Pathfinder Project Planetary Constants and Models, JPL
                   Document 12947, PF-100-PMC-01, 136 pp., December, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.VAUGHAN1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Wellman, J.B., Imager for Mars Pathfinder Coordinate Systems and Imaging
                   Transformations, JPL Document 15212, PF-400-9.0, 16 pp., July 25, 1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.WELLMAN1996B</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MPFR-M-RVRCAM-2-EDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MARS PATHFINDER ROVER MARS ROVER CAMERA 2 EDR VERSION 1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1998-01-04</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1997-07-05T02:18:30.266Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1997-09-25T04:52:07.936Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>ALLAN J. RUNKLE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Runkle, A. J., MARS PATHFINDER ROVER MARS ROVER CAMERA 2 EDR
            VERSION 1.0, MPFR-M-RVRCAM-2-EDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 1998
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Mars Pathfinder Rover Rear Camera Experiment Data Record
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            Mars Pathfinder bounced down and rolled to a stop on the surface
            of Mars on July 4, 1997. After a slight delay in deployment due
            to airbags draped over one of the lander&apos;s petals, the Rover
            rolled down onto the surface of Mars at 5:37am, July 6, 1997
            (UTC).
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    Mars Pathfinder bounced down and rolled to a stop on the surface
    of Mars on July 4, 1997.  After a slight delay in deployment due
    to airbags draped over one of the lander&apos;s petals, the Rover
    rolled down onto the surface of Mars at 5:37am, July 6, 1997
    (UTC).
 
    627 images were collected by the three cameras mounted on the
    Microrover Flight Experiment (also known as the Mars Pathfinder
    Rover or Sojourner).  The rover has two monochromatic cameras
    mounted in front which provide stereo viewing, and a separate
    &apos;color&apos; camera mounted in the rear.  The rear camera obtains
    color pictures through the use of red, green, and blue pixels
    arranged in a &apos;field-staggered 3G&apos; mosaic filter pattern on the
    CCD.
 
 
  Landing Site
  ============
    Using prominent features visible around the landing site, the
    location of the site has been pinpointed at 19.17 degrees north
    and 33.21 degrees west relative to the U.S.  Geological Survey
    cartographic network.  However, two-way ranging and Doppler
    tracking of the lander place the site at 19.30 degrees north and
    33.52 degrees west in inertial space, suggesting that the USGS
    grid may be displaced about 19 km to the north and 7 km to the
    west.  The landing site is an ancient floodplain in the Ares
    Vallis region of Chryse Planitia.
 
    During the rover&apos;s 83 Sol mission on Mars, it nearly
    circumnavigated the lander, staying within a 12 meter radius of
    it.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The Rover Camera EDRs are images; the main parameter is light,
    measured in units of data numbers or DNs.  Each CCD pixel
    (picture element) is represented by a byte value ranging from 0
    (dark) to 255 (saturated).  The wavelength sensitivity of the
    front (black and white) cameras was 830 to 890 nm; the aft
    (color) camera sensitivity was 500 to 900 nm.
 
 
  Data
  ====
    The Rover images on this CD are uncompressed, 8-bit files,
    labelled in conformance with PDS standards.  The images from all
    three cameras are stored as single-banded images.  Additional
    versions of the rear camera images are stored as three-banded
    color images.
 
    The Rover Camera EDRs are contained in the RVR_EDR/ directory on
    the CD.  The front left images are stored in the
    RVR_EDR/RVR_LEFT/ subdirectory, the front right images are in the
    RVR_EDR/RVR_RIGHT/ directory, and the single-banded rear images
    are in the RVR_EDR/RVR_REAR/ directory.  The triple-banded rear
    images are kept in the RVR_EDR/RVR_CLR/ directory.
 
    Individual filenames consist of the instrument identifier &apos;R&apos;,
    followed by the seven least significant digits of the spacecraft
    clock start count, followed by the file extension &apos;.IMG&apos;.  The
    filenames are only unique within their respective directories,
    not within the entire data set.
 
    Each image file is stored with a fixed length record format.
    There is an attached PDS label at the beginning of each image
    file that describes the content and format of the image.  If the
    PDS label size is not an exact multiple of the file record
    length, padding is added after the end of the PDS label.  Thus,
    the image object always starts on a record boundary.
 
    PDS labels are object-oriented.  The object to which the label
    refers (e.g., IMAGE, TABLE, etc.) is denoted by a statement of
    the form:
 
        ^object = location
 
    in which the carat character (&apos;^&apos;, also called a pointer in this
    context) indicates that the object starts at the given location.
    For an object in the same file as the label (as is the case for
    the Rover EDRs), the location is an integer representing the
    starting record number of the object (the first record in the
    file is record 1).  For example:
 
        ^IMAGE = 22
 
    indicates that the IMAGE object begins at record 22 of the file.
 
    A more detailed specification of the rover image file format is
    given in the ROVERSIS file in the DOCUMENT directory.  A complete
    description of the PDS file format is available from the
    Planetary Data System.  (Complete contact information for the PDS
    is available in the AAREADME file in the root directory of this
    CD.)
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    Onboard Processing:
 
    Image capture was executed by applying low-level functions to
    manage the acquisition, readout, and optionally, compression of
    the data.  Valid image data were in rows 6 through 489 and
    columns 0 through 767; row 490 contained dark reference pixels.
    The data was packetized for telemetry, with enclosed identifiers
    describing the exposure (in milliseconds) and image region.
 
    Auto exposure determination was indicated by an exposure time of
    zero.  Given an image region, an overexposed image was taken and
    the brightest (saturated) pixel found.  Then a geometric search
    of exposure times was performed, until an image was found with an
    average pixel value between 40% and 50% of saturation.  Finally,
    exposure time was reduced by 25% as many times as necessary until
    no more than 1% of the pixels were within 5% of saturation.  An
    exposure time of 1 indicated that the last computed auto exposure
    time was re-used.  If no auto exposure had been performed since
    the last wakeup, a new auto exposure time was determined.
 
    As part of the auto exposure, a shift factor was employed to
    manage the A/D conversion from 12 bits to 8 bits.  Proper auto
    exposure for the front B&amp;W cameras generally required a shift
    factor of 2, while the aft color camera used a shift factor of 1.
 
    Used optionally on front camera B&amp;W images only, the block
    truncation coding (BTC) algorithm gave a fixed 4.9:1 compression
    ratio, helping to reduce the communication time without unduly
    sacrificing image quality.  In pre-flight tests, a S/N ratio of
    145:1 was achieved.  Compression was performed on 16 column by 4
    row blocks of image data.  When the BTC compression was
    erroneously performed on aft camera images (indicated by a
    command sequence number of zero), a loss of color information
    resulted.
 
    Ground Processing:
 
    The images were extracted from the telemetry via &apos;real time
    processing&apos;, specifically using the VICAR (Video Image
    Communication and Retrieval) program MPFTELEMPROC.  This program
    obtained the Standard Formatted Data Unit (SFDU) records from the
    Telemetry Delivery Subsystem (TDS), constructed the image files
    from the telemetry data, and decompressed them.  The rear camera
    images were rotated 90 degrees within MPFTELEMPROC so that the
    output image data had its vertical dimension along the image&apos;s
    line dimension, similar to the front camera data.  The images
    were compared to any previously downloaded versions to determine
    which contained the most data.  The versions with the greatest
    amount of data were retained.  The program resulted in VICAR
    formatted image files with a subset of descriptive label items.
    The label information was then supplemented with data derived
    from the mission catalog and SPICE kernels.
 
    The rear camera images are archived in both single-band and
    triple-band format.  Each pixel in the rear camera CCD is
    designated a specific color: red, green, or blue.  The VICAR
    program MPFRVRCLR uses a color map to split these into three
    separate bands.  The missing pixels are filled in using bilinear
    spatial interpolation.
 
    Finally, each image was run through the VICAR program MPFPDSLBL
    to convert the labels to PDS format.
 
    The Rover Camera Experiment Data Records were created at the
    Multimission Image Processing Laboratory at the Jet Propulsion
    Laboratory.
 
 
  Coordinate Systems
  ==================
    The Rover heading and position are measured in the Martian Local
    Level coordinate frame.  The heading is measured clockwise from
    north in units of BAMs (Binary Angle Measurements), where 2**16
    BAMs equals one revolution.  The position is provided as x and y
    offsets in meters north and east, respectively, of the Lander.
 
    The Martian Local Level Coordinate Frame is a right handed,
    orthogonal, frame whose origin is co-incident with the origin of
    the Lander Coordinate Frame.  The XM axis points north, the YM
    axis points east, and the ZM axis points down.  This sytem is
    defined relative to the Mars areocentric coordinate system.
 
    For more information on Mars Pathfinder coordinate systems, see
    the [MELLSTROM&amp;LAU1996], [WELLMAN1996B], and [VAUGHAN1995]
    references.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    The Rover EDR images can be displayed on UNIX, Macintosh, and PC
    platforms using the PDS developed program, NASAView.  This
    software is freely available from the PDS Central Node and may be
    obtained from their web site at http://pds.nasa.gov/.  For
    more information or help in obtaining the software, contact the
    PDS operator at the following address:
 
    Address:     Planetary Data System, PDS Operator
                 Jet Propulsion Laboratory
                 4800 Oak Grove Drive
                 Pasadena, CA 91109
 
    Phone:       (818) 354-4321
    Email:       pds_operator@jpl.nasa.gov
    WWW URL:     http://pds.nasa.gov/
 
    The real time processing of the VICAR-formatted Rover data was done
    using the VICAR suite of image processing programs.  The latest
    version of the VICAR program XVD may also be used for displaying PDS
    formatted images.  For information on obtaining VICAR, please contact:
 
    Address:     Danika Jensen
                 M/S 168-414
                 Jet Propulsion Laboratory
                 4800 Oak Grove Drive
                 Pasadena, CA 91109
 
    Phone:       (818) 354-6269
    Email:       Danika.Jensen@jpl.nasa.gov
    WWW URL:     http://www-mipl.jpl.nasa.gov/vicar.html
 
 
  Media / Format
  ==============
    The Rover Camera EDR data will be stored on compact disc-read
    only memory (CD-ROM) media.  The CDs will be formatted according
    to ISO-9660 and PDS standards.  The data files will not include
    extended attribute records (XARs), and will therefore not be
    readable on some older VMS operating systems.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The Rover cameras and flight software functioned nominally during
    the mission.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    Prior to release, the data will be reviewed by the MPF Rover Team
    and the Planetary Data System.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    The design of the rover rear camera required some loss of spatial
    resolution in exchange for color; thus, the images produced by
    this camera are of noticeably poorer resolution than those
    produced by the front cameras.
 
    As mentioned above, there were a four instances when the rear
    camera acquired images in an emergency mode and erroneously
    compressed them.  As a result, the color information was lost for
    these images, and they were therefore not converted to
    three-banded color images.  The rear camera images which exist as
    single-banded images but which were not converted to three-banded
    images are the following:
 
                    RVR_EDR/RVR_REAR/R7199566.IMG
                    RVR_EDR/RVR_REAR/R7209116.IMG
                    RVR_EDR/RVR_REAR/R7380854.IMG
                    RVR_EDR/RVR_REAR/R9330855.IMG
 
    Early in the mission, there were a few rear camera images in
    which one scan line of the images was skipped; however, this was
    due to a commanding error, not an error in the onboard software.
 
    During the mission, some data packets were lost (indicated in the
    image labels by the RECEIVED_PACKETS value being lower than the
    EXPECTED_PACKETS value); this was due to communication problems
    between the lander and rover, or the lander and Earth.
 
    As the mission progressed, dust accumulated on the lenses, so
    artifacts did become visible during the mission.  This was
    expected.
 
    A table of the rover images received and relevant comments about
    their quality is available in the &apos;Flight Rover Image Status
    Report&apos;, contained in the DOCUMENT/ROVERDOC/DOWNLINK/TABLIMAG.HTM
    file on this CD.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    The Sojourner rover did NOT have an independently powered mission
    clock circuit.  As a consequence, when the rover&apos;s batteries were
    finally exhausted on Sol 58 the rover no longer had an accurate
    means of knowing what time it was when it automatically woke up
    via solar power and the lander was unavailable (i.e., it&apos;s rover
    modem was not yet powered on) to provide a clock/time update.
    This situation created a number of complications in terms of
    analyzing rover data collected after Sol 58, particularly, data
    taken during the early morning hours prior to the rover getting
    an clock update from the lander.  However, given that the Rover
    acquired most of its images after it received a clock update from
    the lander each day, this problem should not have a significant
    impact on the accuracy of the image meta-data.
 
    Complete details of the rover clock problem are provided in the
    data set description for the Rover Engineering data (RVRENGDS.CAT
    in the CATALOG directory on this CD).
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SAFED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

