<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ody-m-grs-5-elements-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 5 ELEMENT CONCENTRATION V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.2001_mars_odyssey::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.ody::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:grs.ody::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-grs-5-elements-v1.0__browserp_ody-m-grs-5-elements-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-grs-5-elements-v1.0__dvo_ody-m-grs-5-elements-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-grs-5-elements-v1.0__pds.us.grs_web_site::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Boynton, W. V., W. C. Feldman, I. Mitrofanov, L. G. Evans, R. C. Reedy, S.
                   W. Squyres, R. Starr, I. Trombka, C. d&apos;Uston, J. R. Arnold, P. A. J.
                   Englert, A. E. Metzger, H. Wanke, J. Bruckner, D. M. Drake, C. Shinohara,
                   C. Fellows, D. K. Hamara, K. Harshman, The Mars Odyssey gamma-ray
                   spectrometer instrument suite, Space Sci. Rev., 110 (1-2): 37-83, 2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BOYNTONETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Boynton, W. V., A. L. Sprague, S. C. Solomon, R. D. Starr, L. G. Evans, W. C.
                   Feldman, J. I. Trombka, and E. A. Rhodes, MESSENGER and the chemistry of
                   Mercury&apos;s surface, Space Science Reviews, submitted, 2006.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BOYNTONETAL2007</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>ODY-M-GRS-5-ELEMENTS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 5 ELEMENT CONCENTRATION V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2006-06-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2002-06-04T00:00:00Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2005-04-03T00:00:00Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>WILLIAM BOYNTON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Boynton, W.V., 2001 Mars Odyssey Gamma Ray Spectrometer Element
            Concentration Data, NASA Planetary Data System,
            ODY-M-GRS-5-ELEMENTS-V1.0, 2007.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set contains Odyssey GRS element concentration maps and
            underlying data for various elements, including chlorine, iron,
            water, potassium, silicon, and thorium.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 5 ELEMENTS data set consists
            of a set of maps and underlying data products originally released
            to the public in March 2006. They contain data that was collected
            by the 2001 Mars Odyssey Gamma-ray Spectrometer between June 4,
            2002 and April 3, 2005. These data are highly processed, and
            represent the fully corrected, CO2 frost free elemental
            concentrations. Data for all non-radioactive species have been
            masked to exclude polar regions where we currently cannot
            adequately deal with dilution by the large amounts of water ice.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Mars Odyssey Gamma-Ray Spectrometer (GRS) is a suite of
      three instruments working together to collect data that
      permits the mapping of elemental concentrations on the surface of
      Mars. The suite of three instruments, the gamma-ray sensor head
      (GS), the Los Alamos National Laboratory (LANL) neutron
      spectrometer (NS) and the Russian Academy of Science Institute
      for Space Research (IKI) high-energy neutron detector (HEND),
      are a complementary set of instruments in that the neutron
      instruments have better counting statistics and sample to a
      greater depth than the GS, but the GS determines the abundance
      of many more elements. A full description of the Mars
      Odyssey Gamma-Ray Spectrometer instrument can be found in
      [BOYNTONETAL2004].
 
      The ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 5 ELEMENTS data set consists
      of a set of maps and underlying data products originally released
      to the public in March 2006. They contain data that was collected
      by the 2001 Mars Odyssey Gamma-ray Spectrometer between 06/04/02
      and 04/03/05. These data are highly processed, and represent the
      fully corrected, CO2 frost free elemental concentrations. Data
      for all non-radioactive species have been masked to exclude polar
      regions where were we currently cannot adequately deal with
      dilution by the large amounts of water ice.
 
      The following paragraphs summarize the process by which the CO2
      frost free elemental concentrations were determined.
 
      Determination of CO2 Frost-Freeness
 
      In order to determine the spatial and temporal ranges when Mars is
      free of Carbon Dioxide frost, observed measurements of Hydrogen
      and Potassium are used (due to the fact that they are among the
      strongest gamma ray emitters and provide statistically significant
      accumulations in relatively short periods of time). Seasonal 5x360
      (latitude by longitude) sums are generated and run through our
      peak measurement algorithms (either by Gaussian fit plus tail
      component or by simple window counting between channels X and Y,
      in both cases, subtracting the continuum baseline contribution
      beneath the given peak of interest). Use of smaller grids on a
      seasonal basis was attempted, but results were not as easy to
      interpret due to statistically poorer accumulations. The 5x360
      system seems to work quite well, and though it is acknowledged
      that there are certainly heterogeneities within a particular
      latitude band (i.e. the planet is certainly not identical, CO2
      frost-free-wise through all 360 degrees of longitude), the
      general assessment of CO2 frost-freeness planet-wide is believed
      to be quite accurate. In this manner, plots are created showing
      each individual 5 degree latitude band vs. time (in terms of
      season, or Ls, where season 0 represents Ls 0 through 15 (center
      Ls 7.5)).  The relative increase and decrease in the H and K
      signals is then used to determine when CO2 frost is present or not
      throughout the mission in each particular 5 degree latitude band.
      For instance, when both H and K agree in terms of apparent maximum
      counts or calculated fluxes or concentrations, this indicates a
      period when CO2 frost is absent or at an extreme minimum, such
      that little or no H or K signal is being attenuated.  This happens
      to be the case in the northern region of the planet between
      seasons 4-6 and seasons 12-14, depending on Mars year, and exact
      latitude (such as +70 to  +80 or +85 to +90, etc.).  Conversely,
      when the apparent H and K signals are at observed minima, this
      does not indicate that the H and K concentrations are actually
      dropping, but rather that the CO2 frost is accumulating and
      attenuating the underlying H and K gamma ray emissions. In this
      way, then, by observing apparent increase and decrease (and
      subsequent plateaus during CO2 frost-free or CO2 frosty durations)
      in measured counts, calculated fluxes, or calculated
      concentrations, it is possible to constrain the spatial and
      temporal ranges of CO2-frost-freeness. The significance, of
      course, is that then, spectra collected over parts of the planet
      during times of CO2 frost-freeness may be co-added together over a
      variety of regions or grids, and the true, unattenuated elemental
      signatures can be observed, and the true concentrations may be
      calculated.
 
      CO2 Frost Free Mars 060802 to 012206
 
      -90 to -80  MY01_20-MY01_23, MY02_20-MY02_23
      -80 to -70  MY01_18-MY02_00, MY02_18-MY02_23
      -70 to -65  MY01_01, MY01_16-MY02_01, MY02_16_MY02_23
      -65 to -60  MY01_01-MY01_02, MY01_15-MY02_01, MY02_15-MY02_23
      -60 to -55  MY01_01-MY01_03, MY01_13-MY02_02, MY02_13-MY02-23
      -55 to -50  MY01_01-MY01_04, MY01_10-MY02_02, MY02_12-MY02_23
      -50 to 55   MY01_01-MY02_23
      55 to 60    MY01_01-MY01_17, MY02_00-MY02_17
      60 to 70    MY01_06-MY01_14, MY02_04-MY02_13
      70 to 75    MY01_05-MY01_13, MY02_05-MY02_13
      75 to 80    MY01_06-MY01_13, MY02_05-MY02_13
      80 to 90    MY01_06-MY01_12, MY02_06-MY02_12p
 
      Calculation of Concentration (wt%)
 
      The calculation of concentration for any given element involves
      several steps, some of which are quite involved. Forward
      modeling, for instance, is a process with extensive documentation,
      to which the reader is referred for details [BOYNTONETAL2007],
      but for the purposes of this summary, the goal is simply to
      explain how one can proceed from  accumulation of gamma rays to
      concentration (wt%) of a particular element on the surface
      (and near subsurface) of Mars.
 
      The first step is measurement of gamma ray counts over a
      particular region on the planet, whether it be geologic, or
      gridded in nature.  That is, one may be interested in a geologic
      region such as Arabia Terra and measuring the counts of a
      particular gamma ray line collected within the boundaries of said
      geologic region; one might also be interested in making a 5x5
      degree map and measuring the counts in each 5x5 degree bin in
      order to establish the basis for the map. In either scenario, the
      first step is measurement of counts.  There are two fundamental
      methods of measuring counts from a continuous spectrum; one is a
      Gaussian fit plus tail component, and the other is a simple
      counting method essentially integrating the counts that fall
      method, as counts in a window between X and Y are counted).  In
      both cases, a fit to the continuum baseline is made, and those
      counts are subtracted so the resultant counts are simply those
      contained within the peak or peaks of interest. In some cases,
      such  as H, K, Si, Th, U, etc., there are spacecraft or instrument
      interferences or backgrounds to take into account, so those
      contributions are quantified and subtracted from the observed
      counts in the peak or peaks.
 
      Once a background/interference adjusted area is measured, then a
      concentration may be calculated. For each peak of interest, there
      is a forward modeled expected contribution of counts from Mars
      for the given peak of interest in the given region or grid of
      interest. There are a number of factors that go into this modeled
      calculation, including atmospheric thickness, detector efficiency
      as a function of angle, footprint of the detector, production
      values of the elements based on an educated component model of
      Martian soil, etc. The reader is referred to the forward model
      documentation [REF?] for an in-depth understanding of these
      contributions. Essentially, though, a particular model of martial
      soil and rock is determined based on ground truth from previous
      and current missions. For the given model, there is a mass
      fraction for each element in the soil mixture, and there is a
      corresponding forward modeled number of counts for each
      particular gamma ray line of interest. So, for example in the case
      of Cl, while there may be nine individual lines, each one will have a
      unique expected number of model counts, but the mass fraction on
      the soil model would be the same for all nine.
 
      From this point, determination of concentration is rather simple.
      The background adjusted (if the element in question had any
      particular instrument, spacecraft, or additional gamma line
      interference) or the raw observed counts themselves are compared
      to the modeled counts (i.e., divided by the forward counts) and
      then multiplied by the mass fraction for the particular model soil
      that was chosen for the planet surface. The calculated value is a
      unitless ratio of measured counts over expected counts times a
      weight percent, which we now refer to as the &apos;raw concentration&apos;.
      In order to transform the value into a true wt% concentration, a
      correction factor (distinct depending on whether the line is
      neutron capture or inelastic scatter), based on water and iron
      content, as well as comparison of Si capture to scatter values
      (as this is the only element that gives us ground truth
      measurements for both types of reactions) is applied to the flux
      to obtain true wt% concentration.
 
      Table of Peaks Used to Determine Elemental Concentrations
 
      Energy (keV)  Element   Z  Source          Method  Process
      ------------  -------   -  ------          ------  -------
      2223.25       H         1  1H(n,g)2H       fit     Capture
      1778.97       Si       14  28Si(n,ng)28Si  window  Scatter
      3538.97       Si       14  28Si(n,g)29Si   window  Capture
      4933.89       Si       14  28Si(n,g)29Si   window  Capture
      4422.89       Si       14  28Si(n,g)29Si   window  Capture-esc-1
      1951.14       Cl       17  35Cl(n,g)36Cl   fit     Capture
      1959.35       Cl       17  35Cl(n,g)36Cl   fit     Capture
      6110.84       Cl       17  35Cl(n,g)36Cl   fit     Capture
      5599.84       Cl       17  35Cl(n,g)36Cl   fit     Capture-esc-1
      7790.33       Cl       17  35Cl(n,g)36Cl   fit     Capture
      1460.82       K        19  40K             window  Radioactive
      1381.75       Ti       22  48Ti(n,g)49Ti   window  Capture
      7638          Fe       26  56Fe(n,g)57Fe   window  Capture-doublet
      7127          Fe       26  56Fe(n,g)57Fe   window  Capt.-doub./esc-1
      2614.53       Th       90  Th-208Tl        window  Radioactive
 
      Correction Factors and Data Smoothing
 
      Final adjustments to the raw concentrations determined from
      capture (of thermal neutrons) and inelastic scatter (by fast
      neutrons) gamma rays are made to account for the interaction of
      thermal and fast neutrons with the atmosphere and regolith, and
      to take advantage of the fact that we have ground truth
      measurements of silicon on Mars. Silicon is used for determining
      these correction factors since we detect statistically
      significant numbers for both capture and scatter produced gamma
      rays, and because silicon varies by less than about 10% over the
      entire surface of Mars, reducing the sensitivity of this
      correction to the precision of the spatial or compositional
      measurements used.
 
      We first make an inelastic scatter correction map for Mars by
      taking our last, best map of H2O and determining a correction
      factor for water&apos;s effect on fast neutrons from the empirically
      derived formula:
 
           fH2O = 1.1165 - 0.04308[H2O] + 0.001401[H2O]^2
 
      where: [H2O] is the mapped concentration of water in wt%.
 
      We make a similar determination for iron&apos;s effect from the last,
      best map of iron using the formula:
 
           fFe = 0.9406 + 0.005056[Fe]
 
      where: [Fe] is the mapped concentration of iron in wt%.
 
      The Si scatter data is then divided by the product of the two
      correction factors, masked to exclude data from high latitudes
      where large water concentrations, and attendant dilutions of
      other elements (including iron and silicon), preclude precise
      determination of the elemental concentration, smoothed with a
      2-d, 15 degree boxcar filter, and re-masked. The resulting map is
      then adjusted by a constant factor such that the value at the
      Pathfinder landing site is set equal to 20.95 wt% silicon. This is
      our &apos;true&apos; silicon content for the regolith of Mars. We then
      divide our masked and smoothed Si-scatter raw concentration map by
      the &apos;true&apos; map to get a map of scatter correction factors, and
      divide our masked and smoothed Si-capture raw concentration map
      by the &apos;true&apos; map to get a map of capture correction factors. As
      with all our maps, these correction maps are based on a 0.5 by
      0.5 degree grid, with a value assigned to each cell within that grid.
      These values are then binned up onto 2x2, 5x5 and 10x10 degree
      bins, with each value in the larger bin being the area-weighted
      average of the 0.5x0.5 degree cells that comprise it.
 
      Finally, we use the correction factors determined in this manner
      to correct the current data for water and iron, producing a new
      set of starting maps from which to determine  and , and iterate
      until there is no significant change in either the resulting
      correction factors or maps. In practice, the first iteration is
      usually sufficient to show that no further iterations are
      required.
 
      The correctly sized capture or scatter correction map, as
      appropriate, is then applied to each raw concentration file before
      smoothing to produce a corrected raw concentration file. This data
      is then smoothed with a 2-d boxcar filter sized for the
      uncertainty in the raw data. Data with low uncertainty are
      smoothed with a small filter to preserve spatial information,
      while data with high intrinsic uncertainty (due to a low number
      of counts, poorly determined continuum, interfering peaks, etc.)
      are smoothed with a large filter in order to reduce spatial
      noise. As with the smoothing performed in the determination of the
      correction factors, the data is masked before and after smoothing
      to prevent the inclusion of spurious (very high uncertainty) data
      from high latitudes.
 
      The 2-d boxcar filters we use are circular in plan view with a
      radius stated in degrees of great circle arc. They are applied to
      data on 0.5 by 0.5 degree grids. Thus any mapped value that falls
      within the filter radius of the point being assessed is given a
      weight equivalent to the area of its 0.5x0.5 degree cell, but no other
      weighting algorithm (such as Gaussian weighting) is applied. At
      high latitudes, many more cells will be included in the smoothing
      for a given point, but the area considered for each point on the
      planet is a constant.
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
N/A
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

