<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ear-c-ccd-3-rdr-grigg-skjell-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>EARTH BASED CCD OBSERVATIONS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.giotto_extended_mission::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.gemgb::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:ccd.gemgb::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:comet.26p-grigg-skjellerup_1_1922_k1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-c-ccd-3-rdr-grigg-skjell-v1.0__browserp_ear-c-ccd-3-rdr-grigg-skjell-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Birkle, K. and H. Boehnhardt, Observations of the Giotto Target Comet
                   P/Grigg-Skjellerup at the Calar Alto Observatory, Earth, Moon, and Planets 57,
                   191-201, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BIRKLE-BOEHNHARD1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Fulle,M., V. Mennella, A. Rotundi, L. Colangeli, E. Bussoletti and F. Pasian,
                   &apos;The dust environment of comet P/Grigg-Skjellerup as evidenced from
                   ground-based observations, AA, 276, p. 582, 1993a.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FULLEETAL1993A</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>EAR-C-CCD-3-RDR-GRIGG-SKJELL-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>EARTH BASED CCD OBSERVATIONS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1994-05-10</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1986-10-22T05:00:41Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1993-09-16T20:40:49Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>SMALL BODIES NODE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>Unknown</citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This data set presents CCD images of 26P/Grigg-Skjellerup
            obtained several ground-based observers. (SAVED DATA)
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set presents images of 26P/Grigg-Skjellerup obtained by
            various observers at several ground-based observatories using CCD
            instruments. These data have not been through the full PDS review
            process.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
      Data Set Overview
      =================
      This data set includes ground-based images from several observers,
      all made using CDC instruments.  The bulk of the images were obtained
      with the ESO CCD instrument and were submitted by Alexandra Rotundi
      for the team of Fulle, M. et al.(1993A).   Data from Calor Alto were
      submitted by Boehnhardt and Matella; most of the data is described
      in Birkle and Boehnhardt (1992).  Three pre-encounter images recorded
      at the AAO through narrow-band filters that measured H2O+ were
      were submitted by a group (Jones, et al.) from the Mullard Space
      Science Laboratory.  Finally, a post-encounter image, a composite of
      five short exposures taken through a broad band red filter at ESO
      was submitted by Karl Joeckers et al.
 
      Parameters
      ==========
      The images from ESO were taken near perihelion in 1992 after the Giotto
      spacecraft had flown by the nucleus of comet 26P/Grigg-Skjellerup.
      These data were used to derive the radial distribution of light away
      from the nucleus.  The original images were taken with a large field
      (1024 x 1024) CCD and used for this dust study.  In the archive are
      cropped images (101 x 101).
 
      Calar Alto data were collected over a seven year-span for astrometric
      positions that would assist in the targeting of the Giotto spacecraft.
 
      Anomalies
      =========
      The ESO data were sent with minimal FITS header and a separate ASCII
      description of the measurements.   A FITS header, combining both sets
      of information, was constructed to detail the observations.   Through
      e-mail contact with A. Rotundi, a proper observation time was assigned.
 
      The images from Calor Alto were sent as FITS files.  Unfortunately,
      some discrepancies were detected in the FITS headers describing
      the data when compared to Birkle and Boehnhardt (1992).  These were
      corrected after consultation with one of the submitters
      (H. Boehnhardt) as follows:
 
      1. Images 26 and 27 from the original submission:  Using the
         published information, two images, identified as
         1987/05/24.86278 and 24.86707 respectively, have the wrong
         exposure, which were changed to 15 and 30 s.
 
      2. Images 15 and 16, identified as 1991/09/12.18236 and 12.19242,
         should have the filter = V (and not R as in the submitted FITS
         header).
 
      3. Image 18, identified as 1991/12/03.98953, has the wrong
         exposure, which has been changed to 400 s (and not 401 as given).
 
      4. There was a general problem with the time specification.  The FITS
         keyword indicated a midpoint time but comparison of data through
         1991 indicates it is a start time expressed in decimal hours.   In
         addition, the accuracy (in decimal hours) is quoted to 7 figures,
         which is unlikely.  All accuracies have been rounded to 4 figures
         in the hour or 1 sec in time.
 
      5. Image 10 was out of order with the other images on that date.
         Rearranging these images in time, shows that two images
         identified in the the published work as 1987/07/24.85777 and
         24.86176 have the wrong decimal hours.   The former also has the
         incorrect exposure.  The correct value for this image in decimal
         hours is 20.5822 and exposure = 30 sec.  For the latter image, the
         correct decimal hour is 20.6406.
 
      6. The earliest three images have the wrong decimal hours (images
         1,2,3).  Using the published work and identifying the images by
         their exposures indicates that the correct identification and
         decimal hours should be:
 
          (1986/10/22) 22.21197   image 1, exp 525, dec hour = 5.0113
          (1986/10/22) 22.22703   image 2, exp 485, dec hour = 5.3814
          (1986/10/23) 23.08935   image 3, exp 800, dec hour = 2.0333
 
      7. The corrections listed above were applied to the FITS headers
         in the following manner:  The TIME-OBS keyword was replaced with
         TIMEUTH, with a description reading &apos;/ UT start time given as
         decimal hours&apos;.   New corrected values were placed in the
         appropriate FITS header and the old value captured as a COMMENT.
         In addition, any changes to the exposure or filter were also
         captured as a COMMENT.
 
      Reduction
      =========
      The data from both groups was processed using standard routines in
      MIDAS.  The bias, flat field, and sky level were subtracted.   Any
      unusual features are recorded in the FITS COMMENT or HISTORY fields.
      The data from ESO was reduced using the full image (1024 x 1024)
      before the cropped image was formed for the archive.
 
      Modification History
      ====================
      Before final submission of this data set to the PDS archive, all PDS
      labels and catalog files were brought up to current (PDS3) standards
      and the errata and addenda collected by personnel at the PDS Small
      Bodies Node were applied and added.
 
      -Anne Raugh, 11 September 2006
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
      Confidence Level Overview
      =========================
      Please consult the notes and comments in the FITS headers and PDS
      labels of the individual images for quality comments from the
      observers.  In addition, the user should reference the publications
      relevant to each set of images.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SAFED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>85-056A-00E</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>PSSB-00025</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

