<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.er2-e-avir-3-rdr-image-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ER2 EARTH AVIRIS CALIBRATED REDUCED DATA RECORD IMAGE V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.geologic_remote_sensing_field_experiment::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.er-2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:avir.er-2::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.er2-e-avir-3-rdr-image-v1.0__browserp_geo_er2-e-avir-3-rdr-image-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.er2-e-avir-3-rdr-image-v1.0__dvo_geo_er2-e-avir-3-rdr-image-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   G. Vane (Ed.), Airborne Visible/Infrared Imaging
                   Spectrometer (AVIRIS). A description of the sensor, ground
                   data processing facility, laboratory calibration, and first
                   results, JPL Publication 1987-38, 1987.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.JPLPUB1987-38</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>ER2-E-AVIR-3-RDR-IMAGE-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ER2 EARTH AVIRIS CALIBRATED REDUCED DATA RECORD IMAGE V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1991-05-28</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1989-09-28T19:28:08.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1989-10-04T19:40:35.000Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>GREGG VANE</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Vane, G., ER2 EARTH AVIRIS CALIBRATED REDUCED DATA RECORD IMAGE
            V1.0, ER2-E-AVIR-3-RDR-IMAGE-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            1991
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This archive contains calibrated reduced data records (RDRs)
            acquired by the Airborne Visible/IR Imaging Spectrometer (AVIRIS)
            during the earth-based 1989 Geologic Remote Sensing Field
            Experiment (GRSFE).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Airborne Visible and Infared Imaging Spectrometer (AVIRIS)
            data are divided into 10x10 square kilometer scenes for purposes
            of standard product generation. More than 40 scenes were
            generated during GRSFE, more than 20 of which are included on the
            CD-ROMs, covering a variety of surfaces. Lunar Crater was covered
            several times in one day (under clear atmospheric conditions) in
            order to evaluate atmospheric scattering and absorption removal
            algorithms and to explore extraction of roughness information
            using variable incidence angle AVIRIS data. The AVIRIS
            multi-temporal data were acquired at the same time that
            ground-based, multi-spectral measurements of atmospheric optical
            depth, and sky radiance at varying scattering angles were
            acquired, along with surface bidirectional reflectance data.
            Accurate wavelength calibration of AVIRIS was performed by JPL
            using laboratory measurements acquired before and after the
            AVIRIS flights. An additional check on the wavelength calibration
            can be made by comparing the positions of known atmospheric
            absorption features to their locations in actual AVIRIS data.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Airborne Visible and Infared Imaging Spectrometer (AVIRIS)
      data are divided into 10x10 square kilometer scenes for
      purposes of standard product generation.  More than 40 scenes
      were generated during GRSFE, more than 20 of which are included
      on the CD-ROMs, covering a variety of surfaces.  Lunar Crater
      was covered several times in one day (under clear atmospheric
      conditions) in order to evaluate atmospheric scattering and
      absorption removal algorithms and to explore extraction of
      roughness information using variable incidence angle AVIRIS
      data.  The AVIRIS multi-temporal data were acquired at the same
      time that ground-based, multi-spectral measurements of
      atmospheric optical depth, and sky radiance at varying
      scattering angles were acquired, along with surface
      bidirectional reflectance data.  Accurate wavelength
      calibration of AVIRIS was performed by JPL using laboratory
      measurements acquired before and after the AVIRIS flights.  An
      additional check on the wavelength calibration can be made by
      comparing the positions of known atmospheric absorption
      features to their locations in actual AVIRIS data.
 
      Each AVIRIS scene is calibrated to radiance.  The radiance
      values are stored as 16-bit integers in units of 100 microwatts
      / (centimeters squared * nanometers * steradians).  Each AVIRIS
      scene is accompanied by 7 ancillary files.  They are the
      navigation, engineering, dark current, offset, dropout,
      radiometric calibration, and raw spectral calibration files.
 
      The navigation file contains the data from the aircraft
      navigation system.  It is recorded by the AVIRIS instrument
      every major frame.  However, it is only updated by the aircraft
      system every five seconds (60 major frames).  It contains the
      following information: flight id, run id, date, time, latitude,
      longitude, N-S velocity, E-W velocity, true heading, ground
      speed, vertical velocity, altitude, true air speed, pitch and
      roll.  The engineering file is from the AVIRIS instrument.  It
      is recorded every major frame and contains the following
      information: detector temperatures, spectrometer temperatures,
      scanner optics mount temperature, scan voltages, calibration
      lamp current, hardware status indicators, scan mirror readings,
      instrument roll gyro readings, instrument yaw gyro readings,
      and instrument firmware status indicators.
 
      The dark current file contains data taken with the fore-optics
      shutter closed during scanner flyback and is recorded every
      major frame.  This data has had the initial dark current
      (offset) data subtracted from it onboard the aircraft.  It is
      therefore a record of how the dark current varies with time
      over a flight line with respect to the initial dark current.
      The offset file contains the initial, raw, dark current data
      taken once, prior to each flight line.  It is taken with the
      fore-optics shutter closed and recorded without any onboard
      subtraction performed (the same values are recorded every major
      frame throughout a flight line).  This data is subtracted from
      the image data onboard the aircraft during a flight line in
      order to keep the image signal level on scale in the signal
      chain.  It is also onboard subtracted from the dark current
      measurements taken during a flight line.
 
      The dropout file contains the data compiled during the logging
      process.  Anomalies in the recording process can cause some
      lines to contain unintelligible data.  These lines are flagged
      at 4096 DN, and are called dropped lines.  The dropout file is
      a list of those lines that have been flagged.
 
      The radiometric calibration file contains the real number
      calibration coefficients which transform the DN values of the
      raw image into units of radiance.  The units of these
      coefficients are microwatts per square centimeter per nanometer
      per steradian per DN.  Note that the AVIRIS image data on the
      GRSFE CD-ROMs are already calibrated and given as radiance
      values.  This data has been adjusted for cross-track vignetting
      and for offsets between the spectrometers.  The raw spectral
      calibration file contains two real numbers per channel.  The
      first number is the wavelength position corresponding to the
      channel number, and the second is the full width half max
      number for the spectral response function of each channel.
 
      Processing Level Id            : 3
      Software Flag                  : N
      Processing Start Time          : 1989-09-29T00:00:00.000
      Processing Stop Time           : 1991-05-28T00:00:00.000
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      Data Set Parameter &apos;RADIANCE&apos;
      -----------------------------
        Radiance is the amount of energy per time per projected area
        per steradian.
 
        Data Set Parameter Name        : RADIANCE
        Data Set Parameter Unit        : WATT/(METER*METER)/STERADIAN
        Sampling Parameter Name        : PIXEL
        Sampling Parameter Unit        : METER
        Minimum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Maximum Sampling Parameter     : N/A
        Sampling Parameter Resolution  : 56.57
        Sampling Parameter Interval    : 20
        Minimum Available Sampling Int : N/A
        Noise Level                    : N/A
 
 
    Source Instrument Parameters
    ============================
      Instrument Host ID              : ER-2
      Data Set Parameter Name         : RADIANCE
      Instrument Parameter Name       : RADIANCE
      Important Instrument Parameters : 1
 
 
    Measurement Information
    =======================
 
      Atmospheric Conditions
      ----------------------
        Not Applicable
 
 
      Source
      ------
        The sunlight reflected from the Earth&apos;s surface is the source
        of the measurement.
 
 
      Calibration Standard
      --------------------
        Not Applicable
 
 
      Wavelength Calibration
      ----------------------
        Not Applicable
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      Processing History
      ------------------
        Source Data Set ID          : N/A
        Software                    : UNK
        Product Data Set ID         : ER2-E-AVIR-3-RDR-IMAGE-V1.0
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Overview
    ========
      The signal-to-noise ratio is at least 100:1 at 0.7 micrometers,
      and at least 50:1 at 2.2 micrometers.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>XD-21A</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

