<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.mgn-v-rdrs-5-c-bidr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MGN V RDRS COMPRESSED BASIC IMAGE DATA RECORD CD ARCHIVE</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.magellan::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.mgn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:rdrs.mgn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgn-v-rdrs-5-c-bidr-v1.0__browserp_geo_mgn-v-rdrs-5-c-bidr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.mgn-v-rdrs-5-c-bidr-v1.0__dvo_geo_mgn-v-rdrs-5-c-bidr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Barry, S., Magellan Mission Operations System: Radar System Interface
                   Requirements, Hughes Aircraft Co. Report HS513-823-3, May 1987
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BARRY1987</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Brill, R., and C. Meisl, Magellan Altimeter Processing: Algorithms and
                   Constants, Jet Propulsion Laboratory Document D-6143, 15 February 1990
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BRILL-MEISL1990</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Cuevas, C., Magellan Radar Sensor Compensation Report, Hughes Aircraft
                   Co. Report HS513-5029, 18 August 1989
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CUEVAS1989</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Davies, M.E., V.K. Abalakin, M. Bursa, G.E. Hunt, J.H. Lieske, B. Morando, R.H.
                   Rapp, P.K. Seidelmann, A.T. Sinclair, and Y.S. Tyuflin, Report of the
                   IAU/IAG/COSPAR Working Group on Cartographic Coordinates and Rotational
                   Elements of the Planets and Satellites: 1988, Celestial Mechanics and Dynamical
                   Astronomy, 46, 187-204, 1989.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DAVIESETAL1989</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Ford, P. G., and G.H. Pettengill, Venus Topography and Kilometer-Scale Slopes,
                   Journal of Geophysical Research, 97, 13103-13114, 1992
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FORD-PETTENGILL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Ford, P. G., Magellan Altimetry and Radiometry Composite Data,
                   USA_NASA_JPL_MG_2nnn, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FORD1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Ford, P. G., Magellan Global Altimetry and Radiometry Data Records,
                   USA_NASA_JPL_MG_3nnn, 1993.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FORD1993</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hagfors, T., and J.V. Evans, Radar Studies of the Moon, Chapter 5 in Radar
                   Astronomy (Evans, J. V., and T. Hagfors, editors), New York: McGraw-Hill,
                   1968
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAGFORS-EVANS1968</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hagfors, T., Backscattering from an Undulating Surface with Applications to
                   Radar Returns from the Moon, Journal of Geophysical Research, 69,
                   3779-3784, 1964.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HAGFORS1964</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lyons, D.T., Magellan Planetary Constants and Models, JPL D-2300, Jet
                   Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, Calif., 1988.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LYONS1988</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Planetary Data System Standards Reference, Jet Propulsion Laboratory Document
                   D-7669, Part 2, 20 November 1992
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PDSSR1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Pettengill, G.H., P.G. Ford, and R.J. Wilt, Venus Surface Radiothermal
                   Emission as Observed by Magellan, Journal of Geophysical Research, 97,
                   13091-13102, 1992.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PETTENGILLETAL1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Project Magellan Software Interface Specification: Magellan Science EDR
                   (TPS-101), 30 January 1991
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SCIEDR</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Project Magellan Software Interface Specification: Full-Resolution Basic
                   Image Data Record, Revision E, 31 August 1992
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SDPS101</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Magellan Project Radar System: Analysis Methods and Performance Estimates,
                   Hughes Aircraft Co. Report HS513-062-49, July 1989
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SE011</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Snyder, J.P., Map Projections - A Working Manual, U.S. Geol. Surv. Professional
                   Paper 1395, 1987.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SNYDER1987</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Tyler, G.L., R.A. Simpson, M.J. Maurer, and E. Holmann, Scattering
                   Properties of the Venusian Surface: Preliminary Results from Magellan,
                   Journal of Geophysical Research, 97, 13115-13139, 1992
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.TYLER1992</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>MGN-V-RDRS-5-C-BIDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MGN V RDRS COMPRESSED BASIC IMAGE DATA RECORD CD ARCHIVE</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1994-07-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1990-09-15T16:23:12Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1992-09-14T02:28:37Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DR. PETER G FORD</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Ford, P. G., MGN V RDRS COMPRESSED BASIC IMAGE DATA RECORD CD
            ARCHIVE, MGN-V-RDRS-5-C-BIDR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            1994
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Magellan Compressed-Resolution Basic Image Data Record
            (C-BIDR) archive contains compressed-resolution image swaths
            acquired by the Magellan spacecraft during its mission to Venus.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains the Magellan C-BIDR (Compressed Resolution
            Basic Image Data Record) archive products. It also contains
            documentation files which describe the C-BIDRs. Each C-BIDR data
            directory contains the compressed image swaths obtained from one
            orbit and the ancillary files necessary to understand the data.
            The C-BIDR products archived on this volume are the exact
            products released by the Magellan Project, with additional PDS
            labels, swath index files, and documentation added for the
            convenience of the user.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Dataset Overview
    ================
  This volume contains Magellan
    C-BIDR (Compressed Resolution Basic Image Data Record) archive
    products.  It also contains documentation files which describe the
    C-BIDRs.  Each C-BIDR data directory contains the compressed image
    swaths obtained from one orbit and the ancillary files necessary to
    understand the data.  The C-BIDR products archived on this volume
    are the exact products released by the Magellan Project, with
    additional PDS labels, swath index files, and documentation added
    for the convenience of the user.  Supporting documentation and
    label files conform to the Planetary Data System (PDS) Standards,
    Version 3.0, Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) document JPL D-7669.
 
    Compressed resolution basic image data files consist of SAR image
    data acquired along one orbit.  Pixel widths are 225m.  Data are
    presented as 8 bit pixel brightness values where the brightness is
    in proportion to the radar scaled backscatter cross section.
    Scaling is accomplished by dividing the radar cross section value
    for each pixel by the value estimated from the Muhleman Law for the
    relevant incidence angle, converting the ratio to decibels, and
    scaling to a 1 to 251 output range.  The 1 value corresponds to -20
    dB and 251 to +30 dB, with a linear quantization of 0.2 dB in
    between.  Data have at least 4 looks.  Specifically, the scaled
    radar backscatter cross section is generated by:
 
    1.  Dividing the radar cross section by the value obtained from the
        Muhleman Law,
                            alpha * cos(i)
          sigma[0] = ---------------------------
                     (sin(i) + beta * cos(i))**3
 
        where i = incidence angle, and alpha and beta are 0.0118 and 0.111,
        respectively [PETTENGILLETAL1988].
 
        (Note: A value of 0.0188 was intended for the multiplicative
        alpha, but 0.0118 was used by mistake.  Also, the incidence
        angles used to compute the Muhleman Law are systematically low
        by 0.5 degrees.)
 
    2.  Converting to dB by taking 10 times log base 10 of the ratio
        generated in the first step.
 
    3.  Scaling output to a byte DN value using the expression:
 
          DN = 1 + ROUND({MIN [MAX(RV,-20), 30] + 20} * 5)
 
        where RV = value produced in step 2, and
           ROUND = round to nearest integer.
 
    C-BIDRs are presented as image files containing two integers at the
    beginning of each line.  The first integer specifies the pixel offset t
    the first valid pixel; the second specifies the pixel offset to the las
    valid pixel.  The remainder of the line consists of scaled backscatter
    cross section values.
 
    Regions within 89 degrees of the equator have C-BIDRs in sinusoidal
    equal area projection; C-BIDR data located more than 80 degrees from th
    equator are also in oblique sinusoidal equal area projections.  For the
    sinusoidal equal area projection, the origin is at 0 degrees latitude
    and the central meridian is the sub-spacecraft longitude at the equator
    adjusted to the nearest multiple of 225m, relative to a pixel centered
    0 degrees longitude.  For details of use of the oblique sinusoidal equa
    area projection see Magellan Software Interface Specification (SIS)
    Document, Full Resolution Basic Image Data Record, SDPS-101 [LEUNG1993]
 
    The first mapping cycle C-BIDRs extend from the north pole to
    approximately 60 degrees south latitude for northern strips and from
    just below the north pole to about 70 degrees south latitude for
    intervening F-BIDR strips. Images sizes are approximately 120 samples b
    70,000 lines.
 
    Each C-BIDR orbit is located in a separate subdirectory on this CD-WO.
    Each product consists of 1 or 2 image files and 12 or 13 ancillary file
    for a total of 13 or 15 files. The higher numbers refer to orbits that
    include either north or south polar mapping. In addition, 1 or 2 index
    files have been added to assist in the use of the product.
 
    Originally, up to 5 orbits of C-BIDR products were located, together
    with a number of other, ancillary files, on one 6250 BPI 2400 foot 9
    track tape.
 
    Each C-BIDR orbit consists of approximately 12 million bytes of image d
    and 13 million bytes of ancillary data.  Included in the ancillary file
    are processing parameters, orbital information, and radar operational
    information.
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
  Consult the ERRATA.TXT file in the root
    directory and ERR.TXT files in the data directories for information
    about errors that were detected during PDS label generation.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>89-033B-01B</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

