<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ody-m-grs-4-cgs-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 4 CGS V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.2001_mars_odyssey::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.ody::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:grs.ody::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-grs-4-cgs-v1.0__browserp_geo_ody-m-grs-4-cgs-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-grs-4-cgs-v1.0__dvo_geo_ody-m-grs-4-cgs-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-grs-4-cgs-v1.0__pds.ua.grs_web_site::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Boynton, W. V., et al., The Mars Odyssey Gamma-Ray Spectrometer Instrument
                   Suite, Space Science Rev., submitted, 2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BOYNTONETAL2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Planetary Data System Standards Reference, JPL Document D-7669, Part 2, Jet
                   Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PDSSR2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Seidelmann, P.K., V.K. Abalakin, M. Bursa, M.E. Davies, C. de Bergh, J.H.
                   Lieske, J. Oberst, J.L. Simon, E.M. Standish, P. Stooke, and P.C. Thomas,
                   Report of the IAU/IAG working group on cartographic coordinates and rotational
                   elements of the planets and satellites: 2000, Celestial Mechanics and Dynamical
                   Astronomy, 82, 83-111, 2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SEIDELMANNETAL2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>ODY-M-GRS-4-CGS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 4 CGS V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2003-01-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2002-02-19T00:00:00.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>WILLIAM BOYNTON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Boynton, W., ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 4 CGS V1.0,
            ODY-M-GRS-4-CGS-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2003 2008
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Mars Odyssey Gamma Ray Spectrometer (GRS) Corrected Gamma
            Spectra (CGS) archive contains gamma ray spectra from the Gamma
            Sensor Head (GSH) corrected to a common energy scale.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Mars Odyssey Gamma-Ray Spectrometer (GRS) is a suite of three
            instruments working together to collect data that will permit the
            mapping of elemental concentrations on the surface of Mars. The
            suite of three instruments, the gamma sensor head (GS), the
            neutron spectrometer (NS) and the high-energy neutron detector
            (HEND), are a complimentary set of instruments in that the
            neutron instruments have better counting statistics and sample to
            a greater depth than the GS, but the GS determines the abundance
            of many more elements. A full description of the Mars Odyssey
            Gamma-Ray Spectrometer instrument can be found in
            [BOYNTONETAL2002].
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Mars Odyssey Gamma-Ray Spectrometer (GRS) is a suite of
      three instruments working together to collect data that will
      permit the mapping of elemental concentrations on the surface of
      Mars. The suite of three instruments, the gamma sensor head
      (GS), the neutron spectrometer (NS) and the high-energy neutron
      detector (HEND), are a complimentary set of instruments in that
      the neutron instruments have better counting statistics and
      sample to a greater depth than the GS, but the GS determines the
      abundance of many more elements. A full description of the Mars
      Odyssey Gamma-Ray Spectrometer instrument can be found in
      [BOYNTONETAL2002].
 
      The ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 2 CGS (CGS) data set is a
      time series collection of corrected gamma spectra measurements
      from the Mars Odyssey spacecraft. The CGS are corrected for
      gain, offset and linearity. The end result of the correction is
      that all the corrected spectra have a common energy scale, which
      allows the direct comparison of individual spectra.
 
      The GRS collects a new spectrum (pixel) approximately every 20
      seconds, 360 times per orbit. Approximately 4200 spectra are
      expected to be received every day. The data (both science and
      engineering) are downloaded from the spacecraft by the Jet
      Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) into the Telemetry Data System
      (TDS). The TDS sends data to a process that translates data
      packets and examines instrument health via messages. Data are
      output to a spooler that passes it to the University of Arizona
      (UA) database ingest process. The ingest process inputs raw data
      into the UA database. Gamma data are processed through a number
      of programs to yield corrected gamma spactra. The corrected gamma
      spectra are retrieved from the UA database to build the CGS
      data.
 
      The CGS is intended to be the first intermediate data product
      available for the gamma portion of the GRS. These data should be
      useful to those scientists who are experienced in gamma
      spectroscopy.
 
 
    Parameters
    ==========
      The CGS data set is composed of a single data type (CGS). The
      objective of compiling the CGS is to create a series of gamma
      data that have been processed to a common energy scale that
      allows for direct comparison to each other. Because there are
      relatively few counts in each individual spectrum, it is
      necessary to sum spectra in order to accumulate enough counts to
      separate the signal peaks from the background. In order to
      perform a summation of spectra, they must all have a common
      energy scale, which is why CGS are created. Each CGS product
      data file will contain a time series of corrected spectra
      collected over a 2-hour time period. The 2-hour data files will
      be grouped by Earth days, i.e., 12 data files per day. The reason
      CGS data files are broken into 2-hour intervals is that the file
      sizes are large.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
      A full description of the gamma data processing can be found in
      the Mars Odyssey Gamma-ray Spectrometer Gamma Data
      Processing document located in the document folder that
      accompanies this release. The following paragraphs are a summary
      of how the data are processed from data receipt through
      corrections.
 
      GRS gamma data are downloaded from the Mars Odyssey spacecraft
      by JPL into the Telemetry Data System (TDS). The TDS sends the
      data to a process called GRS_tl, which translates GRS packets
      from any source to any destination and examines instrument
      health via messages. The data is checked for packet types,
      header information, messages, errors, engineering and
      channelized data values and is output to a spooler, which
      passes data to the UA database ingestion process. The ingestion
      process inputs raw data into the database.
 
      All data packets are processed for timing and spatial
      information. Once time data is extracted from the data packet,
      UTC time is calculated from the spacecraft event time
      (sc_ev_time) by a SPICE function. The UTC time is then inserted
      into the database. The spatial portion of the data packet is
      calculated using other SPICE routines. The returned values are
      all the spatial elements of an observation, including latitude
      and longitude at the mid-point of the observation.
 
      Engineering values have an additional step of processing. Raw
      engineering values (digital) are converted to engineering
      unit values by scaling the raw value with a stored polynomial.
      The polynomials were derived through hardware calibrations, and
      are calculated by a series of database functions.
 
      Once raw gamma data, with associated timing, spatial and
      engineering data is entered into the database, a series of
      processing steps are started to prepare the data for correction.
 
      The processing begins with Engineering Smoothing. The
      Engineering Smoother uses a gaussian-weighted smoothing
      algorithm to remove noise from engineering data, and inserts the
      results into the engineering database tables. The next process
      calculates the temperature for the 170k board, an electrical
      component used for signal amplification in the GS. This
      temperature must be modeled as the temperature of the board is
      not directly measured. The modeled temperature is then inserted
      into the database. The third process extracts and deciphers
      digital housekeeping information that identifies the state of
      various components on the spacecraft. The digital housekeeping
      data is needed for the corrections. The engineering interpolator
      queries the database for uncorrected gamma spectra records where
      the associated engineering data fields are NULL. The program
      queries the engineering tables for one record on each side of
      the record of interest and does a linear interpolation from the
      two engineering records to fill in the engineering fields in the
      record of interest. The next process, fill_apps_gain, uses the
      digital housekeeping information to insert the shaping amp gain
      values into each spectrum record. The gain values are then used
      by the corrector.
 
      The correction process calculates the gain, offset, and
      linearity of the uncorrected spectra based on measured
      temperatures of various spacecraft subsystems. Because there are
      not enough counts in any given collection interval to establish
      a calibration, the correction process uses a spectrum shifting
      algorithm to re-bin the counts in each spectrum, aligning the
      channels in all of the spectra to a common energy scale. The
      corrected spectra can then be directly compared and are a
      scientifically useful data product.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      The CGS data set is composed of a series of time and date
      stamped files that contain 2-hours worth (2 hours, 00:00:00 UTC
      to 02:00:00 UTC, etc) of data.
 
      Corrected Gamma Spectra
      -------------
        Corrected Gamma Spectra data are composed of corrected gamma
        spectra and the associated timing, spatial and engineering
        information. The CGS consists of the cumulative counts of
        gamma rays at the detector over one collection interval binned
        into 16384 channels based on energy. The collection interval
        is approximately 19.7 seconds, but may vary over the course of
        mapping. The counts in Channel 0 are all the counts that would
        have been shifted to 0 or less than 0 by the spectrum shifting
        algorithm. The counts in Channel 16383 are all the counts with
        energies greater than 10MeV, and counts in Channel 16382 are
        all the counts that belong in either 16382 or would have been
        shifted to 16383. The timing and spatial data provided with
        the spectra includes spacecraft clock values and spacecraft
        geometry data. The sc_ev_time, utc time and spatial fields are
        all recorded at the center of the collection interval.
 
 
    Ancillary Data
  	==============
      Ancillary data needed to understand the gamma data processing,
      can be found in the Mars Odyssey Gamma-ray Spectrometer Gamma
      Data Processing document located in the document folder that
      accompanies this release.
 
 
    Coordinate System
    =================
      The coordinate system used for all GRS data is a Mars
      aerocentric system following the IAU convention
      [SEIDELMANNETAL2002], with east longitudes from 0 to 360.
 
 
    Software
    ========
      A library of source code to parse the CGS data product files
      is included in the software directory. This library allows a
      programmer to build applications that display or manipulate
      CGS data. This source is written in the Java language, and
      requires version 1.3 of the Java Runtime Environment (JRE) or
      Java Software Development Kit (SDK).
 
      Documentation for the code is located in the software directory
      in the file GRS_DR_CODE_DOC.ZIP. The contents of this file are
      described in the label GRS_DR_CODE_DOC.LBL and the source and
      the binary classes that make up the library are in the file
      DR_CODE.JAR.
 
 
    Media/Format
    ============
      The CGS will be delivered using DVD media. Formats will be
      based on standards for such products established by the
      Planetary Data System (PDS) [PDSSR2001].
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Confidence Level Overview
    =========================
      The data presented in the CGS is intended to be the first
      intermediate data set released for the GRS. Data presented here
      are a highly processed representation of the GRS data as
      received from the spacecraft. It is possible that changes will
      be made in the processing and correction procedure if errors are
      found. If errors are found, the data will have to be regenerated
      from the raw unprocessed data set. The usefulness of this data
      is limited by a significant factor; the large volume of data
      with a small signal-to-noise ratio.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      The CGS was reviewed internally by the GRS team prior to
      release to the PDS. PDS will also perform an external review of
      the CGS.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
      Data reported are the processed gamma data received from the
      spacecraft during the mapping mission stage. Data coverage and
      quality are addressed in the following sections.
 
 
      Primary Mapping
      ---------------
      The Mapping portion of the mission began February 19, 2002, and
      is expected to last until August, 2004. Primary mapping is
      broken into two phases: stowed mapping and deployed mapping.
 
 
        Stowed Mapping
        --------------
          The stowed mapping configuration began on February 19, 2002
          and lasted until June 1, 2002. The stowed mapping
          configuration is with the Odyssey spacecraft in a mapping
          orbit, with the GRS in data collection configuration without
          the 6-meter boom deployed. The reason for data collection in
          the stowed configuration is to measure the background signal
          from the spacecraft.
 
          During the stowed mapping portion of the mission, two
          anneals were performed on the gamma detector.  The anneals
          were performed between March 8, 2002 to March 22, 2002 and
          May 6, 2002 to May 20, 2002. No science data was collected
          during these two periods. On June 1, 2002 the GRS was
          shutdown to prepare for boom deployment, which occurred on
          June 4, 2002. There may also be short periods of missing
          data due to missing telemetry that cannot be recovered.
 
 
        Deployed Mapping
        ----------------
          Deployed Mapping began on June 5, 2002 and is expected to
          continue until at least August, 2004.  Gamma data collected
          on June 19, 2002 is suspect due a number of temperature
          fluctuations in the gamma subsystem. Data collected from
          July 16, 2002 to July 24, 2002 are suspect due to a large
          solar particle event. There are short data gaps due to
          missing telemetry that cannot be recovered.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    The major limitation of this data set is that it is derived from
    the raw minimally processed data. The data is received from
    spacecraft telemetry, and ingested into a database. If gaps exist
    in the telemetry, data is lost. Timing and spatial components of
    the data set rely on the accuracy of the NAIF SPICE kernels. The
    validity of the corrected gamma spectra is based on the
    &apos;correctness&apos; of each step in the processing. It is possible that
    changes will be made in the processing and correction procedure if
    errors are found. If errors are found, the data will have to be
    regenerated from the raw unprocessed data set.
 
 
  Data Compression
  ================
    No compression is used on the CGS data set.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

