<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lro-l-mrflro-2-3-5-bistatic-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LRO MOON MINI-RF 2/3/5 BISTATIC RADAR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mrflro.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-mrflro-2-3-5-bistatic-v1.0__browserp_lro-l-mrflro-2-3-5-bistatic-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-mrflro-2-3-5-bistatic-v1.0__dvo_geo_lro-l-mrflro-2-3-5-bistatic-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-mrflro-2-3-5-bistatic-v1.0__pds.geo.lro.orbital_data_explorer::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Nozette, S., P. Spudis, B. Bussey, K. Raney, H. Winters, C.L. Lichtenberg, W.
                   Marinelli, J. Crusan, and M. Gates, The LRO Miniature Radio Frequency (Mini-RF)
                   technology demonstration, Space Sci. Rev., submitted, 2009.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.NOZETTEETAL2009</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LRO-L-MRFLRO-2/3/5-BISTATIC-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LRO MOON MINI-RF 2/3/5 BISTATIC RADAR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2013-09-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2009-07-19T12:27:42.7854Z</start_time>
        <stop_time nilReason="unknown" xsi:nil="true"></stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>MINI-RF POC</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            LRO Mini-RF Bistatic Data Set, LRO-L-MRFLRO-2/3/5-BISTATIC-V1.0,
            NASA Planetary Data System, 2012.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Bistatic data product and ancillary files from the LRO Mini-RF
            instrument
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains radar data of the lunar surface from
            bistatic measurements utilizing the Aricebo Observatory
            transmitter and LRO Mini-RF receiver.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Mini-RF Bistatic Data Archive is a time-ordered collection of SAR
      images collected by the Mini-RF instrument during the LRO mission to
      the Moon. These data are the result of bistatic radar measurements
      acquired using the Arecibo Radar Observatory as a transmitter and the
      Mini-RF instrument on NASA&apos;s Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter as a
      receiver. In this architecture, the Arecibo Observatory transmits a
      lefthand circular polarized (LHCP) signal at S-band wavelength that is
      reflected off the lunar surface and received by the Mini-RF antenna in
      orthogonal linear horizontal and vertical polarizations.
 
      This data set includes raw linear polarized data files, reduced data
      products (the four stokes parameters and the circular polarization
      ratio), a set of derived data products that provide geometry
      information, and a browse image.
 
    Parameters
    ==========
 
      Detailed descriptions of each file contained in this data archive are
      provided by the AAREADME.TXT and ERRATA.TXT files in this data
      directory and by original Mini-RF SIS documents, located in the
      LROMRF_XXXX/DOCUMENT directory.
 
    Processing
    ==========
      Level 0 EDRs are produced by Sandia National Laboratories using data
      returned by the mini-rf instrument in 3-bit format, along with
      spacecraft ephemeris and instrument timing information that
      characterize the acquired data. The EDRs are radiometrically and
      polarimetrically calibrated at the POC and used to create Level 1 RDRs
      of the Stokes parameters and circular polarization ratio. A full PDS
      label accompanies each EDR and RDR file and gives a detailed
      description of the content and format.
 
      Additional information on the processing of EDRs and RDRs can be found
      in the DOCUMENT directory of this volume.
 
    Data
    ====
      The level 0 EDRs are bistatic radar images in range and azimuth
      orientation. The range and azimuth resolution can vary on a
      collect-by-collect basis and are not always square. If non-square
      the range spacing is always larger than the azimuth spacing. An
      example of a typical range spacing is on the order of 40 meters,
      and a typical azimuth spacing can be on the order of 2 meters.
      Pixels are in floating point format and indicate image intensity
      values for the real and imaginary portions of the horizontal (H) and
      vertivcal (V) polarized received signal. The level 1 RDRs are
      calculated from these products and are resampled such that the data
      can be presented as 100 meter square pixels.
 
    Ancillary Data
    ==============
      Spacecraft ephemeris and instrument timing information are used by the
      POC to create a level 1 DDR file that includes pixel-to-pixel values
      for the latitude, longitude, bistatic angle, incidence angle, and
      emission angle in degress and the range to the surface in kilometers
      of the acquired data. A full PDS label accompanies each DDR file and
      gives a detailed description of the content and format. A browse image
      of the first Stokes parameter for bistatic collect is also included in
      the EXTRAS/QUICKVIEW directory.
 
    Calibration Data
    ================
      Information on the calibration of the bistatic data can be found in
      the DOCUMENT directory of this volume.
 
  Coordinate System
    =================
      Level 1 data products are not dependent on definition of a coordinate
      system. However, latitude and longitude information is provided in the
      level 1 DDR files for each bistatic collect.
 
    Software
    ========
      No software is included with this archival data set.
 
    Media/Format
    ============
 
      These products are delivered on a hard drive or by ftp and not on a
      specific formatted medium.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
    Overview
    ========
      Data in this archive are collected from orbits around the Moon.
 
 
    Review
    ======
      This archival data set was reviewed by the LRO Mini-RF
      Team prior to submission to the Planetary Data System (PDS).
 
      Prior to creation of the final version of the archival data set, key
      elements of the archive were distributed for preliminary review.  These
      included electronic versions of example PDS labels, CATALOG files, and
      DOCUMENT files.  These materials were distributed to PDS personnel, the
      experiment investigator, and others, as appropriate.
 
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    =========================
    Data reported are the minimally processed data received from the
    spacecraft during five mission phases: Launch, Cruise,
    Lunar_Orbit_Acquisition, Commissioning, and Exploration_Mission.
    These mission phases are defined as:
 
    Phase Name         Start time               End time
                         Date (DOY)               Date (DOY)
    -----------------        ----------------         ----------------
    LAUNCH                   18 Jun 2009 (169)        18 Jun 2009 (169)
    CRUISE                   18 Jun 2009 (169)        23 Jun 2009 (174)
    LUNAR ORBIT ACQUISITION  23 Jun 2009 (174)        23 Jun 2009 (174)
    COMMISSIONING            23 Jun 2009 (174)        14 Sep 2009 (257)
    NOMINAL MISSION          15 Sep 2009 (258)        14 Sep 2010 (257)
    SCIENCE MISSION          15 Sep 2010 (258)        14 Sep 2012 (257)
    EXTENDED MISSION     15 Sep 2012 (258)      14 Sep 2014 (257)
 
    No Mini-RF data were collected during Launch, Cruise, or
    Lunar_Orbit_Acquisition phases. The Mini-RF collected data during each of
    the other two mission phases. During these planned operational periods,
    the Mini-RF functioned nominally and the data quality was good.
 
    A S-Band receive calibration test was conducted on 20 August, 2009.
    S-Band transmit calibration tests were conducted on 22-23 August, 2009.
    These calibrations permit the characterization of both transmit
    polarization purity as well as determining how precisely polarization can
    be measured by the instrument.
 
    Communications demonstration.  Mini-RF experiments to demonstrate
    half-duplex communications were conducted on 16 August and
    20 August, 2009.
 
    The Mini-RF began collecting data over the lunar south polar region
    13 July 2009 to support LCROSS targeting by characterizing the surfaces
    of permanently shadowed regions.  This data collection phase continued
    until the LCROSS impact on 9 October. 2009.
 
    From Oct 14 through Dec. 17, Mini-RF was largely restricted to collecting
    data over non-polar sites that lie equatorward of 63 degrees latitude
    North and South.
 
    Since 26 December 2010, the Mini-RF instrument has not transmitted the RF
    energy required to create radar images of the lunar surface. The Mini-RF
    team looked at the initial 13 collects attempted from that date forward
    and noted that in all but one collect the data appeared bad, looking like
    noise. The team continued to attempt data collections at a reduced rate
    (about 1 collect per day) through January 23, 2011. Products included in
    this data set made from data collected after 26 December 2010 do not
    contain scientifically useful data.
 
    On April 6, 2011 a successful attempt to acquire bistatic radar data
    of the lunar surface using the Arecibo Radar Observatory as a
    transmitter and the Mini-RF instrument on NASA&apos;s Lunar Reconnaissance
    Orbiter as a receiver was conducted. For this attempt a transmit power
    of 35 watts was used. Subsequent to that acquisition, a transmit power
    of 200 kilowatts has been used.
 
    Limitations
    ===========
    This data set includes multiple strips of raw, reduced, and derived
    data. The source data strips are received from the spacecraft
    telemetry, ingested into the LRO Missions Operations Center (MOC) and
    then transferred to the APL Payload Operations Center (POC).
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

