<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.clem1-l-e-y-a-b-u-h-l-n-2-edr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CLEM1-LUN/EAR/SKY-ASTAR/BSTAR/UVVIS/HRES/LWIR/NIR-2-EDR-V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.deep_space_program_science_experiment::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.clem1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:a-star.clem1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:b-star.clem1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:hires.clem1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:lwir.clem1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:nir.clem1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:uvvis.clem1::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.sky::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-e-y-a-b-u-h-l-n-2-edr-v1.0__browserc_clem1-l-e-y-a-b-u-h-l-n-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-e-y-a-b-u-h-l-n-2-edr-v1.0__browserp_clem1-l-e-y-a-b-u-h-l-n-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.clem1-l-e-y-a-b-u-h-l-n-2-edr-v1.0__dvo_imaging_clem1-l-e-y-a-b-u-h-l-n-2-edr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.imaging::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Acton, Jr. C.H., Ancillary Data Services of NASA&apos;s Navigation and Ancillary
                   Information Facility, Planetary and Space Sciences, 44, Number 1, pp. 65-70,
                   1996.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ACTON1996</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Eliason, E.M., E.R. Malaret, and G. Woodward, Clementine Mission: The
                   Archive of Image Data Products and Data Processing Capabilities,
                   (Abstract), Proceedings of the 26-th Lunar and Planetary Conference, in
                   press, pp. 369-370, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.ELIASONETAL1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Gaddis, L., A. McEwen, and M. Robinson, The Distribution of Localized Lunar
                   Pyroclastic Deposits as Related to Crustal Thickness, Proceedings of the
                   26-th Lunar and Planetary Conference, in press, p. 433, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.GADDISETAL1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   McEwen, A.S., and E.M. Shoemaker, Two Classes of Impact Basins on the Moon,
                   Proceedings of the 26-th Lunar and Planetary Conference, in press, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MCEWEN-SHOEMAKER1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   McEwen, A.S., M.S. Robinson, T.C. Duxbury, and B.J.Buratti, Global Albedo
                   Variations on the Moon: Clementine 750-NM Observations, Proceedings of the
                   26-th Lunar and Planetary Conference, in press, pp. 931-932, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MCEWENETAL1995A</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   McEwen, A.S., T. Becker, A. Bennett, J. Bowell, K. Edwards, E. Eliason, L.
                   Gaddis, C. Isbell, A. Howington- Kraus, R. Kirk, E. Lee, H. Morgan, and M.
                   Robinson, New Digital Images on the Moon, Proceedings of the 26-th Lunar
                   and Planetary Conference, in press, p. 929, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MCEWENETAL1995B</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   McEwen, A.S., M.S.Robinson, E.M. Eliason, P.G. Lucey, B.R. Hawke, and T.C.
                   Duxbury, Clementine and Groundbased Observations of the Aristarchus Region
                   of the Moon, Proceedings of the 26-th Lunar and Planetary Conference, in
                   press, p. 933, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.MCEWENETAL1995C</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Shoemaker, E., and M.S. Robinson, Clementine Observations of Melt Rocks and
                   Volcanic Materials in the Schrodinger Basin, Proceedings of the 26-th Lunar
                   and Planetary Conference, in press, pp. 1297-1298, 1995.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SHOEMAKER-ROBINS1995</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CLEM1-L/E/Y-A/B/U/H/L/N-2-EDR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CLEM1-LUN/EAR/SKY-ASTAR/BSTAR/UVVIS/HRES/LWIR/NIR-2-EDR-V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1995</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1994</start_time>
        <stop_time>1994</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>NAVAL RESEARCH LABORATORY</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Clementine Imaging (UVVIS, HIRES, NIR, LWIR) Lunar Experiment
            Data Records
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Clementine EDR (Engineering Data Record) Image Archive
            contains 88 CD-ROM volumes with more than 1.9 million images.
            Each volume contains approximately 3 lunar orbits but may vary in
            the number of orbits depending on the size of each orbit. The
            first volume in the set begins with orbit number 32--the start of
            the systematic lunar mapping phase of the mission. The image data
            products for the engineering checkout and operational rehearsal
            orbits (orbits 1-31), low Earth orbits, and earth phasing loop
            orbits are located on the last eight volumes at the end of the
            volume set.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
    Data Set Overview
    =================
      The Clementine EDR (Engineering Data Record) Image Archive
      contains 88 CD-ROM volumes with more than 1.9 million images.
      Each volume contains approximately 3 lunar orbits but may vary
      in the number of orbits depending on the size of each orbit.
      The first volume in the set begins with orbit number 32--the
      start of the systematic lunar mapping phase of the mission.
      The image data products for the engineering checkout and
      operational rehearsal orbits (orbits 1-31), low Earth orbits,
      and earth phasing loop orbits are located on the last eight
      volumes at the end of the volume set.  Table 1 shows the
      contents of the CD-ROM volume set.
 
 
      Table 1 - Volumes/Mission Phase
      -------------------------------
      CL_0001 through CL_0036 - Lunar Mapping/Systematic Mapping
                                Cycle 1 (orbits 32-164)
      CL_0037 through CL_0070 - Lunar Mapping/Systematic Mapping
                                Cycle 2 (orbits 165-300)
      CL_0070 through CL_0081 - Lunar Mapping/Post-Systematic
                                Mapping (orbits 301-348)
      CL_0081 through CL_0085 - Lunar Mapping/Engineering Checkout
                                (orbits 1-30)
      CL_0085                 - Low Earth Orbit
      CL_0086 through CL_0088 - Earth Phasing Loop A
      CL_0088                 - Earth Phasing Loop B
 
      In addition to the image data, the CD-ROM volumes contain
      documentation, software, timeline data, and index files that
      support the collection.  The &apos;aareadme.txt&apos; file found in the
      root directory of each volume provides the user with overview
      information about the data volumes.  The&apos;document&apos; directory
      contains detailed documentation about the CD-ROM contents,
      image file formats, software, and CD-ROM directory structure.
      The &apos;errata.txt&apos; file found in the root directory of each
      volume provides the user with information about problems and
      anomalies encountered with the data set during the production
      of the CD-ROM volumes.  Volume CL_0088, the last volume in the
      set, contains the most up-to-date software and documentation.
 
      The Clementine spacecraft imaged 100% of the lunar surface at
      resolutions that ranged from 100 meters/pixel at periselene (28
      degrees south latitude for observations during the first month
      and 28 degrees north latitude for the second month) to 400
      meters/pixel at the poles.  Along the orbital track there is
      approximately 15% overlap in image coverage between adjacent
      images of the same spectral band.  Across track overlap is
      approximately 10% at the equator and increases towards the
      poles.
 
      The primary scientific objective of the Clementine imaging
      observations was to provide data for lunar mineral mapping
      investigations.  Imaging was acquired in 12 spectral bands from
      415 to 8750 nm.  Pole-to-Pole NAIDR observations with solar
      phase angles kept to less than 30 degrees at mid-latitudes were
      the predominant viewing conditions during the two month
      systematic mapping phase of the mission.
 
 
    Data
    ====
      Each Clementine EDR data file consists of a single camera
      observation.  The image data have been depacketized and
      reformatted with standard PDS labels but are otherwise raw.
      Raw data contain the geometric and radiometric characteristics
      of unprocessed and unrectified data.  To make full use of the
      data, it is necessary to perform radiometric and geometric
      processing on the data products.
 
      The imaging sensors are framing cameras using charge couple
      device (CCD) technology.  The Star tracker cameras (A-STAR and
      B-STAR) were principally used for spacecraft orientation.  The
      UVVIS, HIRES, and NIR cameras have filter wheels that allow
      images to be acquired under six spectral filters.  The LWIR
      camera has a single spectral filter.  Table 2 shows the pixel
      dimensions of the images acquired by each camera and the center
      wavelength of each filter wheel position.  Other than the image
      dimensions, the data products of each camera are identically
      formatted.
 
      Table 2 - Characteristics of each camera showing the dimension
      of an image in lines (rows) and samples (columns), the number
      of filter wheel positions, and the center wavelength of each
      filter.
 
      Camera/Lines/Samples/# of filt/filt.Wavelengths(Nanometers)
      -----------------------------------------------------------
 
      UVVIS   288   384  6   415,750,900,950,1000,650(broadband)
      HIRES   288   384  6   415,560,650,750,650(broadband), opaque
      NIR     256   256  6   1100,1250,1500,2000,2600,2780
      LWIR    128   128  1   8750
      A-STAR  576   384  N/A (broad band, no filter wheel)
      B-STAR  576   384  N/A (broad band, no filter wheel)
 
 
      Data Compression
      ----------------
        Data compression was done onboard using a compression chip
        provided by Centre National Etudes Spatiales (CNES).  Onboard
        processing was performed on a completed image prior to
        storage on the solid state data recorder (SSDR) when the
        appropriate compression flag was set.  The image data are
        stored on the CD-ROM volumes in the original compressed form
        as sent down by the spacecraft.  In order to decompress an
        image, it is necessary to run the decompression software
        found on the CD-ROM volumes.
 
        The compression chip developed by MATRA under CNES
        specifications is used in two modes, which could be selected
        via a software uplink command.  The first mode involved a
        discrete cosine transformation (DCT), (named Clem-JPEG-1),
        and optimized root mean square error for a nominal
        compression.  The second (called Clem-JPEG-2) provided visual
        optimization at a fixed compression rate.  In the first mode,
        blocks of 8x8 pixel 8-bit data are transformed to a best fit
        cosine series expansion in orthogonal row and column
        directions.  This algorithm tends to preserve high frequency
        information with less data loss than does JPEG at the same
        compression ratio for the lunar data.  Total signal from the
        8x8 block is preserved exactly.  The nominal amount of
        compression was set by limiting the scene error induced by
        compression to a fraction of the camera&apos;s temporal noises.
        Analysis of lunar images during the first part of the mission
        showed that the quantization matrix used by the chip was
        optimum for the imaging cameras.
 
        The HIRES camera was operated in a modified JPEG mode.  The
        high frequency information in the HIRES scenes was spurious
        (it was caused by gain non-uniformity of the intensifier
        tube); eliminating high frequency content allowed higher
        compression without harming the information content of the
        scenes.
 
        The average compression rate for all images obtained during
        the mission was 5.5.
 
 
    Processing
    ==========
 
      Raw Clementine Images
      ---------------------
        The primary data archived is the collection of raw planetary
        images acquired by the Clementine mission.  These data are
        pristine in the sense that they contain the artifacts and the
        radiometric and geometric characteristics of unprocessed and
        uncorrected data.  The only processing performed on the data
        is to organize and format the data according to PDS
        standards.
 
 
      Requantization Matrices for Data Decompression
      ----------------------------------------------
        The requantization matrix for the DCT compression algorithm
        is modified throughout the course of a mapping cycle as the
        viewing conditions and science requirements change.  The
        requantization matrix used for an image is carried as part of
        the image object within a compressed image file.
 
 
      Browse Images
      -------------
        A set of browse images is provided as part of the archive to
        facilitate rapid viewing of the image collection.  Browse
        images can be used to visually search for areas of interest.
        If a browse image shows a potentially interesting scene, the
        image can be decompressed for more detailed inspection.
        Browse images are not in a compressed format, but they are
        reduced in size by averaging 8x8 pixel neighborhoods of the
        original image.  The average is stored as a single pixel in
        the browse image.  A browse image is stored in a secondary
        object in the image file.
 
 
      Histograms
      ----------
        The histogram object is made up of a 256 element array with
        each element stored as a 32-bit unsigned integer.  Each
        element in the histogram object contains the count of the
        number of pixels in the image array that corresponds to a
        specific density number (DN) value.  The first element of the
        histogram is the number of pixels in the image array that
        have a DN value of 0.  The second element contains the count
        of pixels with DN value 1, the sequence thus proceeding to
        the 256-th element which contains a count of the number of
        pixels with a DN value of 255.
 
        Inconsistencies may exist between the histogram statistics
        found in the image histogram object and the actual image that
        is decompressed on your computer platform.  Subtle
        differences in the floating point hardware among computer
        platforms may cause the Density Number (DN) values of a
        resulting decompressed image to be occasionally different
        (within 1 DN) than the decompressed image used to generate
        the image histogram object.
 
 
    Ancillary Data and Information
    ==============================
 
      Documentation
      -------------
        Each volume contains detailed information about the
        organization and contents of the Clementine EDR CD-ROM volume
        set.  The documentation for the collection is found in the
        &apos;document&apos; directory.  Although each volume contains a
        &apos;document&apos; directory, use the documents found on the last
        volume (volume CL_0088) especially to obtain the most
        up-to-date version of the errata.txt file.
 
 
      Software
      --------
        Each volume contains decompression software and simple image
        display programs for MAC, PCDOS or SUNOS platforms.  Although
        each volume contains a &apos;software&apos; directory, use the software
        found on the last volume (volume CL_0088) to obtain the most
        up-to-date version of the software.
 
 
      Image Index
      -----------
        Each volume contains an image index file that describes the
        properties of each image found on the volume.  The image
        index file is an
 
        ASCII formatted table where each row in the table corresponds
        to an image and each column corresponds to an image
        attribute.  The attributes associated with an image include
        the center latitude and longitude, camera state at the time
        of the observation, spacecraft position, viewing angles, and
        photometric parameters.  The image index file is located in
        the &apos;index&apos; directory of each volume.  For more information
        on the image index file, refer to the documentation found in
        this directory.
 
        An updated Image Index of the entire Clementine EDR volume
        set was generated by Clementine Mission Operations after
        completion of the volume set.  The update contains
        refinements in the SPICE kernel data providing improvements
        in the viewing geometry information found in the table.
        Contact the PDS Imaging Node for the most up-to-date Image
        Index information.
 
        A CD-ROM volume may contain a table of missing images which
        lists planned image observations that are not available on
        the Clementine EDR volume set.  An image is missing when (1)
        the planned observation was never acquired due to a
        spacecraft malfunction, (2) an interruption or error occurred
        during the telemetry transmission of data to Earth, or (3)
        data were lost due to problems in the ground processing
        system.
 
 
      Orbit Timeline
      --------------
        Each volume contains a &apos;timeline&apos; directory housing the
        timeline files for each orbit on the volume.  The timeline
        data describes the planned and unplanned events that occurred
        during an orbit.  The data, organized in chronological order,
        are formatted as Microsoft EXCEL (PC Version 5.0) spreadsheet
        files.
 
 
      Geometric Data
      --------------
        The geometric data are an essential part of the archive; they
        contain the data and information to characterize the
        geometric properties of the imaging systems, and to fully
        describe the viewing geometry of a scene.  These data are
        essential to geodetic, cartographic, and photometric
        applications.
 
        The geometric data are provided in NASA&apos;s SPICE kernel
        formats designed by the Navigational and Ancillary
        Information Facility (NAIF) at the Jet Propulsion Laboratory.
        SPICE is an acronym for Spacecraft, Planet, Instrument,
        C-matrix, and Event kernels.
 
        SPICE kernels evolve and improve as further analysis is done.
        Improvements could include correcting not-yet-discovered
        errors and filling in missing items.  For the most up-to-date
        and accurate SPICE information available for the Clementine
        mission please contact the Planetary Data System NAIF Node.
 
        The geometric data found in the PDS data labels and image
        index files are based on the SPICE information available at
        the time of product creation.  Although the geometric data
        found on the CD-ROM volumes are satisfactory for search and
        retrieval methods and locating images on the Lunar surface,
        they are not the most up-to-date data available and thus
        should not be used for precision data processing purposes.
 
        Data reviewers have reported confusion about several
        parameters that describe geometric information about the
        observations.  The SUB_SPACECRAFT_LATITUDE,
        SUB_SPACECRAFT_LONGITUDE, SPACECRAFT_ALTITUDE, and
        SUB_SPACECRAFT_AZIMUTH parameters, found in the image index
        file (IMGINDX.TAB) and the image file labels, are referenced
        with respect to the central body which the spacecraft is
        orbiting, not necessarily the target of the observation.
        During the lunar mapping phase of the mission, the central
        body is the Moon.  Thus, if the target is the Earth, the
        above listed parameters are referenced with respect to the
        Moon and not Earth.
 
 
      Coordinate System
      -----------------
        J2000 (also called EME2000) is the inertial reference system
        used to specify observational geometry.  Latitude and
        longitude coordinates of target are planetocentric.
 
        For a complete description of the coordinate system used for
        the Clementine EDR data set, refer to [ACTON1996].
 
 
      Media Format
      ------------
        The disk has been formatted so that a variety of computer
        systems (e.g.  IBM/PC compatible, Macintosh, Sun) may access
        the data.  Specifically, it is formatted according to the ISO
        9660 level 1 Interchange Standard.  For further information,
        refer to the ISO 9660 Standard Document: Reference Number ISO
        9660-1988, 15 April 1988.  The extended attribute records
        (XAR) supported by the ISO are not used in this volume set.
        The lack of XARs on a file only affects the VAX/VMS user
        community.  It will be necessary for VAX/VMS users to use the
        VMS CONVERT utility to convert document and text files before
        they can be satisfactorily accessed.  VAX/VMS users can
        contact the PDS Imaging Node for support of the Clementine
        EDR archive.
 
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
 
      Review/Validation Process
      -------------------------
      Each CD-ROM volume went through a volume review and validation
      process.  Although the volumes were carefully checked for errors
      and anomalies, problems with the data set not yet discovered may
      exist in the data collection.  Please report any newly
      discovered problems to the PDS Imaging Node.  Errors and
      anomalies found in the data collection are reported in the
      ERRATA.TXT file found in root directory of each volume.  The
      ERRATA.TXT file found on the last volume (volume 88) contains a
      complete list of problems found in the volume set.
 
 
      Data Quality
      ------------
      The DATA_QUALITY_NAME element provides a measure of the quality
      of an observation. For Clementine imaging data,
      DATA_QUALITY_NAME and DATA_QUALITY_ID are analogous.
 
      NOTE:  The data quality indicators are only available through
      the on-line Clementine Navigator system and are not documented
      on the CD-ROM archive.
 
      The standard values for DATA_QUALITY_NAME are:
 
      NOMINAL IMAGE QUALITY (DATA_QUALITY_ID 1)
      The statistics of the image is sufficient for properly
      characterizing the brightness variations of a scene. Less than
      5% of the image contains saturated values and the standard
      deviation of the density values of the image is greater than
      4.0.
 
      UNDEREXPOSED OR DARK-SIDE IMAGE (DATA_QUALITY_ID 2)
      The integration time (exposure time) of the image is
      insufficient for properly characterizing the brightness
      variations of a scene or the image was acquired on the Dark Side
      of the Moon. The standard deviation of the density values of the
      image is less than 4.0. Images with data quality id 2 may not be
      suitable for proper characterization of the target.
 
      MODERATE IMAGE SATURATION (DATA_QUALITY_ID 3)
      The image contains a moderate amount of saturated data. The
      brightness variations within the brightest parts of an image
      can not be properly characterized. The image contains greater
      than 5% saturated data. The integration time (exposure time) of
      the image was too long for the brightest areas of the scene to
      be properly recorded.
 
      SEVERE IMAGE SATURATION (DATA_QUALITY_ID 4)
      The image contains greater than 25% saturated data. The
      integration time (exposure time) of the image was too long for
      the brightness of the scene. Additionally, it is possible that
      the operating mode of the camera was improperly set.
 
      EMPTY IMAGE (DATA_QUALITY_ID 5)
      The LIDAR HIRES camera was acquiring altimetry observations but
      no simultaneous image observation was made. The camera was
      intentionally programmed to not record imaging data. In order
      to operate the LIDAR ranging, the hardware of the HIRES camera
      needed to remain active even though no image data were acquired.
      Most of the LIDAR HIRES imaging data at the mid-latitudes have
      DATA_QUALITY_ID=5. The Clementine engineers were concerned that
      continued operation of the HIRES camera would cause
      deteriorating performance. With the intent of preserving the
      HIRES camera for the Geographos asteroid encounter, the imaging
      was &apos;turned off&apos; for most of the mid-latitude lunar
      observations.  The empty images are stored in the archive for
      the sake of preserving all data from the mission. Perhaps the
      only useful information in an &apos;empty&apos; image is the measure of
      the camera dark current drift.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-ROM</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>94-004A-00D</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

