<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ear-l-mmto_clio-3-cdr-lcross-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>MMT OBSERVATORY 6.5M CLIO CALIBRATED OBSERVATIONS OF LCROSS</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_crater_observation_and_sensing_satellite::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:earth-based.mmto::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:clio.mmto::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.bias::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.flat_field::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:calibration.sky::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:star.hd_22859::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:star.hd_28099::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:star.hd_43607::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-l-mmto_clio-3-cdr-lcross-v1.0__geo_lcross_analysts_notebook::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-l-mmto_clio-3-cdr-lcross-v1.0__geo_lcross_mmto_clio-3-cdr_ftp_resource::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-l-mmto_clio-3-cdr-lcross-v1.0__pds.geo.lcross.webservices::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Farnham, T.L., D.G. Schleicher, and M.F. A&apos;Hearn, The HB Narrowband Comet
                   Filters: Standard Stars and Calibrations, Icarus, 147(1), 180-204, 2000,
                   doi:10.1006/icar.2000.6420.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FARNHAMETAL2000</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Freed, M., P.M. Hinz, M.R. Meyer, N.M. Milton, and M. Lloyd-Hart, Clio: A 5
                   micron camera for the detection of giant exoplanets. Ground-Based
                   Instrumentation for Astronomy, Proc. SPIE 5492, 1561-1571, 2004.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FREEDETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hardorp, J. A. The sun among the stars. I. A search for solar spectral analogs.
                   Astron. Astrophys. 63, 383-390, 1978.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HARDORP1978</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Hastie, M., V. Bailey, P. Hinz, S. Callahan, V. Vaitheeswaran, D. Gibson, D.
                   Porter, F. Vilas, LCROSS Impact Observations from the MMT Observatory. LPSC
                   XXXXI, #2501, 2010.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.HASTIEETAL2010</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Kenworthy, M.A., and P.M. Hinz, Calibration and Correction of Amplifier Induced
                   Artifacts in an InSb Infrared Array, MMT Technical Memoramdum MT-10-1,
                   http://www.mmto.org/MMTpapers/pdfs/tm/tm10-1.pdf, 2010.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.KENWORTHY-HINZ2010</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>EAR-L-MMTO_CLIO-3-CDR-LCROSS-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>MMT OBSERVATORY 6.5M CLIO CALIBRATED OBSERVATIONS OF LCROSS</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2010-02-05</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2009-10-09T07:39:03Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2009-10-09T12:57:39Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>FAITH VILAS</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Vilas, F., MMT Observatory 6.5m CLIO Calibrated Observations of
            LCROSS, NASA Planetary Data System,
            EAR-L-MMTO_CLIO-3-CDR-LCROSS-V1.0, 2010.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This archive contains calibrated observations of the 2009-10-09
            impact of the LCROSS spacecraft on the moon by the CLIO
            instrument on the MMT Observatory 6.5m telescope.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This archive contains calibrated observations of the 2009-10-09
            impact of the LCROSS spacecraft on the moon by the CLIO
            instrument on the MMT Observatory 6.5m telescope. The archive
            consists of calibrated FITS images of the event. This is one of
            several data sets of Earth-based observations of the impact.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The LRO/LCROSS spacecraft was launched on June 18, 2009, and crashed into
    the Cabeus crater near the Moon&apos;s south pole on October 9, 2009. The spent
    upper stage, called the Centaur, impacted the moon at 11:31:19.51 UTC
    at -84.68 deg latitude, -48.69 deg longitude, Mean Earth frame, and the
    LCROSS shepherding spacecraft impacted the surface at 11:35:34 UTC.
 
    This data set includes the observations made on UT October 9, 2009, of
    the Moon and ancillary supporting data during the LCROSS observations at
    the MMTO 6.5-meter telescope with the Clio imager and spectrograph.
 
    These data are the observations with the bias counts removed, and
    corrected for differences in gain among the four amplifiers used to read
    out the data on the array.
 
    The Clio camera is designed for use with the MMTO 6.5-meter telescope
    and the f/15 adaptive secondary AO system.  It incorporates an InSb 9809
    ROIC 256 x 320 array of 30-micron pixels. These pixels were not binned
    during the LCROSS observations.  The detector reads out using 4
    amplifiers, providing a readout rate of 400 kHz.  Readout noise is ~
    350e-.  The camera has a 12 arcsecond x 16 arcsecond field of view.  The
    camera used L&apos; filter imaging to place the 10 arcsecond slit on the
    lunar surface, and a low-resolution direct vision prism with the 10
    arcsecond slit to produce spectra from ~ 2.5 - 4.5 microns.  Due to the
    optical nature of the prism, the resolving power is not linear with
    respect to wavelength, thus resolution will vary with wavelength.  The
    camera is cryogenically cooled.
 
    Further descriptions of Clio can be found in Freed et al. (2004).
    Description of the corrections for amplifier gain differences can be
    found in Kenworthy and Hinz (2009).
 
    The observations were obtained at the MMT 6.5-meter telescope on Mt.
    Hopkins in Arizona.  The facility is owned and operated jointly by the
    Smithsonian Astrophysical Observatory and the University of Arizona.
    This is an altitude-azimuth telescope.  Adaptive optics designed and
    developed for the MMT incorporate an adaptive secondary mirror with
    incoming focal ratio of f/15.  During the LCROSS observations, the f/15
    adaptive optics secondary was used with the MMT natural guide star top
    box and the Clio imager and coronagraph.  Inside the top box, a
    beamsplitter divides the incoming light into visible and infrared
    components, routing light of wavelength &gt; 1.1 micron to the Clio imager.
    The Clio camera was attached externally to the top box to receive the
    near-infrared light (higher wavelength range) signal from the
    beamsplitter.  These observations were taken concurrently with the
    visible observations taken using the CCD47 camera.  The visible
    observations taken using the CCD47 are described in the DATASET.CAT file
    for the data set EAR-L-MMTO_CCD47-2-EDR-LCROSS-V1.0.
 
    Observing conditions were photometric with seeing measured by wavefront
    sensor to be 0.38 arcseconds.
 
    The night of the LCROSS impact event was the only night we were able to
    take preparatory observations (other practice time allocated for
    observations was lost to bad weather).
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
 
    These data have been processed to remove a &apos;bias&apos; frame and to correct
    for nonuniformities among the four Clio readout ampifiers.   Starting
    with a raw Clio multi-extension fits file, the first step is to subtract
    a &apos;bias&apos; frame to each fits extension. Clio is not capable of taking a
    zero second exposure.   M. Kenworthy manufactured a bias frame
    (extrapolating backwards from a short exposure) that is included in the
    calibration directory (CLIO_bias_0msec.fits).   This is described in
    detail in Kenworthy and Hinz (2010).  The bias frame needs to be
    horizontally inverted in order to match the target frames, due to the
    way the array is read out.
 
    The bias-subtracted frame then needs to be corrected for variations in
    the gain settings of the four Clio readout amplifiers. The four
    amplifiers are interleaved on a column-by-column basis such as A, B, C,
    D, A, B, C, D etc.   Corrections are done on a pixel-by-pixel basis
    using a lookup table (clio_lookup_091007.dat) calculated by M. Kenworthy
    (Kenworthy and Hinz, 2010).  Before applying the lookup table, zero and
    maximum value (65000 ADU) clipping of the pixel values should be done to
    facilitate proper results from the lookup table.
 
    The bias subtraction and gain correction is carried out on all frames
    including target, sky, calibration, and standard stars.
 
    Extraction of the spectra can then be executed however the astronomer
    wishes.
 
  Data
  ====
    The sequence of observations includes images of the Moon taken before
    the impact occurred using the L&apos; filter, 2-D spectra taken covering a
    spectral interval of ~ 2.5 - 4.5 microns of the Cabeus crater,
    observations of two A0 stars (HD22859, HD43607) used for wavelength
    calibration (http://irtfweb.ifa.hawaii.edu/), observations of solar
    analogue star HD28099 (Hya 64: e.g., Farnham et al., 2000; Hardorp,
    1978) for data analysis of the lunar reflectance spectra, and images of
    the slit on the Clio chip.  For observations of standard stars, the AO
    system was used.
 
    About 0.33 hr prior to the LCROSS impact, the AO secondary system was
    triggered on a bright star near the Moon; the secondary mirror was
    frozen in corrected figure to remove gross aberrations caused by the
    atmospheric fluctuations; and the telescope was then pointed on the
    Cabeus crater target area.  Observations covered a time range of 8
    minutes before the first impact to 36 minutes after the second impact
    when twilight stopped observations.
 
    Spectra were taken of the Cabeus crater of the Moon where the impact was
    predicted to occur.  The impact observations did not show any
    discernible effect from the impact.  Quick-and-dirty spectral ratioing
    immediately following the event did not show any signature of the event.
    Based upon the observed brightness of the impact by the LCROSS
    shepherding satellite, we expect that we would have been able to see the
    event had we not had unshadowed, illuminated portions of the lunar
    surface in the same field of view.  The observations are described in
    Hastie et al. (2010).
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    All data are stored in FITS format.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Review
  ======
    This data set has been subjected to peer review according to Planetary
    Data System standards.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>LOCALLY_ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

