<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ody-m-grs-4-dnd-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 4 DND V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.2001_mars_odyssey::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.ody::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:grs.ody::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.mars::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-grs-4-dnd-v1.0__browserp_geo_ody-m-grs-4-dnd-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-grs-4-dnd-v1.0__dvo_geo_ody-m-grs-4-dnd-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ody-m-grs-4-dnd-v1.0__pds.ua.grs_web_site::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Boynton, W. V., W. C. Feldman, I. Mitrofanov, L. G. Evans, R. C. Reedy, S.
                   W. Squyres, R. Starr, I. Trombka, C. d&apos;Uston, J. R. Arnold, P. A. J.
                   Englert, A. E. Metzger, H. Wanke, J. Bruckner, D. M. Drake, C. Shinohara,
                   C. Fellows, D. K. Hamara, K. Harshman, The Mars Odyssey gamma-ray
                   spectrometer instrument suite, Space Sci. Rev., Accepted for publication,
                   2003.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BOYNTONETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Feldman, W.C., T.H. Prettyman, R. L. Tokar, W.V. Boynton, R. C. Byrd, K.R.
                   Fuller, O. Gasnault, J.L. Longmire, R.H. Olsher, S.A. Storms, and G.W.
                   Thornton, Fast neutron flux spectrum aboard Mars Odyssey during cruise, J.
                   Geophys. Res. - Space Physics, v. 107(#A6) p. 1083, 2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.FELDMANETAL2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Planetary Data System Standards Reference, JPL Document D-7669, Part 2, Jet
                   Propulsion Laboratory, Pasadena, CA, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PDSSR2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Prettyman, T.H., W.C. Feldman, F.P. Ameduri, B.L. Barraclough, E.W. Cascio,
                   K.R. Fuller, H.O. Funsten, D.J. Lawrence, G.W. McKinney, C.T. Russell, S.A.
                   Soldner, S.A. Storms, C. Szeles, and R.L. Tokar, Gamma-ray and neutron
                   spectrometer for the Dawn mission to 1 Ceres and 4 Vesta, IEEE Trans. Nucl.
                   Sci., Volume 50, Issue 4, pp. 1190-1197, August 2003, DOI
                   10.1109/TNS.2003.815156
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.PRETTYMANETAL2003</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Seidelmann, P.K., V.K. Abalakin, M. Bursa, M.E. Davies, C. de Bergh, J.H.
                   Lieske, J. Oberst, J.L. Simon, E.M. Standish, P. Stooke, and P.C. Thomas,
                   Report of the IAU/IAG working group on cartographic coordinates and rotational
                   elements of the planets and satellites: 2000, Celestial Mechanics and Dynamical
                   Astronomy, 82, 83-111, 2002.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SEIDELMANNETAL2002</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>ODY-M-GRS-4-DND-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 4 DND V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2003-07-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2002-02-19T00:00:00.000Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2003-01-01T00:00:00.000Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>WILLIAM BOYNTON</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Boynton, W.V., Mars 2001 Odyssey Gamma Ray Spectrometer Derived
            Neutron Data V1.0, ODY-M-GRS-4-DND-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data
            System, 2003.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The Mars Odyssey Gamma Ray Spectrometer (GRS) Derived Neutron
            Data (DND) archive contains data derived from Neutron
            Spectrometer (NS) experiment data records (EDRs).
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The Odyssey GRS Derived Neutron Data (DND) data set includes
            prism counting rates, normalizations, corrections, and thermal,
            epithermal, and fast neutron counting rates derived from neutron
            data collected by the Neutron Spectrometer of the Odyssey GRS
            instrument suite.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The Mars Odyssey Gamma-Ray Spectrometer (GRS) is a suite of
    three instruments working together to collect data that will
    permit the mapping of elemental concentrations on the surface
    of Mars. The suite of three instruments, the gamma sensor head
    (GS), the neutron spectrometer (NS) and the high-energy neutron
    detector (HEND), are a complementary set of instruments in that
    the neutron instruments have better counting statistics and
    sample to a greater depth than the GS, but the GS determines
    the abundance of many more elements. A full description of the
    Mars Odyssey Gamma-Ray Spectrometer instrument can be found in
    [BOYNTONETAL2003].
 
    The ODY MARS GAMMA RAY SPECTROMETER 4 DND data set is a time
    series collection of derived neutron data (DND) measurements
    from the NS sub-system of the Mars Odyssey Gamma-Ray
    Spectrometer. The DND are an intermediate data product. These
    data are the neutron data that must be derived from the raw
    Level-0 data before a set of calculations can be run that will
    result in thermal, epithermal, and fast neutron fluxes.
 
    The GRS collects a new spectrum (pixel) approximately every 20
    seconds, 360 times per orbit. Approximately 4200 neutron
    measurements are expected to be received every day. The data
    are downloaded from the spacecraft by the Jet Propulsion
    Laboratory (JPL) into the Telemetry Data System (TDS). The TDS
    sends data to a process that translates data packets and
    examines instrument health via messages. Data are output to a
    spooler that passes it to the University of Arizona (UA)
    database ingest process. The ingest process inputs raw data
    into the UA database. Neutron data are processed through a
    number of programs to yield the derived neutron data. The
    derived neutron data are retrieved from the UA database to
    build the DND data.
 
    The DND product is intended to be the first intermediate data
    product available for the NS portion of the GRS data. These data
    should be useful to those scientists who are experienced in
    neutron spectroscopy.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
    The DND data set is composed of a single data type (DND). The
    objective of compiling the DND is to create a series of neutron
    data that have been processed to yield the intermediate results
    necessary for final processing. Each DND product data file will
    contain a time series of neutron data collected over a 24-hour
    time period. The data files are labeled as Earth days. Each DND
    data file is a table containing 63 columns, with one row of data
    for each approximately 19.7 second collection interval.
 
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The product of our data reduction algorithms is a time-series
    data set, corrected for variations in the instrument response
    and the cosmic ray background, that can be used to produce
    thermal, epithermal, and fast neutron global maps of Mars
    binned on coarse or fine time intervals (as short as two weeks
    for high latitude studies).  An overview of these algorithms is
    provided here. References to the DND or EDR column names are in
    capitals, and a lower case x in the name refers to either prism
    1,2,3,or 4.  See [PRETTYMANETAL2003] for details of the
    neutron data reduction process. See [FELDMANETAL2002] and
    [BOYNTONETAL2003] for details of the neutron spectrometer
    design and operation.
 
    The NS detector consists of a cubical block of boron-loaded
    plastic scintillator. It is segmented into four prism-shaped
    quadrants that are optically isolated from each other. Thermal-
    and epithermal-neutrons are detected via the 10B(n,alpha)7Li*
    reaction, which produces a distinct peak in the pulse height
    spectrum at 93 keV electron equivalent light output due to the
    recoil of the reaction products. Fast neutrons are detected by
    construction of a pulse height spectrum from the early and late
    time histograms recorded in the NS EDR data.
 
    The first step in processing NS DND data is a calculation using
    the NS EDR EVENTS array. The results of this processing are used
    to monitor the time dependence of the gain of each prism of the
    NS by calculating the centroid (PRISMx_CENTROID) of the 93 keV
    electron equivalent peak in the second-pulse spectrum
    constructed from event mode data. (Additional information
    regarding the event-mode parameters can be found in
    [FELDMANETAL2002].) For each collection interval, the event mode
    data is accumulated over coarse time intervals, 721 x ~19.75s.
    The event mode data is accumulated using a sliding scale, i.e.
    by summing the event data from 360 collection intervals before
    and 360 collection intervals after the collection interval of
    interest with the collection interval of interest. The event
    values are added to the accumulation if the time to second pulse
    values are between 3 to 53, the event values are subtracted from
    the accumulation if the time to second pulse values are between
    199 and 259. If the time to second pulse is not within either
    range than nothing is added or subtracted to the total. The
    resulting spectrum reveals the 93 keV electron equivalent peak
    as the second peak in the spectrum. The peak location is
    proportional to the gain of the prism, which is found to change
    with time. The centroid (PRISMx_CENTROID) of the peak is
    calculated using a gaussian fitting algorithm. This centroid is
    recorded, and used later in the processing.
 
    For each prism, the net count rate (peak area) for the pulse
    height spectrum at 93 keV electron equivalent light output is
    determined from the Category 1 pulse height spectrum (NS EDR
    CAT1_x_HIST), a spectrum of single-interaction events recorded
    every ~19.75s. During a single measurement interval, the
    spacecraft traverses approximately one degree of arc length
    (roughly 60 km). The algorithm used to generate time series
    Category 1 peak area data (CAT1_PRISMx_PEAK_AREA) is implemented
    as a sliding window 3 x ~19.75s long, with one record before and
    one record after being summed with the collection interval of
    interest. The time interval is selected such that counting
    precision is sufficient to reliably determine the background and
    the distance traveled by the spectrometer is small compared to
    the footprint (approximately 10-degrees of arc length). The
    background under the peak for each prism is determined by
    fitting a line to points above and below the peak
    (CAT1_PRISMx_BACKGROUND).
 
    The thermal neutron count rate (CAT1_PRISM4_PEAK_AREA,
    CAT1_PRISM2_PEAK_AREA) is determined by subtracting 0.85
    times the count rate measured by the backward looking prism (P4)
    from the forward looking prism (P2). For the purpose
    of making a thermal neutron map, use the latitude/ longitude
    values projected 4.5-degrees ahead of the spacecraft (LAT_4_5,
    LON_4_5). The rationale for selecting the factor 0.85 is
    described in [PRETTYMANETAL2003]. The epithermal neutron count
    rate is taken to be the count rate for P1
    (CAT1_PRISM1_PEAK_AREA). The 1-degree projected latitude/
    longitude values should be used to make epithermal neutron maps
    (LAT_01, LON_01).
 
    For fast neutrons, histogram data (EARLY_HIST, LATE_HIST in NS
    EDR data) for which first pulses with magnitude above a pre-set
    threshold are binned into histograms for early and late time
    windows are used for the fast neutron spectrum calculation. The
    early time interval is selected so that it is sensitive to
    neutrons slowing down in the spectrometer. The late time
    interval is selected so that it is well beyond the die-away time
    of neutrons in the spectrometer and thus contains accidental
    events. Subtraction of the late from early time histograms
    yields a pulse height spectrum that is sensitive to fast
    neutrons. Only the sum of the first two energy bins (which
    correspond to energies between 0.7 and 1.6 MeV) are used for the
    fast_sum_counts (CAT2_PRISMx_FAST_SUM).
 
    Counting data can, for each prism, be normalized to the average
    count rate observed between latitudes plus or minus 40-degrees
    (the &apos;belly-band&apos;) every 12 orbits, which is about one Martian
    day.  An average, belly-band count rate is determined for each
    measurement location using a sliding window that extends plus
    or minus 6 orbits relative to the location (PRISMx_FAST_NORM,
    PRISMx_PEAK_NORM). We recommend that each count rate be divided
    by its corresponding belly-band average to produced a normalized
    count rate. For example, the normalized thermal neutron count
    rate would be:
 
    (CAT1_PRISM2_PEAK_AREA/PRISM2_PEAK_NORM) - (0.85 *
    CAT1_PRISM4_PEAK_AREA/PRISM4_PEAK_NORM)
 
    The &apos;belly-band&apos; normalization is designed to minimize
    variations in count rate due to instrumental drift, variations
    in the galactic cosmic ray flux, and diurnal and seasonal
    changes in globally averaged atmospheric mass. This
    approach to normalization assumes that the mid-latitude
    composition does not change significantly with time, which
    enables precise determination of seasonal variations in count
    rates at polar latitudes. The normalization period of 12-orbits
    was selected so that nearly full coverage of the mid-latitudes
    was achieved by the spectrometer. To get a time series of
    absolute counting rates, multiply the normalized count rate by
    that observed at a reference time or the average count rate
    observed for a selected time interval (see ancillary data for
    these values). For example, the absolute thermal neutron count
    rate would be:
 
     ((CAT1_PRISM2_PEAK_AREA/PRISM2_PEAK_NORM) * 9.681) - (0.85 *
     ((CAT1_PRISM4_PEAK_AREA/PRISM4_PEAK_NORM) * 3.148))
 
 
  Data
  ====
   The DND data set is composed of a series of date stamped files
   that contain 24-hours worth of data.
 
 
    Derived Neutron Data
    --------------------
      Derived Neutron Data are composed of the derived neutron
      data and the associated timing, spatial, and engineering
      information for each ~19.7 second collection interval. The
      derived neutron data consists of 39 columns of data that are
      output from the derived neutron data processing. The timing
      and spatial data provided with the DND includes spacecraft
      clock values and spacecraft geometry data. The sc_ev_time,
      UTC time and spatial fields are all recorded at the center
      of the collection interval. The associated engineering data
      is obtained from a linear interpolation of the engineering
      data packet received just before and just after the neutron
      data collection interval of interest.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
    The &apos;absolute&apos; normalization constants are as follows:
 
    N1: 7.325 (CAT1, Prism 1)
    N2: 9.681 (CAT1, Prism 2)
    N3: 2.684 (CAT1, Prism 3)
    N4: 3.148 (CAT1, Prism 4)
    F1: 1.445 (Fast Histogram, Prism 1)
    F3: 1.183 (Fast Histogram, Prism 3)
 
    The units are counts per second.
 
 
  Coordinate System
  =================
   The coordinate system used for all GRS data is a Mars
   aerocentric system following the IAU convention
   [SEIDELMANNETAL2002], with east longitudes from 0 to 360.
 
 
  Software
  ========
    A library of source code to parse the DND data product files
    is included in the software directory. This library allows a
    programmer to build applications that display or manipulate
    DND data. This source is written in the Java language, and
    requires version 1.3 of the Java Runtime Environment (JRE) or
    Java Software Development Kit (SDK).
 
    Documentation for the code is located in the software directory
    in the file GRS_DR_CODE_DOC.ZIP. The contents of this file are
    described in the label GRS_DR_CODE_DOC.LBL and the source and
    the binary classes that make up the library are in the file
    DR_CODE.JAR.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
    The DND will be delivered using CDROM media. Formats will be
    based on standards for such products established by the
    Planetary Data System (PDS) [PDSSR2001].
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    The data presented in the DND is intended to be the first
    intermediate data set released for the neutron spectrometer
    sub-system of the GRS. Data presented here are a highly
    processed representation of the neutron data as received from
    the spacecraft. It is possible that changes will be made in the
    neutron processing algorithms if errors are found. If errors
    are found, the data will have to be regenerated from the raw
    unprocessed neutron data set.
 
 
  Review
  ======
    The DND was reviewed internally by the GRS team prior to
    release to the PDS. PDS will also perform an external peer
    review of the DND.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    In order to consider data for inclusion in the time series, we
    required that the instrument be aligned along the bore-site
    vector.  This eliminated instances such as when the spacecraft
    was in event mode in which P1 was not pointed in the nadir
    direction.  We also required that the data in the 3 x 19.75s
    buffer be contiguous, separated by no more than 1-degree of arc
    length.  This avoided the introduction of errors in the
    counting data when orbital data were missing.  Finally, we did
    not process data for time intervals in which the overload
    monitor of the neutron spectrometer exceeded 7000 counts per
    second, which corresponded to solar energetic particle events.
 
 
  Limitations
  ===========
    The major limitation of this data set is that it is derived from
    the raw minimally processed data. The data is received from
    spacecraft telemetry, and ingested into a database. If gaps
    exist in the telemetry, data is lost. Timing and spatial
    components of the data set rely on the accuracy of the NAIF
    SPICE kernels. The validity of the derived neutron data is based
    on the &apos;correctness&apos; of each step in the processing. It is
    possible that changes will be made in the processing if errors
    are found. If errors are found, the data will have to be
    regenerated from the raw unprocessed data set.
 
 
  Data Compression
  ===============
  No compression is used on the DND data set.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED_ACCUMULATING</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>NULL</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

