<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.ear-a-rdr-3-52color-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>52 COLOR ASTEROID SURVEY V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.support_archives::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:unk.unk::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:asteroid.asteroid::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.ear-a-rdr-3-52color-v1.0__browserp_ear-a-rdr-3-52color-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.sbn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Cruikshank, D.P., and W.K. Hartmann, The meteorite-asteroid connection:
                   Two olivine-rich asteroids, Science 223, 281-283, 1984.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.CRUIKSHANK-HARTM1984</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>EAR-A-RDR-3-52COLOR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>52 COLOR ASTEROID SURVEY V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1995-03-31</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1983</start_time>
        <stop_time>1987</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>JEFFREY F. BELL</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Citation TBD
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            52-color IR spectra of numbered asteroids
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The observations were made using a double CVF (circularly
            variable filter). The short wavelength portion of the CVF covered
            the octave from 0.8 to 1.6 microns with 3 percent resolution,
            while the long wavelength portion covered 1.5 to 2.6 microns with
            5 percent resolution. There is some overlap in the spectral
            coverage between 1.5 and 1.6 microns, which is evident as a
            discontinuity in the wavelengths after the first 32 values, which
            were obtained with the short wavelength portion, while the
            remaining 20 values were obtained with the long wavelength
            portion.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
  The observations were made using a double CVF (circularly variable
  filter).  The short wavelength portion of the CVF covered the
  octave from 0.8 to 1.6 microns with 3 percent resolution, while the
  long wavelength portion covered 1.5 to 2.6 microns with 5 percent
  resolution.  There is some overlap in the spectral coverage between
  1.5 and 1.6 microns, which is evident as a discontinuity in the
  wavelengths after the first 32 values, which were obtained with the
  short wavelength portion, while the remaining 20 values were
  obtained with the long wavelength portion.
 
  Errors were computed from the standard deviation of the multiple
  scans through the CVF.  If only one scan was performed, the error
  is left blank.  Note that due to the small number of scans, the
  errors are often both underestimated and overestimated.
 
  Some wavelength positions correspond to telluric features and were
  intentionally blanked.  In other cases, especially near the ends of
  the CVF, the data were either not taken or were hopelessly noisy,
  so those entries were also blanked.
 
  The following code letters are used for the various solar analog
  stars:
                 A = 18 Aquarii
                 B = 16 Cygni B
                 O = 13 Orionis
                 V = 70 Virginis
 
  The observation date for 113 Amalthea is given as 054/05/85 in the
  original machine readable data file.  The assumption has been made
  that the 4 is a typographical error, based on the fact that other
  observations were made on 05/05/85.
 
  Not all dates of observation are available.  In particular, those
  asteroid observations contributed by R.H. Brown did not include
  observation dates in the original machine readable data file.
 
  One observation was taken from the literature, namely Cruikshank
  and Hartmann (1984) [CRUIKSHANK&amp;HARTM1984].
 
  Reference:  Cruikshank, D.P., and W.K. Hartmann 1984.  The
  meteorite- asteroid connection: Two olivine-rich asteroids.
  Science 223, 281-283.
 
 
  Parameters
  ==========
  The data tables have one entry for each observation, with fields
  for the following parameters.  Asteroid catalog number, a code for
  the solar analog star used with that observation, the date of
  observation, and reflectances and error values for each of 52
  bandpasses.
 
 
  Data
  ====
  The reflectances in each of the 52 bands are given in the table
  &apos;52color.tab&apos;.  The errors are given in the table &apos;52error.tab&apos;.
  The asteroid identification, solar analog code, and observation
  date are provided in each of these two files.
 
 
  Ancillary Data
  ==============
  The ancillary file &apos;52waves.tab&apos; presents the effective wavelengths
  of each of the 52 positions of the CVF which were used for the
  survey, arranged in a single record with a separate field for each
  wavelength.  The file &apos;52waves2.tab gives the same information
  arranged with one wavelength per record.  Each record also contains
  the FWHM of the bandpass.
 
 
  Media/Format
  ============
  This dataset is released in the form of ASCII files which may be
  stored on disk or other magnetic medium and which may be
  distributed by ftp, email, real-time access by remote login, or by
  whatever means is most convenient.
 
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Review
  ======
  This dataset was included in an external review on March 31, 1995.
 
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>SUPERSEDED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>CD-WO</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>GD-11F</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

