<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.co-e-sw-j-s-mag-3-rdr-calib-shm-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>CASSINI SCALAR MAGNETOMETER CALIB DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.cassini-huygens::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:mag.co::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.earth::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.jupiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.saturn::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:planet.venus::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:plasma_stream.solar_wind::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.titan::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.co-e-sw-j-s-mag-3-rdr-calib-shm-v1.0__browserp_co-e-sw-j-s-mag-3-rdr-calib-shm-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Dougherty, M.K., S. Kellock, D.J. Southwood, A. Balogh, E.J. Smith, B.T.
                   Tsurutani, B. Gerlach, K.H. Glassmeier, F. Gleim, C.T. Russell, G. Erdos, F.M.
                   Neubauer, and S.W.H. Cowley, The Cassini Magnetic Field Investigation, Space
                   Science Reviews, Vol. 114, Nos. 1-4, pp. 331-383, September 2004
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.DOUGHERTYETAL2004</description>
        </External_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Smith, E.J., M.K. Dougherty, C.T. Russell, and D.J. Southwood, Scalar helium
                   magnetometer observations at Cassini Earth swing-by, J. Geophys. Res., 106,
                   30129, 2001.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.SMITHETAL2001</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>CO-E/SW/J/S-MAG-3-RDR-CALIB-SHM-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>CASSINI SCALAR MAGNETOMETER CALIB DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2006-07-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1999-08-16T00:00:03.935Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2005-10-12T00:28:38.488Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>PETER SLOOTWEG</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Dougherty, M.K., S. Kellock, A.P. Slootweg, and N. Achilleos,
            CASSINI E/SW/J/S MAG CALIB SHM V1.0,
            CO-E/SW/J/S-MAG-3-RDR-CALIB-SHM-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System,
            2004.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            This dataset contains calibrated (RDR) full sampling resolution
            scalar magnetic-field data acquired during the cruise and tour
            phases of the Cassini mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains magnetic-field data acquired during the
            cruise and tour phases of the Cassini mission to Saturn. Data
            collection began on 16 August (day 228), 1999. On this date, two
            days before the spacecraft commenced Earth swingby, the
            magnetometer boom was unfurled into its extended position; a
            configuration it maintained for the remainder of the mission.
            This dataset contains the data collected from the helium
            magnetometer while in scalar mode (SHM). The SHM mode is used
            only when high fields are expected, this means that SHM data is
            only collected infrequently and ceased being collected after 17
            November (day 321), 2005 due to an instrument failure.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    This data set contains magnetic-field data acquired during the
    cruise and tour phases of the Cassini mission to Saturn. The data
    set begins with data collected on 16 August (day 228), 1999 and ends
    on 17 November (day 321), 2005 when the instrument failed.
    On 16 August, 1999 two days before the spacecraft commenced Earth
    swingby, the magnetometer boom was unfurled into its extended
    position; a  configuration it maintained for the remainder of the
    mission.  Magnetic-field data acquired prior to boom deployment are
    limited and are significantly affected by spacecraft noise. These data
    are of no scientific value and, consequently, do not form part of this
    data set.
 
    Cassini carried two magnetometers: a fluxgate magnetometer (FGM)
    and a vector-helium magnetometer capable of operating in both
    vector and scalar mode (V/SHM). This data set contains the magnetic-
    field and calibration data recorded by the helium magnetometer when
    operating in scalar mode. The data are divided into time periods of one
    day and saved in files using the UCLA flatfile system. In this system,
    data are recorded in binary files that have associated text header files
    describing the format and content of the data.
 
    The magnetic-field data are contained in the SHM data
    products which can be identified from the &apos;SHM*_C&apos; in their file
    names. The SHM submitted is already calibrated.
 
    Data are received from Cassini in science or housekeeping telemetry
    packets. Data from both these streams form part of this data set.
    The naming convention used for data files allows the telemetry
    source and date of acquisition to be readily determined from the
    file name. On any given date, the science and housekeeping data for
    a particular magnetometer cover the same time interval to within a
    few seconds. Science and housekeeping data files have identical
    formats and are processed in exactly the same way.
 
    The magnetic-field data have been extracted from telemetry packets,
    assigned time tags, and formatted into simple binary tables of
    values in nano-Teslas.
 
    The MAG data products in this dataset is:
    Data    Description
    SHM_C   Calibrated scalar data from helium magnetometer
 
    The format of files containing this data product is described in
    full in the archive volume SIS, found on this volume called the
    &apos;THE CASSINI MAGNETIC FIELD INVESTIGATION&apos; by Dougherty et al.
 
  Data
  ====
 
    SHM data is given in the following columns:
      1. time TAI (SCET in seconds since 12:00:00.000Z 1 Jan 2000)
      2. B_SHM (in nT)
      3. X_IAU_S (in Km)
      4. Y_IAU_S (in Km)
      5. Z_IAU_S (in Km)
 
 
  Data Parameters
  ===============
    Magnetic-field units
    --------------------
    The units of the magnetic-field data are given as
    nanoTesla (nT). They represent the magnetic field values at
    the given time.
 
 
    MAGStatus
    ---------
    There are no status words in the calibrated files
 
    MAG times
    ---------
    The Cassini spacecraft clock (SCLK) is a counter that advances by
    one tick nominally every 1/256 seconds. SCLK times have the format
    cccc:ttt, in which cccc specifies the number of full counts that have
    elapsed (one full count = 256 ticks), and ttt indicates by how many
    ticks the clock has advanced towards the next count, since the epoch
    00:00:00Z 1 January 1958.
 
    SCLK counts may also include a partition number, p/cccc:ttt. This
    number is initially 1 but is incremented during the mission if the
    SCLK counter is reset or somehow interrupted or altered. The following
    discussion assumes a partition number of 1. For other partition
    numbers, the determination of SCLK times requires knowledge of the time
    at which the current partition was initiated.
 
    SCLK times are commonly recorded in MAG files as decimal counts. Time
    may also be represented in MAG files as Spacecraft Event Time (SCET)
    which, for Cassini, is Universal Time Coordinated (UTC). The
    relationship between SCLK and SCET/UTC is dependent on the count rate
    of the Cassini SCLK. Like most counter-based clocks, this rate is not
    constant but drifts with time. Consequently, conversion of SCLK times
    to SCET/UTC times requires knowledge of the drift rates. These rates
    are recorded in the SCLK/SCET coefficients file maintained by the
    Cassini Spacecraft Operations (SCO) team at JPL. As the Cassini mission
    progresses, the difference between SCLK and SCET will typically be of
    order tens of minutes.
 
    Times in MAG data files
 
    The times associated with magnetic-field scalar values in MAG data files
    are SCET in seconds since epoch 2000 in TAI (International Atomic Time)
 
    Times in MAG header files
 
    FIRST TIME
    SCLK time of first record in data file; derived from primary header of
    CHDO file
 
    LAST TIME
    SCLK time of last record in data file; derived from primary header of
    CHDO file
 
    SCLK (in ABSTRACT)
    SCLK count obtained from tertiary header of CHDO file; also converted
    into year, day of year, month, date, time format; may differ from
    FIRST TIME by some minutes
 
    SCET (in ABSTRACT)
    year, day of year, month, date, time format; determined from corrected
    SCLK count; also converted into an equivalent SCET count of seconds
    since 1958
 
    Times in MAG label files
 
    START_TIME
    SCLK time of first record in data file; obtained from FIRST TIME in
    flatfile header
 
    STOP_TIME
    SCLK time of last record in data file; obtained from LAST TIME in
    flatfile header
 
    SPACECRAFT_CLOCK_START_COUNT
    SCLK time of first record in data file; determined from SPICE
    utility CHRONOS using START_TIME; format p/ssss.ttt
 
    SPACECRAFT_CLOCK_STOP_COUNT
    SCLK time of last record in data file; determined from SPICE utility
    CHRONOS using STOP_TIME; format p/ssss.ttt
 
    SCLK (in NOTE)
    SCLK count obtained from tertiary header of CHDO file; also converted
    into year, day of year, month, date, time format; obtained from
    flatfile-header ABSTRACT; may differ from START_TIME by some minutes
 
    SCET (in NOTE)
    year, day of year, month, date, time format; determined from
    corrected SCLK time; also converted into an equivalent SCET count of
    seconds since 1958; obtained from flatfile-header ABSTRACT
 
  Processing
  ==========
    The processing software converts time from SCLK(1958) to TAI, subtracts
    a small calibration correction from the scalar field values, and appends
    XYZ position of Cassini with respect to either Earth or Saturn in
    IAU_EARTH or IAU_SATURN coordinate systems respectively. Only valid
    Scalar data points (LOCK bit = TRUE) are written to the output flatfile.
    A delay of 0.7s is subtracted from each time tag, 0.5s because the input
    time stamp is the end of the 1s interval over which the measurement is
    made, and an additional 0.2s determined from a fit of ESB data to the
    model field. The additional 0.2s delay is subject to revision. In order
    to calculate the calibration correction to the SHM value of B, the
    approximate angles of the field are needed, which can be obtained from
    the FGM. So for each SHM value, an FGM vector avg is calculated over
    [t-1sec,t], where t is the SHM time. The FGM vector is then transformed
    into the SHM/VHM sensor coordinate system (nominal deployed orientations
    are used). A total correction, including a Bloch-Siegert correction, is
    then calculated.
 
  Ancillary data
  ==============
    Data such as analog, command validation, configuration image,
    error counter and user-defined engineering data, are included
    in this archive for completeness and are not required for
    processing the magnetic-field data.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    There is irregular timing in the data samples.  This is caused by
    the limited resolution of the msec counter in the time field.
    For example, there are 128 FGM vectors in each science packet, the
    time of the packet corresponds to the time of the first vector in
    the packet. Times are calculated for the other vectors using the
    known onboard vector sample rate and average exponent. These
    calculated times don&apos;t have the reduced resolution of the msec
    counter. Thus at the first vector of each packet there can be a
    small time jump due to the msec counter resolution. This time
    difference is maximum 8 msecs (not 4msecs which is the resolution
    of the counter) because the DPU software only generates even msec
    values due to internal truncation.
 
    Data Coverage and Quality
    -------------------------
    There are routine events that cause data quality problems so
    chronological listings of them have been included in this archive:
      -calibration activities superimpose calibration data on top of
       science data and are documented in SCAS_TIMES.ASC (for more
       information on calibration activies refer to &apos;THE CASSINI MAGNETIC
       FIELD INVESTIGATION&apos; by Dougherty et al in this archive)
      -data spikes may be seen at instrument range changes. Range changes
       are documented in RANGE_CHANGES.ASC
      -mode changes affect which sensors produce instrument data and
       spikes or rapid changes in data averaging may be seen at mode
       changes.  The first few packets after the instrument is unmuted or
       after Science Packets recommence can be highly or incorrectly
       averaged.  MODE_CHANGES.ASC lists the times of these events.
    Range changes are the only routine events that will normally effect
    SHM data.
 
    Data gaps may be instrument related (e.g. a sensor turning on/off) or
    mission related (e.g. telemetry downlink problems). The former are
    documented in MODE_CHANGES.ASC. All mission related gaps are listed in
    GAP_FILEs - GAP_FILE_SCI_HK.ASC for science data in the housekeeping
    packets and in GAP_FILE_SCI_SD.ASC for science data in the science
    packets. Instrument related gaps of less than one day also show up in
    the GAP_FILES as well as in MODE_CHANGES.ASC
 
    Most of the information in the GAP_FILEs are extracted from packets
    received reports and so follow a fixed-width tabular format.
    Multi-day gaps are not documented in the source listings and have been
    added manually with a different format including an explanation of the
    gap - if a reason is known.  A summary of scientifically significant
    gaps is included below.
 
    Gaps
    ----
 
   SHM On
   1999-230
        Earth Swing-by
   2000-209
        Quiet Test no data collected
   2000-267
         Quiet Test no data collected
   2003-236
        SSR Library Test no data collected
   2004-178 to 183
        A VHM/SHM mode change was scheduled to occur at this
        time but it did not occur
   2004-344
        SHM test no data collected
   2005-047T21:15:09 to 2005-048T04:29:00
        SATURN INTFLD AND ENCELADUS FLYBY
   2005-068T08:05:26 to 2005-068T15:09:18
        ENCELADUS FLYBY, SATURN INTFLD AND TETHYS FLYBY
   2005-088T23:59:45 to 2005-089T03:14:17
        ENCELADUS FLYBY AND SATURN INTFLD
        A power failure and other technical problems resulted in 66% of
        science data from day 88 being lost.  This includes a data gap
        from 19:30 to 24:00 during which the craft was flying by Enceladus
        and in Saturn&apos;s internal field.
        The SHM actually went on earlier than recorded but the first SHM
        data received is from 23:59:45.
        SHM on/VHM off
   2005-104T19:00:25 to 2005-105T03:39:15
        SATURN INTFLD AND MIMAS FLYBY SHM on/VHM off
   2005-122T22:20:28 to 2005-123T05:54:19
        TETHYS FLYBY AND SATURN INTFLD SHM on/VHM off
   2005-141T02:35:26 to 2005-141T10:09:17
        ENCELADUS FLYBY AND SATURN INTFLD SHM on/VHM off
   2005-159T07:10:28 to 2005-159T14:44:19
        SATURN INTFLD SHM on/VHM off
   2005-177T12:13:29 to 2005-177T19:47:20
        SATURN INTFLD SHM on/VHM off
   2005-195T18:41:28 to 2005-196T02:14:19
     ENCELADUS FLYBY AND SATURN INTFLD SHM on/VHM off
   2005-214T02:21:27 to 2005-214T09:55:18
     SATURN INTFLD AND MIMAS FLYBY SHM on/VHM off
   2005-232T07:44:26 to 2005-232T15:19:18
     SATURN INTFLD SHM on/VHM off
   2005-248T07:26:24 to 2005-248T10:52:06
     SATURN INTFLD SHM on/VHM off
     SHM off earlier than planned due to BIU sick
   2005-266T17:30:24 to 2005-267T01:39:14
     SATURN INTFLD AND TETHYS FLYBY SHM on/VHM off
   2005-284T21:28:25 to 2005-285T05:36:16
     SHM on/ VHM off
   2005-322
     V/SHM failed, data degraded data from or after this
     day is not suitable for science use and will not be
     submitted
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>IN_PEER_REVIEW</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

