<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lp-l-eng-6-sunpulse-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LP MOON SUN PULSE DATA V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_prospector::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:eng.lp::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lp-l-eng-6-sunpulse-v1.0__browserp_lp-l-eng-6-sunpulse-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lp-l-eng-6-sunpulse-v1.0__browser_geo_lp-l-eng-6-sunpulse-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lp-l-eng-6-sunpulse-v1.0__dvo_geo_lp-l-eng-6-sunpulse-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.ppi-ucla::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Binder, A.B., W.C. Feldman, G.S. Hubbard, A.S. Konopliv, R.P. Lin, M.H. Acuna,
                   and L.L. Hood, Lunar Prospector searches for polar ice, a metallic core, gas
                   release events, and the moon&apos;s origin, Eos, Trans. AGU, 79, 97, 1998.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.BINDERETAL1998</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LP-L-ENG-6-SUNPULSE-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LP MOON SUN PULSE DATA V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>1998-06-01</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>1998-01-07T09:36Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>1999-07-29T18:10Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>ALAN B. BINDER</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Binder, A.B., W.C. Feldman, A.S.Konopliv, R.P. Lin, M.H. Acuna,
            L.L. Hood, and E.A. Guinness, LP MOON SUN PULSE DATA V1.0,
            LP-L-ENG-6-SUNPULSE-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 1998.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            The sun pulse data set is a record of times that the Lunar
            Prospector sun sensor detects the Sun.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            The sun pulse data set is a record of times that the Lunar
            Prospector sun sensor detects the Sun. These sun pulse times are
            derived from ground processing of the sun sensor data, earth-moon
            limb sensor data, and the spacecraft ephemeris. This data set is
            part of the Lunar Prospector Level 0 data archive. The sun pulse
            times are used in determining the spacecraft spin rate and
            orientation as a function of time. Because the Lunar Prospector
            spacecraft is sometimes in eclipse with the Sun, the sun pulse
            data set is generated on the ground to include both actual sun
            pulse times based on the sun sensor measurements and estimated
            sun pulse times based on the history of spin rate change during
            all prior eclipses.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
    The sun pulse data set is a record of times that the Lunar Prospector
    sun sensor detects the Sun.  These sun pulse times are derived from
    ground processing of the sun sensor data, earth-moon limb sensor data,
    and the spacecraft ephemeris.  This data set is part of the Lunar
    Prospector Level 0 data archive.  The sun pulse times are used in
    determining the spacecraft spin rate and orientation as a function of
    time.  Because the Lunar Prospector spacecraft is sometimes in eclipse
    with the Sun, the sun pulse data set is generated on the ground to
    include both actual sun pulse times based on the sun sensor
    measurements and estimated sun pulse times based on the history of
    spin rate change during all prior eclipses.  See the
    CONFIDENCE_LEVEL_NOTE field for further information on how sun pulse
    time is estimated during eclipses.
 
    The sun pulse data set is organized into files, each of which cover
    about 4-6 hours of time.  In general, each sun pulse file matches the
    time range of a corresponding merged telemetry file.  There is usually
    one sun pulse record for every other minor frame of the merged
    telemetry file.
 
 
  Science Objectives
  ==================
    The Lunar Prospector science objectives relevant to this data set are
    to map the Moon&apos;s surface composition and its magnetic field, and to
    determine the frequency and location of gas release events.  A special
    emphasis of the science objectives is to search for polar water ice
    deposits [BINDERETAL1998].
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
 
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
    When Lunar Prospector was in sunlight, the sun pulse time was set
    equal to the sun sensor time extracted from the telemetry files.  When
    the spacecraft was in eclipse, the sun pulse was estimated using the
    pre-eclipse measured spin rate, the calibrated spin rate change during
    eclipse, and limb sensor telemetry.  The uncertainty in an estimated
    sun pulse time was also determined and stored in the data set.  Each
    sun pulse record contains a flag indicating whether the value is an
    actual or estimated value.
 
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
    Sun sensor data were acquired continuously by Lunar Prospector during
    the Primary and Extended Missions.  However, gaps can occur in the
    telemetry data.  The times of these gaps are documented in a log file
    included with the level 0 archive.  There were 18 sun pulse files
    missing from the archive volume that contained the matching telemetry
    file because solutions were not complete at the time the archive
    volume was produced.  The missing sun pulse files are included on the
    last level 0 volume (LP_0019) in the SUNPULSE/DXXX directory. The 18
    late sun pulse files are documented in the ERRATA.TXT file.
 
    The earth-moon limb sensor was turned off toward the end of the
    Primary Mission and into the Extended Mission to extend the spacecraft
    battery life.  Thus these data were not always available for
    estimating sun pulses during times of spacecraft eclipses.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>ELECTRONIC</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

