<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.sch" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<Product_Data_Set_PDS3 xmlns="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"
 xmlns:pds="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1"  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
 xsi:schemaLocation="http://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1 https://pds.nasa.gov/pds4/pds/v1/PDS4_PDS_1600.xsd">
    
    <Identification_Area>
        <logical_identifier>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:data_set:data_set.lro-l-lola-3-radr-v1.0</logical_identifier>
        <version_id>1.0</version_id>
        <title>LRO MOON LASER ALTIMETER 3 RADR V1.0</title>
        <information_model_version>1.6.0.0</information_model_version>
        <product_class>Product_Data_Set_PDS3</product_class>
        <Modification_History>
            <Modification_Detail>
                <modification_date>2016-10-01</modification_date>
                <version_id>1.0</version_id>
                <description>
                    extracted metadata from PDS3 catalog and
                    modified to comply with PDS4 Information Model
                </description>
            </Modification_Detail>
        </Modification_History>
    </Identification_Area>
    
    <Reference_List>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:investigation:mission.lunar_reconnaissance_orbiter::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_mission</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument_host:spacecraft.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument_host</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:instrument:lola.lro::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_instrument</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:target:satellite.moon::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_target</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:resource:resource.lro-l-lola-3-radr-v1.0__browserp_lro-l-lola-3-radr-v1.0::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_resource</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <Internal_Reference>
            <lidvid_reference>urn:nasa:pds:context_pds3:node:node.geoscience::1.0</lidvid_reference>
            <reference_type>has_node</reference_type>
        </Internal_Reference>
        <External_Reference>
            <reference_text>
                   Lemelin, M., P.G. Lucey, G.A. Neumann, E.M. Mazarico, A. Kakazu, D. Trang, D.E.
                   Smith, and M.T. Zuber, Improved calibration of reflectance data from Lunar
                   Reconnaissance Orbiter Lunar Orbiter Laser Altimeter (LOLA) and implications
                   for space weathering, Icarus, submitted.
            </reference_text>
            <description>reference.LEMELINETAL2016</description>
        </External_Reference>
    </Reference_List>
    
    <Data_Set_PDS3>
        <data_set_id>LRO-L-LOLA-3-RADR-V1.0</data_set_id>
        <data_set_name>LRO MOON LASER ALTIMETER 3 RADR V1.0</data_set_name>
        <data_set_release_date>2015-12-15</data_set_release_date>
        <start_time>2009-09-15T21:52:46Z</start_time>
        <stop_time>2010-09-16T19:15:57Z</stop_time>
        <producer_full_name>DAVID E. SMITH</producer_full_name>
        <citation_text>
            Smith, D.E., 2009 Lunar Orbiter Laser Altimeter Radiometry Data
            Set, LRO-L-LOLA-3-RADR-V1.0, NASA Planetary Data System, 2015.
        </citation_text>
        <data_set_terse_desc>
            Radiometry (albedo) science data from the nominal mission phases
            of the 2009 Lunar Reconnaissance Orbiter mission.
        </data_set_terse_desc>
        <abstract_desc>
            This data set contains archival radiometric data derived from
            reduced altimetry measured by the Lunar Orbiter Laser Altimeter
            instrument during LRO&apos;s Nominal Mission. LOLA is a pulse
            detection, time-of-flight laser altimeter that measures the
            distance between the LRO spacecraft and the surface of the Moon.
            LOLA transmits a 5-spot pattern, thus providing 5 simultaneous
            profiles across the lunar surface whose separation depends on
            spacecraft altitude. LOLA also measures the energy of the return
            pulses, which enables the calculation of the surface albedo after
            calibration.
        </abstract_desc>
        <data_set_desc>
 
  Data Set Overview
  =================
  This data product is presented as along-track profiles that contain normal
  albedo, the radiance of the Moon at zero phase angle relative to a Lambert
  surface illuminated normally.  Calculations are done as described in
  LEMELINETAL2016 using laser data collected during the thirteen Nominal
  Mission phases.
 
  Normal albedo has been corrected for the sensitivity drift of the laser
  with time, and for the loss of signal from temperature-dependent loss of
  alignment of the laser transmitter in the polar regions.
 
  Each TAB file contains data for a given LRO orbit, where each line
  corresponds to a laser return. The data is stored in 13 columns: latitude
  (degrees), longitude (degrees), normal albedo, Terrestrial Dynamic Time,
  laser used, detector used, reflectance (fraction), received energy (zJ),
  transmit energy (mJ), range (km), solar incidence angle (degrees), Off
  nadir angle (degrees), dropoff fit (fraction).  These values, as well as
  their locations with each data file, are described in the accompanying
  LOLARADR.FMT file.
 
  Not every return with valid altimetry has a corresponding albedo value, as
  the energy measurement quality also depends on the solar incidence angle.
  The following conditions were applied to qualify pulses for inclusion in a
  data file: solar incidence angle lower than 90 degrees (daytime data),
  received energy greater than 0.14 zJ, a spacecraft off-nadir angle
  between 0.2 and 0.4 degrees, and an overall range lower than 70 km from
  the surface.
 
  The data acquired using Laser 1 and Laser 2 are archived in separate
  directories.  Instabilities in passive Q-switched lasers cause strong
  variations in the transmitted energy. When normal albedo is calculated
  using data acquired by Laser 1, these anomalies are removed and yield
  proper normalization of the data for the transmitted energy variation.
  However, in the case of Laser 2 data, normalization leaves a residue
  of several percent positive anomalies near the boundaries of change in
  out-going laser pulse energy. The transmitted energy collected by LOLA
  when using Laser 2 may not be a full characterization of the out-going
  laser pulse energy. The normal albedo calculated using data from Laser 2
  has substantially higher uncertainty than that using Laser 1.
 
  Data in the PolarPatch_NP and PolarPatch_SP folders contain normal albedo
  data acquired by Laser 1 at solar incidence angles greater than 90
  degrees (nighttime data), which have been used to fill the gaps in
  coverage near the poles that occur when using day time data only. For the
  south polar region, nighttime data from orbits 4014-4264
  (used in ZUBERETAL2012) were included between 85-90 degrees South.
  For the north polar region, nighttime data from orbits 4850-4971 and
  orbits 5318-5360 were included, between 87-90 degrees North. The nighttime
  normal albedo data have been scaled to the day time normal albedo from
  Laser 1 in overlapping regions.
 
  The data are stored in the following directory structure:
 
  DATA
    |--LOLA_RADR
         |
         |--LASER1
         |     |
         |     |--LRO_[mission phase]_[orbital cycle]
         |     |     |
         |     |     |--LOLARADR_yydddhhmm.TAB
         |     |
         |     |--POLARPATCH_[NP or SP]
         |           |
         |           |--LRO_[mission_phase]_[orbital cycle]
         |                 |
         |                 |----LOLARADR_yydddhhmm_[NP or SP].TAB
         |
         |--LASER2
               |
               |--LRO_[mission phase]_[orbital cycle]
                     |
                     |--LOLARADR_yydddhhmm.TAB
 
  Each data file is accompanied by a PDS label file with the same name,
  extension &apos;.LBL&apos;.
        </data_set_desc>
        <confidence_level_note>
  Confidence Level Overview
  =========================
  The active measurement of reflectance meets the requirements of the LRO
  mission to locate potential lunar resources and map them at ~25-400m scales
  in shadows where exposures of ice-regolith mixtures may be detected. The
  LOLA instrument implemented this measurement with an electronic energy
  measurement function that integrates and samples the peak of the amplified
  detector hybrid output with a track-and-hold function, followed by an 8-bit
  digitizer. The output of the digitizer is proportional to the energy for a
  given amplifier gain. Throughout the bulk of the mission the gain has been
  fixed at its maximum. The baseline of the digitized signal and constant of
  proportionality for each of the five receiver-detector-electronic systems
  were calibrated on the ground. The calibration parameters did not match the
  results obtained in flight, and an independent estimate of the baseline
  was derived by fitting the response as a function of range distance. A
  further estimate of the proportionality was derived from comparisons with
  imaging systems on other missions whose radiometric calibration was more
  precise than can be obtained with a pulsed system. The resulting energy
  measurement is limited to a range of 0.1 - 3 fJ at the detector. Its
  precision above 0.2 fJ is 12% until it reaches saturation, which occurs
  only rarely in flight. Likewise the transmitted energy was calibrated
  on the ground and its precision is nominally 2% when corrected
  for temperature response of the monitor. The accuracy of the transmit
  energy is affected by the proportion of the laser beam sampled which will
  inevitably change in flight as the beam shape changes with age. The scale
  factor of the measurement is affected by the optical system used to sample
  the beam by means of partial transmission and has increased with age.
  Thus the reflectance measurement in flight is limited in range and must be
  calibrated with empirical adjustments.
 
  Calibration Observations
  ========================
  Observations of the LOLA laser and detector through the Earth&apos;s atmosphere
  have been performed in 2009 and 2014. Owing to the slews necessary to put
  the five laser spots within the field of view of the ground system and the
  operational difficulties of pointing the instrument deck away from the Moon
  it has only been possible to characterize the laser beam qualitatively and
  observe changes in its pattern that corroborate the reduction in output
  of each of the two lasers during limited time intervals. The atmosphere
  attenuates the energy as well in an unpredictable fashion. Thus the nominal
  instrument response is adjusted empirically. Lastly, the Earth observations
  have confirmed a misalignment of the laser beams with the detectors that is
  induced by thermal contraction when facing the cold night surface of the
  Moon or deep space. The transition from dayside to night changes the
  alignment and the portion of energy reaching the detector over the course
  of a few minutes on each orbit, and varies with the angle of the orbital
  plane with respect to the sun (beta angle). During the highest beta angle
  season that occurs semiannually the misalignment over the terminator is
  most severe and precludes measurements.
 
  Mission Phases and Intervals
  =========================
  Observations are interrupted by monthly orbit trim maneuvers and data are
  broken into approximately monthly Phases during the LRO Nominal Mission.
  The energy measurements have a more limited range of availability than the
  altimetry and therefore depend strongly on altitude and laser output.
 
  Data Coverage and Quality
  =========================
  The highest quality observations were obtained during the LOLA Nominal
  Mission Phases 01-13.
 
  Mission Phase  Start Time (DOY)  End Time (DOY)
  -------------  ----------------  --------------
  LRO_NO_01      2009-258T21:00    2009-296T17:22
  LRO_NO_02      2009-296T17:22    2009-324T16:00
  LRO_NO_03      2009-324T16:00    2009-351T21:00
  LRO_NO_04      2009-351T21:00    2010-013T19:00
  LRO_NO_05      2010-013T19:00    2010-040T18:18
  LRO_NO_06      2010-040T18:18    2010-068T17:24
  LRO_NO_07      2010-068T17:24    2010-095T16:54
  LRO_NO_08      2010-095T16:54    2010-123T15:59
  LRO_NO_09      2010-123T15:59    2010-150T16:25
  LRO_NO_10      2010-150T16:25    2010-178T17:15
  LRO_NO_11      2010-178T17:15    2010-205T15:41
  LRO_NO_12      2010-205T15:41    2010-232T12:18
  LRO_NO_13      2010-232T12:18    2010-259T18:15
 
  Some Science Mission and Extended Mission Phases have permitted more
  limited measurement of reflectance.  Those data are not currently part of
  this dataset.
 
  Limitations
  ===========
  The precision of individual spot measurements is limited and averaging
  of data along track with exclusion of weaker or inconsistent measurements
  is required to map the observations to the lunar terrain.
        </confidence_level_note>
        <archive_status>ARCHIVED</archive_status>
        <NSSDC>
            <medium_type>N/A</medium_type>
            <nssdc_collection_id>NULL</nssdc_collection_id>
        </NSSDC>
    </Data_Set_PDS3>
</Product_Data_Set_PDS3>

